
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> anniversary of the discovery of the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> came to an end,
        the engaging autobiography of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> further enlivened the drama of this
        event. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Wilkins</ENAMEX>, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">87</TIMEX>, postpones the account of his involvement in the DNA affair
        until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> of the book. Recounting his background and interesting life before
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34 years</TIMEX>) in plain but telling sentences brings to life a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that is almost as
        much out of the ordinary as those of the more flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Watson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first six years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Garden of Eden</ENAMEX>) were followed by a long,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vividly</ENAMEX> described trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> eventually settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>. His
        boyhood was marked by immersion in astronomy and telescope-making, but saddened by the
        painful illness of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX> in school physics was the key for getting into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, where he reveled in the world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Rutherford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Oliphant</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernal</ENAMEX>. Given his leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leanings</ENAMEX>, it was inevitable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> would become involved in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> movement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, with its close connection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>.
        Perhaps too much involvement led to a low degree grade in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> and no hope of remaining at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>. Instead, he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> and joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Luminescence Lab</ENAMEX> being
        established by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Randall</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with whom he would be closely connected for many
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. The work there contributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX>'s scheme for making radar practical in air
        defense—the cavity magnetron that may have turned the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
        Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oliphant</ENAMEX>, then at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, left to work on the atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>
        and took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> along. Life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> was exciting, but beneath the excitement of bomb
        work and mixed feelings upon its success at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erwin Schrodinger</ENAMEX>'s 
        What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Life</ENAMEX>? Along with others who were to unravel the secrets of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>,
        this planted the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>. When, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three transitional years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College London</ENAMEX>'s physics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of a biophysics research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> sponsored by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Research Council</ENAMEX> (MRC), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> was his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>. The attack on DNA structure
        soon began.
        That X-ray diffraction might play a major role in this search rested on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pillars
        unique to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. One was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> lead in using X-ray diffraction to determine
        molecular structures—a crown jewel built on the work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braggs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>),
        Bernal, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Hodgkin</ENAMEX>. The other was the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">pre-World War II</ENAMEX> work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Astbury</ENAMEX> in
        showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fibers</ENAMEX> displayed some crystallinity that, if developed, might be the basis
        of helping to determine the structure. Wilkins confides that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> he knew little of how
        such X-ray analysis might be done. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> he was presented with an opportunity in
        the form of samples of carefully prepared calf <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, given to him by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signer</ENAMEX>. With this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, much better <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> could be obtained and much sharper diffraction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diagrams</ENAMEX> emerged.
        The exploitation of this advance, however, became mired in a colossal error in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Without telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX>, he wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalind Franklin</ENAMEX>, who was on
        her way to join the DNA effort, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> was withdrawing from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> work and that she
        would take over. Unaware of this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Stokes</ENAMEX> continued their work and reported
        at a meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1951</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> were probably in a helical
        conformation with a diameter of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Å</NUMEX>. At the close of the meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin</ENAMEX> assailed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX>, saying that he should stop his DNA work (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX> had written would be the
        case). Understandably, but regrettably, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> continued working in isolation from
        each other.
        Matters worsened. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> and set up DNA structure
        studies with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick</ENAMEX>. They quickly arrived at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-stranded helical structure. But
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> soon demolished it. Likewise, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings College</ENAMEX>
        had a very short life. As if to trump these failures, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bragg</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> studies at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> should stop and that the work should continue
        only at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>. Mismanagement and noncooperation were taking their toll. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> was moving
        toward a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-stranded structure, but away from helices. Indeed, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1952</TIMEX> she initiated a
        discussion with an announcement about the death of the helix. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mysteriously</ENAMEX>, she put aside a
        striking photo of the diffraction pattern of B-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major structural forms
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>) that emerged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1953</TIMEX> as a perfect signature of the helical form. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>
        continued downhill. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> stopped DNA work that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
        Suddenly, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>, life returned to the DNA effort. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linus Pauling</ENAMEX> had just
        published a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-stranded) that did not long survive, but the entrance of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s leading structural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX> into the race reawakened everyone to the centrality of
        DNA structure. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Gosling</ENAMEX> gave to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> the very well-oriented
        diffraction photo of B-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> had taken in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1952</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> assumed
        that it was given to him to do as he wished; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days later</TIMEX>, he showed it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX>.
        Though hardly an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in X-ray diffraction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> sensed that it was strong evidence for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helices</ENAMEX> and sketched it for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick</ENAMEX> on his return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that January</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
        announced she would be moving from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings College</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birkbeck College</ENAMEX> to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernal</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. In giving her final seminar, she switched from her earlier insistence that B-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was
        nonhelical, but did not show the photo that gave the strongest evidence for helicity. This
        shift put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> in a position to move forward on the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, but without
        others' resorting to model <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, the goal would have remained elusive.
        Finally, in mid-February, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Perutz</ENAMEX>, who was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> overseeing
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biophysics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings College</ENAMEX>, passed on to Crick his copy of a report from that
        unit. This report contained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s results that the phosphates were on the outside and
        that the A-form of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> had a special crystalline arrangement called the monoclinic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C2</ENAMEX> space
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. From his work with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crick</ENAMEX> saw immediately that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> in the helical
        structure must be antiparallel and that there were probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> entwined. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX>
        used other data in the report to deduce that there were indeed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erwin Chargaff</ENAMEX> had recently shown that in the base composition of all DNAs examined,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adenines</ENAMEX> and thymines as well as guanines and cytosines are equal, i.e., A = T and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> = C.
        Now released from the ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick</ENAMEX> engaged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a frantic</TIMEX> search
        using model <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. They found a unique way to fit the bases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> by pairing,
        and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7</TIMEX> they had the double-helix model constructed: it obeyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chargaff</ENAMEX> ratios,
        it fit the X-ray data for B-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, and it provided a rational way to encode and transmit
        genetic information to subsequent generations.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> was invited to view the model in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>. He found it stunning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX> asked
        him to be a coauthor of the paper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX>, true to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, declined, as he had not
        been involved in the final monumental stage. Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> had already moved to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birkbeck</ENAMEX>. She received the news of the discovery with equanimity. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a later</TIMEX> examination
        of her notebooks showed that she had moved to favor helices and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> (or possibly a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>) model.
        With the rather complicated story of the greatest discovery in biology in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>
        now reasonably complete, what is one to make of it? There are many answers. I will mention
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX>.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the key role played by model <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> diffraction there is not
        enough information, by orders of magnitude, to locate every atom, as would be possible in
        diffraction by perfect crystals that give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of sharp reflections. Instead, the
        fiber diagram can only provide cues and some specifics, such as the repeat distance. Model
        building is a way of bringing into the picture previously determined bond distances and
        bond angles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> such as the purine and pyrimidine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> and the sugars that are
        unavailable from the fiber diagram. That this was not seen at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings College</ENAMEX> left the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> there well behind in a field that they had pioneered.
        A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lesson is the importance of bringing the full knowledge of single crystal
        analysis to fiber diagram interpretation. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> missed noting that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monoclinic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C2</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> meant that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> in the fiber had to be antiparallel robbed
        them of an important clue to the structure.
        And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biophysics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings College</ENAMEX> was a recipe for
        failure. Riddled by secrecy, diffuse lines of authority, the absence of strategies, and a
        lack of open congeniality, all so well described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX>, who refers to it as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> is a model of how not to succeed in group research.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> research continued at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings College</ENAMEX> in a gradually improving environment: important
        details were worked out. But there was no real renewal, such as aiming at how <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">configured</ENAMEX> to accommodate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> in the nucleus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> enjoyed being included in the
        subsequent awards—the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lasker</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel prizes</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick</ENAMEX>, he was annoyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX>'s
        rendering of events in 
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Double Helix</ENAMEX> . The final chapter of his own autobiography addresses
        the criticism that some have leveled against his cold relation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>, but also his
        happiness in newfound family life. Research gradually gave way to the pursuit of pacifist
        goals in a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and to the popularization of science. His has been a
        useful life, a part of which contributed to the great revolution in biology. It is good to
        have the insight that this book presents in a candid and personal way.
      
    
  
