
  
    
      
        
        In the wake of declarations supporting open access to research literature from
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OECD</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">United Nations' World Summit</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Society</ENAMEX> (WSIS), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> appear to have agreed that the issue warrants a robust, ongoing
        dialogue‚Äîa development undoubtedly in the interest of the scientific community, regardless
        of its ultimate outcome.
        To the extent that listserv messages, editorials, and conference presentations are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of more widespread reactions to the debate, there appear to be a number of
        common misconceptions about what open access is and what problems it can or cannot solve.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> , we plan to explore the more pervasive of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misunderstandings</ENAMEX>, in an effort to expose the real challenges that need to be overcome and
        to identify some possible solutions. Here we address the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of these‚Äîthe perception that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>-charge model puts an unfair burden on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. Subsequently, we will
        address concerns about the long-term economic viability of the open-access model, the
        integrity and quality of work published in open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, and the effect that open
        access will have on scholarly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Publication Charges‚ÄîNothing New</ENAMEX>
        By charging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> a fee to have their work published in lieu of charging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to
        access articles, open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library of Science</ENAMEX> (PLoS) and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioMed Central</ENAMEX> (BMC) have transformed the traditional publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>. This reliance on a
        seemingly untested revenue stream has generated skepticism that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> will be both
        willing and able to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> charges.
        Publication fees are not a phenomenon born of the open-access movement. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        regularly pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several thousands of dollars</NUMEX> in page charges, color charges, correction
        costs, reprint costs, and other fees to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, even when such costs are entirely
        voluntary. In the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMBO Journal</ENAMEX> , for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> are allowed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> pages of text free,
        but are then charged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> per page beyond that. A review of recent issues shows that almost
        all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> pages, voluntarily paying on average over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800</NUMEX> to publish their
        articles.
        Furthermore, in addition to paying other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> charges, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> may be willing to
        pay extra for their articles to be made open access, as several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> have recently
        recognized. A recent survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in the 
        Proceedings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy of Science</ENAMEX> (
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PNAS</ENAMEX> ) found that although 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PNAS</ENAMEX> already makes its content freely available after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>, nearly
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PNAS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> expressed a willingness to pay an ‚Äúopen-access surcharge‚Äù of
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> or more to make their papers available for free online immediately upon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">publication‚Äîthis</ENAMEX> above and beyond the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,700</NUMEX> in page charges that the average 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PNAS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> already pays (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cozzarelli et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        Although we recognize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> who submit to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> may well be a self-selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of enthusiastic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">open-access</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, we have found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 90%</NUMEX> of those who submit manuscripts do
        not request a fee waiver, and the few who do still offer to pay some portion of the
        fee.
        The concern about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' ability to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> charges will become less pressing
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> increasingly support open-access
        publication on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>' behalf. More funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Medical Institute</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellcome Trust</ENAMEX>, and others who have already designated funds
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">open-access</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. (For more information about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">funders</ENAMEX>' announcements and
        other international policy statements relevant to open access, see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plos</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/openaccess.</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Universities</ENAMEX>, too, are supporting open access directly by setting aside funds for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">open-access</ENAMEX> publication through institutional memberships with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> or through
        discretionary funds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> can tap into to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> charges. Such approaches
        reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' reliance on individual grants to support charges directly and ensure equal
        access to publishing options that require such payments.
      
      
        The Disenfranchised
        Even with the steady increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to pay publication fees, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> claim that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">open-access</ENAMEX> publishing may lead to a situation in which some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> are simply unable to
        publish their work due to lack of funds. The response to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is that the ability
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> charges must never be a consideration in the decision to
        publish their papers. To ensure that this happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> has a firewall in place such that
        neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> know which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have indicated whether or not they
        can pay. Because all work judged worthy of publication by peer review should be published,
        any open-access business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> should be designed to account for fee waivers, just as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX> have always absorbed some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' inability to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> and color charges. PLoS
        grants full or partial publication-charge waivers to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> who requests them, no
        questions asked.
        In part, the savings to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, nongovernmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> provided by open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> could help to establish funds for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> who are less well supported. In the developing world, as free online access to
        scientific literature is increasingly seen as a political imperative, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Network</ENAMEX> for the Availability
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific Publications</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SciELO</ENAMEX> are likely to become more willing to pay
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">open-access</ENAMEX> publication charges for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> who cannot afford them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Society</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> (OSI) already pays such costs for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in a
        number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> is active by way of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Institutional</ENAMEX>
        Membership that grants waived publication charges to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> while providing compensatory
        revenue for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX>.
        Perhaps the real misconception about the unfair burden that open access places on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> resides in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">terminology‚Äîthe term ‚Äúauthor charge‚</ENAMEX>Äù is itself misleading.
        Publication fees are not borne purely by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, but are shared by the many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
        whose missions depend on the broadest possible dissemination and communication of
        scientific discoveries. Some of those may provide funding for open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> as
        intermediaries between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> does. Others‚Äîincluding many
        government-financed funding agencies‚Äîdo so directly through their research grants to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. In both cases, funding open access is an effective way to fulfill mandates for
        public access to and accountability over scientific research and to ensure that all worthy
        research is published.
      
    
  
