
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA interference</ENAMEX> (RNAi) has been called ‚Äúone of the most has exciting discoveries in
        biology in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple decades</TIMEX>,‚Äù and since it was <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Fire et</ENAMEX>
        al. in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, it has quickly become one of the most powerful and indispensable tools in the
        molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX>'s toolkit. Using short double-stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (dsRNA) molecules, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> can
        selectively silence essentially any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> in the genome. It is an ancient mechanism of gene
        regulation, found in eukaryotes as diverse as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> and mammals, and probably plays a
        central role in controlling gene expression in all eukaryotes. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> is
        routinely used to reveal the genetic secrets of development, intracellular signaling,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, infection, and a full range of other phenomena. But can the phenomenon hailed by
        the journal 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúBreakthrough of the Year‚</ENAMEX>Äù in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> break out of the lab
        and lead to novel therapies as well? Pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> are hoping so, and several
        biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have bet their futures on it, but not everyone is sanguine about the
        future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> therapy.
        At the heart of its promise as a powerful therapeutic drug lies the exquisite
        selectivity of RNAi: like the fabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">‚Äúmagic bullet</ENAMEX>,‚Äù an RNAi sequence seeks out and
        destroys its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> without affecting other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. The clinical applications appear
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX>: any gene whose expression contributes to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> is a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>, from viral
        genes to oncogenes to genes responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>,
        and more.
        But for all its promise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> therapy is a long way from entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>. While it
        is a proven wunderkind in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, to date no tests have been done in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, and only the
        most modest and circumscribed successes have been demonstrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to
        clinical success is littered with great ideas that have come a cropper along the way,
        including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNA-based</ENAMEX> therapies, antisense and ribozymes, both of which showed
        promise at the bench but have largely stumbled before reaching the bedside. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> also
        likely to fall short? Or is it different enough to make this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> try the charm?
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinical Na√Øvet√©</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mysterious Mechanisms</ENAMEX>
        To be a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, a molecule must overcome a long set of hurdles. First, it must
        be able to be manufactured at reasonable cost and administered safely and conveniently.
        Then, and even more importantly, it must be stable enough to reach its target cells before
        it is degraded or excreted; it must get into those cells, link up with its intracellular
        target, and exert its effect; and it must exert enough of an effect to improve the health
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> taking it. And, finally, it must do all this without causing significant
        toxic effects in either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> or nontarget tissues. No matter how good a compound looks in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, if it fails to clear any one of these hurdles, it is useless as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNA-based</ENAMEX> therapies, manufacture has been seen as a soluble problem, while delivery,
        stability, and potency have been the most significant obstacles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThere</ENAMEX> was a lot of
        clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">na√Øvet√©‚Äù</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of antisense and ribozymes, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nassim Usman</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research and Development</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirna Therapeutics</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄúCompounds were pushed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> prematurely.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Sirna</ENAMEX> began as the biotech startup
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ribozyme Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, which tried to develop ribozymes to treat several conditions,
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> C. A ribozyme is an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> molecule whose sequence and structure allow it
        to cleave specific target <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> molecules (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). ‚ÄúThe initial results with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX>
        C were not that inspiring,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usman</ENAMEX>, because the molecule they used had low potency and
        a short half-life once in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. Despite ‚Äúenormous doses,‚Äù the viral load was not
        significantly affected. ‚ÄúIt just didn't have the characteristics to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>,‚Äù he says. No
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ribozyme</ENAMEX> has yet been approved for use by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>).
        Similarly, despite much initial enthusiasm, attempts to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">antisense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> have
        been largely disappointing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antisense</ENAMEX> is a single strand of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, complementary to a
        target messenger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (mRNA) sequence; by pairing up with it, the antisense strand prevents
        translation of the mRNA (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). At least that was the theory, and early clinical
        results seemed to support the theory: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antisense drugs</ENAMEX> effectively reduced tumor sizes in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anticancer</ENAMEX> trials and viral loads in antiviral trials. But closer inspection revealed these
        results were largely due to an increase in production of interferons by the immune system
        in response to high doses of the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>, rather than to specific silencing of any
        target genes. (The relatively high proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C‚</ENAMEX>ÄìG sequences in antisense mimics
        bacterial and viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, thus triggering the immune response.) When the antisense dose
        was lowered to prevent the interferon response, the clinical benefit largely disappeared as
        well. Thus, rather than being a highly specific therapy, antisense seemed to be a general
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> system booster.
        But as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were getting better, does it matter what the mechanism was? ‚ÄúIt
        doesn't matter if you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, but it does matter if you are trying to develop the
        next <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cy Stein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate Professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine and Pharmacology</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
        antisense for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX>. ‚ÄúIf you get the mechanism wrong, you're not going to be
        able to do it.‚Äù
        To date, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> antisense <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> has received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> approval. Vitravene, from Isis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, is used to treat cytomegalovirus infections in the
        eye for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitravene</ENAMEX> is actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA antisense drug</ENAMEX>, which binds to viral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, though, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usman, ‚Äúit</ENAMEX>'s unclear whether it actually works by an antisense
        mechanism.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Stein</ENAMEX> expresses a similar skepticism about the mechanism of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> antisense
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genasense</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genasense</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-based treatment that targets <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-2</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expressed
        in high levels in cancer cells, which is thought to protect them from standard
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemotherapy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> is currently reviewing an application for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genasense</ENAMEX>, based on
        promising results in the treatment of malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">melanoma</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        RNAi: A Natural Alternative
        Growing disillusionment with antisense and ribozymes coincided with the discovery of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> and the realization that it was a far more potent way to silence gene expression. RNAi
        uses short dsRNA molecules whose sequence matches that of the gene of interest. Once in a
        cell, a dsRNA molecule is cleaved into segments approximately <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22 nucleotides long</NUMEX>, called
        short interfering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAs</ENAMEX> (siRNAs) (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). siRNAs become bound to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>-induced
        silencing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (RISC), which then also binds any matching mRNA sequence. Once this
        occurs, the mRNA is degraded, effectively silencing the gene from which it came. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Details</ENAMEX>
        of the structure and function of the RISC are still largely unknown, but it is thought to
        act as a true enzyme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, requiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> or several siRNA molecules to degrade many
        times that number of matching mRNAs.)
        The extraordinary selectivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX>, combined with its potency‚Äîin theory, only a few
        dsRNAs are needed per cell‚Äîquickly made it the tool of choice for functional genomics
        (determining what a gene product does and with what other products it interacts) and for
        drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> discovery and validation. By ‚Äúknocking down‚Äù a gene with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> and determining
        how a cell responds, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> can, in the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few days</TIMEX>, develop
        significant insight into the function of the gene and determine whether reducing its
        expression is likely to be therapeutically useful. But does RNAi have a better chance to
        succeed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> than antisense or ribozymes?
        ‚ÄúThe fundamental difference favoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> is that we're harnessing an endogenous,
        natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathway</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nagesh Mahanthappa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporate Development</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alnylam</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major biotech company
        developing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RNAi</ENAMEX>-based therapy. The exploitation of a pre-existing mechanism, he says, is
        the main reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> is orders of magnitude more potent than either of the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> strategies.
      
      
        Delivery, Delivery, Delivery
        More potent in the test tube, at least. But stability and delivery are also the major
        obstacles to successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> therapy, obstacles that are intrinsic to the biochemical
        nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> itself, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s defenses against infection with foreign
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nucleotides</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúFor the strongest reasons, you can't get away from this,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúThe
        problem is that a charged oligonucleotide will not pass through a lipid layer,‚Äù which it
        must do in order to enter a cell. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rossi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Molecular</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biology at City of Hope Hospital in Duarte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, who has worked on RNA-based
        therapies for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX>, concurs. ‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> doesn't want to take up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>,‚Äù he says, which
        makes evolutionary sense, since <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">extracellular RNA</ENAMEX> usually signifies a viral infection.
        Injected into the bloodstream, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unmodified RNA</ENAMEX> is rapidly excreted by the kidneys or
        degraded by enzymes.
        To solve the problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> penetration, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have either complexed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
        with a lipid or modified the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>'s phosphate backbone to minimize its charge. Mahanthappa
        thinks the complexing approach is unlikely to be a simple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> approval
        would require independent testing of the lipid delivery system as well. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alnylam</ENAMEX> is
        pursuing backbone modification. ‚ÄúSome minimal modification is going to be necessary‚Äù to
        increase cell uptake and to improve stability in the blood stream, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahanthappa</ENAMEX> says. ‚ÄúWhat
        we have learned from the antisense field is that even without other delivery strategies,
        when you administer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> at sufficient doses, if it's stable, it gets taken up by
        cells.‚Äù
        ‚ÄúAnything that can be done to increase half-life in circulation would improve delivery,‚Äù
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Lieberman</ENAMEX>, a Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigator</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Blood Research and Associate</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pediatrics</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Medical School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. But that may
        not be the only problem, she cautions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> recently demonstrated the ability of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> to silence expression of the Fas gene in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, protecting them from fulminant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Fas</ENAMEX> triggers apoptosis, or programmed cell death, in response to a variety of
        cell insults. In her experiment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> delivered the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> by high-pressure injection
        into the tail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> got to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>, silenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fas</ENAMEX>, and protected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX>. However, a significant fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart failure</ENAMEX>, brought on
        because the injection volume was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20%</NUMEX> of the mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> volume. Such a delivery
        scheme simply will not work in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúDelivery to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is still an obstacle,‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> explains. ‚ÄúUnless you really focus on how to solve that problem, you're not going
        to get very far.‚Äù
      
      
        Unanswered Questions
        Even assuming delivery problems can be solved, other questions remain, including that of
        whether therapeutic levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> may be toxic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahanthappa</ENAMEX> says, ‚ÄúThe conservative answer
        is we just don't know. The more aggressive answer is there's no reason to think so.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Rossi</ENAMEX>
        isn't so sure. ‚ÄúThe target of interest may be in normal cells as well as cancer cells,‚Äù he
        says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThat</ENAMEX>'s where you get toxicity.‚Äù
        But if small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">RNAs</ENAMEX> can be delivered to target cells efficiently and without significant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">toxicity</ENAMEX>, will they be effective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>? Usman of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirna</ENAMEX> is confident they will be. ‚ÄúIf
        you can get it there, and if it's in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece, there no doubt in our minds that it will
        work,‚Äù he says. To date, numerous experiments in animal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> can
        downregulate a variety of target genes effectively. However, there are still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unanswered
        questions about whether that will translate into effective therapy.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX>'s exquisite specificity is really an advantage beyond the
        bench. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s unclear whether highly specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> give you a big therapeutic effect,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cy Stein</ENAMEX>. For instance, he says, ‚Äúmost active <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antitumor medicines</ENAMEX> have multiple mechanisms
        of action. The more specific you make it, the less robust the therapeutic activity is
        likely to be.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Rossi</ENAMEX> agrees: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúOverspecificity has never worked,‚Äù he says.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question is what effect an excess of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> will have on
        the normal function of the RISC, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> at the heart of the RNAi mechanism. The number
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RISCs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is unknown, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is that the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> needed to have a
        therapeutic effect may occupy all the available <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúWe are usurping a natural cell
        system that is there for some other purpose, for knocking out endogenous gene function,‚Äù
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>. With the introduction of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>, will the system continue to perform its
        normal function as well, or will it become saturated? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThat</ENAMEX>'s the big black box in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>,‚Äù he says.
      
      
        Looking Ahead to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinic</ENAMEX>
        Despite the questions and unsolved problems, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirna, Alnylam</ENAMEX>, and several other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
        are moving ahead to develop RNAi therapy; indeed, some outstanding questions are probably
        only likely to be answered in the process of therapeutic development. The first
        applications are likely to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> (targeting out-of-control oncogenes) or viral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infection</ENAMEX> (targeting viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>). To avoid some of the problems of delivery, initial
        trials may deliver the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> by direct injection into the target tissue (for a tumor, for
        instance) or ex vivo, treating white blood cells infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>, for example.
        Having spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> trying to develop ribozymes, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirna</ENAMEX> is prepared for the
        rough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> it faces. ‚ÄúWe haven't solved all the problems, but we know how to proceed to
        work through them. It's no surprise to us‚Äîwe've seen this movie before.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Usman</ENAMEX> expects
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirna</ENAMEX> to file an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Investigational New Drug Application</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2004</TIMEX> and
        to have a human clinical trial in progress in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. ‚ÄúWithout a doubt, there will be an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RNAi</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Usman</ENAMEX> predicts.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> isn't so sure and thinks that too much is still to be learned about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> and the
        body's reaction to it to be confident that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNA-based</ENAMEX> therapies will ultimately be
        successful. ‚ÄúThe whole field was founded on the belief it was rational, but there are huge
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gaps</ENAMEX> in our knowledge, and so you need a bit of luck to be successful,‚Äù he says. ‚ÄúI think
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are surprised at how complicated it is, but why should it be any other way? It's an
        intellectual conceit to think that nature is simple.‚Äù
      
    
  
