
  
    
      
        
        On the basis of his retrospective at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, it is
        evident that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> forged a narrow trajectory through the thickets of
        contemporary art. Unlike some of his protean fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hockney</ENAMEX> or Frank
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX>, he found his style early in his career and followed its course with almost
        scientific precision for his entire life. Through an obsessive focus on the techniques of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graphic</ENAMEX> production, he turned popular imagery into a high form of art and an exploration of
        the limits of visual perception.
        The core concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>'s art is the iconic—drastic simplification of line and
        shadowing to reduce to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Platonic</ENAMEX> ideal of the object depicted—golf ball, truck tire,
        composition book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in love, or even the basic brushstroke of a daub of paint [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. The
        basic inspiration of these icons is advertising imagery and comic book frames. Throughout
        his artistic life, he drew his imagery from the detritus of printed material—gum wrapper
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comics</ENAMEX> and small ads from the backs of newspapers—deliberately elevating visual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> at
        the opposite pole from the high art of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> comic works were
        motivated by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, who challenged him by saying if he was such a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, could he
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">draw Mickey Mouse</ENAMEX> for them? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> was so stimulated by the result that he worked in
        the comic book style from then on. Interesting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Close</ENAMEX> tells a similar story about his
        own work, although in reverse. In his case a group of school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were not “getting” his
        art and challenged him in the same way to prove his expertise. Close passed the test, but
        continued in his compulsive style, exploring the minutiae of the pixel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in his
        grandiose portraits, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> explored the iconographic largesse of the new
        domain opened up by this challenge.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>'s cartoon style of representation can be seen as an ironic commentary on
        the elitism of art, implying that art is merely a selection from the endless variety of
        images that bombard us. His self-mockery is exemplified by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> picture in the
        exhibition, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canvas</ENAMEX> bearing the letters “ART” [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. In this piece <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> is
        explicitly interrogating the artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> on the boundaries of the concept of art. Is
        the raw symbol placed in a gallery sufficient to constitute an artistic statement? This was
        a game that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> had been playing in earnest since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the 20th</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">century—Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> came up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more variation on the theme. His later work consists
        of an extensive series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">graphic “reflections”</ENAMEX> on the themes of classical art, from the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> period of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pompeii</ENAMEX>, to the light explorations of the Impressionists, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landscapes</ENAMEX>, all in his egregious comic book pastiche.
        The iconic is by now commonplace—the idea that cartoons capture the essence of an image
        was popularized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Attneave</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], when he drew attention to the way the outline
        of an object (and, indeed, the points of maximum curvature of the outline) captures most of
        the information of the full object image. The rest of the image can be thrown away without
        significant loss of its import. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel-</ENAMEX>Prize-winning experimental work conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torsten Wiesel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX> consolidated this notion with the discovery that
        individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurons</ENAMEX> in the visual cortex can be characterized as simple line detectors,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, that they are most active when a line of a particular orientation is found in a
        particular part of the visual world [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. The work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiesel</ENAMEX> illustrated that
        neural processing encodes the most relevant features in complex images. Indeed, they
        discovered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of neurons called end-stopped cells that respond to the ends of
        lines and points of high line curvature in the manner required by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attneave</ENAMEX>'s analysis.
        Interestingly, this confluence immediately predated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>'s entrée into the world of
        the comic book image, but the relationship seems to be coincidental in view of the
        iconographic symbolism of his choices. The likelihood that he had heard of these scientific
        developments seems remote, particularly in view of the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX> was following
        the same track of using cartoon material, reputedly in mutual ignorance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>'s
        breakthrough.
        Beyond the iconographic, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> plays with the visual impression derived from
        enlarging the halftone dots of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum-wrapper comics</ENAMEX>. Through time, the dots become
        progressively larger and more insistent, emerging from their role as background fillers to
        dominate the entire canvas in a dizzying field of scintillations. In this sense,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> seems to go beyond the role of cultural expositor and gadfly to explore the
        sensory implications of the optical redundancy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>'s screen. The regular dot
        arrays shimmer and scintillate, ingraining themselves in our neural memory and projecting
        onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> walls and neighboring paintings in a reminder of our visual fallibility.
        Such effects represent a resonance with so-called optical art (“op art”), a style promoted
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1960s—by</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Riley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Vasarely</ENAMEX>, in particular—that relies on visual
        illusion generated at the early levels of the nervous system: the retinal, the receptoral,
        the oculomotor, and the neural. Despite its name, it is not concerned with strictly optical
        effects such as diffraction, diffusion, interference, scintillation, polarization, and
        related optical phenomena. It is concerned with the visual and perceptual effects of
        dancing grids, jazzy dots, clashing colors, sliding waves, and so on.
        Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>'s effects are a by-product of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>'s screen structure that
        is enlarged along with the other details of the printed image structure. His work seems to
        have been a major precursor of the op art movement, although he is not generally identified
        as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of it. Indeed, he plays with the dot-screen as a theme in his later works,
        notably in the vast 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panels</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>), which shows nothing but the mirror surface
        reflecting empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>, apparently rendered in the transparent sheets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benday</ENAMEX> dots in
        common use by graphic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Refreshingly</ENAMEX>, this is one of the few works that does not
        contain references to other art genres, but jousts with the concept of the image itself,
        again a reflection of nothing at all.
        For the visual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, the most compelling painting in the exhibition may be 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rouen Cathedral Set V</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>], a meditation on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Monet</ENAMEX>'s
        mediation on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rouen Cathedral</ENAMEX>, itself a series of impressionistic paintings of the cathedral
        in different lighting conditions. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> abandons the cartoon-style bravura of
        line and text bubbles in a triplet of silk-screen close-ups of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX>'s painterly
        impressions, differing only in the choice of colors for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX>. The dot-screen
        now plays the role of a muslin or gauze curtain through which the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cathedral</ENAMEX> is glimpsed,
        forming a vibrant haze that formalizes the image space into a kind of crystallized
        transparency that never quite settles into known categories of visual experience. While the
        left and right panels of the triptych are in bold shades of color, the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> is
        rendered in accurate red-green isoluminance. As discovered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gregory</ENAMEX>, form
        processing is much weakened when the luminance differences are removed and forms are
        represented in colors that are accurately equated for their luminance values [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. Although
        the colors are well seen, the form seems to shimmer and fluctuate, indicating that the
        shape-processing mechanisms are not well activated by the pure color differences. In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>, the shimmer of the isoluminance interplays with the shimmer of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dot</ENAMEX>-screen to evoke a visual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enigma</ENAMEX>, as we explore the image space to see whether the
        structure is indeed the same as in the flanking panels. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the pleasures of art is its
        ability to slow down our sensory processing so that we become aware of the processes
        themselves, not just their symbolic role in our goal-oriented lives. Very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> have
        played with the power of isoluminance to achieve this role in form processing: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>
        seems to have been on to this property <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade earlier</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory</ENAMEX>, although he soon
        retreats back to the boldness of his cartoon pop-art style to explore a potpourri of the
        icons of classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
        There is much more that could be analyzed to place <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> in an art-historical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">framework</ENAMEX>, but perhaps one should just enjoy the power of the concrete image, simplified to
        its high-tone essentials and projected at large visual angle onto our excitable retinas.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> comes away from the exhibit with a sense of the power of raw imagery that one may not
        have felt since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the grade-school days</TIMEX> of reading illicit comics when one was supposed to be
        learning the dates of battle sequences through history. But what does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>'s dot
        obsession reveal about neural processing? Why does repeated fine-grain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> wreak such
        havoc with our visual stability? This question was raised, in particular, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald MacKay</ENAMEX>
        with his high-density radial ray figure (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), which generates powerful complementary
        effects in both current viewing and as an aftereffect [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. Just why high-density dots and
        lines elicit such powerful responses from our visual apparatus remains unexplained. Indeed,
        the issue does not seem even to be a topic of current research interest, despite the
        proliferation of research activities in visual processing in general. Contemplation of an
        exhibit such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>'s sparks a realization of the wealth of neural processes still
        to be studied and explored.
      
    
  
