
  
    
      
        
        frontier‚Äîis not as inexhaustible as it once seemed. While we have yet to fully explore the
        reaches of the sea, technology has granted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> the ability to harvest its wealth. We can
        now fish anywhere, at any depth, for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> frontier range's bison
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wolf populations</ENAMEX> brought to the brink of extinction swordfish and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> are the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ocean</ENAMEX>'s most pursued prizes. The disadvantages associated with the depth and dimensions of
        this open range, however, have long obscured the real consequences of fishing. Indeed,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have the formidable challenge of assessing the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> whose home
        covers over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> recent highly publicized papers‚Äîa trifecta detailing troubled waters‚Äîcall
        attention to overfishing's contributions to the dramatic declines in global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX>.
        Delving into the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Jackson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>) combined local historic records
        with current estimates to detail the ecological impacts of overfishing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reg Watson</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Pauly</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>) drew attention to distortions of global catches, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ransom Myers</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Boris Worm</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>) highlighted the depletion of the majority of the largest ocean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX>.
        While some have valid criticisms of the assumptions and aggregation of historic data used
        to assess the global situation, few disagree with the overriding conclusion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>
        have drastically altered not only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">biodiversity</ENAMEX>, but, increasingly, the ocean
        itself.
        maintains the world's most complete global fisheries database, appear to validate the
        conclusions of these studies. The most recent FAO report states that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX> of global stocks
        are significantly depleted or overexploited, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47%</NUMEX> are either fully exploited or meet the
        target maximum sustainable yield. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 24%</NUMEX> of global stocks are either under- or moderately
        exploited. As the sea is increasingly harvested, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ecologists</ENAMEX> wonder how the ecosystem
        will continue to function (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). Although economic and social
        considerations often supercede scientific assessments, science will continuously be called
        upon to deliver management options that will straddle the needs for conservation and
        production, even in areas where there is only subsistence fishing (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
        debate the details of global fisheries assessment, they are also including studies of the
        long-term ecosystem effects and options for recovery efforts. Like was done on the open
        range, shall we conserve or farm the sea‚Äîor both?
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collapses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Controversies</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAO</ENAMEX> began keeping fisheries records in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>. Unfortunately, an enormous amount of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> comes directly from each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s fishing industry, which is often biased as a result
        of unreported discarding, illegal fishing, and the misreporting of harvests. For example,
        mid-level <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> seeking promotions systematically enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fisheries</ENAMEX> numbers in recent years‚Äîwhich inflated and skewed international catch rates.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAO</ENAMEX> data show that catches, excluding a recent surge in anchoveta and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">suspect</ENAMEX> numbers, reached a peak of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 million metric tons</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX> and have since
        begun to decline. Regional studies validate these trends. ‚ÄúMost of the line fish around the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast of South Africa</ENAMEX> are depleted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì15%</NUMEX> of pristine levels,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Branch</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director General</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldFish</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>-specific
        database called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TrawlBase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldfishcenter</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/trawl/</ENAMEX>) confirms that the region's
        commercial species have been depleted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì30%</NUMEX> of what they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30‚Äì40 years ago</TIMEX>.
        Obtaining accurate information on highly migratory species is challenging, to say the
        least. It is not hard to imagine that data quality is the biggest disadvantage to any
        scientific assessment. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> managed stocks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northeast Atlantic Ocean‚</ENAMEX>Äîincluding
        invertebrates, sport fishes, and major commercial finfish‚Äîdata are kept on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only one-fifth</NUMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish species</ENAMEX> in the region, but only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> are of
        commercial interest and merit inquiry. ‚ÄúWe know next to nothing about noncommercially
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fished species</ENAMEX>,‚Äù notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Hutchings</ENAMEX>, a conservation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalhousie University</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Halifax</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova Scotia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>). And that is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX> have adequate access to current
        monitoring programs. ‚ÄúWith the recent expansion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fleets</ENAMEX>, we
        don't have the kind of sampling programs needed for those kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
        Deriso, a fisheries <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inter-American Tropical Tuna Commission</ENAMEX> (IATTC) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>).
        Couple these inadequacies with previously unknown bycatch rates (i.e., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> caught
        in addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> catch) and illegal catches, and it is easy to see that the task
        is formidable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAO</ENAMEX> estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly one-quarter</NUMEX> of the marine commercial catch
        destined for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">consumption‚</ENAMEX>Äîsome <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18‚Äì40 million metric tons</NUMEX> of fish‚Äîis thrown back in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX>, a harvested catch that is never utilized or counted. It is estimated that the illegal,
        unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fisheries surpass allowed fishing quotas by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300%</NUMEX>. IUU
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fishers</ENAMEX> operate in areas where fishing is not permitted, use banned technologies or
        outlawed net types, or underreport catches. ‚ÄúThe IUU fishery for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patagonian</ENAMEX> toothfish
        expanded rapidly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>, likely on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20‚Äì30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constable</ENAMEX>, an ecological modeler at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian Antarctic Division</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>), who also works with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific Committee of the Commission</ENAMEX> for the
        fishing could reduce stocks to threshold levels in some areas in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to five years</TIMEX>,‚Äù he
        adds.
        Often overlooked is the inescapable fact that even sustainable harvest rates reduce fish
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> quickly. ‚ÄúIf the goal is a productive fishery, we're automatically talking
        about up to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deriso</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Resource Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge Csirke</ENAMEX>, states that ‚Äúfrom a stock point of view, there is
        no way to preserve integrity of wild stocks and exploit them at the same time.‚Äù Indeed, the
        be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 40%‚Äì60%</NUMEX> of virgin levels. But once fish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> dip below the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì20%</NUMEX> mark,
        declines are of serious concern.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> cod in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> waters suffered a total population collapse and are now on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> list (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). From <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 billion</NUMEX> breeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in the
        1960s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> cod <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> have declined by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 90%</NUMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hutchings</ENAMEX>. While
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisors</ENAMEX> called attention to declining cod stocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constable</ENAMEX> notes that by the time a
        significant declining trend has been detected by traditional catch assessments, stocks are
        likely to be in poor shape, if not already depleted.
        Given the task of compiling data on only the economically important <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, fisheries
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> developed a single-species management approach in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, which assumed that
        fisheries affect each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> in isolation. This approach, although now rife with problems,
        served the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> well during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> of abundant resources.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThey</ENAMEX> brought the approach of single-species <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to near-perfection,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Worm</ENAMEX>, a marine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ecologist</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Marine Science</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kiel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. A growing
        discontent with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, in addition to greater awareness of ecological interactions,
        however, prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Worm</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalhousie University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ransom Myers</ENAMEX> to question the
        sustainability of the single-species approach. Attempting a comprehensive assessment, their
        widely cited recent paper (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worm 2003)</ENAMEX> indicated that the global ocean has lost
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 90%</NUMEX> of large predatory fishes, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>, and rays.
        However, this new approach to assess fish stocks is not without its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisheries</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> point out that the nuances of management contained in fisheries data‚Äîsuch as
        altered fisher behavior, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">variable ‚Äúcatchability‚Äù</ENAMEX> of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, and altered
        gear use‚Äîwere discounted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Worm</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>) assessment and led to
        misinterpretations for some species, notably tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tunas</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). A number of tuna
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> have expressed concern that these omissions have left the mistaken impression
        that all tuna <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> are among the list of declining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampton et al 2003</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Worm</ENAMEX>
        acknowledges that his approach can be improved, but says, ‚ÄúThe whole point of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> was
        to aggregate species to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> to see what the overall ecosystem is doing.‚Äù
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecosystem Sustainability</ENAMEX>
        Despite the controversy, most agree that the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>,
        skates, rays, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marlin</ENAMEX>, are in the most dire straits. Unlike other lower-trophic order
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, the wholesale removal of top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX> has enormous effects on the rest of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ecosystem</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> consequence is that overall reproduction rates can potentially suffer. Fish
        size, gender, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at maturity have a substantial impact on individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>'
        reproduction rates. Since larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> are the most susceptible to fishing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>'s
        age structure can shift as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, are fished out. For example,
        a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23-inch</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">59-cm</NUMEX>) female vermilion rockfish can produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> times the young of a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">14-inch</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">36-cm</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. Given uncertainties with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> dynamics, the fact that basic biological
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> are missing makes the job even harder. While knowledge of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> is still
        quite spotty, tuna inventories, for example, have started collecting gender data on
        catches.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Pauly</ENAMEX>, a fisheries <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Vancouver</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>), has shown that increased fishing has caused the industry to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúfish down
        the food web,‚Äù or systematically move to lower trophic levels over time as higher ones were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depleted</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pauly et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>). The impact to ecosystems is only beginning to be uncovered.
        ‚ÄúIf you fish out an abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that it was eating or competing with
        will increase,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worm</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúThe problem is that the ecosystem may change in such a way that
        recovery is inhibited because a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> niche space is taken or altered.‚Äù
        Fisheries science has taken steps to increase the quality of data in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.
        ‚ÄúTraditional fishery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> assumed that a fishery was a homogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thing‚Äîlike bacteria</ENAMEX> in
        a bottle‚Äîrather than a spatially diverse system,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Kleiber</ENAMEX>, a fisheries
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Islands Fisheries Science Center of the NMFS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>). He adds that recent work accounts for spatial diversity. In addition,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fisheries</ENAMEX> are now dealing with the inherent uncertainty of their work and are factoring
        that into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and decision-making. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúUncertainty</ENAMEX> didn't used to be dealt with at all in
        formulating fishery management advice,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> confirms <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Sainsbury</ENAMEX>, a marine ecologist with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>), adding that its absence gave rise to an awful lot of troubles.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúTraditional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> tended to assume perfect data with no holes in it,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleiber</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúNow
        we've tried to craft a model to fit the realities of missing data.‚Äù
        As well as incorporating spatial diversity and uncertainty, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are beginning to
        comprehend the ecological damage caused by different types of fishing gear. Indeed,
        trawling the bottom of the seafloor for groundfish can destroy a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">half-acre footprint</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">habitat</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Detailed reports document that, depending on the habitat's stability,
        bottom trawling can not only remove <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> from seafloor habitats, but alter bottom relief
        such that it compromises the ability of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> to survive (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1002</TIMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>,
        for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lingcod</ENAMEX> rely on undisturbed bottom relief to lay their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, while other
        groundfish species depend on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> seafloor habitats for the majority of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄúScience is getting more realistic, but it is getting more difficult,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ecological</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are far more complex than traditional fisheries <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Csirke</ENAMEX>,
        adding that more model variables make it more difficult to apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX>, an industry
        whose focus is, understandably, not conservation. Despite its incorporation into national
        fisheries policies, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ecosystem</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> remains a loosely defined term. It is not a
        well-defined concept because it is not possible to optimize every <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deriso</ENAMEX>.
        An additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> is that of biomass resilience in the face of
        environmental changes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Chavez</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey Bay Aquarium</ENAMEX>
        Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moss Landing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), recently demonstrated that
        over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 25-year</TIMEX> period, warmer and cooler <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> waters tilt the distribution of anchoveta
        versus sardines, both open-ocean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chavez et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Ni√±o</ENAMEX> influenced
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">crash of the</ENAMEX> heavily fished <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> anchoveta industry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>. These
        examples illustrate how susceptible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX> are to environmental fluctuations. When the
        biomass of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is reduced, it is much more sensitive to environmental change. We
        do not know how environmental fluctuations like these will affect the natural production of
        young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleiber</ENAMEX>, expressing the concern that without a better understanding of
        climate, fisheries <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> end up trying to estimate moving targets.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have their doubts about the influence of science on
        decision-making. ‚ÄúMy personal view is that it's na√Øve to think that modifying and improving
        models will necessarily lead to improved natural resource <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Jennings</ENAMEX>,
        a fisheries <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre for Environment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisheries</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquaculture Science</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowestoft</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Council for the Exploration of</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copenhagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>) recently recommended a total ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Sea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Sea</ENAMEX>
        cod stocks, based on single-species assessment. Although the more intensive ecosystem-based
        models could not have produced a more stringent recommendation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> allowed
        harvests at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly half</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s catch.
      
      
        To Conserve or to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm</ENAMEX>?
        While lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX>' effort seems the most logical approach to the recovery of
        depleted fisheries, social and economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> often stymie political action. Yet demand
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> continues. Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> also are investigating both conservation and
        alternative production options.
        Given the social, economic, and political problems associated with that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> have
        often used closures to help a hard-hit species recover. In many cases, however, the
        recovery time for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">exploited species</ENAMEX> is longer than once thought (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchings 2000).</ENAMEX> ‚ÄúBased on
        the available information, it is not unusual for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> to show no or little
        recovery even after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchings</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúAll else being equal, we predict the
        earlier the age of maturity, the faster the rate of recovery,‚Äù he adds. And that depends on
        environmental conditions as well. ‚ÄúIn the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Antarctic species</ENAMEX>, some overexploited
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> remain at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 5%</NUMEX> pre-exploitation abundance after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constable</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> management strategy to recover species is to create marine protected areas (MPAs),
        zones that restrict all removal of marine life (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 2</ENAMEX>). A number of marine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ecologists</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staunch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAs</ENAMEX> for both conservation and fishery's recovery. What looked like
        sustainability in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> were fisheries out of our reach‚Äînaturally protected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">areas‚</ENAMEX>Äîsays
        Pauly, adding that our increasing ability to harvest fisheries necessitates the creation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAs</ENAMEX> now. In theory, these areas are refugia for fishes to reproduce, spilling over not
        only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy adults</ENAMEX> but also potentially transporting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of viable young‚Äîseeding
        surrounding waters. To date, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1%</NUMEX> of the ocean's area is protected, which hinders
        the ability to conclusively determine if spillover rates have the predicted impact on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fishery</ENAMEX>'s recovery.
        A review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Halpern</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), demonstrated that the
        average number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> inside a reserve increases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 60%‚</TIMEX>Äì and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halpern 2003).</ENAMEX> In
        addition, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59%</NUMEX> of the sites had increased diversity. While the numbers inside the reserves
        look good, the crucial condition of larval spillover has yet to be proven. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
        involved in the debate agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAs</ENAMEX> should be one component in an overall management
        scheme, but worry that until the crucial element of fishing effort is resolved, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAs</ENAMEX> may
        just displace the vast industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fleets</ENAMEX>.
        In terms of simply producing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> for global <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> needs, aquaculture (also known as fish
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">farming</ENAMEX>) is another, increasingly popular, option. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> produced <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX>
        of total fishery's production via aquaculture. These numbers are projected to steadily
        increase, but some question whether aquaculture would be sufficient to supply what has been
        lost by overexploited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX>.
        Concentrated in coastal areas, aquaculture has aroused numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. Indeed, in
        developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> grow carnivorous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, which necessitates growing fish
        to feed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. While the process has become more efficient in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, due in part to a
        growing reliance on vegetarian diets, it still takes <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3 pounds</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.36 kg</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> to
        create <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.2 pounds</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 kg</NUMEX>) of desirable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldhous 2004).</ENAMEX> Yet, the total catch of food
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> continues to grow, as do concerns about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nutrient</TIMEX> runoff and estuary pollution
        resulting from aquaculture. Increasingly, coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> often complain about the
        aesthetics of such activities, and there is also new research that indicates that
        farm-raised <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> harbor more cancer-causing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> than wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hites et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        To alleviate many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, open-ocean aquaculture is now being considered.
        Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMFS</ENAMEX> is set to propose a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conduct for Offshore Aquaculture</ENAMEX>, which would
        open up the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200-mile</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">322-km</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Exclusive Economic Zone</ENAMEX> to net pens seaward of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coastal</ENAMEX> state boundaries and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Grant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> in conjunction with
        interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, is also currently assessing the carrying capacity of open-water pens
        as well as their potential environmental impact. Given increased industrial interest and
        unchanging demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX>, many think farming the sea may be around the corner.
        Undoubtedly, scientific effort will continue to inform both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservationists</ENAMEX> and
        industry about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX>' capacity and potential recovery options. As attitudes towards
        fisheries continue to change, increased understanding of the ecological underpinnings
        should help strike a more informed balance between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisheries</ENAMEX>' conservation and production.
        ‚ÄúThe big mistake is suggesting that you can manage fish stocks,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niels Daan</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netherlands Institute for Fisheries Research</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IJmuiden</ENAMEX>, The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>). ‚ÄúIn my opinion, we can only manage human activity.‚Äù
      
      
        
      
    
  
