
  
    
      
        
        Stuttering, with its characteristic disruption in verbal fluency, has been known for
        centuries; earliest descriptions probably date back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biblical Moses</ENAMEX>' ‚Äúslowness of
        speech and tongue‚Äù and his related avoidance behavior (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus 4</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10‚Äì13</NUMEX>). Stuttering occurs
        in all cultures and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimmermann et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>), although
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevalence</ENAMEX> might differ. Insofar as many of the steps in how we produce language normally
        are still a mystery, disorders like stuttering are even more poorly understood. However,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genetic</ENAMEX> and neurobiological approaches are now giving us clues to causes and better
        treatments.
      
      
        What Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuttering</ENAMEX>?
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuttering</ENAMEX> is a disruption in the fluency of verbal expression characterized by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">involuntary</ENAMEX>, audible or silent, repetitions or prolongations of sounds or syllables (Figure
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). These are not readily controllable and may be accompanied by other movements and by
        emotions of negative nature such as fear, embarrassment, or irritation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wingate 1964).</ENAMEX>
        Strictly speaking, stuttering is a symptom, not a disease, but the term 
        stuttering usually refers to both the disorder and symptom.
        Developmental stuttering evolves before puberty, usually between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> of
        age, without apparent brain damage or other known cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">(‚Äúidiopathic‚Äù</ENAMEX>). It is important to
        distinguish between this persistent developmental stuttering (PDS), which we focus on here,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acquired stuttering</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neurogenic</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acquired stuttering</ENAMEX> occurs after a definable brain
        damage, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, intracerebral hemorrhage, or head trauma. It is a rare phenomenon
        that has been observed after <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> in a variety of brain areas (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ciabarra et al. 2000</ENAMEX>).
        The clinical presentation of developmental stuttering differs from acquired stuttering
        in that it is particularly prominent at the beginning of a word or a phrase, in long or
        meaningful words, or syntactically complex utterances (Karniol <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natke et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>),
        and the associated anxiety and secondary symptoms are more pronounced (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringo</ENAMEX> and Dietrich
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>). Moreover, at repeated readings, stuttering frequency tends to decline (adaptation)
        and to occur at the same syllables as before (consistency). Nonetheless, the distinction
        between both types of stuttering is not strict. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with perinatal or other brain
        damage, stuttering is more frequent than in age-matched controls, and both types of
        stuttering may overlap (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>).
      
      
        Who Is Affected?
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDS</ENAMEX> is a very frequent disorder, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 1%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> suffering from
        this condition. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">An estimated 3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55 million</NUMEX> people
        worldwide stutter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prevalence</ENAMEX> is similar in all social classes. In many cases, stuttering
        severely impairs communication, with devastating socioeconomic consequences. However, there
        are also many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stutterers</ENAMEX> who, despite their disorder, have become famous. For instance,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX> had to rehearse all his public speeches to perfection and even practiced
        answers to possible questions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> to avoid stuttering. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Darwin</ENAMEX> also
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stuttered</ENAMEX>; interestingly, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erasmus Darwin</ENAMEX> suffered from the same condition,
        highlighting the fact that stuttering runs in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and is likely to have a genetic
        basis.
        The incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDS</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 5%</NUMEX>, and its recovery rate is up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80%</NUMEX>, resulting in
        a prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDS</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1%</NUMEX> of the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. As recovery is considerably more
        frequent in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, the male-to-female ratio increases during childhood and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adolescence</ENAMEX> to reach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> to every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> female in adulthood. It is not clear
        to what extent this recovery is spontaneous or induced by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> speech therapy. Also, there
        is no good way of predicting whether an affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> will recover (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yairi</ENAMEX> and Ambrose
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
        The presence of affected family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> suggests a hereditary component. The concordance
        rate is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 70%</NUMEX> for monozygotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felsenfeld et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>),
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30%</NUMEX> for dizygotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felsenfeld et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> of the same sex (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>). Given the high recovery rate, it may well
        be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> abnormalities observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> reflects impaired recovery rather than
        the causes of stuttering (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>).
      
      
        Changing Theories
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the centuries</TIMEX>, a variety of theories about the origin of stuttering and
        corresponding treatment approaches have been proposed. In ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, theories referred
        to dryness of the tongue. In the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
        th <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>, abnormalities of the speech apparatus were thought to cause
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stuttering</ENAMEX>. Thus, treatment was based on extensive ‚Äúplastic‚Äù surgery, often leading to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutilations</ENAMEX> and additional disabilities. Other treatment options were tongue-weights or
        mouth prostheses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz 1977)</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>, stuttering was primarily
        thought to be a psychogenic disorder. Consequently, psychoanalytical approaches and
        behavioral therapy were applied to solve possible neurotic conflicts (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plankers 1999).</ENAMEX>
        However, studies of personality traits and child‚Äìparent interactions did not detect
        psychological patterns consistently associated with stuttering (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>).
        Other theories regard stuttering as a learned behavior resulting from disadvantageous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">external</ENAMEX>, usually parental, reactions to normal childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dysfluencies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson 1955).</ENAMEX>
        While this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> has failed to explain the core symptoms of stuttering (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimmermann et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>), it may well explain secondary symptoms (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>), and guided early
        parental intervention may prevent persistence into adulthood (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onslow et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). The
        severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDS</ENAMEX> is clearly modulated by arousal, nervousness, and other factors (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">al. 1983</ENAMEX>). This has led to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-factor model of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDS</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> factor is believed to cause
        the disorder and is most likely a structural or functional central nervous system (CNS)
        abnormality, whereas the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> factor reinforces the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, especially through
        avoidance learning. However, one should be careful to call the latter factor ‚Äúpsychogenic‚Äù
        or ‚Äúpsychological,‚Äù because neuroscience has shown that learning is not simply
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúpsychogenic‚Äù</ENAMEX> but leads to measurable changes in the brain (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kandel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Dell 1992).</ENAMEX>
        In some cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arousal</ENAMEX> actually improves stuttering instead of making it worse.
        Consequently, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous stutterers</ENAMEX> have ‚Äútreated‚Äù their stuttering by putting themselves
        on the spot. Anecdotally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX>, who began stuttering at the age
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>, joined a drama <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> in high school and his stuttering vanished in front of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuttering a Sensory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motor</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cognitive Disorder</ENAMEX>?
        Stuttering subjects as a group differ from fluent control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> by showing, on average,
        slightly lower intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> on both verbal and nonverbal tasks and by delays in
        speech development (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paden et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). However, decreased
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> need to be interpreted carefully, as stutterers show a schooling
        disadvantage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX> symptoms comprise delays
        in tasks requiring a vocal response (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peters et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>) and in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> bimanual timed
        tasks such as inserting a string in the eye of a needle (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster 1989)</ENAMEX>, whereas
        many other studies on sensory‚Äìmotor reaction times yielded inconsistent results (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">al. 1983</ENAMEX>). Alterations of auditory feedback (e.g., delayed auditory feedback,
        frequency-altered feedback), various forms of other auditory stimulation (e.g., chorus
        reading), and alteration of speech rhythm (e.g., syllable-timed speech) yield a prompt and
        marked reduction of stuttering frequency, which has raised suspicions of impaired auditory
        processing or rhythmic pacemaking in stuttering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berson</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jerger</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salmelin et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have also reported discoordinated
        and delayed onset of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> articulation patterns in stuttering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caruso et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Lieshout et al. 1993).</ENAMEX> The assumption that stuttering might be a form of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">dystonia‚Äîinvoluntary</ENAMEX> muscle contractions produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNS‚</ENAMEX>Äîspecific to language
        production (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiziltan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akalin 1996)</ENAMEX> was not supported by a study on motor cortex
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excitability</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sommer et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>).
        Neurochemistry, however, may link stuttering with disorders of a network of structures
        involved in the control of movement, the basal ganglia. An increase of the neurotransmitter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dopamine</ENAMEX> has been associated with movement disorders such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tourette syndrome</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comings et</ENAMEX>
        al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abwender et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), which is a neurological disorder characterized by repeated
        and involuntary body movements and vocal sounds (motor and vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tics</ENAMEX>). Accordingly, like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tourette syndrome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stuttering</ENAMEX> improves with antidopaminergic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>, e.g., neuroleptics
        such as haloperidol, risperidone, and olanzapine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady 1991; Lavid et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maguire et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">al. 2000</ENAMEX>), and anecdotal reports suggest that it is accentuated or appears under treatment
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dopaminergic medication</ENAMEX> (Koller <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shahed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jankovic 2001).</ENAMEX>
        Hence, a hyperactivity of the dopaminergic neurotransmitter system has been hypothesized to
        contribute to stuttering (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wu et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>). Although dopamine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> have a positive
        effect on stuttering, they all have side effects that have prevented them from being a
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> line treatment of stuttering.
      
      
        Lessons from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imaging the Brain</ENAMEX>
        Given reports on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acquired stuttering</ENAMEX> after brain trauma (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ciabarra et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">al. 2000</ENAMEX>), one might think that a lesion analysis (i.e., asking the question where do all
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> that lead to stuttering overlap) could help to find the location of an abnormality
        linked to stuttering. Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> leading to stuttering are widespread and do
        not seem to follow an overlapping pattern. Even the contrary has been observed, a thalamic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> after which stuttering was ‚Äúcured‚Äù in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muroi et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
        In fluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, the left language-dominant brain hemisphere is most active during
        speech and language tasks. However, early studies on EEG lateralization already strongly
        suggested abnormal hemispheric dominance (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Haynes 1980</ENAMEX>) in stutterers. With the
        advent of other noninvasive brain imaging techniques like positron emission tomography
        brain activity of stutterers and compare these patterns to fluent controls. Following
        prominent theories that linked stuttering with an imbalance of hemispherical asymmetry
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Travis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Haynes 1980</ENAMEX>), an important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PET</ENAMEX> study (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>) reported
        increased activation in the right hemisphere in a language task in developmental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stutterers</ENAMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PET</ENAMEX> study (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braun et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>) confirmed this result, but added an
        important detail to the previous study: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braun</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> found that activity in the
        left hemisphere was more active during the production of stuttered speech, whereas
        activation of the right hemisphere was more correlated with fluent speech. Thus, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> concluded that the primary dysfunction is located in the left hemisphere and that
        the hyperactivation of the right hemisphere might not be the cause of stuttering, but
        rather a compensatory process. A similar compensatory process has been observed after
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> and aphasia, where an intact right hemisphere can at least partially compensate for
        a loss of function (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weiller et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>). Right hemisphere hyperactivation during fluent
        speech has been more recently confirmed with fMRI (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neumann et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PET</ENAMEX> and fMRI have high spatial resolution, but because they only indirectly index brain
        activity through blood flow, their temporal resolution is rather limited.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnetoencephalography</ENAMEX> (MEG) is the method of choice to investigate fine-grained temporal
        sequence of brain activity. Consequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEG</ENAMEX> was used to investigate stutterers and fluent
        controls reading single words (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salmelin et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, stutterers were reported
        to have read most single words fluently. Nevertheless, the data showed a clear-cut
        difference between stutterers and controls. Whereas fluent controls activated left frontal
        brain areas involved in language planning before central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> involved in speech
        execution, this pattern was absent, even reversed, in stutterers. This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> study
        to directly show a neuronal correlate of a hypothesized speech timing disorder in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stutterers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Riper 1982).</ENAMEX>
        Thus, functional neuroimaging studies have revealed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important facts: (i) in
        stutterers, the right hemisphere seems to be hyperactive, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) a timing problem seems
        to exist between the left frontal and the left central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cortex</ENAMEX>. The latter observation also
        fits various observations that have shown that stutterers have slight abnormalities in
        complex coordination tasks, suggesting that the underlying problem is located around motor
        and associated premotor brain areas.
        Are there structural abnormalities that parallel the functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abnormalities</ENAMEX>? The first
        anatomical study to investigate this question used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">high-resolution MR scans</ENAMEX> and found
        abnormalities of speech‚Äìlanguage areas (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broca's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wernicke</ENAMEX>'s area) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundas et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>).
        In addition, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> reported abnormalities in the gyrification pattern.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gyrification</ENAMEX> is a complex developmental procedure, and abnormalities in this process are an
        indicator of a developmental disorder.
        Another recent study investigated the hypothesis that impaired cortical connectivity
        might underlie timing disturbances between frontal and central brain regions observed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEG</ENAMEX> studies (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Using a new MRI technique, diffusion tensor imaging (DTI), that
        allows the assessment of white matter ultrastructure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> saw an area of
        decreased white matter tract coherence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolandic</ENAMEX> operculum (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sommer et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). This
        structure is adjacent to the primary motor representation of tongue, larynx, and pharynx
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>) and the inferior arcuate fascicle linking temporal and frontal
        language areas, which both form a temporofrontal language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> involved in word
        perception and production (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Price et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>). It is thus conceivable that disturbed signal
        transmission through fibers passing the left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolandic</ENAMEX> operculum impairs the fast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">sensorimotor</ENAMEX> integration necessary for fluent speech production. This theory also explains
        why the normal temporal pattern of activation between premotor and motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cortex</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disturbed</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salmelin et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>) and why, as a consequence, the right hemisphere language
        areas try to compensate for this deficit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>).
        These new data also provide a theory to explain the mechanism of common fluency-inducing
        maneuvers like chorus reading, singing, and metronome reading that reduce stuttering
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instantaneously</ENAMEX>. All these procedures involve an external signal (i.e., other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> in
        chorus reading, the music in singing, and the metronome itself). All these external signals
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> into the ‚Äúspeech production system‚Äù through the auditory cortex. It is thus possible
        that this external trigger signal reaches speech-producing central brain areas by
        circumventing the frontocentral disconnection and is able to resynchronize frontocentral
        decorrelated activity. In simple terms, these external cues can be seen as an external
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúpacemaker.</ENAMEX>‚Äù
      
      
        Future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions in Research</ENAMEX>
        There are numerous outstanding issues in stuttering. If structural changes in the brain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cause PDS</ENAMEX>, the key question is when this lesion appears. Although symptoms are somewhat
        different, it would be interesting to find out to what extent transient stuttering (which
        occurs in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì5%</NUMEX> in childhood) is linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDS</ENAMEX>. It is possible that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who show
        signs of stuttering develop a structural abnormality during development, but this is
        transient in those who become fluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>. If this is the case, it is even more
        important that therapy starts as early as possible if it is to have most impact. This
        question can now be answered with current methodology, i.e., noninvasive brain imaging
        using MRI.
        Given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> times less likely to recover from stuttering than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>,
        it is tempting to speculate that all stutterers have a slight abnormality, but only those
        that can use the right hemisphere for language can develop into fluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>. Language
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lateralization</ENAMEX> is less pronounced in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGlone 1980) and</ENAMEX> might therefore be related to
        the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> show an overall lower incidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDS</ENAMEX>. Again, a developmental study
        comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who stutter with fluent controls and, most importantly, longitudinal
        studies on these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should be able to answer these questions.
        It is unlikely that stuttering is inherited in a simple fashion. Currently, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multifactorial</ENAMEX> model for genetic transmission is most likely. Moreover, it is unclear
        whether a certain genotype leads to stuttering or only represents a risk factor and that
        other environmental factors are necessary to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDS</ENAMEX>. Again, this question might be
        answered in the near future, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> has recently completed
        the data collection phase of a large stuttering sample for genetic linkage analysis.
      
    
  
