
  
    
      
        
        My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate adviser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney Brenner</ENAMEX>, used to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">exclaim ‚ÄòRevenons √† nos mutants!‚Äô</ENAMEX> as he sat
        down at the bench to search for yet more genetic variants of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> elegans . Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mutants</ENAMEX> won him a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX>, some thirty
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armand Leroi</ENAMEX> is another aficionado of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> elegans mutants, but he decided to write a book‚Äîand then to
        make a television series‚Äîon mutants of humanity, not of worms. He says at the beginning and
        end of the series: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWe are all mutants, but some of us are more mutant than others.‚Äù This
        is a good slogan, and very proper for embracing humanity as a whole. He backs it up with an
        aphorism from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Etienne Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> of teratology, who proclaimed: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúThere</ENAMEX>
        are no monsters and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> is one.‚Äù What <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geoffroy</ENAMEX> meant was that abnormalities provide
        clues to normal processes, and hence are invaluable to science, if they can be properly
        understood. But monsters and mutants are, undeniably, fascinating in their own right.
        
        Mutants , the book, is excellent: impressively researched and illustrated
        and extremely well written. The resulting television series on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel 4</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> has a distinctly different impact. The series covers only a few of the subjects
        dealt with in the book, and handles the material in a different way. Inevitably, television
        can't include much science or scholarly detail, but it compensates with human images that
        are wholly gripping‚Äîboth the preserved specimens and the living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> who talk about the
        strange conditions that they live with. It's a freak show, but a freak show with thoughtful
        scientific commentary.
        Each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programmes in the series has a particular theme. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, ‚ÄòThe
        Mystery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Growth‚Äô</ENAMEX>, is devoted mainly to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">skeletal disorders</ENAMEX>. We meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole Ozel</ENAMEX>, who copes
        with extraordinary courage with a terrible disease called fibrodysplasia ossificans
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progressiva</ENAMEX> (FOP), in which bony tissue forms throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, gradually immobilizing
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> skeleton. Later we encounter a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of charming and articulate dwarfs
        taking time out from a disco at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> convention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little People of America</ENAMEX>. They
        are happy to be called dwarfs or little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but midget is no longer an acceptable term.
        Being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf</ENAMEX>, in fact, is sometimes a ticket to fame and fortune, as in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
        Boruwlawski, last of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> dwarfs, who enchanted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">royalty</ENAMEX>, married a beautiful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and lived happily to the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄòThe Dangerous Womb‚Äô</ENAMEX>, is about birth defects, conjoined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>, and
        basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryology</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of the piece went to the trouble of getting the developmental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biologist Eddie de Robertis</ENAMEX> to reconstruct the classic experiment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mangold</ENAMEX> and Spemann
        that revealed the underlying basis of some of these defects. The programme goes into some
        detail about what is now known about the molecular basis of normal and abnormal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, and how we can begin to explain such extraordinary forms as that of the Parodi
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twins</ENAMEX>, who had distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> and shoulders, but merged into a single torso and a single
        pair of legs.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> programme, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄòThe Meaning of Beauty‚Äô</ENAMEX>, deals with lesser but still striking
        abnormalities such as albinism and hypertrichosis (excess <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>). It also moves into
        contentious areas, in a frank discussion of race genetics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leroi</ENAMEX> makes the essential point
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loudly</ENAMEX> and clearly: there is much more genetic variation within any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> on earth than
        there is between different human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. We are extraordinarily unified, from a
        genetic standpoint. But, as he notes, the idea of race persists, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 7%</NUMEX> of global
        genetic variation in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIMs</ENAMEX>, ancestry informative markers. Some of these
        distinguish, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> and provide objective information about
        the ancestry of different human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.
        This being television, the series closes with a discussion of beauty, which Leroi
        proposes to be simply the absence of visible mutant defects, using <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saira Mohan</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's idea of human facial perfection, as an exemplar. Yes, she
        looks nice, but nice can be boring. Beauty, above all other human attributes, is profoundly
        influenced by culture, and it is hard to take this interpretation of beauty as an adequate
        explanation, rather than just a pretty way to finish the series.
        For the most part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leroi</ENAMEX> makes an agreeable and humane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>, though he is not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> to the slight self-satisfaction that seems to overcome all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> on television.
        The camera also spends an excessive amount of time dwelling on him, to a point where it
        becomes irritating to see him walking‚Äîfrequently in slow motion‚Äî into yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> or
        laboratory. Sometimes the focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX> pays off, as when we see the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six-foot</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> looking like a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> beside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Greener</ENAMEX>, the tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, or
        witness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leroi</ENAMEX>'s faint chagrin at discovering that his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>, despite his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> family history. More questionable are the bits where he paddles casually
        through a tub of preserved viscera from some long-gone sufferer from situs inversus
        (mirror-reversed organs) and succumbs to laughter at the sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ditto</ENAMEX>, the amazing
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-faced <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>. This may be an honest attempt at portraying the conflicted reactions we all
        have to abnormality, but it seems bound to cause trouble.
        Arty camerawork is a running feature of the programmes, and there is a great deal of
        smoke and mirrors about the whole production. Perhaps this is deliberate, reminding us that
        it is hard to look directly at extreme deformity, but there is an air of ‚ÄòI wants to make
        your flesh creep‚Äô about the many sidelong shots of mutant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> in bottles in the Vrolik
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>, to which we return again and again throughout the series. Viewing the already
        distorted fetuses through further distorting camera angles and under green lighting doesn't
        really achieve anything. The treatment begins to resemble the first 
        Alien movie, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was never allowed to see the monster
        directly.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, what is most memorable about these programmes is the living people
        themselves, and how they have coped with their various genetic disorders. It is very
        touching to see the home movies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany York</ENAMEX>, born with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mermaid syndrome</ENAMEX>, or sirenomelia
        (in which the legs are fused together), taking her first tottery steps after corrective
        surgery, and to listen to her talking philosophically about her life as she floats in a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> swimming pool. It is similarly cheering to hear from the dwarfs and albinos, or
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chuy Aceves</ENAMEX>, who has hypertrichosis and looks like the original <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wolfman</ENAMEX> but
        suffers no ill effects and is proud of his rare <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">condition</ENAMEX>. For these sections alone, let
        alone the serious and well-explained scientific background, the series is well worth
        seeing. It makes one feel surprisingly good about the human race and the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
