
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Hamilton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Briton</ENAMEX> who first described zebrafish (
        Danio rerio ) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1822</TIMEX>, would be astounded to see the scientific
        attention now afforded to this <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two-inch-long</NUMEX> native of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> rivers. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> with no
        economic worth was how he described this little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>. Yet recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>
        awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euros</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> to study zebrafish <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for
        human development and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. When and why did zebrafish swim from home aquaria into
        research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>, and what can we learn about our biology from this surprising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>?
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Early Days</ENAMEX>
        It was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1960s</TIMEX> when phage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geneticist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Streisinger</ENAMEX> began to look for a model
        system in which to study the genetic basis of vertebrate neural development. His passion
        for tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> led him to the humble zebrafish. He was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äòvisionary‚Äô</ENAMEX>, remembers
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neurobiologist Judith Eisen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), ‚Äòwho
        laid the groundwork for the use of zebrafish as a developmental model‚Äô.
        Eisen, who now heads her own research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> to work on 
        Xenopus neural development but soon became attracted to
        zebrafish as a model <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, she explains, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Streisinger</ENAMEX> had worked out
        many of the genetic tricks needed to tackle zebrafish development. What's more, the fish
        had ‚Äòwonderful embryology‚Äô. The embryo, which develops outside its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, is transparent.
        ‚ÄòYou can see different cell types, watch individual cells develop, do transplantation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">experiments‚Äô</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisen</ENAMEX> enthuses, ‚Äòand development is quick but not too quick‚Äô. Being able to
        watch individual neurons developing in real time opened up whole new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> of research
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisen</ENAMEX> and other neurobiologists.
      
      
        Fast Forward to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Screen</ENAMEX>
        The properties of zebrafish that attracted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisen</ENAMEX> soon attracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interested in
        other aspects of vertebrate development to the stripy tiddler (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). As Eisen
        comments: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄòNo other developmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> has risen to prominence so quickly‚Äô. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are listed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZFIN</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States‚Äìbased</ENAMEX> information resource
        for the zebrafish research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
        The speedy expansion was driven in great part by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> genetic screens initiated in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992‚Äì1993</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christiane N√ºsslein-Volhard</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">T√ºbingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang Driever</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Fishman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. The aim of both screens was to identify genes with
        unique and essential functions in zebrafish development, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> an issue of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX> was dedicated to the mutants that had been isolated and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">characterised</ENAMEX>. These screens, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralf Dahm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Planck Institute for Developmental</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T√ºbingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>), project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>, ‚Äòwere the first
        major zebrafish projects, and they showed that zebrafish was a model <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">reckoned with‚Äô.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄòThat</ENAMEX> was a fantastic time‚Äô, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Stemple</ENAMEX>, then a postdoc with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Driever</ENAMEX> but now a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group leader</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>) and a
        ZF-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MODELS participant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄòFrom Wolfgang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, I was able to take the mutations that affected
        notochord development, and have been studying them ever since‚Äô. The notochord is an
        embryonic structure that forms the primitive axial skeleton of the developing embryo, and
        because mutations affecting notochord development result in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">shortened embryos</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of the
        affected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> have been named after the dwarves in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow White‚Äîzebrafish</ENAMEX>, like some other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">developmental</ENAMEX> models, have many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">imaginatively</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mutants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stemple</ENAMEX> now knows the identity
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of these mutated genes, all of which lead to disruption of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement membrane</ENAMEX> around
        the notochord.
        Many mutants from those <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> screens are still used by developmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX>,
        but another set of mutants has recently been isolated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Hopkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amgen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About ten years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> started to develop insertional mutagenesis in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zebrafish</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). In this approach, mutations are caused by the random insertion of
        viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">genome</ENAMEX>. The inserted DNA acts as a tag, making cloning of
        mutated genes very straightforward, although the efficiency of the initial insertional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutagenesis</ENAMEX> is much lower than that of the chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mutagenesis</ENAMEX> used in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992‚Äì1993</NUMEX>
        screens. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> has isolated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> mutants in her screen, representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around 400</NUMEX> different
        genes, and has cloned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300</NUMEX> of these genes to date. Some of the fruits of this
        project are published in this issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is now collaborating
        with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> external <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> on the annotation of the mutant collection with funding from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for Research Resources</ENAMEX>, part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States National Institutes</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T√ºbingen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> did another chemical mutagenesis screen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 2000 and 2001</TIMEX>,
        and are now starting a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> screen of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> genomes as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> project.
        ‚ÄòEach of our screens has built on the previous one by including more specific assays‚Äô,
        explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahm</ENAMEX>. Mutagenesis for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> screen is underway, but the assays, which include
        looking for defects that specifically affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, are still at the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>; this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">autumn</ENAMEX>, the project's executive committee, which is headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N√ºsslein-Volhard</ENAMEX>, will decide
        which assays to use in the full-scale screen. ‚ÄòJust <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consortium</ENAMEX> will come to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T√</ENAMEX>ºbingen to do screens‚Äô, predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahm</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄòBy bringing in expertise
        in different systems in this way we should greatly increase the efficiency of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">screen‚Äô.</ENAMEX>
      
      
        What Else Will ZF-MODELS Do?
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>, which is funded under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sixth Framework</ENAMEX>
        Programme, aims to establish zebrafish <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for human diseases, discover genes that will
        lead to the identification of new drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, and gain fundamental insights into human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄòWe</ENAMEX> will mainly focus on using advanced technologies that have recently become
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">available‚Äô</ENAMEX>, says scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Geisler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Planck Institute for</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Developmental Biology</ENAMEX>). For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geisler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> will use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> chip technology to
        investigate gene expression patterns in zebrafish mutants and so provide increased
        knowledge of the regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> that act in zebrafish development.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consortium</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will also use ‚Äòreverse genetics‚Äô to investigate these pathways. In
        reverse genetics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> start with a gene of interest and investigate the phenotypic
        effect of altering its activity; by contrast, in ‚Äòforward genetics‚Äô the starting point is
        to look for a particular phenotype and then hunt out the altered gene that is causing it.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> reverse genetics approaches will be used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>. Gene expression will be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transiently</ENAMEX> knocked down with morpholinos, short segments of the gene that block its
        function. In addition, a recently developed technique known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TILLING</ENAMEX> (targeting induced
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> in genomes) will be used to knock out gene activity permanently.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TILLING</ENAMEX> is to mutagenise male zebrafish and mate them with untreated
        female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stemple</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> who will use
        this approach. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Offspring</ENAMEX> are raised to adulthood, and the DNA of each individual is then
        genotyped for the exon of interest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> already has a collection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> such
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, and once a fish carrying a mutation in the gene of interest has been
        identified, it will be outcrossed to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of which will carry the
        desired mutation on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of their chromosomes. ‚ÄòIt is then a matter of identifying these
        heterozygote <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and incrossing them to get homozygous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in which you can see the
        phenotype that correlates with that mutation‚Äô, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stemple</ENAMEX>.
        As well as helping to produce knock-outs for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stemple</ENAMEX> is also using
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TILLING</ENAMEX> technique to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">zebrafish models</ENAMEX> for muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dystrophy</ENAMEX>. Among the genes
        that are important in notochord development are those that encode laminins. This led
        Stemple into studying muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dystrophy</ENAMEX> because laminins are involved in the human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄòWhen we used morpholinos to disrupt [the production of] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dystroglycan</ENAMEX>, a laminin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, we got a good model for muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dystrophy‚</ENAMEX>Äô, he explains. Now, he plans to use
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TILLING</ENAMEX> to disrupt <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 30</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> known to be involved in human muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dystrophy</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄòIn particular, we will look for hypomorphic mutants, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that are viable but on the edge
        of falling apart‚Äô. These mutants can be used to identify small molecules that push the fish
        into muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dystrophy</ENAMEX>. Finding molecules that can cause a disease in this way ‚Äòmight give
        us a handle on something to fix the disease‚Äô, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stemple</ENAMEX>.
        In another strand of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> project, zebrafish expressing green fluorescent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (GFP) in specific cells or tissues will be generated and characterised (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        In such <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, developing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> can be easily imaged over time in the living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embryo</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> working on this aspect of the project is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Wilson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Developmental Genetics</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">College London</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GFP</ENAMEX> lines can be made
        either by attaching to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> gene regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> that control, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äòdrive‚Äô, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> expression
        in selected cell types or by allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> gene to insert randomly in the genome and
        looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> with specific expression patterns. ‚ÄòThere are now many lines of fish
        available with different GFP expression patterns‚Äô, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>, ‚Äòand it is important to
        catalogue their expression so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can use the most appropriate lines for their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">research‚Äô.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s own interest is in neuroanatomy. Together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Clarke</ENAMEX>, another
        developmental neurobiology group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">College London</ENAMEX>, he plans to analyse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GFP</ENAMEX> lines in which small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of neurons or particular parts of neurons are labelled, and
        in this way start to build a detailed reconstruction of early brain neuroanatomy. This, in
        combination with other work on zebrafish carrying mutations affecting neural development,
        will give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> ‚Äòa better picture of how a vertebrate brain is built‚Äô.
        A final, important aspect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> project, adds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahm</ENAMEX>, is database construction.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄòWe</ENAMEX> will be developing a set of databases that will integrate all of the project data‚Äô, he
        explains. ‚ÄòIn addition, we hope to integrate our data with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZFIN</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to make one central zebrafish resource‚Äô.
      
      
        But <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish Aren't People</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> are understandably excited about
        participating in what will, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geisler</ENAMEX>, bring an already strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> zebrafish
        community closer together. But zebrafish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are also excited
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> project. ‚ÄòWe need big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> models like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZF-MODELS</ENAMEX> in developmental biology‚Äô,
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX>, noting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> working in isolation are long gone. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consortium</ENAMEX>, adds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hughes Medical Institute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Zon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Medical</ENAMEX>
        School, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), ‚Äòwill not only have an effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        zebrafish science but also on how it is done in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States‚Äô.</ENAMEX>
        But how much can zebrafish tell us about human development and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>? A lot, say
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zebrafish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄòFish really are just little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with fins‚Äô, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄòOf
        course, there are developmental differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, and no one pretends
        that we can answer every question about human development in zebrafish‚Äô. Nevertheless,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zebrafish</ENAMEX> studies can provide valuable clues to the genes involved in human diseases and to
        potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> for therapeutic interventions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> provides the following
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">illustration: ‚</ENAMEX>ÄòWe have been doing ‚Äúshelf screens‚Äù, in which we go back to our collection of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutants</ENAMEX> to find all those that affect the development of a single organ. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhaoxia Sun</ENAMEX>,
        a postdoc in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> who now has an independent position at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Medical School</ENAMEX>, screened
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cystic kidney disease</ENAMEX>, she found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> were known
        to cause human cystic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney disease</ENAMEX>, so we knew we were in the human disease pathway
        somewhere, but we had no idea what the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes were‚Äô</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins and Sun</ENAMEX> have since
        identified the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, and these point to a single pathway being involved in the
        human disease.
        Developmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geneticist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didier Stainier</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) is also using zebrafish to study organ development, in
        particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart</ENAMEX> development. The zebrafish heart is like the early human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heart‚</ENAMEX>Äîa tube
        with an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">atrium</ENAMEX>, ventricle, and valves. ‚ÄòEverything we have found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> is relevant to
        the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heart‚Äô</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stainier</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄòObviously</ENAMEX>, there are additional processes involved in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, but the basic outline of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart</ENAMEX> development in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is largely similar‚Äô.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stainier</ENAMEX> has a collection of zebrafish in which valve formation is faulty. ‚ÄòSome of the
        genes we have found will be involved in human congenital valve defects‚Äô, he predicts.
        Knowing the identity of these genes will be useful diagnostically, but, in addition,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zebrafish</ENAMEX> studies can reveal exactly what has gone wrong at a cellular level. The ability
        to follow individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> as organs develop is key to this, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stainier</ENAMEX>, who reported in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> that fibronectin is required for heart development because, by regulating the
        polarisation of epithelial cells, fibronectin ensures the correct migration of myocardial
        cells. And in this issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology, Stainier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> have identified another zebrafish
        gene that is involved in heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">development‚Äîcardiofunk</ENAMEX>, which encodes a special type of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">muscle protein</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Proliferation of Zebrafish Models of Human Disease</ENAMEX>
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are now recognising the value of zebrafish models of human disease.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three to four years</TIMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zon</ENAMEX>, this area of research has become a growth
        industry. The interest in disease <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> has grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX>-in-hand with the development of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morpholinos</ENAMEX> to knock out specific genes, and the advent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TILLING</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zon, ‚Äòhas</ENAMEX> set off
        a whole new fury. There are now large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> who will try to knock out
        their favourite gene and come up with a model‚Äô.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zon</ENAMEX> has worked on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> models for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), blood vessel, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disorders</ENAMEX>
        but is currently studying zebrafish models of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄòWe</ENAMEX> started by doing chemical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutagenesis</ENAMEX> and screened for cell-cycle mutants. These were embryonic lethals, but when we
        looked at heterozygote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> of these mutations, some developed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> at a high rate as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adults‚Äô.</ENAMEX> Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zon</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have returned to the cell-cycle mutant that yielded
        this cancer-susceptible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heterozygote</ENAMEX> and are using embryos in high-throughput screening
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assays</ENAMEX> to look for small molecules that can suppress the cell-cycle phenotype. These
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molecules</ENAMEX>, reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zon</ENAMEX>, may have potential as anticancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        And the Future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zebrafish Research</ENAMEX>?
        Bigger and bigger seems to be the consensus. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical</ENAMEX> screens like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zon's</ENAMEX> for anticancer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> can be set up for other human diseases such as muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dystrophy</ENAMEX>. Work like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stainier</ENAMEX>'s on organ development may have applications in tissue engineering. ‚ÄòIf we can
        find out what drives differentiation in zebrafish‚Äô, he suggests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äòwe</ENAMEX> might be able to do
        the same for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells‚Äô</ENAMEX>, making human tissue replacement therapy a practical possibility.
        And while many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zebrafish researchers</ENAMEX> will continue to study development, others are now
        moving into the realms of physiology and behavioural studies.
        Geisler sums up zebrafish developmental research past, present, and future as follows:
        ‚ÄòNo other [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vertebrate</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> offers the same combination of transparent and accessible
        embryos, cost-effective mutagenesis screening, and, more recently, a sequenced genome,
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>] chip, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX>, and knockout technology‚Äô. Add to that the potential of zebrafish embryos
        as a screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> for small molecule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> and the new technologies that allow
        forward and reverse genetics, and it is clear that zebrafish are not about to revert to
        being pretty pets swimming in small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> in the corner of the living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Where to Find Out More
        ZF-MODELS
        More details of the work included in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union Integrated Project</ENAMEX> can be found
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX>zf-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>
        ZFIN
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZFIN</ENAMEX> Web site, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://z.n.org/ZFIN</ENAMEX>, provides an extensive database for the
        zebrafish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> including genetic, genomic, and developmental information; search
        engines for zebrafish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>; listings of meetings; and links to many
        other zebrafish sites, including <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> with movies of zebrafish development.
        The special issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec 1</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">123: 1‚Äì461</ENAMEX>) on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mutagenesis
        screens contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> research articles and can be freely accessed at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://dev.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/content/vol123/issue1/</ENAMEX>index.shtml
      
    
  
