
  
    
      
        
        The launch of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Biology —only</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX> ago—was just a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of Science</ENAMEX>. Our initial goal was to create a flagship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> for the broader PLoS
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> by providing an open-access alternative to the best subscription <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> in the
        life sciences, and to put open access firmly on the map.
        Despite its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> is already becoming established as a publication of high
        standing, and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> is rapidly heading in the same direction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Submissions</ENAMEX> to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> have steadily grown, recently surpassing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> mark, and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> sees international coverage of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. With the increasing support for open
        access in general, the time is now ripe to build on the success of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> flagship
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> by taking the next step and launching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> will give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> an opportunity to publish a greater range
        of high-quality papers in open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, so that anyone can read, use, and build on
        their work. But these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> will also serve another function—they will provide
        examples that other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> can follow, and will increase confidence in the sustainability
        of open-access publishing as a business model. More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> are exploring ways to remove
        existing subscription barriers and edge towards open access. And more funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are
        expressing their commitment to make the findings of the research they support freely
        available to the public. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> will lend further weight to this
        inexorable shift towards open access.
        Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> will cover a broad field of research—so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> serve
        specific scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are also run by the community—academic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> and associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. And some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>
        will be collaborations with established community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Society</ENAMEX>
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Computational Biology</ENAMEX> (ISCB), with whom we are partnering for the launch of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Computational Biology</ENAMEX> . The twin strands of open-source software and
        public databases of biological information converge on this burgeoning discipline, and the
        case for an open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> in computational biology is easily made. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISCB</ENAMEX> has taken
        a bold step, in the best interests of its discipline and membership. We hope that this
        action by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISCB</ENAMEX> will inspire other scholarly societies to follow suit and will be only
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many such collaborations between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
        The editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> running the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> already comprise a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, each headed by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor-in-chief</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip E. Bourne</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Computational Biology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ploscompbiol</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne N. Frankel</ENAMEX> (The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Laboratory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Genetics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plosgenetics</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A. T. Young</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salk</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Pathogens</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plospathogens</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>). The willingness of so many
        leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to devote precious time to these new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> is testament to the level
        of commitment to open access that now exists within the research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and the trust
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> has gained as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> of science and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>.
        And what of the relationship between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> ? Does 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> still want papers in the areas in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> launches new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX>? Will 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> be rejecting more such papers in the knowledge that
        they will find a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">PLoS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>? Let us assure you that we—the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology —remain</ENAMEX> committed to publishing the best research across all
        of biology.
        Moreover, our relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> is one of strict editorial
        independence. There is some overlap of membership on the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> and the community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, reflecting a level of dedication
        to open access, but as with all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> who serve on multiple editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> who review for multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are governed by
        confidentiality. That said, if an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> would like a manuscript that has been turned down
        by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> to be passed on to another, along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>' reports and their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">identities</ENAMEX>, we are happy to cooperate, subject to the permission of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>. This can
        help to expedite the review process, saving time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are committed to offering a
        peer-review service that is as constructive, transparent, and efficient as possible.
        In the world of scientific publishing, there is nothing quite like launching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>,
        especially when the case for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is as strong as it is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX>. It's enthralling, nerve-racking, and relentless work. But when the manuscripts
        begin to arrive, the editorial process kicks into action, and the production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> starts
        crafting the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> accepted articles, it's hard to contain the excitement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> is still a
        relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> have played a part in preparing for the
        introduction of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> is much bigger than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the payroll.
        It's the research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that is making PLoS work, as demonstrated most emphatically by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> and editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who have stepped up to launch the first
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. Please join us in making them a success, and enjoy your
        share of the excitement.
      
    
  
