
  
    
      
        
        In what is usually referred to as the most famous experiment in embryology, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Spemann</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilde Mangold</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>) showed that a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> in early frog embryos called the
        blastopore lip can induce a second complete embryonic axis, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, when
        transplanted to a host <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embryo</ENAMEX>. Most of the axis, including the nervous system, was derived
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, whose cells were induced to form an axis by the graft, therefore named the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Induction</ENAMEX> refers to the change in fate of a group of cells in response to
        signals from other cells. The signal-receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> must be capable of responding, a
        property termed competence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spemann‚</ENAMEX>ÄìMangold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>. which‚Äîas the transplantation
        experiment shows‚Äîis able to turn cells whose original fate would be gut or ventral
        epidermis into brain or somites, is the prototypical inducing tissue. And neural induction
        has for a long time been regarded as a process by which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> signals, in their normal
        context, redirect ectodermal cells from an epidermal towards a neural fate. The nature of
        the neural inducer or inducers and the mechanism of neural induction have been and remain
        hot topics in developmental biology.
        For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spemann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mangold</ENAMEX>, studies on amphibians monopolized the
        subject, and even more recently, a large part of the progress in analyzing organizer
        formation and function and neural induction was based on amphibians, mostly the model
        species 
        Xenopus laevis . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>, however, work in other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vertebrate</ENAMEX> and nonvertebrate chordate systems has come to play an important role in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX> and has shed light on generalities and differences among chordates. If the present
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX> uses 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xenopus</ENAMEX> to illustrate the process, it is because it accompanies
        an article in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> dealing with neural development in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuroda et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al. 2004) and</ENAMEX>, of course, because of the experience of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. Here I shall outline
        the understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> formation and neural induction as it has evolved over recent
        times and attempt to integrate recent results from different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> into a common
        pattern.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cortical Rotation and Nuclear Localization</ENAMEX> of Œ≤-Catenin
        The frog <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> is radially symmetrical around the animal‚Äìvegetal axis that has been
        established during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">oogenesis</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Fertilization</ENAMEX> triggers a rotation of the cortex relative to
        the cytoplasm that is associated with the movement of dorsal determinants from the vegetal
        pole to the future dorsal region of the embryo (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerhart et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>). (A brief
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">parenthetical</NUMEX> point is in order here. Conventionally, the side of the amphibian and fish
        embryo where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> forms has been called dorsal, with the opposite side labeled as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ventral</ENAMEX>. This axis assignment does not project unambiguously onto the clearly defined
        dorsal‚Äìventral polarity of the larva, as pointed out forcefully in recent publications
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX> and Sheets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000, 2002</TIMEX>]. In these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, a new proposal is made
        for polarity assignments in the gastrula that, I believe, has some merit, but also presents
        some difficulties. As the conventional approach of equating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> side with dorsal
        seems to remain in wide use at present, I shall apply this convention, albeit with the
        reservation above.)
        While the nature of the dorsal determinants is still in dispute, it is clear that the
        consequence of their translocation is the nuclear localization of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Œ≤-catenin</NUMEX> in a wide arc
        at the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer side</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schneider et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schohl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fagotto 2002).</ENAMEX>
        Nuclear localization of Œ≤-catenin appears to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> event that determines
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dorsal/ventral</ENAMEX> polarity in the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xenopus</ENAMEX> and zebrafish embryos (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hibi et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). No comparable
        early event appears to be involved in amniote (e.g., chick and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>) embryos.
      
      
        Induction by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Organizer: Antagonizing Bone Morphogenetic Protein</ENAMEX>
        As gastrulation starts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spemann‚</ENAMEX>ÄìMangold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>, which includes mostly axial
        mesodermal precursors, was classically believed to instruct na√Øve ectoderm to convert to
        neural tissue. In transplant or explant studies, animal ectoderm that forms epidermis, when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undisturbed</ENAMEX>, is susceptible to neural induction by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>. This fact prompted a
        search for neural inducers that eventually led to the identification of several substances
        with the expected properties‚Äîorganizer products that can neuralize ectoderm. Their
        molecular properties were at first surprising: they proved to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> of other
        signaling factors, mostly of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone morphogenetic proteins</ENAMEX> (BMPs) and also of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNT</ENAMEX> (a secreted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein homologous</ENAMEX> to the 
        Drosophila Wingless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nodal</ENAMEX> factors (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sasai</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De</ENAMEX>
        Robertis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hibi et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). These observations led to the formulation of a ‚Äúdefault‚Äù
        model of neural induction (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hemmati-Brivanlou 1997</ENAMEX>), which states that
        ectodermal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> will differentiate along a neural pathway unless induced to a different
        fate. The heuristic simplicity and logical cogency of this model facilitated its wide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX>, although it did not explain the processes that set the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúdefault</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Some of these
        processes have been the subject of subsequent studies that were conducted in several
        different species, and this has led to a more refined (and probably more accurate)
        picture.
      
      
        The Role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fibroblast Growth Factor</ENAMEX>
        For example, additional signaling pathways are now known to operate. Recent work on
        neural induction comes to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major conclusions: (i) the fibroblast growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (FGF)
        signaling pathway plays a major role in this process, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) neural specification starts
        well before gastrulation and thus before the formation and function of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>.
        Studies on the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> in early 
        Xenopus development initially discovered its role in mesoderm
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX> and the formation of posterior tissues (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kimelman et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>). And while the
        involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> in neuralization was observed early in this system (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harland</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Launay et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hongo et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardcastle et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), in view of the
        impressive effects seen with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chordin</ENAMEX> and other BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>, the relevance of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> in neural specification in amphibians and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> was slow to be recognized. It took
        elegant studies, mostly in chick embryos (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Streit et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), and their eloquent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exposition</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Streit</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Edlund</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern 2002)</ENAMEX> to turn the tide,
        but there is now no doubt that the FGF signaling pathway plays a major role in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specification</ENAMEX> and early development of the neural ectoderm in chordates.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> does not seem to behave as a classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>-derived neural inducer, however.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maternal FGF</ENAMEX> mRNA and protein appear to be widely distributed in the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embryo</ENAMEX>, and at
        least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> is expressed primarily in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, pre-ectodermal region
        during blastula stages (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slack 1996).</ENAMEX> A detailed study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> where
        different signaling pathways are active during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">embryogenesis</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schohl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fagotto 2002</ENAMEX>)
        showed that the entire ectoderm is probably exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> signals at or prior to the time
        of neural induction, with the more vegetal, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mesoderm-proximal</ENAMEX> region of the ectoderm being
        exposed to higher levels. Thus, exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> is required to endow the ectoderm with the
        competence to respond to additional signals that will act later on its way towards neural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specification</ENAMEX>. Such a process was deduced from experiments in the chick, where an FGF
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> must be followed by exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> signals to sensitize the tissue to BMP
        antagonists that ultimately stabilize the neural fate (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern 2002).</ENAMEX>
        An exciting recent study shows that exposure of the epiblast (ectoderm) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> induces,
        after a time delay, a transcription factor named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> expression inhibits
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell ingression</ENAMEX> leading to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mesoderm</ENAMEX> formation; the cells remaining in the epiblast assume a
        neural fate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheng et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). The time delay in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> induction appears to be the
        key in explaining how one signal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX>, can be involved in mesodermal and neural development
        at the same time in cells that are in close proximity. The question how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> signaling can
        lead to different outcomes was also addressed in a study on neural specification in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascidians</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertrand et al. 2003).</ENAMEX> Here, the FGF signal leads to neural induction through
        the coordinated activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> transcription factors, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ets1/2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATAa</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> does
        not activate GATAa during its function in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mesoderm</ENAMEX> formation. Thus, similar input leads to
        distinct output as a result of different responses by target tissues, stressing the
        importance of competence in this inductive process.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Predisposition</ENAMEX>
        Not surprisingly, then, attention has turned to the target tissues and to the
        prepatterns that might already exist. In 
        Xenopus , it was long known that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> region or
        pre-ectoderm is not uniform or na√Øve, in that the dorsal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>-proximal region is
        predisposed towards a neural fate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpe et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>). The paper by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuroda et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>)
        adds much information about neural specification before gastrulation in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xenopus</ENAMEX> and the factors involved in this process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        identify a region in the dorsal ectoderm of the blastula that they name the ‚Äúblastula
        Chordin- and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nogginexpressing‚Äù</ENAMEX> (or BCNE) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). They show that this region,
        which I prefer to simply call dorsal ectoderm, expresses 
        siamois , 
        chordin , and 
        Xnr3 , another Œ≤-catenin target. The dorsal ectoderm or BCNE is fully
        specified as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anterior neural ectoderm</ENAMEX>, as excision of this region led to headless embryos,
        and explants differentiated into neural tissue in culture, even when the formation of any
        mesodermal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was blocked by interference with nodal signaling (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuroda et al. 2004).</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuroda et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) further show that induction of anterior neural tissue initiated by
        Œ≤-catenin requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chordin</ENAMEX>, whereas formation of posterior neural tissue does not. This
        latter point concerns an issue not yet mentioned here, namely anterior‚Äìposterior patterning
        of the neural ectoderm, a process that occurs in concert with neural induction per se. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">patterning</ENAMEX> appears to involve the interaction of various signaling factors, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX>,
        BMP, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNT</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">retinoic acid</ENAMEX>, all of which act as posteriorizing factors (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kudoh et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). Suppression of BMP signaling by expression of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> is the condition that
        specifies the dorsal ectoderm or BCNE as future anterior neural ectoderm; in contrast,
        posterior neural ectoderm may form under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> even in the presence of BMP
        signaling. The work by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuroda et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) thus shows that initial specification of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anterior</ENAMEX> neural ectoderm in 
        Xenopus , as in other vertebrates, takes place before
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gastrulation</ENAMEX> and does not require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> signals; this is not to say that full
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> and patterning of the nervous system could be achieved without organizer
        participation.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Induction</ENAMEX> and Competence
        The formation of the vertebrate nervous system thus depends on multiple signaling
        pathways, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNT</ENAMEX> signaling cascades, that interact in complex ways
        (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pera et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). In contrast to the classical view, neural induction is not
        exclusively promoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>-derived signals, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that earlier</TIMEX> signals and intrinsic
        processes that determine ectodermal competence are prominently involved. Whether inductive
        signals or competence of responding tissue is more important in embryology has been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">debated</ENAMEX>, much like the nature‚Äìnurture controversy in the behavioral arena. Current work has
        given some boost to the competence side of the argument, but, as in behavior, the truth
        lies somewhere in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, though not necessarily at the halfway mark. Studies such as
        those discussed here bring us closer to finding the answer to this question.
      
    
  
