
  
    
      
        
        the clear inequalities in science between developing and developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and to the
        challenges of building <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> across these gaps that should bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and
        the world scientific community closer to each other (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan 2003).</ENAMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> stressed the
        importance of reducing the inequalities in science between developed and developing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, asserting that ‚ÄúThis unbalanced distribution of scientific activity generates
        serious problems not only for the scientific community in the developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, but for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> itself.‚Äù Indeed, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s sentiments have also been echoed recently by
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, who present overwhelming evidence for the disparity in scientific
        output between the developing and already developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (Gibbs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX>;
        Goldemberg <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riddoch 2000).</ENAMEX> For example, recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations Educational</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cultural Organization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX>) estimates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>) indicate that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the
        developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> accounted for some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84%</NUMEX> of the global investment in scientific research
        and development, had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 72%</NUMEX> of the world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, and produced approximately
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88%</NUMEX> of all scientific and technical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> registered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Citation Index</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCI</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> clearly dominate the number of scientific publications
        produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36.6% and 37.5%</NUMEX>, respectively, worldwide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>).
        
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> clearly dominate the number of scientific
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
          
        
        It is rather obvious that richer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are able to invest more resources in science
        and therefore account for the largest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. It is also likely that there
        is a statistical bias on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCI</ENAMEX> as a bibliometric database, since it
        represents <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> far better than those of the rest of
        the world (Gibbs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alonso and Fern√°ndez-Juricic</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vohora</ENAMEX> and Vohora
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). But is the disparity in scientific contributions between the developed and
        developing worlds actually remaining unchanged or even increasing, as Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> has
        implied? A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">closer</ENAMEX> look at the trends over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX> reveals important advances in
        developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, although representing,
        respectively, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1.8% and 2%</NUMEX> of scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> worldwide, have increased the
        number of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 and 1997</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36% and 70%</NUMEX>, respectively, which is a
        much higher percentage than the increments reached by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) and industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX>). The percentage of global scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> actually
        decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> over the same period (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>).
      
      
        Publishing Trends in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americas</ENAMEX>
        Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCI</ENAMEX> databases produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Scientific Information</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISI</ENAMEX>), as
        well as data compiled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Iberoamericana de Indicadores de Ciencia y Tecnolog√</ENAMEX>≠a
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RICYT</ENAMEX>), we examined the differences in the number and proportion of scientific
        publications between the developed world and the developing world from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 until 2000</TIMEX>,
        focusing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX> as a case study. Not surprisingly, there was a huge disparity in
        the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 until 2000</TIMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> contributing the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lion</ENAMEX>'s share (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84.2%</NUMEX>), followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.35%</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> as a whole contributed
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5.45%</NUMEX> to the total number of scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these ten years</TIMEX> (RICYT
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
        The total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, however, is not necessarily the best measure for
        assessing scientific productivity or technical advances (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX>). More relevant
        measurements for these factors include the proportional change in the number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> and the total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> when corrected for investment in research
        and development (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX>). The proportional change in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, using
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> as a comparison, revealed that scientific publishing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> increased the
        most rapidly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX>, far outpacing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        Further analyses, correcting the number of overall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> for the amount of money
        invested in research and development for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX>, also show that, in contrast to both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> has been an increase in relative
        output throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Moreover, when taking into account the amount of
        research money available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> actually out-published the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Although the cost of research is undoubtedly
        cheaper in the developing world due to relatively low <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> salaries, overhead and
        other work standards, these factors do not explain the substantial increase in the number
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> per amount of money allocated to research and development in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>,
        particularly from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 until 2000</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        Other relative indicators of scientific productivity, such as the number of publications
        picked up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCI</ENAMEX> in relation to the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> in a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, also
        demonstrate that such developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> are making substantial
        contributions to science, despite the fact that the average proportion of gross domestic
        product (GDP) invested in science in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> throughout this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> period was only
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX> of the amount invested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (RICYT <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). Indeed, this scientific
        productivity is remarkable when we compare it with the relatively low investment in science
        itself as compared with the GDP of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> as a whole. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albornoz</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>)
        concluded that, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> could afford to invest a much higher proportion
        research and development represented <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 0.59%</NUMEX> of the regional GDP in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, a very weak
        effort compared with that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.84%</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX>).
        Among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, there is a high degree of variability in publication
        rate as well as in financial investment in science and technology. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have
        performed particularly well. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uruguay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> averaged,
        respectively, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.3</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.2</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> of research and
        development investment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 10 years</TIMEX> studied, which is notoriously high compared with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.5</NUMEX>) and even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.3</NUMEX>) (RICYT <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>, have invested a much greater proportion of their GDP in
        research and development than the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of this region (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albornoz 2001).</ENAMEX>
        
          
            Why has the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> per dollar invested in research and
            development been increasing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> while decreasing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>?
          
        
      
      
        Explaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Increase in Publishing Productivity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> potential explanation for the increase in scientific productivity in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
        is that scientific development during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> was particularly strong for many countries
        of this region. Indeed, this would explain the rapid rise in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> compared with the relatively flat increases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>,
        which were publishing just as well at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the decade</TIMEX>. A potentially more
        important question, however, is why the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> per dollar invested in
        research and development has been increasing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> while decreasing in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. This pattern could be the result of a variety of factors, none of
        which are mutually exclusive. It is possible that publishing in international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> as a
        measure of scientific productivity is becoming more important in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>. Increased
        funding to the most productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> from the national science development programs
        might have been an important stimulus. International cooperation resulting in more
        scientific collaborations among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
        may also have increased the relative number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>. In contrast,
        the decreasing trends in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> per investment dollar in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> could reflect a trend towards more costly research in larger scientific
        programs.
      
      
        Scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impact</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
        What, exactly, is the relative impact of such developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> on the
        scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>? We used SCI <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> data to examine the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in
        the area of ecology (including the fields of evolutionary biology, conservation biology,
        and global change biology) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 2002</TIMEX> in both the two top general science
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> (
        Nature and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> ; with impact factors of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">27.96 and 23.33</NUMEX>, respectively) and in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> top ecological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> (with impact factors of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.51‚Äì2.47</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2001a</ENAMEX>). We credited
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> with a publication if any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> were affiliated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> from
        that region. Thus, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> would receive credit for a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> if
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> had been written by multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of different
        regions.
        For the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ecological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subcontinents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North America</ENAMEX> accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62%</NUMEX> of the publications worldwide. Within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX>,
        however, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> represented <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 6%</NUMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> accounted,
        respectively, for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13% and 82%</NUMEX> of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ecological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. When we examined the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> as contributions to the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ecological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> (impact factors <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.51‚Äì3.31</NUMEX>) versus
        the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11‚Äì20</NUMEX> (impact factors <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.28‚Äì2.47</NUMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> contributed nearly
        twice as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> category (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11‚Äì20</NUMEX> compared
        with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>). These findings suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> from such developing
        regions as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> are falling short of reaching the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. In contrast, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> contributed somewhat more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> to the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84%</NUMEX>) than the
        top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11‚Äì20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79%</NUMEX>). The difference in the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> contributed by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> and top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> was even more pronounced when we
        examined it in respect to worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. In this case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
        contributed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> to the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 40%</NUMEX> of the publications
        to the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11‚Äì20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>.
        Interestingly, the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> across all subject areas in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> and 
        Nature were nearly identical to those of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ecological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>.
        In 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americas</ENAMEX>
        versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ecological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX>
        versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82% and 12%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX>, respectively. These similarities suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are not shying away from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">top-ranked general</ENAMEX> science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>.
        However, publishing in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> and 
        Nature was not enough to gain prominence, as evidenced by the number of
        citations of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>. The latest list of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">247</NUMEX> most-cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ecology</ENAMEX> and environmental sciences emphasizes the overwhelming contributions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73%</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2001b</ENAMEX>). No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> working in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> was included in the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>. Overall, these data indicate that
        the scientific output in the field of ecology in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> is having a relatively low
        impact in the international scientific community and is underrepresented in the top
        international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, despite its robust productivity as measured by the number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> funding amount. Similar findings were also reported for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swinbanks et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>) and thus could be a general phenomenon in the developing world.
        Although there are outstanding scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in the developing world who
        independently are making important contributions to the international scientific community,
        they are the exception. Why, in general, do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> often fail to reach
        the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> or become amongst the most cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in their fields? One
        possibility is that the main research agendas between both regions are somewhat different
        and that the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, which are published in the developed world, respond more to the
        scientific mainstream of the developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>. This is not to suggest any sort of
        conspiracy, but rather it implies that the perception of the most important science is
        linked to the region and that because the major funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> as well as most prominent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> share a similar economic region, they also share the same perception of what
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> is most interesting to them. Another consideration is that more local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> from
        developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> are listed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCI</ENAMEX> than similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> from developing regions
        (Gibbs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>). Consequently, there are more high-profile regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> opportunities
        available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> from the developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX>, whereas much of the research published
        locally in the developing world is overlooked. But it takes more than publishing good
        papers to become a highly cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>. It requires attending international meetings and
        introducing novel research findings in multiple scientific forums. Funding these
        activities, however, requires a greater proportion of research money being spent on
        meetings for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in the developing compared with the developed world.
      
      
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Long Road Yet to Travel</ENAMEX>
        The positive trends in scientific productivity in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> should not be
        misinterpreted as a reason to be unconcerned about the existing gap highlighted by Mr.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>. There are many compelling reasons for the push to increase scientific input from the
        developing world (Goldemberg <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan 2003).</ENAMEX> One is that science, as a discipline, would
        benefit from the contributions of many disparate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> around the world, rather than being
        dominated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> geographic regions. Many scientific problems could be solved much more
        readily with the cooperation and scientific insight of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> from developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>.
        Climate change and biodiversity research, for example, urgently need the scientific input
        from those developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> that are so important for these global processes. It is also
        critical for the developing world to promote, through research and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, those
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of concern that are having a proportionally greater scientific and social impact upon
        them. There are now examples in which research on priority areas for the developing nations
        can actually become pioneering work in areas neglected by the research agenda of the
        industrialized world. This has been the case for research on renewable energy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Goldemberg 1998</ENAMEX>) and biomedical sciences in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro D√≠az-Balart 2002).</ENAMEX> These
        examples are important not only for those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> of the developing world, but are also in
        themselves scientific innovations that can greatly advance the knowledge of the rest of the
        world.
        
          
            Climate change and biodiversity research urgently need the scientific
            input from those developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> that are so important for global processes.
          
        
        Although the evidence presented here demonstrates that there is a long way to go before
        developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> contribute a more equitable share to the international scientific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, there are also reasons to be optimistic. The relative increase in the number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>, especially when corrected for the amount of money available in research and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, demonstrates that many developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are heading in the right
        direction. The extremely high scientific productivity of many developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, corrected
        for and despite the rather limited availability of funds, suggests that increased funding
        to the sciences will be an excellent investment by developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> in terms of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> as a measure of scientific output, particularly if these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> can
        target the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> that have the greatest impact. Although there may still be a long road
        to travel, we feel optimistic that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> mentioned by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> are slowly being
        built.
      
    
  
