
  
    
      
        
        From a human perspective, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX> seem a relatively simple thing to get one's head
        around‚Äîthere are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, and there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>. But our perspective seems biased and narrow
        when applied to life as a whole, says evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Hurst</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Bath</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>.‚ÄúIf you were a single-celled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alga</ENAMEX> sitting in a pond, you
        wouldn't see the world as splitting into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        In fact, different species have evolved a bewildering number of ways to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix</ENAMEX> and match
        the attributes of sexes. Some do not have males and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, but have adaptations that mean
        each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> performs a specific role during sex. There are other species of which every
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> is sexually equivalent, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> nevertheless divide into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for the
        purposes of mating. And in some species, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> make both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). This
        biological diversity has produced a semantic muddle among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists‚Äîeveryone</ENAMEX> who thinks
        about the evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX> seems to have a slightly different take on what a sex is. ‚ÄúThe
        literature is highly confusing‚Äîwe need to clarify our terminology,‚Äù comments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolf Hoekstra</ENAMEX>,
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geneticist</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Waageningen</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>.
        As things stand, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main aspects to the definition of a sex: who you are,
        who you can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with, and who your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> part of this trinity‚Äîparental
        number‚Äîshows the least variation in nature. No known <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> needs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> mother
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. But even this assumption is now starting to break down at the level of
        biological systems. In a recently discovered hybrid system within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">harvester ant</ENAMEX> genus 
        Pogonomyrmex , queens must mate with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> to
        produce both reproductive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> are the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> known which truly has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> sexes‚Äîwith <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> effectively having three
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parents‚Äî</ENAMEX> argues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Parker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lausanne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX>'s ideas might reactivate evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX>' interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX>, which has
        lain somewhat dormant since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. It could also provide a new route to experiments‚Äî
        something often lacking in the field. Not everyone agrees that it makes sense to define the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX>' genetic quirks as new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX> is still only a mix the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from no more than
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, after all. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> believes that our current ideas about mating systems may
        not be adequate to describe the ingenuity of evolution. ‚ÄúUntil you see a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-sex system,
        you don't know what it'll look like,‚Äù he says.
      
      
        Little and Large
        To address whether these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX>, we first need to look at other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX>, their numbers in different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, and how these systems evolved.
        One thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> do agree on is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> count as different sexes. And
        they also agree that the main difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is gamete size: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> make lots of
        small gametes‚Äîsperm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX> in plants‚Äîand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> produce a few big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. But
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> also think that before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> evolved, sex occurred between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> with equal-sized gametes, a state called isogamy.
        Evolutionarily speaking, an isogamous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> faces <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pressures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> can make
        more smaller gametes, thus increasing their potential number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>, or they can make
        fewer bigger gametes, thus giving their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> a better start in life by providing them
        with more resources. Theoretical analyses suggest that this pressure is particularly great
        if being big carries large benefits, making isogamy unstable. The original identical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gametes</ENAMEX> will evolve towards the opposite ends of the size spectrum.
        In many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, however, one size of gamete still fits all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> that have
        hung on to isogamy are found among the less complex branches of life, such as fungi, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX>,
        and protozoa. This might be because large gametes, yielding well-funded zygotes, are likely
        to be more strongly selected if the resulting offspring needs to grow into a large and
        complex <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>. The benefits of large gametes in simple and unicellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> are not
        so obvious. Some support for this hypothesis comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX> belonging to the group
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvocales</ENAMEX>. The variation in gamete size within each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> matches its degree of
        complexity. For example, the unicellular species 
        Chlamydomonas rheinhardtii is isogamous, while 
        Volvox rouseletti , which lives in balls of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 50,000</NUMEX> cells,
        has large and small gametes (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>).
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Opposite of Sexes</ENAMEX>?
        The question of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX>, and their number, is complex in isogamous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. Such species
        still typically comprise different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for mating purposes. They have genes that allow
        them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with everyone except those belonging to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúmating type‚Äù</ENAMEX> (this is
        presumably to avoid inbreeding and to produce offspring that are genetically diverse to
        cope with environmental change or biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Species</ENAMEX> with mating types, rather
        than males and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, aren't limited to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> interbreeding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>: the ciliate protozoan 
        Tetrahymena thermophila has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushroom</ENAMEX> 
        Schizophyllum commune has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 28,000</NUMEX>, for example. Some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">biologists</ENAMEX> call these mating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types sexes</ENAMEX>; others think that, in the absence of traits other
        than sexual compatibility or the lack thereof, it makes more sense to view species with
        many mating types as having no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX>, rather than lots.
        Yet most isogamous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> mating types. This seems perverse‚Äîit excludes
        half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> as potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> without gaining the benefits of specialization in
        sexual biology. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hamilton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX> came up an explanation for this apparent
        inefficiency.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> mating systems, they proposed, evolved as a way for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in the nucleus to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> in organelles. Cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> with their own genomes, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mitochondria</ENAMEX> and chloroplasts, can divide more rapidly than the cells that house them. If
        the inheritance of organelles was biparental, selfish mutations in their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> could spread
        rapidly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> showed. A nuclear gene that enforces uniparental inheritance of
        organelles, along with a label that allows such cells to recognize each other so that their
        nuclear genes can share the benefits of cytoplasmic policing, should be favored.
        The mating biology of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">isogamous species</ENAMEX> offers considerable support for this idea. The
        aforementioned 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> rheinhardtii , for example, comes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mating types called
        plus and minus. When the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fuse, the plastid of the minus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is detroyed. Most
        isogamous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that fuse cells have a similar mechanism. Male-killer parasites such as 
        Wolbachia , a parasite of arthropods, show the selection
        pressure that intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> can exert (see also the primer by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wernegreen</ENAMEX> in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> ). And <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cellfusion</ENAMEX> experiments hint that biparental
        inheritance of organelles does indeed cause problems, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúHybrids are often
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rubbish</ENAMEX>, but they can be better if a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is administered that inhibits the mitochondria of
        one cell line.‚Äù
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that have lots of mating types, such as ciliate protozoa, exchange nuclear
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, but not cytoplasm, and hence not intracellular organelles. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are freed
        from the need to police their organelles or keep out parasites, selection favors the widest
        assortment of possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>, and thus the evolution of a large number of mating types so
        that one's own type‚Äîwhich one can't mate with‚Äîis a small subset of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. It is
        possible to imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> with cytoplasmic policing likewise having many mating types,
        but such a situation would be much more prone to break down and be invaded by selfish
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> clearly defined types, which is what we usually see in nature.
        Some have argued that cytoplasmic policing might also be a selective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for
        different-sized gametes. Sperm could be small so that they do not import mitochondria into
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>.
        More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> after he devised it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX>'s is still the leading hypothesis
        explaining the number of mating types in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. But experimental evidence remains
        frustratingly elusive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> wouldn't say I was entirely satisfied,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúWe've got
        all these ideas, and they turn out to be quite hard to test‚Äîthere's no simple thing one can
        do on a single species.‚Äù There are species where the uniparental inheritance of organelles
        is not so strictly enforced, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoekstra</ENAMEX>, such as yeasts and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s not easy to
        see if selection [on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organelles</ENAMEX>] is strong enough,‚Äù he says.
      
      
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'s Company</ENAMEX>
        Yet even in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> such as 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. commune</ENAMEX> , with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of mating types, each sexual
        encounter involves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> cells. Nor are we likely to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that defies this
        pattern. The technical difficulties of combining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> sets of genetic information
        into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, and of parceling out that information during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">meiosis</TIMEX>, must be vast,
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Charlesworth</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúWe've reached the point of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        cells fusing, and stuck with that; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cells are probably just as good as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>,‚Äù he
        says.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant colonies</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> suggests have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are a hybrid of the species 
        Pogonomyrmex rugosus and 
        P. barbatus . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX> have not yet been classed as a new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, but they are well established across the southwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and there is
        no evidence of contemporary gene flow between <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parent species</ENAMEX>.
        Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> if it is male, because male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> are produced from unfertilized
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> if it is female. But each sex also comes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> genetic strains. If a queen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> with a male of her own strain, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> will be queens, and if she <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> with a
        male from the other strain, the sperm will give rise to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. So, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> to
        function fully it‚Äîand the queens it produces, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> raise queens‚Äîmust have two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. And if any one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were to disappear, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> as a whole
        would go extinct‚Äîunlike fungal mating types, where it's easy to imagine that the species
        would carry on if a few disappeared. ‚ÄúIf you lose any one, the whole thing collapses,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s really different from any other system.‚Äù
        So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> argues, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pogonomyrmex</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> of each
        strain. The idea is particularly potent if one views a social insect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúsuperorganism</ENAMEX>,‚Äù with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> equivalent to the cells of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. It's as if a female
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> with one male to produce her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>'s somatic cells, and another to produce its
        germ cells. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> form chaotic mating swarms, so most queens have no problem mating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multiply</ENAMEX> and getting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX>, although one would expect that males
        would strongly favor mating with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> of their own strain.
        It's not known how the system originated. Separating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> and reproductive castes
        by genetics‚Äîother social <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> do this by environment, that is, by rearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and
        reproductives differently‚Äîmay allow selection to operate more efficiently on each lineage,
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> may benefit from hybrid vigor: field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> report them as being
        highly aggressive. In an echo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX>'s hypothesis, the system also mixes mitochondrial
        and nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> differently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">queens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
        Some evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlesworth</ENAMEX>, do not consider 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pogonomyrmex</ENAMEX> '
        s mating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types sexes</ENAMEX>, arguing that to define sexes in yet another way
        only confuses the picture further. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äú</ENAMEX>[The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX>] are an interesting system, but I wasn't
        persuaded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX>'s interpretation,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Charlesworth</ENAMEX> says. ‚ÄúI'm not a fan of the idea that
        it's useful to use the word ‚Äòsex‚Äô to describe compatibility between mating types‚Äîit muddies
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù Others</ENAMEX> are more positive towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX>'s interpretation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX> deserves to be
        taken seriously,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E√∂rs Szathm√</ENAMEX>°ry of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Collegium Budapest</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúHe</ENAMEX>'s thrown a stone in the water‚Äînow we need to see what kinds of ripples it
        makes. You can't falsify a definition in the way you can a hypothesis; what determines
        their fate is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find them useful or not.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Species</ENAMEX> in which some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> give up their reproductive opportunities to form part
        of a breeding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">slime molds</ENAMEX>, might have a system similar to that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX> believes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThere</ENAMEX> may be hidden mating incompatibilities,‚Äù he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúNow</ENAMEX> [that]
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know to look, we're going to start seeing more of these systems.‚Äù
      
      
        
      
    
  
