
  
    
      
        
        Imagine this scenario. You're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the world's largest medical
        research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>, and you receive notification from one of your funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX> reporting some exciting progress toward the development of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>.
        The work has just been published, so you log onto the Web to do a quick keyword search, and
        a link to the article is brought up on your screen.
        Then imagine the frustration when you click on the link to read the message, ‚ÄúAccess
        Denied‚Äîaccess to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is restricted to registered institutional and individual
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        And there's the rub: this actually happened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellcome Trust</ENAMEX>. Prior
        to this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that advises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellcome Trust Library</ENAMEX> were already asking whether
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> should adopt a formal position on the continually increasing prices of journal
        subscriptions and the problems this trend was causing research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>.
        These events encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> to investigate the publication of scientific research,
        to see if there was anything research-funding organisations could be doing to stimulate
        change in what appears to be a failing market. As it turns out, there is quite a lot. I now
        believe it is the funders of research‚Äîcharities, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, and other publicly funded
        bodies such as national research agencies‚Äîwho hold the purse strings that can untie
        scientific discoveries from a publishing market that is no longer serving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> as
        well as it could. That is why <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> is a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for enabling free
        access to research literature through support for new publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, such as that of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library of Science</ENAMEX>, and the establishment of publicly accessible repositories,
        working in partnership with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States National Institutes of Health‚</ENAMEX>Äìfunded PubMed
        Central [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>].
        It is worth noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX> in seeking better ways to disseminate
        research findings. The fact that the sequence of the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX> is an openly accessible
        work is due in large measure to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX>'s determination that this information be in the
        public domain and not hidden behind commercial subscriptions. As a consequence of that
        insistence, we believe, these data are a more widely used and valuable resource.
        
          ‚ÄúTrust-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> will have to deposit an electronic version of their
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manuscripts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMC</ENAMEX> to be made available for free via the Internet within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 months</TIMEX> of
          publication.‚Äù
        
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> began its investigation of the scientific publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> by commissioning
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pieces of research: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to inform itself of the economics of the publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>, and
        a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to explore whether there were alternative business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> out there that could
        enable research to have the quality assurance it needs (peer review) whilst being available
        for free, using the Web as the medium of publication.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics of Publishing</ENAMEX>
        The first Trust-commissioned study described how scientific research publishing has
        traditionally worked and why it can be described, in economic terms, as a failing market
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Essentially, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>) are isolated from any of the costs within the system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> give away the
        copyright to their work, for free, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, who organise the peer review and
        copyedit the article. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> then sell it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> at prices that range from
        enough to cover their costs through to some pretty high profits‚Äîsome <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 30%</NUMEX>. These
        profits escape from an otherwise self-contained financial cycle to satisfy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> or
        run learned societies; unlike typical publishing relationships, none are returned directly
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> who wrote the piece) or even to the consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> (the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> who provided the peer review).
        At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> access the material, if they are able to do so,
        through their employing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, either using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> or‚Äîmore typically now‚Äîvia the
        Internet through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>'s subscription. To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> this access appears
        free, effectively creating a market system that has no pressures from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to change. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> consequence of this is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> have been able to increase
        subscription prices well above inflation; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> has seen subscription rates
        rise by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 200%</NUMEX> in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackwell</ENAMEX>'s periodical price indexes; [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]).
        The money used to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> is all public money, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 90%</NUMEX> of the funds paying
        for research in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK university</ENAMEX> system is either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or charitable [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>]‚Äîso in a
        sense the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are paying for the research cannot access its findings without paying
        an additional fee.
        This then begs the question of what alternatives there are to this traditional system,
        now that the Internet has become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>'s tool of choice for searching and
        accessing the literature. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> piece of research commissioned by the Trust looked at
        different business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for research publishing, in order to address this question [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        It compared open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, which often levy a charge to publish but provide the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX> for free, and the majority of the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, which take the research for
        free but charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to read it.
        This study convinced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> that the best way forward to improve access to research
        findings would be through open access to scientific research articles. This essentially
        means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, that the copyright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> must grant to the public a
        free, irrevocable, perpetual license to use, copy, distribute, and make derivative works of
        their research article, in any medium for any purpose (excepting those that constitute
        plagiarism or other dishonest acts, of course); and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, that a digital copy must be
        deposited in an open public archival repository (for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US National Library</ENAMEX> of
        Medicine's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMed Central</ENAMEX>). Whilst a debate continues as to the most appropriate route to
        achieve open access to all research literature, it is important to bear in mind that the
        publication and the archiving of research articles are intrinsically linked. Both aspects
        of open access need to be explored and experimented with, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> is actively
        pursuing solutions for the problems of both.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alternative Business Models</ENAMEX>
        The findings of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> report seem to have caused quite a controversy‚Äîparticularly
        in the suggestion that moving wholesale to an open-access publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> might produce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 30%</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> common misinterpretation of this conclusion is that any such
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> would be due solely to discontinuing the printed versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> that are
        freely available online. This is incorrect. In fact, if savings are to be made in an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">open-access</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, they will largely be found in the variable costs of journal
        production‚Äîsince an open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> will not have to cover the costs of subscription
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, licence negotiations, or sales, and little is required for marketing and
        distribution.
        In a comparison included in the report, an article in a good- to high-quality journal
        produced in the subscription <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is estimated to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">US$2,750</NUMEX>. The equivalent cost under
        an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>-side payment model is estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as US$1,950‚</NUMEX>Äîa comparable saving of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> on the
        costs, and a saving of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> when the variable costs are compared. It must be remembered that
        cost does not equate to price, so to these figures, regardless of the mode of publication,
        must be added overhead expenses and, of course, profit. However, if a truly competitive
        market is created‚Äîwhere payments are directed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> not by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> but by
        those directly involved in the scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, who could easily compare the varying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> processing charges of different open-access publishers‚Äîthen the actual savings
        might well be substantially higher.
        At its essence though, the open-access debate is not about economics, it is about
        access. That is why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> has been in discussion with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US National Library</ENAMEX> of
        Medicine about the possibility of creating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK PubMed Central</ENAMEX> (UKPMC) as a publicly
        accessible repository for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX>-funded research.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK PubMed Central</ENAMEX>
        The proposal is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UKPMC</ENAMEX> will be run as a proper electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>: it will
        collect, collate, and archive whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and be developed to receive single articles as
        well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Submission</ENAMEX> will be as straightforward as attaching a document to an email. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UKPMC</ENAMEX> will
        be able to accept manuscripts in any format, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>, and it will be the
        responsibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UKPMC</ENAMEX> to convert the files it receives into extensible markup language
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XML</ENAMEX>) to enable the appropriate document type definition (DTD) to be assigned. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UKPMC</ENAMEX> will
        also correct the structural, content, and consistency errors that occur when converting
        text for digital preservation, and provide the conversion process to print a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúclear‚Äù PDF</ENAMEX>
        version of included articles to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who download them. This is a process well used
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library of Medicine</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> most suited for the long-term, digital
        preservation of articles.
        And once articles are in a digital format they can be searched and used in different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. For example, genome sequence data, chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compounds</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> structures embedded
        within an article can be searched for in other articles and linked directly to genome or
        structural databases uncovering new genetic markers, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> uses, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> functions. The
        articles themselves become live research material greatly improving the efficacy of the
        research itself.
        For a funder, having all its research in one format, ‚Äúunder <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> roof‚Äù, and searchable
        will improve the efficiency of strategy setting‚Äîfor example, setting funding
        priorities‚Äîassessing the outputs of the funded research, and even gaining an insight into
        the impact of the work. As grants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> becomes more electronic, there can be a direct
        link between original research proposals and the research outputs.
        For a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX>, I believe it is our duty to actively encourage the
        most efficient processes available to maximise the likelihood that the research we fund
        will have the greatest possible health benefit.
        That is why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> will be making it a requirement of its grant conditions that
        Trust-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> deposit an electronic version of their manuscripts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UKPMC</ENAMEX> to be
        made available for free via the Internet within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 months</TIMEX> of publication. The delay means
        that this is not open access in the truest sense. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> considers that the
        development of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMed Central</ENAMEX> portal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> offers the best next step in the
        transition towards a situation where all high-quality peer-reviewed research is available
        for free via the Internet, whilst leaving all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> room for manoeuvre in this
        changing market.
      
    
  
