
  
    
      
        
        Open access is gaining momentum. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> are submitting papers in ever-increasing
        numbers to open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. Several prominent research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>, including the
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNRS</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institut National de la Sant√© et de la Recherche</ENAMEX> (INSERM), have recently
        pronounced that open access is the best way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> they support to publish
        their work. Several established commercial and not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> have announced
        plans to experiment with open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for some or all of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>.
        Delighted and encouraged, we gear up for the launch of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> this autumn‚Äîthe next step in our efforts to bring the
        benefits of open access to the entire scientific and medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. We aim to make 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> a premier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, providing open access to the best
        medical research to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> and other caregivers, and to the public.
        The case for open access to medical research is even stronger than it is for basic
        research in biology. There are more interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>;
        biotechnology and pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that develop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and medical devices; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, and other healthcare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>; and health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> at the national and
        international levels. The goal of the medical research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise is‚</ENAMEX>Äîor should
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">be‚Äîscientifically</ENAMEX>, ethically, and socially responsible medicine, which means research that
        will benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> worldwide.
        The reality looks somewhat different. Large investments into basic research have not yet
        lived up to their full potential to save lives and improve their quality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> do not have ready access to the combined peer-reviewed
        evidence from medical research. The prices for the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> often put them out of reach
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> or poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> without universal healthcare
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. Moreover, research focuses disproportionately on the potentially lucrative
        treatments for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> of wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>, shortchanging the poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> the greatest burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>.
        A medical journal by itself cannot change this reality. But with the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        and practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> around the world who recognize the need and opportunity for
        change, we seek to create a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> that promotes medical research and practice that is
        both scientifically rigorous and compassionate.
        Open access to this literature will strengthen the medical research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> by giving 
        all stakeholders free and immediate access to the latest medical
        research, along with new and more powerful search tools and links between the literature
        and other relevant information.
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> will be an international, modern, general medical journal,
        covering all areas in the medical sciences, from basic studies to large clinical trials and
        cost-effectiveness analyses. We will concentrate on human studies that enhance our
        understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease epidemiology</ENAMEX>, etiology, and physiology; the development of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prognostic</ENAMEX> and diagnostic technologies; and trials that test the efficacy of specific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX> and those that compare different treatments. We will publish original
        research and commentary that promotes translation both of basic research into clinical
        investigation and of clinical evidence into practice.
        A truly broad medical journal is an ambitious project, but we want 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> to promote an integrated understanding of the patient‚Äîto
        make it easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to read outside their specialty area. ‚ÄúDoctors are systems
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biologists</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> put it, and inspiration can often be found in
        unfamiliar territory.
        Articles published in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> will be rigorously peer-reviewed. Academic and professional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> peer-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>, will select those studies that drive research
        forward‚Äîin this case, toward medical applications and benefits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        This issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Äúhuman‚Äù</ENAMEX> studies that met our criteria for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX> and originality, a paper by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Chang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> (found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOI</ENAMEX>:
        10.1371/journal.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pbio.0020007</NUMEX>) on the microarray analysis of tumors and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowland-Jones</ENAMEX> and coworkers (found at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">DOI: 10.1371/journal</TIMEX>.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pbio.0020020</NUMEX>) that examines how
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> exhausts the capacity of the immune system. Similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> submitted in the future will
        be published in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , alongside studies that have more direct implications for
        clinical practice. This issue also contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> articles describing more basic advances
        with medical implications: a study by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry van Dyke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> (found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOI</ENAMEX>:
        10.1371/journal.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pbio.0020022</NUMEX>) describing a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> model for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, a report on a
        novel approach to drug synthesis by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaitan Khosla</ENAMEX> and coworkers (found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOI</ENAMEX>:
        10.1371/journal.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pbio.0020031</NUMEX>), and an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Dowdy et al.</ENAMEX> (found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOI</ENAMEX>:
        10.1371/journal.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pbio.0020036</NUMEX>) on targeted modulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> activity. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> will continue to solicit and publish such articles, but we
        will bring them‚Äîand similar ones published elsewhere‚Äîto the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> .
        Like 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> must be a community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> to achieve its goals. If you
        are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> or an individual anywhere in the world who has a stake in medical research
        and if the goals of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> outlined here resonate with you, please contact us. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> will accept submissions beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2004</TIMEX>, and we are
        looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> who will help to spread the word about open access and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> in the global medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> who
        will submit excellent research, review submitted articles, and contribute editorials and
        commentaries. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> is and will stay a work in progress, and we want to consult
        with as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as possible, both before the launch and as 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> evolves. Sign up to join the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plos</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and help us to
        make the best of medical research and practice accessible to a global <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
