
  
    
      
        
        At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">preschool classroom</ENAMEX> on the other side of the two-way mirror looks
        like any other‚Äîbrightly colored rugs, scattered toys, and tiny chairs. But almost
        immediately an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> notices differences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team Toddle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> here at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>).
        A therapist instructs a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> on his colors, flashing a rapid sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> at
        him. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> starts rocking in his chair and repeatedly touching his forehead, the
        therapist physically restrains his hands, placing them back on the tabletop until he stops
        the repetitive behaviors and focuses once again on her face and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX>. During
        playtime, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> sits by herself in the corner, fixated on some picture cards,
        oblivious to a group of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> playing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">racetrack</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapist</ENAMEX> who
        tries to draw her out to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> lack some of the key social skills that normal toddlers pick up
        naturally‚Äîlooking to others for reassurance or cues, focusing on faces, and playing
        together. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> and communication impairment is a hallmark of autism and can show up as
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as 12‚Äì18 months of age</TIMEX>. But with an unknown cause, and genetic linkages still hazy,
        there is little consensus among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> on how the disorder develops in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
        how it causes a broad spectrum of social, language, and behavioral deficits.
        Following one line of research, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Amaral</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.I.N.D. Institute</ENAMEX> at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at Davis Medical Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>) has recorded, in autistic brains, a brain volume increase in a specific structure,
        the amygdala, which is thought to be important for social behavior. A similar study at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> (UW) (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) has reached
        the same conclusion. ‚ÄúThere are so few facts about autism, to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> come up with
        the same data is phenomenal,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amaral</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúWe feel confident this is a real finding, but
        what does it mean to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>?‚Äù
        On another research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>, using functional imaging, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph-Axel M√ºller</ENAMEX>, a cognitive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuroscientist at San Diego State University</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) sees a
        scattering of brain activation in autistic brains that he views as an indication of a more
        general brain development problem underlying the disorder (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). He has hypothesized
        that the early-developing basic functions may require more brain area in autism, pushing
        out and disturbing the later specialization for more complex functions. ‚ÄúI'm sure this is
        wrong,‚Äù he says, ‚Äúbut it will allow us to look in a more hypothesis-driven way at animal
        studies of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cerebral cortex</ENAMEX> develops specialization.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù Animal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> may, in turn,
        yield clues about normal and abnormal brain development in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄúSince there is no major hypothesis as to cause [of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">autism</ENAMEX>], there are many plausible
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideas,‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amaral</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúIf we go after all of them, we will waste all of our resources. [We
        have to] come to some consensus about which are most plausible.‚Äù <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least two</NUMEX> levels of
        pursuit exist for tracing brain problems associated with autism‚Äîthe exploration of the
        general developmental disruptions that result in an autistic brain, and the examination of
        more specific problems in particular brain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> that produce symptoms. Although
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> still debate how autism evolves in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, the field has begun in the last
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> to replicate findings and make science-based arguments for interventions. Progress
        has come in small steps, with advances in neuroimaging and more rigorous experimental
        designs.
        Research focuses have shifted from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúcuring‚Äù autism</ENAMEX> to finding better diagnostics for
        early intervention, improving behavioral therapies, and gaining insight into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and function of the autistic brain. Both advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and government
        programs have started to bring together neuroscience and genetics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, clinicians, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to sharpen the focus of studies and ensure progress in what has often been a messy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Apart</ENAMEX>
        Autism spectrum disorder strikes between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and six</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around
        the world, but diagnosis and treatment are currently limited to developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Autism
        is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times more prevalent in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, but makes no racial, ethnic, or
        socioeconomic distinctions. It is characterized by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main symptoms: impaired language,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> and communicative deficits, and repetitive and stereotyped behaviors, such as hand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flapping</ENAMEX>, rocking, and unusual responses to sensory stimuli. Autism spectrum disorders can
        be broken down into other categories, such as low-functioning autism (IQ below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>),
        high-functioning autism (IQ above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Asperger syndrome</ENAMEX> (similar to high-functioning
        autism but with no language deficit).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> suspect that there are even more distinct subsets of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">autism</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. For
        example, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> also have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">epilepsy</ENAMEX>, and it has been suggested that there is a
        regressive form of autism‚Äîchildren who, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years of age</TIMEX>, appear to regress and
        lose developmental milestones they had already achieved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> say that sorting out
        these different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">profiles‚Äîor phenotypes‚Äîof autism</ENAMEX> will be especially important in sorting
        out which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> or which brain abnormalities are implicated for particular deficits. This
        sorting should also help clarify the mounds of contradictory data that have dogged the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>, by tamping down the experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúnoise‚Äù</ENAMEX> in studies. Boosting the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        studied and following them from early infancy through adolescence and beyond will also be
        key components of future studies.
        ‚ÄúThere is not going to be rapid progress in autism research unless we subtype,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Amaral</ENAMEX>
        says. He predicts that ‚Äúbrain differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with a regressive form of autism will be
        different than those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with the more congenital type of autism.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù He</ENAMEX> and others are
        teaming up in an autism phenotyping project that will characterize <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> into
        categories of autism (comparing them to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controls</ENAMEX>). Splitting autism into subtypes will boost both neurobiology and genetics studies
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>) to find real effects related to specific traits.
      
      
        Facing Up to Autism
        A key area of research explores the brain's response to human faces at a young age.
        Studies at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">UW Autism Center</ENAMEX> have shown that unlike typically developing
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year-olds</TIMEX>, autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do not show a differential brain response to their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>'s face compared to that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dysfunctional</ENAMEX> face recognition may be
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the more devastating symptoms for caregivers, it is also one of the most promising
        avenues for research to determine how autistic brains process their world differently.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Webb</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child psychologist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UW</ENAMEX>, has followed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 70</NUMEX> autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> since the
        age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> for a longitudinal study that will test many parameters until they reach age
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>. Her work has already shown that autistic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year-olds</TIMEX> process seeing a strange toy
        differently from seeing a favorite toy, in the same way a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> does. But activity
        in their brains‚Äîmeasured through a network of electrodes placed on the scalp‚Äîis similar
        whether the face is familiar (for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>) or strange. This, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webb</ENAMEX> says, led to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        hypotheses: either the brain area for face processing is not set up correctly in autistic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, or the way these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> incorporate experiences from their environment is so
        different that the brain area develops improperly.
        ‚ÄúWe think the latter is a more likely explanation at this point,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webb</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúBy the
        time they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, they are showing the [proper] response for familiar
        faces.‚Äù Indeed, a functional MRI (fMRI) study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UW</ENAMEX> neuroimaging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
        Aylward showed that the brains of high-functioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> did activate the
        face-recognition <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, the fusiform gyrus, when shown a very familiar face. However, the
        same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> did not activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> when viewing strange faces. This points to the
        possibility that greater experience seeing the familiar face (i.e., on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis for
        many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) can eventually influence the appropriate brain areas.
        ‚ÄúYou need the biological wiring set up properly, but you also need experience for it to
        function normally,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aylward</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúWe're guessing what is missing is the experience.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù To</ENAMEX>
        test that idea, one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate students</ENAMEX> will ‚Äútrain‚Äù <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in
        face recognition‚Äîsomething most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> pick up on their own‚Äîby having them study,
        manipulate, and match faces using computer games. Then fMRI scans will be done again to see
        if the fusiform gyrus might now be activated when viewing strange faces, as it is in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Intense training of a similar type for reading has already been shown to
        effect change in brain activation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as little as three weeks</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dyslexia</ENAMEX>.
        In their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, it is as if ‚Äúall the parts are there, ready to go, but somehow they
        haven't gotten the ignition turned on,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aylward</ENAMEX>. At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> annual meeting of the
        center <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Dawson</ENAMEX> explained that this tackling of specific deficits will
        help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> attach them to particular ‚Äúmind modules‚Äù in the brain and will ultimately
        lead to the genes that control the development or function of those modules. That modular
        view, however, is not shared by many of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> elsewhere, who argue that autistic
        behaviors are the result of a system-wide perturbation of early brain development and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">connectivity</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Structural Support
        For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M√</ENAMEX>ºller points to structural studies that seem to uphold his theory of
        overall disorganization of the brain's cortex. Work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel Casanova</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúminicolumns‚Äù</ENAMEX> of neurons that make up the cortex are narrower and more numerous in autistic
        brains. Normally, these organized bundles appear very early in the developing fetal brain.
        In postmortem studies of autistic brains, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casanova</ENAMEX> found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">minicolumns</ENAMEX> had the same
        number of neurons, but smaller margins between the bundles. The margins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casanova</ENAMEX> says, may
        act like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúa shower curtain</ENAMEX> of inhibition that prevents information from flooding adjacent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">minicolumns</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        Reducing those margins, he hypothesizes, could mean that an autistic brain has too much
        positive feedback, acting like a noisy amplifier. ‚ÄúFor an autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who is trying
        to piece together too much information from a face, maybe it's like looking at the sun,‚Äù he
        says.
        More general studies of adult autistic neuroanatomy have given conflicting results‚Äîmost
        likely from diversity in the study populations‚Äîthat make functional inferences difficult,
        if not impossible. But recent studies that focus on developing autistic brains earlier in
        life have revealed intriguing differences from normally developing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
        Several studies have shown that from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages two to four</TIMEX>, autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have larger
        overall brain volumes (and correspondingly larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> circumferences) than normal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but that the difference had disappeared by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about age six or seven</TIMEX>. Since autism
        is usually diagnosed around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age two or three</TIMEX>, when the brain is already abnormally large,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) hypothesized that brain overgrowth must occur <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, before
        signs of autism appear.
        In an elegant retrospective study, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> analyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> circumference and brain volume
        measurements of autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that started at birth and continued until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 months</TIMEX> of
        age. The study revealed that at birth, autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> size is much smaller than
        healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 25th</TIMEX> percentile, but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6‚Äì14 months</TIMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> size had increased
        to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">84th</NUMEX> percentile, an excessive growth rate. The increase correlated with increased
        brain volumes of both gray and white matter regions measured by structural imaging between
        ages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to five</NUMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courchesne</ENAMEX> study strongly suggests that with autism, significant unregulated brain
        growth occurs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> of life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> also found an association between greater
        increases in brain size in infancy and a later age for first word, worse repetitive
        behavior, and a trend toward more severe autistic symptoms later, at diagnosis. The rapid
        growth of autistic brains may produce too many connections too quickly, without the
        opportunity to be shaped by the experience and input that a typically developing child
        accumulates over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age six or later</TIMEX>, when the growth slows, the already
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">derailed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> may no longer be able to incorporate experiences. ‚ÄúBy that time,‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">write Courchesne et al.</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúthe period of plasticity that allows the exquisite and graceful
        complexity of the human brain to emerge will have passed.‚Äù
      
      
        Playing Well with Others
        This idea that autistic brains are developing at warp speed, to their detriment, fits
        intriguingly well with what is known about treatment of autism‚Äîthe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and more intense
        behavioral therapy an autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> receives, the better the outcome will be. That's why
        the toddlers at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> training by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX>, who fire rapid questions and
        physically repeat tasks until they sink in.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanny Freeman</ENAMEX>, co-director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Early Childhood Partial Hospitalization</ENAMEX> program at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), says these methods would be alien to, and
        lost on, typically developing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year-olds</TIMEX>, who would be bewildered by such a highly
        structured environment. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> and co-director, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanya Paparella</ENAMEX>, chimes in, ‚ÄúIt as
        if we are opening a window or door to the autistic brain.‚Äù Keeping that door open as long
        as possible in very young <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">autistic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> seems to give them a better prognosis than
        older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, who are more difficult to treat.
        But while most agree that early and intense therapy is good for autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, until
        recently, little research on intervention methods existed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie Kasari</ENAMEX>, an educational
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paparella</ENAMEX>, has run one of the first
        randomized, controlled trials on therapies designed to teach autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> social skills.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> tested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> skills in particular‚Äîsharing attention with others and pretend playing
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> hypothesizes that these skills, which normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> pick up easily
        and early, lay important groundwork for language development.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s results show that autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can learn these skills from intense
        training. At least anecdotally, some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have gone on to function in normal
        school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>, even making a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, although they are still a bit socially
        awkward. Whether or not improvements in those skills will correlate with language
        improvements will require further testing. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasari</ENAMEX> notes that this work is not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universally</ENAMEX> accepted in the autism therapy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and that many more controlled studies
        will have to be published before a system-wide change in autism preschool education can
        occur.
      
      
        Funding the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> funding for autism research has
        increased from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million to $80 million</NUMEX>, and much of that has been funneled into large,
        multidisciplinary research projects. Advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cure Autism Now</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Alliance</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autism Research</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) greatly influence which autism research projects get funded, both
        through their own grant programs and also by lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for increased federal
        grants. Some question whether it is wise to let emotions and the desire to find a cure
        drive research agendas. In the past, tensions between government programs and advocacy
        programs have run high.
        Casanova, for one, criticizes the disproportionate flow of money to what he calls
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imaging</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">genetic ‚Äúfishing expeditions‚Äù</ENAMEX> and says more should go to neuropathology
        studies. He points out that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 40</NUMEX> postmortem, mostly adult, autistic brains have
        been studied so far, a tiny fraction compared to those studied in other neuropathological
        disorders like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>.
        But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Geschwind</ENAMEX>, a neurogeneticist at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>, defends this approach, saying that a
        well-planned fishing expedition that uses the right technology and looks in the appropriate
        places can result in a ‚Äúfreezer full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù He</ENAMEX> also says that parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> keep
        the field honest by ‚Äúconstantly reminding us to keep an eye on the ball and don't get
        distracted.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Geschwind</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amaral</ENAMEX>, and other top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have recently been recruited by
        advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to shift some of their research
        questions to examining autism.
        As more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in genetics and neuroscience have become involved, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amaral</ENAMEX> says, the
        tensions between the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> have eased. ‚ÄúThe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> communicated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> the tremendous need for research and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
        convey back to them which [research projects] make sense to fund,‚Äù he says. He adds that
        advocacy groups have been indispensable to research, setting up large genetic and brain
        tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and enlisting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to participate in those efforts.
        So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> say, the goals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> programs and the
        advocacy programs have started to come together to focus on well-executed studies that
        might lead to better diagnostics and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, proven interventions. The work of Courchesne
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">et al.</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at risk for autism might easily be diagnosed by head
        circumference measurements as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as the first few months</TIMEX> of life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imaging</ENAMEX> studies
        combined with training programs, such as the work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UW</ENAMEX> on face recognition, may one day be
        able to verify that behavioral interventions are effective at activating target brain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> work to untangle the causes and effects of brain dysfunctions in
        autism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aylward</ENAMEX> notes, there is good reason to be hopeful: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúAlthough this is a genetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disorder</ENAMEX>, we know there is plasticity in the young brain.‚Äù
      
    
  
