
  
    
      
        
        I need a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äútricorder‚Äù‚Äîthe</ENAMEX> convenient, hand-held device featured on 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Trek</ENAMEX> that can detect life forms even from orbit. Unfortunately, we
        don't have a clue how a tricorder might work, since life forms don't seem to have any
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">observable</ENAMEX> property that distinguishes them from inanimate matter. Furthermore, we lack a
        definition of life that can guide a search for life outside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. How can we find what we
        can't define? An answer may lie in the observation that life uses a small, discrete set of
        organic molecules as basic building blocks. On the surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX> and in the subsurface
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>, we can search for alien but analogous patterns in the organics.
      
      
        Life As We Know It
        The obvious diversity of life on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> overlies a fundamental biochemical and genetic
        similarity. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polymers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biology‚Äîthe nucleic acids</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">polysaccarides‚Äîare</ENAMEX> built from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> nucleotide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>, and a few sugars,
        respectively. Together with lipids and fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, these are the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> of
        biomass: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware</ENAMEX> of life (Lehninger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, p <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> software of life is
        also common, indicating shared descent (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woese 1987).</ENAMEX> But with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> example of life‚Äîlife
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth‚</ENAMEX>Äîit is not all that surprising that we do not have a fundamental understanding of
        what life is. We don't know which features of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> life are essential and which are just
        accidents of history.
        Our lack of data is reflected in our attempts to define life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koshland</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>) lists
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> features of life: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) program (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) improvisation (response to environment), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
        compartmentalization, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) energy, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) regeneration, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) adaptability, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) seclusion
        (chemical control and selectivity). A simpler definition is that life is a material system
        that undergoes reproduction, mutation, and natural selection (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay 1991</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleland</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chyba</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>) have suggested that life might be like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, hard to define
        phenomenologically, but easy to define at the fundamental level. But life is like fire, not
        water‚Äîit is a process, not a pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. Such definitions are grist for philosophical
        discussion, but they neither inform biological research nor provide a basis for the search
        for life on other worlds.
        The simplest, but not the only, proof of life is to find something that is alive. There
        are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> properties that can determine if an object is alive: metabolism and motion.
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolism</ENAMEX> is used here to include an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>'s life functions, biomass increase, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reproduction</ENAMEX>.) All living things require some level of metabolism to remain viable against
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entropy</ENAMEX>. Movement (either microscopic or macroscopic) in response to stimuli or in the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> can be a convincing indicator of a living thing. But both metabolism
        (fire) and motion (wind) occur in nature in the absence of biology.
        The practical approach to the search for life is to determine what life needs. The
        simplest list is probably: energy, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX>, liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and a few other elements such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nitrogen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphorus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay 1991</ENAMEX>). Life requires energy to maintain itself
        against entropy, as does any self-organizing open system. In the memorable words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erwin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schr√∂dinger</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>), ‚ÄúIt feeds on negative entropy.‚Äù On <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, the vast majority of life
        forms ultimately derive their energy from sunlight. The only other source of primary
        productivity known is chemical energy, and there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ecosystems</ENAMEX> known, both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">methanogen</ENAMEX>-based (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">McKinley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chapelle et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), that rely exclusively
        on chemical energy (that is, they do not use sunlight or its product, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>).
        Photosynthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> can use sunlight at levels below the level of sunlight at the
        orbit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pluto</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravens et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>); therefore, energy is not the limitation for life.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Carbon</ENAMEX>, nitrogen, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphorus</ENAMEX> are the elements of life, and they are abundant in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Solar System</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> and the outer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Solar System</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10,000</NUMEX> times
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX> content of the bulk of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay 1991</ENAMEX>). When we scan the other worlds of our
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solar System</ENAMEX>, the missing ecological <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredient</ENAMEX> for life is liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. It makes sense,
        then, that the search for liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is currently the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in the search for life
        on other worlds. The presence of liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is a powerful indication that the ecological
        prerequisites for life are satisfied.
        Orbital images, such as the canyon in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, show clear evidence of the stable and
        repeated, if not persistent, flow of a low-viscosity fluid on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> at certain times in its
        past history. The fluid was probably <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, but the images could also suggest wind, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>,
        lava, even <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX>. Recently, results from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Exploration</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rover</ENAMEX> missions have shown that this liquid carried salts and precipitated hematite in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concretions</ENAMEX>. The case for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, we could say, is tight.
        On <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>'s moon <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX>, the cracks and icebergs on the surface of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> indicate
        water beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>, but not necessarily at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the present time</TIMEX>. Present <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX> is
        indicated by the magnetic disturbance <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX> makes as it moves through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>'s magnetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>, not unlike the way coins in the pocket of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> will set off an airport metal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detector</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europa</ENAMEX> has a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX>, and this is most likely a global, salty layer of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Viking on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars: Been There, Tried That</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viking</ENAMEX> missions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> (and as yet, the only)
        search for life outside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viking</ENAMEX> conducted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">incubation</ENAMEX> experiments to detect
        the presence of metabolism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martian</ENAMEX> soil. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lander</ENAMEX> also carried a sophisticated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gas</ENAMEX> Chromatograph <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass Spectrometer</ENAMEX> for characterizing organic molecules. The results were
        unexpected (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978, 1999</TIMEX>). There was a detectable reaction in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the incubation
        experiments. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúGas Exchange‚</ENAMEX>Äù experiment, a burst of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> was released when the soil
        was exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúLabeled Release‚</ENAMEX>Äù experiment showed that organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> was
        consumed, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> was released concomitantly. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Labeled Release</ENAMEX>
        experiment, this reaction ceased if the soil was first heated to sterilizing temperatures,
        but the reaction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gas Exchange Experiment</ENAMEX> persisted.
        If considered alone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Labeled Release</ENAMEX> results would be a plausible indication for
        life on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gas Chromatograph Mass Spectrometer</ENAMEX> did not detect the presence
        of any organic molecules in the soil at level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biemann 1979).</ENAMEX> It is
        difficult to imagine life without associated organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>, and this is the main
        argument against a biological interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> results (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; but cf.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straat 1981).</ENAMEX> It is also unlikely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> release in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gas Exchange</ENAMEX>
        experiment had a biological explanation, because the reaction was so rapid and persisted
        after heating. It is generally thought that the reactivity observed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> biology
        experiments was caused by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more inorganic oxidants present in the soil, and was
        ultimately produced by ultraviolet light in the atmosphere. Consistent with the apparently
        negative results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> biology experiments, the surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> also appears to be
        too dry for life. Indeed, conditions are such that liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is rare and transient, if
        it occurs at all (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hecht 2002).</ENAMEX>
      
      
        It's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life, Jim</ENAMEX>, but Not As We Know It
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> shows a categorization of life as we have observed it. Using this diagram, we
        can speculate about how life might be different on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX>. At the bottom of the
        table, life is composed of matter‚Äîa reasonable assumption for now. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Carbon</ENAMEX> and liquid water
        are the next level; this makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX> likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, because they have carbon
        and have, or have had, liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Other worlds may have a different chemical baseline
        for life. The usual speculation in this area is that the presence of ammonia and silicon,
        rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and carbon, might be preconditions for life on other planets. Such
        speculation has yet to lead to any specific suggestions for experiments, or to new ways to
        search for such life, but this may just reflect a failure of human imagination rather than
        a fundamental limitation on the nature of life.
        Life on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> is also likely to be the same at the top of the table: at the ecological
        level. Primary production in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX> ecosystem is likely to be phototrophic, using carbon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dioxide</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Heterotrophs are likely to be present to consume the phototrophs and in
        turn to be consumed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX>. Darwinian evolution would result in many of the same
        patterns we see in ecosystems on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. While it may be similar at the top (ecological) and
        bottom (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX>) levels, life on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> could be quite alien in the middle, in the realm of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biochemistry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pace</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>) has argued that alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biochemistry</ENAMEX> will turn out to be the same
        as biochemistry on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, because there is one best way to do things and that natural
        selection will ensure that life everywhere discovers that way. Only observation will tell
        if there is one possible biochemistry, or many.
        Future missions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> might find microfossils in sedimentary rocks such as those at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meridiani Planum</ENAMEX>. Microbes don't readily form convincing fossils; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception may be
        the strings of magnetite formed by magnetotactic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friedmann et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). As
        interesting as fossils might be, we could not be sure that a fossil found on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> was not
        merely another example of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> life. We know that rocks have come to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>, and
        it is possible that such rocks could have carried life between the planets (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mileikowsky et</ENAMEX>
        al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weiss et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>). Finding fossil evidence for life on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> does not demonstrate
        a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> genesis in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Solar System</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Way to Search for Alien Life</ENAMEX>
        If we were to find organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> in the subsurface of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> or on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ice of Europa</ENAMEX>,
        how could we determine whether it was the product of a system of biology or merely abiotic,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">organic</ENAMEX> material from meteorites or photochemistry? If this life were in fact related to
        Earth life, this should be easy to determine. We now have very sensitive methods, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> and fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody markers</ENAMEX>, for detecting life like us. This case would be the
        simplest to determine, but it would also be the least interesting. If the life turned out
        to be truly alien, then the probes specific to our biology would be unlikely to work. What,
        then, could we do to determine a biological origin?
        The question is open and possibly urgent. On space <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> already being planned, we
        may have the opportunity to analyze the remains of alien organics on the surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europa</ENAMEX>
        or frozen below ground on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>. The instruments that will make this analysis must be
        designed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of years</TIMEX>.
        One approach appears promising. I call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúLego Principle</ENAMEX>.‚Äù It is based on the
        patterns of the molecules of life. Biological processes, in contrast to abiotic mechanisms,
        do not make use of the range of possible organic molecules. Instead, biology is built from
        a selected set. Thus, organic molecules that are chemically very similar to each other may
        have widely different concentrations in a sample of biological organics. An example of this
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> used in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and the use of the left-handed version of
        these amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>. The selectivity of biological processes is shown schematically in Figure
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> by the distribution of spikes in contrast to a smooth, nonbiological distribution.
        General arguments of thermodynamic efficiency and specificity of enzymatic reactions
        suggest that this selectivity is required for biological function and is a general result
        of natural selection. Different life forms are likely to have different patterns, and at
        the very least we might find the mirror symmetry of life on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, with 
        d - instead of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">l</ENAMEX> -amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>.
        This approach has immediate practical benefit in the search for biochemistry in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solar System</ENAMEX>. Samples of organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> collected from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX> can be easily
        tested for the prevalence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chirality of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> over the other. More generally, a
        complete analysis of the relative concentration of different types of organic molecules
        might reveal a pattern that is biological even if that pattern does not involve any of the
        familiar biomolecules. Interestingly, if a sample of organics from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX> shows a
        preponderance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, this would be evidence of life, and at the same time would
        show that this life was distinct from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> life. This same conclusion would apply to any
        clearly biological pattern that was distinct from that of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> life.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Organic</ENAMEX> material of biological origin will eventually lose its distinctive pattern when
        exposed to heat and other types of radiation, (examples of this include the thermal
        racemization of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>), but at the low temperatures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX> permafrost,
        calculations suggest that there has been no thermal alteration (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanavarioti</ENAMEX> and Mancinelli
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>). An interesting question, as yet unanswered, is how long organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> frozen into
        the surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX> would retain a biological signature in the strong radiation
        environment.
        On <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX>, the organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> for our tests might be collected right from the dark
        regions on the surface. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>, there is ice-rich ground in the cratered southern polar
        regions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feldmann et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), which presumably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overlies</ENAMEX> deeper, older <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. The surprise
        discovery of strong magnetic fields in the southern hemisphere of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acu√±a et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Connerney et al. 1999</ENAMEX>) indicates that the area may be the oldest undisturbed permafrost on
        that planet. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mammoths</ENAMEX> extracted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX>, any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX> microbes
        found in this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> would be dead, but their biochemistry would be preserved. From these
        biological remains, it would then be possible to determine the biochemical composition of,
        and the phylogenetic relationship between, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> life and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Martian</ENAMEX> life. We may then have,
        for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, a second example of life.
      
    
  
