
  
    
      
        
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mule deer</ENAMEX> in a research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort Collins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> apparently began to react badly to their captivity. At least, that was the guess of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> working on the natural history and nutrition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>, which became listless
        and showed signs of depressed mood, hanging their heads and lowering their ears. They lost
        appetite and weight. Then they died‚Äîof emaciation, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX>, and other complications‚Äîor
        were euthanized. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> dubbed it chronic wasting <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> (CWD), and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they
        thought it might be caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, nutritional deficiencies, or poisoning. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade</TIMEX>
        later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> was identified as one of the neurodegenerative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> called spongiform
        encephalopathies, the most notorious example of which is bovine spongiform encephalopathy
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>), more commonly known as mad cow disease. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> is epidemic in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Although no proof has yet emerged that it's transmissible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, scientific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> haven't ruled out the possibility of a public health threat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have
        concentrated on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have responded with escalated funding over
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX> for fundamental research into the many questions surrounding this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mysterious disease</ENAMEX>.
        Quite apart from how little is yet known about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX>, media interest is reason enough to
        step up investigation of it, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo Salman</ENAMEX>, a veterinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epidemiologist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado State</ENAMEX>
        University in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Collins</ENAMEX>. He's been scientifically involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, since it was first
        discovered among <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. He recalls predicting that lay
        interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> would wane after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. Instead, the disease was found in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1990s</TIMEX> to be capable of killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> who ate tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> was wrong, and it really
        changed my way of thinking, to differentiate between scientific evidence and the public
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perception,‚Äù Salman</ENAMEX> admits. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúBecause CWD</ENAMEX> is similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, the public perception is that
        we need to address this disease, to see if it has any link to human health.‚Äù
        
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> is the only spongiform encephalopathy known to naturally infect both
            free-ranging and captive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, a situation that greatly complicates efforts to
            monitor, control, or eradicate it.
          
        
      
      
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>) declared an emergency after
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> was first diagnosed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi River</ENAMEX>, indicating a potential
        nationwide problem. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> is developing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX> certification program to help
        prevent the movement of infected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in the game farming industry. This will bolster
        monitoring already underway in virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">postmortem</NUMEX> examinations of
        game killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> and by sharpshooters in mass culling operations.
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2003</TIMEX>, brain tissue from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 111,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> had been sampled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">629</NUMEX> were found to have tested positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX>. That's a small epidemic
        compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> cases detected in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> is
        thought to be slow-spreading and perhaps lurking undiscovered elsewhere. So far, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> are the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in which it has been identified, apart from a few
        imported cases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Korea</ENAMEX>, but surveillance has not been thorough in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and is virtually nonexistent in the rest of the world.
        Considered <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> fatal once clinical signs develop, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> has struck <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> species of the
        cervid <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">family‚Äîmule deer</ENAMEX>, white-tailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rocky Mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elk‚Äîwhich</ENAMEX> roam wild and are
        raised on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and hunting. It's the only spongiform encephalopathy known to
        naturally infect both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-ranging</ENAMEX> and captive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, a situation that greatly
        complicates efforts to monitor, control, or eradicate it.
        The economic costs are hard to quantify, but a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> survey by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Census</ENAMEX> shows that big-game <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> nationwide spend more
        than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">US$10 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> for trips and equipment. By far, their main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> is deer.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wildlife</ENAMEX> watching of large land mammals, principally <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>, drew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Deer Farmers Association</ENAMEX> represents <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75,000</NUMEX> cervid
        livestock raised for their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and for velvet antler, a health-food supplement made from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antlers</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than US$111 million</NUMEX>.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s emphasis on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> has been ‚Äúquite high‚Äù
        compared to other wildlife diseases, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterinarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Goeldner</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúIn no
        small part, that's because the disease has cropped up in new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX>, and those are states
        that have political clout.‚Äù It has now been found in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> beyond what became
        known as the endemic region of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">US$14.8 million</NUMEX> to monitor and manage the disease, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goeldner</ENAMEX> says the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> expects to get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about US$16 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prion Diseases</ENAMEX>
        Those figures don't include scientific research funded by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, such as
        the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">US$42.5 million</NUMEX> received by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> to start
        up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Prion Research Program</ENAMEX>. The prion is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> that causes
        transmissible spongiform encephalopathies (TSEs). Its normal function is uncertain, but
        when it misfolds into an abnormal or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúinfectious‚Äù form</ENAMEX>, it causes the microscopic holes and
        globs of toxic, misshapen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> found in the brains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. Unlike viruses,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prions</ENAMEX> don't contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acids‚Äîonly protein</ENAMEX>. Without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> to issue biochemical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commands</ENAMEX>, abnormal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prions</ENAMEX> shouldn't be able to convert normal prions to the infectious
        state, but that's exactly what they do (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>).
        Prion diseases occur in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. In domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX>, prion diseases occur
        as scrapie, which has a virtually worldwide distribution. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> have
        also reported rare cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX> in ranched mink. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Humans</ENAMEX> get kuru, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creutzfeldt-Jacob</ENAMEX> disease
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJD</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gerstmann-Str√§ussler-Scheinker</ENAMEX> syndrome‚Äîall rare‚Äîand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> itself manifests in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a variant form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJD</ENAMEX>. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> outbreak, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> has been discovered
        in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, most recently in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> fear rose of possible
        CWD transmission to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> who eat infected venison, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control and Prevention</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>) released a report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> of its investigation into several
        deaths among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">venison eaters</ENAMEX> who might have had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX>. The report concluded that none of the
        deaths could be attributed to venison, but it nevertheless cautioned that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> showing
        evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> should be excluded from the human and animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 2</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> is the least understood of all the prion <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. Its origins are unknown and may
        well never be discovered. The question is largely academic, unless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hypothesis is proven
        true, that it derives from scrapie. In that case, the knowledge might help in efforts to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> diseases through <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX> and flock management.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> are working to determine the minimum incubation time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> before clinical
        signs appear, now roughly estimated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 months</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12‚Äî34 months</TIMEX> in elk. They're
        trying to discover whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> strains exist that can affect the length of the disease
        process and different regions of the brain or that can infect different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. They are also investigating the period during which the prion is passed on, as well
        as its modes of transmission. They want to know whether disease <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX> exist in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bodily fluids</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, in the environment, or both. They're racing to develop a diagnostic
        test that can be performed on live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, enabling identification of the disease before
        clinical signs appear, which would eliminate the need to kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of apparently
        healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in areas where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> is detected. But among the first things they need to
        clarify are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX>'s distribution across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> and its prevalence.
        
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äú‚Ä¶the disease</ENAMEX> has cropped up in new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX>, and those are states that
            have political clout.‚Äù
          
        
      
      
        An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Initial Step: Improved Surveillance</ENAMEX>
        ‚ÄúBefore you can start to control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX>, you need to understand where it is and how much of
        it you have,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says veterinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Williams</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wyoming</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laramie</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúSo I think you really need surveillance.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Research</ENAMEX> on its pathogenesis and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transmission</ENAMEX> will help to develop better diagnostic tools, which will improve surveillance,
        adds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, who first identified the disease as a TSE more than a quarter-century
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado State</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salman</ENAMEX> argues that current surveillance is primarily a series of
        reactions to reported cases, rather than a systematic strategy designed to determine where
        and at what prevalence the disease exists and where it's absent. The estimated prevalence
        is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1%</NUMEX> in elk and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salman</ENAMEX> says, ‚ÄúWe don't have a good idea of areas
        in which we are saying we haven't found the disease because these areas are not yet, in my
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">estimation</ENAMEX>, negative for the disease. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scrapie</ENAMEX> is a wonderful example of systematic
        surveillance but, to be fair to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decision-makers</ENAMEX> and technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX>,
        surveillance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife species</ENAMEX> is very difficult.‚Äù
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goeldner</ENAMEX> declares, ‚ÄúWe have the goal and the hope to eradicate the disease
        from the farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.‚Äù But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Department of Wildlife</ENAMEX> veterinarian and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> expert
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Miller</ENAMEX> warns, ‚ÄúGiven existing tools, it seems unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> can be eradicated from
        free-ranging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> once established.‚Äù
        The gold standard of diagnosis is based on examination of the brain for spongiform
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> and abnormal prion aggregation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Suspect animals</ENAMEX> are decapitated and their bodies
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incinerated</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúThis is an approach that nobody wants, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implement it,‚Äù</ENAMEX> says wildlife <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ecologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Samuel</ENAMEX>, principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States Geological Survey‚ÄìWisconsin Cooperative Wildlife Research Unit</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>.
        Nevertheless, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> white-tailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> shot by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> in the south-central part of
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 2001</TIMEX> were diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX>, the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> took swift
        action. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 2003</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> had been sacrificed and sampled for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, both within and without a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">411 square-mile</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1065 square-kilometer</NUMEX>) region dubbed
        the eradication zone. There the goal was to remove as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> as possible, whereas the
        plan in contiguous outlying areas was to reduce density to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about ten deer per square mile</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> is thought to spread more efficiently in high-density <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, and normal densities
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50‚Äì100 deer per square mile</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> times that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. The main objectives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> culling were to discover where the disease
        existed and its prevalence in affected areas. In the eradication zone, it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì7%</NUMEX>,
        although in the outlying region it was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1%‚Äì2%</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Samples</ENAMEX> elsewhere in the state tested
        negative.
      
      
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search of a Live</ENAMEX> Assay
        A key to combating the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> is to put into widespread use a preclinical
        diagnostic test on live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> recently developed and validated the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such assay, based on a biopsy of lymphoid tissue, where the infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is known
        to incubate. They showed that tonsillar biopsies taken from live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> can confirm
        disease <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 20 months</TIMEX> prior to death and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 14 months</TIMEX> before the onset of clinical
        signs. Although the method is a useful screening tool, it requires much time and training.
        Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> must be anaesthetized and blindfolded, placed in a restraint, its mouth held open
        with a gag, the tonsil visualized with a laryngoscope, and the biopsy taken with endoscopic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forceps</ENAMEX>. Lymphoid tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX> was first used as a preclinical test in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep scrapie</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄúMany attempts have been made to develop and evaluate tests for live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, but it is
        fraught with difficulties,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> declares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Matthews</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government's Veterinary Laboratories Agency</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weybridge</ENAMEX>. He says that a live test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> is likely to be evaluated shortly by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Food Safety Authority</ENAMEX>, but
        warns of a major problem: test samples are collected early in the incubation, whereas brain
        pathology only arises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three years later</TIMEX>. This creates long delays in determining
        whether a positive preclinical test result is, in fact, accurate: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúHow can one do an
        appropriate evaluation?‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> appears to be a useful medium for testing scrapie in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>,
        but current technology cannot deliver a tool applicable across a range of different scrapie
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genotypes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúLike sheep</ENAMEX>, elk and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mule deer</ENAMEX> do have a peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pathogenesis</ENAMEX>, which suggests
        that the blood test route may have some potential, especially if the genotype variability
        is more restricted than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transmission Mysteries</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scrapie</ENAMEX> can be vertically transmitted from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>, either in the womb or
        from the transfer of infected germ plasm. It also can be transmitted horizontally, from any
        one animal to another. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX>, the only other known contagious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX>, is thought to be
        transmitted solely by as-yet-undetermined direct or indirect horizontal contact. It
        probably is not transmitted through infected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>, as is the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>.
        A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are currently on the trail of suspected CWD disease <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saliva</ENAMEX> is a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, because clinical signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> include excessive thirst,
        drinking, and drooling. Work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lab animals</ENAMEX> suggests that the infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> might be
        produced in salivary glands and, if so, it could be transmitted through social
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feces</ENAMEX> is also a possible reservoir because <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> nose in the ground for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>, and urine is yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, because it is involved in the scenting activities
        of cervids.
        Soil could be an environmental reservoir, because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cervids ingest dirt</ENAMEX> to supplement
        their diets with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">minerals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bucks</ENAMEX> also lick soil on which does have urinated to ascertain
        their mating status. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX> soil science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Pedersen</ENAMEX> has
        discovered that abnormally folded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prions</ENAMEX> stick to the surface of some soil types, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clay</ENAMEX>, resisting environmental and chemical damage. ‚ÄúCaptive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elk</ENAMEX> contracted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CWD</ENAMEX> when
        introduced into paddocks occupied by infected elk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 12 months earlier</TIMEX>, despite
        fairly extensive efforts to disinfect the enclosures,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Pedersen</ENAMEX> notes. He has begun a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">five-year</ENAMEX> project to characterize interactions between infectious prions and soil particles
        and determine the extent to which infectivity is retained.
        No matter how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> is transmitted between cervids, the likelihood of human susceptibility
        seems low. Laboratory evidence has demonstrated a molecular barrier against such
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-species infection, based on the failure of abnormal cervid prions to efficiently
        convert normal human prions to the infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Likewise, abnormal cervid prions don't
        easily convert normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> prions, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> won't get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> and pass it on to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> who eat tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> can contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX> if inoculated with the
        infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, long-term studies placing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> in close proximity to diseased cervids
        have resulted in no cases of natural transmission. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> summarizes what all this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">suggests: ‚ÄúNever</ENAMEX> say never, but based on the [molecular] work, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>'s findings, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epidemiology</ENAMEX>, we certainly don't have evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> have gotten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWD</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
      
      
        
      
    
  
