
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúDr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Octopus</ENAMEX>,‚Äù the villain that terrorizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the most recent film of the
        popular 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Spider-Man comic</ENAMEX>, is the ultimate characterization of a brain‚Äìmachine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interface</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>) on the big screen. In 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spider-Man 2</ENAMEX>, the brain is that of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto Octavius</ENAMEX>,
        who dreams of harnessing nuclear fusion. The machine is a harness of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> mechanical arms
        designed with tentacle-like flexibility, gripping and vision capabilities, and an
        artificial intelligence module that gives them some autonomy. The interface between the
        machine and the brain is at the spinal cord level, with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúinhibitor chip‚Äù</ENAMEX> to prevent the
        artificial intelligence module in the mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> from taking over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Octavius</ENAMEX>'s brain.
        Controlling this mechanical device with his own thoughts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Octavius</ENAMEX> is able to manipulate
        hazardous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> during his fusion experiments. However, things go terribly wrong during
        the exhibition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these experiments: the mechanical arms fuse to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Octavius</ENAMEX>'s body
        while the inhibitor chip is disabled, resulting in the machine gaining partial control of
        his brain. Unable to subvert the machine to his will and conscience, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Octavius</ENAMEX>, together
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>, becomes the villainous <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dr. Octopus</ENAMEX>. At the end of the movie, in a flicker of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanity</ENAMEX> and heroism, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Octavius</ENAMEX> dramatically sacrifices his life as the only way to terminate
        the evil machine and save the world.
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Octopus</ENAMEX> is a fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, a figment of a vivid imagination,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> are fascinated by the fact that he is a human <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMIs</ENAMEX> straddle the worlds of
        fact and fiction. While the entertainment industry has focused primarily on applications
        for augmenting cognitive and sensorimotor function, as seen in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Trek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Firefox</ENAMEX>, and many other science-fiction scenarios, the
        scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has targeted clinical applications, such as neuroprostheses for
        restoring motor function after traumatic lesion of the central nervous system. The current
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> approach is based on the idea that a human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> could enact voluntary motor intentions
        through a direct interface between his brain and an artificial actuator in virtually the
        same way that we see, walk, or grab an object with our own natural limbs. Proficient brain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of an external device or actuator should be achievable through training using any
        combination of visual, tactile, or auditory feedback. As a result of long-term use of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>, the brain should be able to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúincorporate‚Äù</ENAMEX> (or adapt to) the artificial actuator as an
        extension of its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. With these goals in mind, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last five years</TIMEX> have witnessed a
        dramatic increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>-related studies in academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> around the world.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subjects</ENAMEX> have learned to utilize their brain activity for different purposes, ranging from
        electroencephalogram- and electrocorticographic-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolpaw et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Leuthardt et al. 2004</ENAMEX>), in which human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> control computer cursors, to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">multielectrode</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>, in which nonhuman primates control the movements of cursors
        and robots to perform different kinds of reaching and grasping tasks (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serruya et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmena et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musallam et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        These examples of what could be called the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMIs</ENAMEX> have something in
        common: they have been exclusively controlled by neural signals. Even with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMIs</ENAMEX> that use
        neural activity recorded with invasive electrodes to yield higher bandwidth and thus allow
        for the execution of more complex tasks, it remains unclear whether the quality of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> will ever suffice for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to freely, safely, and effectively control a
        prosthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> to perform daily tasks. For instance, the level of motor skill required for
        dexterous finger manipulation is outstanding. Planning paths and avoiding obstacles while
        reaching and grasping in unconstrained environments requires similarly fine motor control.
        Thus, realistic motion through a complex environment with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> is extremely challenging
        and, perhaps, not feasible with the relatively low bandwidth (‚à<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">º10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hz</ENAMEX>) of current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMIs</ENAMEX>. Even
        if significant improvements are made in the algorithms used to decode neural activity by,
        for example, incorporating knowledge from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neurophysiological</ENAMEX> experiments of how motor
        signals that underlie movements are encoded in the brain, current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bandwidth</ENAMEX> still may
        not be sufficient to reach the performance level an injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> would desire.
        What does this mean for second-generation BMIs? We may find some inspiration in Dr.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Octopus</ENAMEX>. The fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spider-Man 2</ENAMEX> is innovative in the sense that it is a hybrid system that
        incorporates both neuronal and artificial control signals. It makes perfect sense to take
        advantage of the fields of engineering (control theory) and artificial intelligence to
        build better BMIs‚Äîpart brain and part robot. In principle, these hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BMIs</ENAMEX> would allow a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to accomplish a task more efficiently than those relying on neuronal signals alone.
        For example, in a common task such as reaching for and grasping a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, a hybrid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> would be fed with both brain and machine control signals; the intention of movement
        would be decoded directly from neuronal signals, leaving obstacle avoidance and grasping
        stabilization to the artificial control module of the system. Such a module would get
        inputs from sensors embedded in the robot, and would produce a control signal that would
        fuse with the neuronal control signal to augment the final output command.
        What ratio of neuronal versus artificial signal would be needed for optimal control of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>? In the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Octavius</ENAMEX>'s crisis is a severe unbalance in favor of machine control.
        Science fiction aside, we see the more realistic potential problems of having a physical
        device gaining autonomous control. Technically, this could be analyzed as too much gain in
        the artificial control signal, which, in a realistic scenario, would likely result in
        oscillating behavior, jerky grasping, etc. Hence, safeguarding measures (characterized in
        the movie as the inhibitor chip in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Octavius</ENAMEX>'s brain stem) would be needed to avoid
        dangerous situations when a chronic neuroprosthesis freely interacts with the real world.
        For both science and science fiction, the question is the same. Brain and machine: which
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gets the power?
      
    
  
