
  
    
      
        
        Despite the biases that a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> inevitably brings to a subject, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> or a
        few closely interacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> can bring coherence, synthesis, and vision to a broad and
        complex topic. A symposium volume just doesn't do the job. Few topics in biology are as
        simultaneously encompassing, complex, and controversial as the origin of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, i.e.,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speciation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speciation</ENAMEX> is, after all, the process responsible for biological diversity, at
        least of sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>, so it is hardly a minor topic. But even though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> have
        seen the publication of symposia on speciation and books on the ever-contentious issue of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species concepts</ENAMEX>, it has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verne Grant</ENAMEX>'s authoritative 
        Plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Speciation</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41 years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ernst Mayr</ENAMEX>'s magisterial and
        highly influential 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animal Species</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Evolution</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>]‚Äîthe last syntheses of research on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speciation</ENAMEX>. Now, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outstanding new books not only treat speciation as a conceptually
        unified topic in both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, but also provide rich review
        and analysis of a vast subject that has progressed at least as much since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant</ENAMEX>
        wrote as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> that preceded their work.
        These books are very different, but wonderfully complementary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> reviews and
        adds to mathematical theories and simulation studies of speciation and related issues, such
        as fitness landscapes and selection in heterogeneous environments. A deep reading of his
        book will require considerably more mathematical competence than most evolutionary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biologists</ENAMEX> (including this reviewer) have, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> provides excellent verbal
        explanations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>' assumptions and conclusions, as well as comparisons and
        critiques of related models. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> cites empirical studies (with which he has very
        broad familiarity) plentifully, but as a theoretician, he does not evaluate them or
        describe them in depth. That task is undertaken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>, who introduce most topics
        with a verbal overview of theory, review empirical evidence and its bearing on hypotheses,
        and conclude with incisive assessments of what they think we know and what remains
        uncertain or unexplored. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavrilets</ENAMEX>, they offer a number of novel ideas or suggestions
        about how to proceed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> have both worked mostly on speciation genetics in 
        Drosophila , so it is hardly surprising that their treatment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speciation</ENAMEX> bears a strong genetic emphasis and draws heavily on 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> work (perforce, since this is almost the only source
        of evidence on some topics, such as the genetics of hybrid sterility and inviability). Even
        the most drosophilophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, however, will be pleased by the extent to which Coyne
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> have conscientiously scoured the literature on nonmodel <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>.
        To appreciate the landmark status of these books, consider what has happened in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speciation</ENAMEX> studies since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant</ENAMEX> published theirs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> articulated
        positions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> and speciation that had developed during and soon after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>
        Synthesis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s and 1940s</TIMEX>, when modern evolutionary theory developed from a
        reconciliation of genetics, systematics, and paleontology. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> drew on abundant
        systematic data on patterns of divergence and experimental data on genetic differences
        between related species. They rightly identified reproductive isolation (RI) as a critical,
        even defining, property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, and allopatric divergence (i.e., in disjunct geographic
        areas) as the major geographic mode of speciation. They recognized that trait differences
        between species, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX>, usually have a polygenic basis, and that different coadapted
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">epistatically interacting</NUMEX>) sets of genes underlie incompatibility (e.g., hybrid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sterility</ENAMEX>). They emphasized the role of ecological selection as a driving force in
        speciation, largely by extrapolation from the primacy of selectionist thinking that
        developed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synthesis</ENAMEX>. They accepted that natural selection can reinforce
        prezygotic isolation (i.e., lack of mating or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">zygote</ENAMEX> formation) between <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> and thereby
        reduce production of unfit <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX>, even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayr</ENAMEX> did not share <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dobzhansky</ENAMEX>'s belief that
        this was the norm. Mayr combined selection with genetic drift in his theory of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>-effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">speciation</TIMEX> (divergence in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> founded by just a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>),
        which became widely accepted. (It became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eldredge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX>'s [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>] theoretical foundation
        for punctuated equilibrium <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayr</ENAMEX>'s book appeared.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> wrote
        against a background that almost entirely lacked any mathematical theory of speciation
        (which I suspect neither of them would have drawn on even if it had been developed), any
        relevant molecular data (other than early allozyme studies by the time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant</ENAMEX> published),
        and any rigorous phylogenetic methodology. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kimura</ENAMEX>'s neutral theory of molecular evolution
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>] had not yet been published when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayr</ENAMEX> wrote, and had not been vindicated when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant</ENAMEX>
        wrote, so genetic drift and a neutral (nonselectionist) interpretation of molecular data
        were still suspect. Detailed analysis of genetic architecture was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> away, and of
        course insights into selection and historical demography from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequence data were a dim
        dream at best.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> analyze a new world of speciation studies. Theoretical
        studies of speciation, for example, now include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> topic alone,
        the evolution of prezygotic isolation. (Gavrilets laments that the theoretical work suffers
        from domination by simulation rather than analysis, so that it is often hard to draw
        general conclusions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> that use different assumptions, but he nevertheless draws
        some fairly strong conclusions, as I note below.) Molecular studies have provided important
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> on such issues as the absolute dates of speciation events, the duration of speciation,
        and the time course of the evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX>. The field of molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phylogeography</ENAMEX>, which
        documents the history of spatial isolation and geographic expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, has
        developed. The relation between range overlap of related <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> and their molecularly
        dated time of divergence provides some evidence on the role of geographic versus sympatric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speciation</ENAMEX> (i.e., speciation without geographic segregation). In all these areas and
        others, our knowledge has increased steadily. For instance, molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> enable more
        detailed dissection of the genetic architecture of species differences, and support the
        conclusion that they are usually rather highly polygenic, but that much of the variance can
        be explained by a few major gene substitutions. We now have good evidence, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emphasize</ENAMEX>, that at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, hybrid infertility is caused by differences in gene
        action, not by structural chromosome differences or failure of meiosis.
        Regarding the mechanisms of speciation, evidence for the role of divergent ecological
        selection in allopatric speciation is sparse, because this crucial topic has been
        unaccountably neglected until recently. Very different kinds of data, ranging from DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> to correspondence between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX> and ecological divergence, support natural
        selection, but there is hardly enough evidence, in my opinion, to support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>'s
        strong conclusion that ‚Äúat least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> important debate has been settled: selection plays a
        much larger role in speciation than does drift‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 410</ENAMEX>). Even more astonishing than the
        paucity of studies of the role of ecological selection in speciation is the fact that the
        likely role of sexual selection was not even recognized until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 20 years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayr</ENAMEX>'s
        book. I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> that the theory and evidence for speciation by sexual
        selection is one of the most important advances in speciation studies, but it is important
        to recognize that the evidence consists mostly of correlations between diversification
        rates and indices of the likely strength of sexual selection; as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> note, there
        are no cases in which we understand just how sexual selection has caused speciation. This
        is a rich, largely unexplored area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> feels that divergent evolution by sexual
        conflict (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> evolve resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>' advances) is a potentially important
        process, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> are skeptical that this will prove widespread. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>
        remark that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> may diverge in male signals because of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intrasexual</ENAMEX> selection
        (competition among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>), and that female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> preference may follow. Quite so, but even
        though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berglund et al.</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>] summarized many examples in which male signals appear to serve
        both inter- and intrasexual functions, this topic has been almost ignored in the literature
        of both speciation and sexual selection. On a related theme, an important speciation
        process appears to be the extraordinarily rapid evolution of male reproductive proteins
        (e.g., sperm surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>), which may contribute to the ‚Äúfaster male evolution‚Äù that is
        a cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúHaldane's rule‚Äù</ENAMEX> (that hybrid sterility and inviability first appear in the sex
        that has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unlike sex chromosomes).
        Despite their very different approaches, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> arrive at rather
        similar conclusions on some of the most controversial issues in speciation. One such is the
        role of genetic drift in speciation. Gavrilets analyzes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>-effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">speciation</TIMEX> (which
        combines drift and selection), agrees with most other theoreticians (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlesworth</ENAMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>] that it is very improbable, and argues instead for his model of evolution
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúholey landscapes</ENAMEX>,‚Äù whereby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allopatric populations</ENAMEX> can evolve by genetic drift along
        ridges of roughly equal fitness to different, incompatible gene constitutions. He admits
        that the time to speciation under this process will ordinarily be very long unless
        selection is involved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> fully accept both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlesworth</ENAMEX>'s critique
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets</ENAMEX>'s alternative model. But while admitting the plausibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets</ENAMEX>'s
        models of speciation by genetic drift, they nevertheless maintain that ‚Äúthe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> seem
        unnecessary when compared to adaptive ones‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 398</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> appear to adopt selection as the null hypothesis for speciation, whereas
        drift is generally taken as the null hypothesis in much of evolutionary genetics, for the
        simple reason that drift operates at all loci in all finite (i.e., real) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>,
        whereas selection need not. The burden of demonstrating that selection is 
        not responsible for an evolutionary event (i.e., demonstrating a
        negative) is, of course, far heavier than the burden of demonstrating selection; indeed,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> do not address the difficult question of what would constitute evidence for
        drift. Having, perhaps, stacked the deck, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> find almost no evidence that drift
        has contributed to speciation in nature, but conclude that there is ‚Äúconsiderable evidence‚Äù
        that selection has done so. However, the amount of evidence is hardly on a par with, say,
        the evidence for allopatric speciation. It consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about eight</NUMEX> studies of
        ecological selection, indications that diversification rates are associated with greater
        scope for sexual selection, selection signatures in a few genes that underlie genetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incompatibility</ENAMEX>, and a paucity of molecular evidence for bottlenecks (i.e., opportunities
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> events) in the history of recently formed species. But the evidence on the role
        of sexual selection is very indirect, and the high levels of genetic variation revealed in
        molecular studies argue against past bottlenecks only if this is ancestral variation,
        rather than variation generated anew since a possible bottleneck‚Äîa question that has been
        addressed in only a few cases. Assuming that experiments with laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> can be
        validly extrapolated to natural speciation processes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>-effect speciation may indeed
        be a moribund hypothesis, but I do not believe long-term genetic drift can yet be ruled
        out, and cannot agree that this ‚Äúimportant debate has been settled‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 410</ENAMEX>).
        The geography of speciation continues to be one of the most difficult and contentious
        topics, and undoubtedly will remain so despite the careful analyses by these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. They
        agree that parapatric speciation (evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX> between neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> that
        exchange genes) is theoretically plausible, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> notes that although it has become
        clear that its likelihood is sensitive to several model parameters, parapatric speciation
        is difficult to model and has been shamefully neglected. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> do not doubt that it
        is a fairly common mode of speciation, yet ‚Äúit is almost impossible to demonstrate
        parapatric speciation in nature‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 118</ENAMEX>), and no cases have been well documented.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> provides an exhaustive analysis of the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> of sympatric speciation,
        and identifies some key issues that have been underemphasized. For example, the sympatric
        evolution of behavioral isolation by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúmatching traits‚Äù</ENAMEX> (e.g., genetically independent male
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> and female preference) is generally much more difficult than ‚Äúsimilaritybased‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mating</ENAMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females choose males</ENAMEX> that have the same phenotypic trait as themselves).
        Just how common the latter is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> is an open question that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>
        unfortunately do not address. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> also identifies the cost of female choosiness as a
        critical issue: many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> of sympatric speciation depend on the assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>
        always succeed in mating even if the male type they prefer is rare, so their choosiness has
        no cost. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavrilets</ENAMEX> criticizes some popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> of sympatric speciation on these and
        other grounds, and while granting that sympatric speciation by divergent habitat or host
        preference is plausible, he concludes that it need not be faster than allopatric speciation
        and that ‚Äúcontrary to common claims in recent theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, conditions for sympatric
        speciation are not wide and sympatric speciation does not occur easily‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 404</ENAMEX>).
        For their part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> feel that the prevalence of sympatric speciation is an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">empirical issue</ENAMEX> (but a very difficult one), and undertake a broad, detailed review. They
        identify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> examples of completed speciation in which a sympatric scenario ‚Äúseems
        plausible.‚Äù I see no reason to accept one of these cases, a pair of sister species of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúparasites‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fig wasps</ENAMEX>) on the same host <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, since allopatric speciation of a
        widespread parasite need not be accompanied by speciation of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX> note weaknesses in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> cases, as well as in examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúhost races‚Äù</ENAMEX> that have
        been advanced as species 
        in statu nascendi . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>'s conclusion echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrilets's</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúIt is
        hard to see how the data at hand can justify the current wave of enthusiasm for sympatric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">speciation‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 178</ENAMEX>). 
        Bravi!
        I have indicated some disagreements with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>, and could certainly cite others.
        But whatever weaknesses their book may have (more ecology and phylogeny, anyone?) are much
        less important than its strengths. The strengths of 
        Speciation are not only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>'s comprehensive, scholarly coverage
        of an exceedingly broad subject, but also, and especially, their rigorous, incisive
        analysis, coupled with strongly stated conclusions and suggestions for how to resolve
        controversies. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will have a visceral reaction against their position on
        sympatric speciation, reinforcement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>-effect speciation, or other issues‚Äîbut can
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> counter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>'s arguments with equally cogent analysis? Or are these
        subjects that simply require more, and perhaps more imaginative, research?
        Together, these books provide a comprehensive, thoughtful synthesis of our current
        understanding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most important processes in evolution. They are required
        reading for anyone who studies <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> and speciation. I recommend 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speciation</ENAMEX> and the nonmathematical final <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter (‚ÄúGeneral Conclusions‚Äù</ENAMEX>)
        of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fitness Landscapes</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Origin of Species</ENAMEX> to all evolutionary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biologists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> alike. It may not take another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> for the
        next foundational books on speciation to appear, but these books will fill that role for a
        long time to come.
      
    
  
