
  
    
      
        
        The ongoing battle between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> and pathogens has long been of interest to evolutionary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> and pathogens act as environments for each other, their
        intertwined struggle for existence is both continual and rapid. At the molecular level,
        this cycle of environmental change and evolutionary response means that mutations are
        continually being tried out by natural selection. It is therefore little wonder that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and pathogen genes that control infection and immunity frequently show high levels of
        genetic diversity and present some of the best examples of positive selection (adaptive
        evolution) reported to date (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bielawski 2000).</ENAMEX> In particular, rates of
        nonsynonymous substitution per site (resulting in an amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> change; d
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> ) often greatly exceed those of synonymous substitution per site
        (silent change; d
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> ), as expected if most mutations are fixed because they increase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fitness</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        At the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> level, most studies of the selection pressures acting on immune system genes
        have concentrated on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> implicated in the adaptive immune response against microbial
        pathogens, particularly those producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sitnikova</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nei</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumiyama et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), or genes encoding reconnaissance molecules known as the major histocompatibility
        complex (MHC), which control the action of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nei</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeager</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). As its name suggests, the role of the adaptive immune response is to
        stimulate and ‘memorise’ immunity to specific pathogens. As microbial pathogens such as
        viruses are both abundant and rapidly evolving, positive selection on components of the
        adaptive immune response is often very strong (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeager</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughes 1999).</ENAMEX> Far less attention
        has been directed toward the less specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">innate (‘nonadaptive’</ENAMEX>) immune response, even
        though this response requires a wide array of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and acts as the front line of immune
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). Would we expect the same strength of positive selection on a generalized
        pathogen control system? This is a question of fundamental importance because the luxury of
        adaptive immunity is not available to most organisms, having probably evolved along with
        the vertebrates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartl et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), whereas the more widespread innate immune system is
        often depicted as a primitive characteristic.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Evolution</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Innate Immune System</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> involved in innate immunity have recently come under the molecular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evolutionists</ENAMEX>' gaze. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> are the defensins, a large class of short
        antimicrobial peptides that constitute an effective immune response <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> as
        diverse as <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and primates (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boman 1995).</ENAMEX> Because defensins are cationic (positively
        charged), they are able to interact with negatively charged molecules on the surface of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microbes</ENAMEX> and permeate their membranes. Sequence analyses of defensins and similar
        antimicrobial peptides have revealed the telltale signatures of positive selection, with d
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> greater than d
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> in many comparisons (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes 1999; Duda et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> of the innate immune system also seem to be subject to powerful positive
        selection. One dramatic example described in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APOBEC3G</NUMEX> gene of primates (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer et al. 2004).</ENAMEX> This
        case is especially striking because rather than killing pathogens through <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> or
        cellular interactions, like most immune genes, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G</TIMEX> works by manipulating the genome
        sequence of the invading microbe.
        The genomes of primates contain a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> APOBEC genes that encode enzymes
        involved in the editing of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> through the deamination of cytosine (C), so that
        this nucleotide mutates to uracil (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>). This is essential for various aspects of cellular
        function. APOBEC1, for example, is involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C→U</ENAMEX> editing of apolipoprotein B mRNA
        (therein christening the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>), while another family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, the activation-induced
        deaminase, has a vital role in adaptive immunity in that it assists in the diversification
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. Two more enzymes, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G and APOBEC3F</TIMEX>, form part of the innate immune
        system; they function as antiviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents</ENAMEX> and are being intensively studied in the context
        of infection with the human immunodeficiency virus (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>), the cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. In particular,
        APOBEC3G targets the reverse transcription step of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> life cycle, in which the viral
        genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> is converted into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proviral DNA</ENAMEX>, which is then integrated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> genome
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mangeat et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). APOBEC3G-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deamination</ENAMEX> at this stage results in monotonous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guanine</ENAMEX>-to-adenine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G→A</ENAMEX>) nucleotide changes, a phenomenon called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G→A</ENAMEX> hypermutation that had
        long been noted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> without a clear understanding of its cause. We now know
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G→A</ENAMEX> hypermutation is part of the innate immune response to retroviral infections.
        Although there is still some debate over exactly how <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">APOBEC3G</ENAMEX> leads to viral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eradication</ENAMEX>, the most likely scenario is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G3A</ENAMEX> hypermutation results in the generation
        and incorporation of a multitude of deleterious mutations that fatally disrupt viral
        functions. This strategy is likely to work well for retroviruses like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> because their
        genomes are so compact that individual sequence regions often perform multiple functions.
        Under these cramped conditions, most mutations are likely to severely disrupt some aspect
        of viral function and thereby reduce fitness (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes 2003).</ENAMEX> Indeed, it has been estimated
        that the deleterious mutation rate in viruses that replicate using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA polymerases</ENAMEX> (either
        reverse transcriptase in the case of retroviruses or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA-dependent RNA polymerase</ENAMEX> for other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA viruses</ENAMEX>) is on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> error per replication cycle, so that many of the viral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progeny</ENAMEX> produced by replication are defective (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moya 1999).</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> is normally able
        to overcome this burden of deleterious mutation because of its remarkable reproductive
        power; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>, on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> virions are produced in a single infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perelson et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), so that enough fit and able <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> will make it through to the next
        generation.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Treating RNA Virus Infections Through Lethal</ENAMEX> Mutagenesis
        The high mutation rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> viruses mean that adaptively useful genetic variation is
        produced frequently. The rub, however, is that fitness-enhancing mutations are a small
        minority, and the preponderance of deleterious mutations means that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> viruses live on the
        edge of survival (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domingo 2000).</ENAMEX> By increasing the rate at which deleterious mutations
        appear, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G</TIMEX> pushes viruses over this edge, causing a form of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‘lethal mutagenesis’</ENAMEX> that
        results in their destruction; the rate of mutation becomes so high that no genome can
        reproduce itself faithfully, and the population crashes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intriguingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        designing new antiviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> have also begun to realise that forcing viruses into this
        sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‘error catastrophe’</ENAMEX> might be an effective way to treat them (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). There are a
        growing number of studies in which mutagens, such as ribavirin and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-fluorouracil</ENAMEX>, are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to viral infections in vitro and in vivo, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>, in the hope that these
        will induce so many deleterious mutations that the virus suffers an error catastrophe and
        is cleared (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loeb et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crotty et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruiz</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarabo et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). The results produced to date are highly encouraging, particularly when these
        error-inducing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are combined with more conventional treatment strategies that aim to
        reduce the rate of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replication</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pariente et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). The discovery that a natural
        antiviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G</TIMEX>, probably works in much the same way should provide even more
        encouragement.
        Sadly, however, the pathogens have fought back. The anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> properties of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G</TIMEX> were
        discovered because most viral strains escape its neutralising properties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lentiviruses</ENAMEX> like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> possess a gene that encodes an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vif (‘viral infectivity factor’</ENAMEX>) that
        counters APOBEC3G (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheehy et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). Hence, it is probably only in naturally occurring
        Vif-defective mutants that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APOBEC3G</ENAMEX> is effective against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, because positive
        selection on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G</TIMEX> has operated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 30 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and lentiviruses in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> in particular, are likely to be more recently evolved than this, it is
        clear that a broad range of retroviral pathogens have been responsible for the adaptive
        evolution of this particular immune gene (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer et al. 2004).</ENAMEX> Given the frequency with
        which the remnants of past retroviral infections are found in the mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">genome</ENAMEX> (Smit
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>), in the form of usually defunct endogenous retroviruses (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>), it is likely that
        our genomes are continually bombarded with retroviruses like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> but that the majority are
        cleared by innate immune mechanisms like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G</TIMEX>. It is possible that the retroviruses
        that successfully infect us are those, like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>, that have managed to evolve strategies to
        avoid the destructive capacities of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G</TIMEX>.
        The intense selective pressure on the defensins and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APOBEC3G</ENAMEX> illustrates that although
        the innate immune response is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generalist</ENAMEX> in its action, it is as highly and intricately
        evolved as its better-studied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, the adaptive immune system. Rather than being an
        evolutionary remnant, it is a dynamic and continually adapting system. Less clear is
        whether other host <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> act in the same manner as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APOBEC3G</TIMEX>. In particular, the most
        common and destructive pathogens faced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and other mammals are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA viruses</ENAMEX>, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">influenza A</ENAMEX>, yellow fever, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> C. In most cases, our ability to survive these
        viral infections is simply a combination of good luck and good breeding; with the right
        combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> alleles, itself a function of population history and what we by chance
        inherit from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> may be more able to fight off viral infections
        than others. The ubiquity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA viruses</ENAMEX> hints that our genomes might also contain an
        innate, yet highly adapted, defence system that targets this abundant class of pathogens by
        manipulating their mutation rate. Although utilizing lethal mutagenesis might one day be an
        important way to design new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> against a variety of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathogens</ENAMEX>, it would come as no
        surprise if nature got there first.
      
    
  
