
  
    
      
        
        Consider a piece of text, either this one that you are now reading or any other. Surely
        they are all pretty much alike, in so far as they are all run-on strings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. In
        this same sense, we can envision that all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA strands</ENAMEX> are alike because all are monotonous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polymers</ENAMEX> with the same general chemical makeup. Indeed, this is how we think of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> when
        considering its basic function of inheritance, in which all parts of all chromosomes must
        be duplicated and then passed from one cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> to the next. The capacity for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inheritance</ENAMEX> is fundamentally a consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>'s general molecular structure, and not of
        its sequence per se, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crick</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>), and indeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muller</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>) long before them,
        well appreciated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muller</ENAMEX> did not know that genes are made of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, but he did realize that,
        whatever genes were made of, they must have a general capacity to replicate, regardless of
        the information they carry (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muller 1922).</ENAMEX>
        But sequence does matter when <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> fulfills its other, more directly functional role.
        When the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> that makes up a gene is exposed and expressed, when a gene is serving its
        individual function, then the detailed sequence means all.
        So where does recombination (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>) fit in? Is recombination something that happens to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> generally? Or does it happen to particular sequences? <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacteria</ENAMEX> have their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chi (χ</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX>, which is a specific series of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> base pairs in the DNA of the bacterial
        chromosome that stimulate the action of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that bring about recombination (Eggleston
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). Similarly, the immunoglobulin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> of mammals have recombination signal
        sequences that are involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-J</ENAMEX> joining—a kind of somatic recombination involving the
        joining of a variable gene <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> and a joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> to form an immunoglobulin gene
        (Krangel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). But does normal meiotic recombination depend on the local DNA sequence? In
        yeast, as well as mammals (<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>), the answer is partly yes, for it is clear that
        chromosomes have local recombination hotspots where crossing over is much more likely to
        occur than in other places on the chromosome. Recombination hotspots are local regions of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chromosomes</ENAMEX>, on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">base</ENAMEX> pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (or less—their length is
        difficult to measure), in which recombination events tend to be concentrated. Often they
        are flanked by “coldspots,<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">”</ENAMEX> regions of lower than average frequency of recombination
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lichten</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldman 1995).</ENAMEX>
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diverse Implications of Recombination Hotspots: The Study of Meiosis and the Mapping</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Disease</ENAMEX> Alleles
        Recombination hotspots are of strong interest to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> quite different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX>. For geneticists and cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> who study meiosis, the existence of
        recombination hotspots offers a way to learn what other processes are associated with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recombination</ENAMEX>. This is partly how we know that homologous crossovers in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> and other
        eukaryotes are initiated by the cleavage of single chromosomes, called <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">“double</ENAMEX>-strand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breaks”</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). It turns out that because of this causal linkage, the hotspots for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doublestrand</ENAMEX> breaks and the hotspots for recombination are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the same (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Game et al.</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keeney et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lopes et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lichten</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter 2003).</ENAMEX>
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> geneticists, much of the interest in recombination hotspots comes from
        their possible effect on the patterns of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequence variation along human chromosomes and
        from the possibility that these patterns could be used to map the position of alleles that
        cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. When multiple copies of the DNA sequence of a gene, or of a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> of
        a chromosome, are aligned, they reveal the location and distribution of variation at
        individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nucleotide</ENAMEX> positions—single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs). Each particular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX>, or haplotype, will carry a configuration for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> for that region (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> have long known that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> that are adjacent or near each other tend to be
        highly correlated in their pattern and to exhibit strong linkage disequilibrium (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). It
        is this linkage disequilibrium that enables <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to map the locations of mutations
        that cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heritable genetic diseases</ENAMEX>. If alleles that cause a disease have the same kind
        of linkage disequilibrium with nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> generally have with each other, then one
        could search for genes with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> alleles by looking for a pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> that is found
        only in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have the disease. This general method for mapping disease alleles is
        called “association mapping,” and it is basically a search for linkage disequilibrium
        between disease alleles and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX>. Whether or not association mapping works depends on
        the actual patterns of linkage that occur among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, and these
        patterns depend in turn on how much recombination has occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> (as well as on
        other demographic and mutation processes).
        With the advent of larger human haplotype data sets, it has become clear that there are
        often fairly long regions with very high linkage disequilibrium (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daly et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patil et</ENAMEX>
        al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel et al. 2002).</ENAMEX> This pattern of variation has been characterized as
        occurring in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">“haplotype blocks</ENAMEX>,” which are apparent regions of low recombination (or high
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">linkage disequilibrium</ENAMEX>). Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> shows a hypothetical example of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">haplotype</ENAMEX> blocks among
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> haplotypes for a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> found over a region of a chromosome. Given diverse
        evidence of recombination hotspots in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, a much discussed question is whether
        recombination hotspots play a large role in the formation of the pattern of haplotype
        blocks (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Innan et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillips et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stumpf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldstein</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). The occurrence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">haplotype</ENAMEX> blocks has inspired the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAPMAP</ENAMEX> project
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hapmap</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/</ENAMEX>), which has the goal of identifying a subset of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> that capture
        most of the relevant linkage information in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX> (IHC <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). If one had a
        subset of all common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SNPs</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> per haplotype block, then this subset would
        contain much of the available information for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> mapping of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> alleles.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Evolution of Recombination</ENAMEX> and (Possibly) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recombination Hotspots</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recombination</ENAMEX> is a nearly ubiquitous feature of genomes, and a great many theories have
        been put forward to explain why it would be evolutionarily advantageous for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> to
        regularly break with one another to join new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlesworth 1998).</ENAMEX> By and
        large these theories predict that recombination should occur more often where genes occur
        in higher concentration and that it should happen less often in areas of the genome where
        genes are spaced far apart. This expectation is roughly born out in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX>, where
        recombination rates are higher in regions of the genome with higher gene density (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fullerton</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">et al. 2001</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kong et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
        To consider the possible evolutionary advantages of individual recombination hotspots,
        we can draw from theory on the evolution of recombination modifiers. In particular, recent
        population genetic theory has brought to light some fairly general circumstances for which
        mutations that raise recombination rates would be favored by natural selection (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenormand 2002).</ENAMEX> The basic idea
        is that linkage disequilibrium can easily occur (for many reasons) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between two</NUMEX> (or more)
        polymorphic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> that are under selection. When this occurs, an allele that raises the
        recombination rate (and decreases the linkage disequilibrium) can cause selection to act
        more efficiently. If an allele that is under positive or negative selection always occurs
        with an allele at another locus that is also under selection (i.e., the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loci</ENAMEX> are in
        strong linkage disequilibrium), then selection cannot act on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> locus independently of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> locus. As new, multilocus configurations of beneficial <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">alleles</ENAMEX> are generated (by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recombination</ENAMEX>) and increase in frequency by selection, the modifiers of recombination that
        caused the production of those beneficial configurations increase in frequency with them. A
        key piece of evidence supporting this kind of theory of the evolution of recombination is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">directional</ENAMEX> selection, like that which occurs in artificial selection experiments, which
        often generates a correlated elevation in recombination rates (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Otto</ENAMEX> and Lenormand
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
        Connecting these ideas about the evolution of recombination modifiers to the question of
        recombination hotspots, we come to the possibility that individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotspots</ENAMEX> may have arisen
        as a byproduct of linkage disequilibrium between genes on either side of the hotspot that
        were under selection. This situation would create a kind of selection pressure favoring
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recombinant</ENAMEX> haplotypes and thus also favoring those chromosomes that happen to have a high
        recombination rate between the selected genes. If true, then we might expect local
        recombination rates (i.e., hotspots and coldspots for recombination) to fluctuate in
        location and intensity, in ways that would be hard to precisely predict without knowing
        what genes have been under selection and what patterns of linkage disequilibria there may
        have been.
        In this light, the paper by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ptak et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> is especially interesting. They report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX> do
        not have a recombination hotspot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the TAP2</TIMEX> region where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> have a fairly well
        characterized recombination hotspot (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeffreys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neumann 2002).</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ptak et al.'s</ENAMEX> is a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statistical</ENAMEX> study of linkage disequilibrium in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the TAP2</TIMEX> region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>,
        and is less direct than the sperm-typing study of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeffreys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neumann</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). However the
        contrast in linkage patterns between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and our closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> suggests that
        recombination hotspots can evolve fairly quickly.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Functional Constraints on Recombination Hotspots</ENAMEX>
        As appealing as the recombination modifier theory of recombination hotspots may be,
        there is circumstantial evidence that argues against it and that suggests that
        recombination hotspots are not directly the byproduct of selection on alleles in linkage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disequilibrium</ENAMEX>. Particularly important in this regard is that some wellstudied organisms
        (notably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worm</ENAMEX> 
        Drosophila melanogaster ) have not shown evidence of
        recombination hotspots. If we compare these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> and mammals, which do show
        hotspots, we gain some more insight into the factors affecting the evolution of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotspots</ENAMEX>.
        Recall that double-strand breaks are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> where recombination is initiated during
        meiosis, and that this is true regardless of the presence of hotspots for both phenomena.
        Apparently it is the case in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> and mammals that both recombination and double-strand
        breaks are also prerequisites for the proper formation of the synaptonemal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (SC)
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) and thus for proper orientation of the spindle apparatus and accurate
        segregation of chromosomes during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">meiosis</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paques</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Haber</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; Lichten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawley 2003).</ENAMEX> In contrast, neither double-strand breaks nor recombination
        appear to be required for the formation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> melanogaster or 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> elegans (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zickler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kleckner</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacQueen et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKim et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawley 2003).</ENAMEX> Double-strand breaks and
        recombination do indeed co-occur in these model <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>, and are required for proper
        chromosome segregation, but they occur after the formation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>. Both of these species
        have broad chromosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> where crossing over occurs at higher rates than others, but
        there have been no reports of local recombination hotspots.
        Recombination during meiosis seems to be required for proper chromosome segregation;
        however, in those organisms where recombination and double-strand-break hotspots occur,
        these phenomena are also required for proper formation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>. It is as if the
        recombination machinery has been partly co-opted for chromosome alignment in some
        eukaryotes more so than in others. The implication of these findings is that recombination
        hotspots are byproducts of other functional constraints associated with the recombination
        process. This does not rule out the evolutionary theory of recombination modifiers, or that
        the location and intensity of recombination hotspots may evolve rapidly, but it does
        suggest that we may not need to invoke the evolutionary modifier theory to explain the
        existence of recombination hotspots.
      
      
        Conclusions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recombination hotspots</ENAMEX> co-occur with double-strand-break hotspots in some eukaryotes,
        and together these phenomena appear to play an important role in the formation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> in
        those organisms. Given the limited phylogenetic occurrence of recombination hotspots (i.e.,
        their occurrence in some, but not all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>), general theories for the evolution of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recombination</ENAMEX> may not be very helpful for understanding the existence of recombination
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotspots</ENAMEX>. However, in those species where they do occur, it is quite possible that
        recombination hotspots do evolve in location and intensity. Furthermore, the presence of
        recombination hotspots in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> may have large effects on the length of local patterns of
        linkage disequilibrium (haplotype blocks) and thus on our ability to map disease alleles by
        their association with other markers.
      
      
        
      
    
  
