
  
    
      
        
        There's a cheap, common, and mostly safe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> use for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, that only lately has been investigated for its therapeutic potential
        for a long list of common ills. The list includes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson disease</ENAMEX>,
        even pain and obesity. Why has interest in this potential cure-all been slow to develop?
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason: in its current forms the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> offers pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> no possibility of
        substantial profit. Another, perhaps more important: the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is reviled as the world's
        most addictive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, of course, is nicotine.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotine</ENAMEX> is an alkaloid in the tobacco plant 
        Nicotiana tabacum , which was smoked or chewed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americas</ENAMEX>
        for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> invaders also succumbed to its pleasures and shipped
        it back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old World</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotine</ENAMEX> has always been regarded as medicinal and enjoyable at
        its usual low doses. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> chewed tobacco to treat intestinal symptoms, and in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1560</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Nicot de Villemain</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco seeds</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, claiming tobacco had
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medicinal</ENAMEX> properties and describing it as a panacea for many ailments. Higher doses are
        toxic, even lethal‚Äîwhich is why nicotine is used around the world as an insecticide. Yet
        few of the horrendous health effects of smoking are traceable to nicotine itself‚Äîcigarettes
        contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 4,000</NUMEX> other compounds that play a role. Until recently, nicotine research
        has been driven primarily by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nicotine</ENAMEX>'s unparalleled power to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> smoking, rather
        than its potential therapeutic uses.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotine</ENAMEX> locks on to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> that are normally targeted by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">threaded</ENAMEX> through cell membranes. When activated, either by acetylcholine or by nicotine,
        they allow selected ions to flow across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell membrane</ENAMEX>. In vertebrates nAChRs are all
        over the autonomic and central nervous sytems and the neuromuscular junction. A nAChR is
        composed of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five polypeptide subunits</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), but there are many nAChR subtypes made of
        different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">subunit</ENAMEX> combinations, a diversity that helps explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nicotine</ENAMEX> can have so
        many different physiological and cognitive effects.
        It is now conventional wisdom that acetylcholine and nicotine act at these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> to
        alter <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">electrochemical properties</ENAMEX> at a variety of synapses, which can in turn affect the
        release of several other neurotransmitters. This wisdom exists thanks in part to work by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorna Role</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúIn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, we turned
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s attention to how nicotine works as a modulator, tuning synapses and increasing the
        gain on transmitter release,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Role</ENAMEX> recalls. Although all nAChRs are activated by nicotine,
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> could be found or designed that affect only a subset of these receptor types.
        ‚ÄúIf you can dissect out the important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> with respect to which nicotine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are
        tuning [a] particular set of synapses, then that provides another way to potentially target
        the therapeutics.‚Äù
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotine</ENAMEX> and the Brain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> with depressive-spectrum disorders, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult ADHD</ENAMEX> tend to smoke
        heavily, which suggested to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> that nicotine may soothe their symptoms. Common to
        all these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> is a failure of attention, an inability to concentrate on particular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimuli</ENAMEX> and screen out the rest. Nicotine helps. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute</ENAMEX> on
        Drug Abuse have shown via functional magnetic resonance imaging that nicotine activates
        specific brain areas during tasks that demand attention (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). This may be because of its
        effects, shared with many other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">addictive drugs</ENAMEX>, on the release of the neurotransmitter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dopamine</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúSchizophrenia is a disorder largely of the dopamine system,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dani</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor College of Medicine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. Dopamine signals in the brain occur in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> modes‚Äîa kind of background trickle, punctuated by brief bursts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s thought that
        schizophrenics have a hard time separating that background information from important
        bursts. We've shown that nicotine helps to normalize that signaling by depressing the
        background but letting the bursts through well,‚Äù he says. ‚ÄúI'll be surprised if there's not
        a co-therapy [to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schizophrenics</ENAMEX>] that takes advantage of nicotine systems in less than
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>.‚Äù
        Nicotine may be the link between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> that appear to figure in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Leonard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Freedman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Colorado</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, have
        shown that expression of the gene for the alpha <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> neuronal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nicotinic receptor</ENAMEX> is reduced in
        schizophrenics, and have argued that alpha <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> abnormalities lead to attention problems.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX> and elsewhere have shown that a different gene, for the growth
        factor neuregulin, also appears to figure in the disease. Neuregulin, Role and her
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have shown, governs the expression of nAChRs in neurons and helps to stabilize
        the synapses where they are found. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are currently studying interactions
        between neuregulin and alpha <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, which Role thinks will prove important.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Smokers</ENAMEX> also have lower rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">neurodegenerative disorders</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nicotine</ENAMEX> improves
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cognitive</ENAMEX> and motor functioning in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson disease</ENAMEX>. The
        prevailing hypothesis is that nicotine increases release of neurotransmitters depleted in
        those diseases. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dani</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have recently shown that acetylcholinesterase
        inhibitors‚Äîwhich block the degradation of acetylcholine and hence prolong its action‚Äîused
        to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> also stimulate dopamine release. They suspect that
        malfunctioning of the dopamine system may be affecting noncognitive aspects of dementia
        such as depressed mood, and that this might be alleviated by nicotine.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Newhouse</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Vermont</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>,
        are studying nicotine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> as potential therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for cognitive dysfunction.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, a long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nicotine researcher</ENAMEX>, is heading the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> study ever to examine the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">efficacy</ENAMEX> and safety of nicotine patches for treating mild <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cognitive impairment</ENAMEX>, thought to
        be a precursor of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> hope to see a positive effect on
        attention and learning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> also heads <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> studies of nicotinic stimulation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>,
        using the patch, nicotine blockers, and some novel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that activate nicotine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotine</ENAMEX> and Pain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotine</ENAMEX>'s salutary effects in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with neurodegenerative and mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> have
        been studied a lot and are fairly well known. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two much</NUMEX> newer topics of academic research
        are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nicotine</ENAMEX>'s potential for pain relief and for treating obesity.Nicotine itself has
        provided modest pain relief in animal studies. Although the analgesic effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that
        mimic acetylcholine were originally attributed to a different class of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, it is now
        clear that nAChRs play an important role in the control of pain. For instance, epibatidine,
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that is extracted from the skin of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ecuadorian</ENAMEX> frog and that acts at nAChRs, has
        been shown to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> times more potent than morphine at blocking pain in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. Current
        animal research is aimed at discovering just where, how, and which classes of nAChRs work
        against pain, with the aim of developing more selective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
        Meanwhile, nicotine is also being investigated as an analgesic in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. For example,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Flood</ENAMEX>, an anesthesiologist at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, is investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nicotine</ENAMEX>'s future as a
        postoperative analgesic. She recently completed a pilot study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> undergoing
        gynecological surgery. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had access to unlimited morphine and also got either a
        single <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-mg dose of nicotine nasal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> or a placebo. The placebo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had peak pain
        scores of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> out of a possible <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first hour</TIMEX> after surgery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> who got
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nicotine</ENAMEX> averaged a pain score of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>. Despite the small sample size, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flood</ENAMEX> says, the
        results were highly significant. ‚ÄúAs far as I know this is the first clinical study to use
        nicotine for analgesia, and it was much more successful than I ever would have
        imagined.‚Äù
        ‚ÄúThe nice thing about nicotine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> like nicotine is that they have opposite side
        effects to anesthetics. Instead of being respiratory depressants, they are respiratory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stimulants</ENAMEX>. Instead of being sedating, they increase alertness. So theoretically this class
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is actually the perfect thing to add to an opioid regimen. The fact that they're
        synergistic was a fortuitous thing that we had never looked at, and neither had anybody
        else.‚Äù
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weight Gain</ENAMEX>
        Nicotine may be the most effective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> around for weight control. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-smokers</ENAMEX> know,
        to their rue, one of the worst things about quitting cigarettes is putting on pounds‚Äîas
        much <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as 10%</NUMEX> of body weight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúSomething</ENAMEX> about being addicted to nicotine and then going off
        it causes massive increase in weight,‚Äù Role points out.
        Young-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hwan Jo in Role</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> is looking at a particular brain circuit involved in
        motivational behavior, especially feeding behavior. It is lodged primarily in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lateral</ENAMEX>
        hypothalamus but has projections all over the cortex, especially the nucleus accumbens,
        which is the center of reinforcement. ‚ÄúThis is where information that has come in to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thalamus</ENAMEX> and the hypothalamus is relayed to cortical areas with some sense of salience or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remembrance</ENAMEX>. It presumably is involved in changing perception and motivation for eating.
        It's not, ‚ÄòI have to eat this,‚Äô it's, ‚ÄòI want to eat this,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Role</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jo</ENAMEX> has been comparing the synaptic effects of nicotine, which reduces appetite, to those
        of cannabinoids, which stimulate it. ‚ÄúControl of these projection neurons seems to be
        oppositely regulated by these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>,‚Äù Role notes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX> doesn't necessarily mean we've found
        the root of the munchies, but it at least points to pathways that these things have in
        common.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Jo</ENAMEX> is also examining how nicotine and cannabinoids modulate these pathways in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">genetically obese mice</ENAMEX>, and also their interactions with leptins. Role says tuning these
        pathways up or down might be a reasonable aim. ‚ÄúIf that could be done in a selective
        fashion, maybe that could be introduced in appetite control. Certainly I see‚Ä¶antagonism of
        some of these pathways that nicotine activates or the complementary activation of the
        cannabinoid pathways as very important targets for therapeutics with respect to the
        anorexia that's associated with chemotherapy.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Li</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, are
        studying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nicotine</ENAMEX>'s effects on weight and on expression of genes that nicotine upregulates
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orexin</ENAMEX> and neuropeptide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> and, more recently, that it also regulates leptin signaling. All
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> molecules regulate feeding behavior controlled by the hypothalamus. In the weight
        study, nicotine-treated rats not only lost weight, they lost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20%</NUMEX> of their body fat
        compared to saline-treated controls. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> suggest that, among its other effects,
        nicotine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alters fat</ENAMEX> storage.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have scoured the literature for genes related to
        nicotine, and they are developing microarrays to study the expression of these genes
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). While nicotine seems to affect all the molecules known to influence weight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li</ENAMEX>
        says it's clear the story is even more complex. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThat</ENAMEX>'s the reason we keep looking at
        different molecules, to find key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> involved in this regulation.‚Äù The ultimate hope is
        to develop new drug applications.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dani</ENAMEX> predicts that weight control is likely to be one of the earliest nicotine-based
        therapies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThere</ENAMEX>'s a very good chance that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is unlikely to be‚Ä¶nicotine
        itself, but will take advantage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nicotinic receptors</ENAMEX> in the therapy,‚Äù he says. ‚ÄúI know
        there are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> now being tested by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> just for that purpose.‚Äù
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotine</ENAMEX>'s Future
        Developing new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that selectively target specific subtypes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nicotine receptors</ENAMEX> is
        an expensive, albeit potentially lucrative, proposition. And therein lies a question. Will
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">nicotine</ENAMEX>-based therapy consist mostly of costly new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> from the pharmaceutical industry?
        Or can less expensive nicotine products like the patch, chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>, and nasal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray‚</ENAMEX>Äîwhich
        are generally intended for smoking cessation but widely available, usually without
        prescription‚Äîfind their way into the world's medicine cabinets?
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s a little early to call whether nicotine will be used itself as a therapeutic agent
        or whether these more specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that are being produced or maybe even used in
        combination with other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> may be the most important way to go,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dani</ENAMEX>. But he
        doesn't see the medicinal use of plain nicotine as very likely. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dani</NUMEX> points out that the
        body's own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, acetylcholine, acts over milliseconds to activate nicotinic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>,
        whereas nicotine itself stimulates these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. That lengthy action means
        that, although nicotine activates the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, it then often turns particular receptor
        subtypes off again, a process called desensitization. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s hard to predict inside of a
        body what you're getting. Am I getting an activation or am I turning the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        off?‚Äù
        Yet much of the work to date showing nicotine's effectiveness on a huge range of
        disorders has involved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> available at any drugstore and intended to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> quit
        smoking. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> is using patches for mild <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cognitive impairment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flood</ENAMEX> has demonstrated
        pain relief with nasal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> and will use patches in her next study. And Role feels that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> hasn't been adequately explored for its therapeutic potential. Nicotine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>, she notes,
        is a better imitator of smoking than the patch because it delivers brief hits rather than a
        steady supply. She's also uncertain whether natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nicotine</ENAMEX> has been studied enough. But
        Role also points out that nicotine has its serious problems‚Äîaddictive potential,
        cardiovascular damage, and (especially when delivered through the mucosa) <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dani</ENAMEX> says, ‚ÄúPeople are probably going to have to find creative ways to understand which
        subtypes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nicotinic receptors</ENAMEX> they're turning on and which ones they're desensitizing.
        Maybe drug delivery methods will matter. Maybe subtype specificity will matter. It's less
        than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> that we've known how important nicotinic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are. Now we have to move
        forward from there.‚Äù
        ‚ÄúWe've made an enormous amount of progress on understanding the biology of these
        receptor systems and how to target them. What has been trickier has been to develop an
        appropriate pharmacology that allows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to selectively target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for particular
        therapeutic purposes with an adequate safety index,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Newhouse</ENAMEX> says. ‚ÄúBut some of the drugs
        that are coming on in human trials now are very promising. So I'm cautiously optimistic
        that we're on the road to developing some useful nicotinic therapies.‚Äù
      
    
  
