
  
    
      
        
        Reinforcement, like sympatric speciation (see <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>), has charisma. Evolutionary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> are still deeply uncertain about how often these processes take place, and hence
        how important they are in explaining the biological diversity we see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empirical</ENAMEX> and
        theoretical support for both ideas has waxed and waned over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX>. Yet both ideas
        have consistently garnered an unusual amount of attention.
        Much of the appeal of both reinforcement and sympatric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">speciation</ENAMEX> lies in the way they
        unite micro- and macroevolution. Reinforcement, a concept popularized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobzhansky</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>),
        is a process by which speciation, a macroevolutionary process, can be driven directly by
        natural selection, one of the primary microevolutionary forces. Sympatric speciation can
        make the same claim. Because of this close linkage between the concepts, the study of one
        can tell us a great deal about the other (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirkpatrick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RavignÃ</ENAMEX>© <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). Such studies
        can also reveal a lot about the general role of microevolution in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species divergence</ENAMEX>.
        Reinforcement provides a pathway toward the completion of the speciation process.
        Imagine that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> divergent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> (potentially even classified as separate species)
        come into contact after a period of allopatry (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> have been
        apart for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>, evolved differences between them will cause a certain degree of
        incompatibility when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> come together. Often, this incompatibility comes in
        the form of low hybrid fitness (postzygotic isolation) or mismatched mating characteristics
        (premating isolation). The degree of the development of these isolating mechanisms is
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> proportional to the genetic distance between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, reflecting the fact
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incompatibilities</ENAMEX> accumulate over time (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr 1989).</ENAMEX>
        If the isolating mechanisms between these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> are only partially complete,
        extensive hybridization may occur. This can result in fusion back into a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>,
        or in the swamping of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>'s gene pool by the genes of the other (extinction).
        But there is another possibility, one that can cause the speciation between the two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> to proceed. Remember that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> have been separated for long
        enough, it is likely that hybrids between them will have relatively low fitness.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> who mate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> will therefore produce
        offspring of poor quality, and hence have lower fitness than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> within
        their own population. This favors the evolution (or further divergence) of characteristics
        that cause mating within, rather than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1C</NUMEX>). Speciation between
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> is driven further towards completion through this increase in premating
        isolation.
        This process, the evolution of premating isolation after secondary contact due to
        selection against <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX>, is reinforcement sensu <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobzhansky</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>). Recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have
        broadened the definition of reinforcement to include as a driving force any form of
        selection against mating between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Servedio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noor 2003).</ENAMEX> This could
        include, for example, lower fertility, or higher mortality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. In all definitions, however, the microevolutionary process of
        selection is essential for reinforcement. In fact, in reinforcement, speciation itself can
        be thought of as an adaptive response to selection. It is little wonder that this causal
        linking of micro- and macroevolution has appeal for many evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Reinforcement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">21st Century</ENAMEX>
        Despite the substantial progress in our understanding of reinforcement that has been
        achieved over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few decades</TIMEX>, many questions remain about the process. These
        questions lend themselves to exploration by a broad variety of disciplines (evolution,
        ecology, behavior, phylogenetics, phylogeography, genetics), approaches (experimental,
        observational, comparative, theoretical) and taxonomic systems.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doubtless</ENAMEX>, the most important unanswered question about reinforcement is how often it
        occurs. It is very difficult to prove that reinforcement is occurring, or has occurred,
        between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. Reinforcement occasionally leaves a signature, called reproductive
        character displacement, in which mating characteristics have diverged between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>
        in areas of sympatry but not areas of allopatry (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) (the relationship between
        reinforcement and reproductive character displacement, and controversy over the definition
        of the latter, is reviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard 1993).</ENAMEX> In sympatric areas, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> are capable of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">producing hybrids</ENAMEX>, which drives reinforcement, while in allopatry hybrid production, and
        hence the selection for reinforcement, is absent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reproductive</ENAMEX> character displacement has
        been found to be common, suggesting to some that reinforcement may be common as well
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard 1993).</ENAMEX> It is universally acknowledged, however, both that reproductive character
        displacement can be caused by processes other than reinforcement, and that reinforcement
        can occur without leaving this signature (e.g., when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> ranges are completely
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sympatric</ENAMEX>). Proving that reinforcement has occurred requires the ruling out of several
        alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hypotheses</ENAMEX>, which are themselves difficult to assess (Noor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        Several isolated examples of reinforcement between specific pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> have been
        demonstrated, fairly conclusively, in a variety of taxa including 
        Drosophila pseudoobscura and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> persimilis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Noor 1995</ENAMEX>), flycatchers (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SÃ¦tre et al. 1997</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sticklebacks</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rundle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Schluter 1998</ENAMEX>), spadefoot toads (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pfennig 2003</ENAMEX>), and
        walking-stick <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nosil et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>) (see also reviews of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Noor 1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). These studies involve a variety of behavioral tests of mate choice, analyses of
        hybrid fitness and the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX> in the wild, and controls for alternative
        explanations.
        While examples such as these provide essential information about reinforcement, their
        slow rate of compilation and biased reporting do not provide efficient ways to assess how
        often reinforcement occurs in general. Comparative approaches, which examine patterns
        across a broader taxonomic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, can also provide support for reinforcement without these
        detailed mechanistic analyses (review in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr 2004).</ENAMEX> The revival of reinforcement
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX> began with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such study in the genus 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orr 1989).</ENAMEX> By comparing patterns across a
        wide number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, such studies can give a better assessment of the potential
        frequency with which reinforcement occursâ€”without, however, providing conclusive evidence
        for reinforcement between specific species pairs.
        Another area where further research is essential is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of which
        biological factors promote reinforcement, as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> fusion. Theoretical
        studies, using mathematical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and computer simulations, are proving useful in
        pinpointing the effects of many factors such as migration rates and patterns, the type of
        selection against interspecific mating, and the genetic basis of premating isolation
        (reviews in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turelli et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Servedio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noor 2003).</ENAMEX> Fortunately, some of the cases of
        reinforcement in specific species pairs are now being developed to the point where they can
        address similar questions (e.g., sex linkage of mating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SÃ¦tre et al. 2003</ENAMEX>). Both
        theoretical studies and these well developed empirical systems are also starting to address
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> important area of research: how reinforcement interacts with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, such as
        ecological selection pressures, that promote speciation (e.g., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Servedio 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nosil et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). These integrated studies are essential to the correct placement of reinforcement
        within the bigger context of speciation processes.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, exciting developments have started to take place in the analysis of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genetics</ENAMEX> of reinforcement (reviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Servedio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noor 2003).</ENAMEX> These developments both
        parallel and overlap with progress made on the genetics of speciation and species
        differences in general. For example, significant progress has recently been made in
        identifying the genetic control of hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">incompatibilities</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presgraves et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Barbash et al. 2003</ENAMEX>). This progress has been accompanied by a new understanding of how
        chromosomal rearrangements may allow these incompatibilities to be maintained despite
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX> in sympatry (Rieseberg <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sympatric</ENAMEX> maintenance of incompatibilities, of course, has profound implications for
        reinforcement, which requires these incompatibilities as the force driving divergence (Noor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">et al. 2001</ENAMEX>).
        Genetic analysis is also allowing a new understanding of the mechanisms by which
        reinforcement might be taking place in specific cases. Work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrientos et</ENAMEX> al.
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> illustrates the extent of the insights that can be made with
        this approach. Using high-resolution genetic mapping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have identified the
        locations of genes that cause increased discrimination against 
        Drosophila persimilis <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> by 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> pseudoobscura <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, due to reinforcement in sympatry.
        Surprisingly, these genes map to very different areas of the chromosomes than do genes that
        cause a basal level of mating discrimination between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> in allopatry. Among other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insights</ENAMEX>, the position of these genes suggests that the reinforced discrimination is based
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">odor</TIMEX>, not on the mechanism used in allopatry, male song. This leads to the novel
        conclusion that reinforcement is not just increasing the strength of an already existing
        mechanism of species discrimination, but is occurring through the development of a new
        discrimination system. These kinds of developments can also motivate more realistic
        theoretical models of the reinforcement process.
      
      
        Implications and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Extensions of Reinforcement</ENAMEX>
        What if, when our assessment of the frequency of reinforcement is improved, it turns out
        to have been a rare occurrence in the generation of current biological diversity? The study
        of reinforcement is broad and varied enough that many of our findings about the process
        would still have wide-reaching implications.
        First, recall the claim, at the start of this article, that studying reinforcement
        reveals much about the role of microevolution in the macroevolutionary process of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speciation</ENAMEX>. Knowledge gained about this relationship is not only directly applicable to the
        very similar process of sympatric speciation, but can also tell us a great deal about
        speciation caused by ecological adaptation and sexual selection, which are critical
        components of reinforcement in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nosil et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haavie et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        Studies looking for reinforcement have also led to insights into the formation and
        maintenance of hybrid zones (e.g., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Butlin 1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britch et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). Situations where
        reinforcement fails to occur likewise teach a lesson, elucidating possible mechanisms of
        extinction when secondary contact occurs between species.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, analysis of reinforcement clarifies the interactions between levels of
        reproductive isolation that occur at different stages in the life cycle. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reinforcement,</ENAMEX>
        broadly defined, can be driven by isolation at the postzygotic level or by
        incompatibilities that occur between mating and zygote production (postmating-prezygotic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incompatibilities; Servedio</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). Postzygotic isolation can likewise cause divergence at
        the premating stage (reinforcement) or potentially at the postmating-prezygotic stage,
        through the evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conspecific sperm precedence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). These various
        stages of isolation have different degrees of importance among <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-spawning</ENAMEX> marine
        invertebrates, and other internally and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">externally fertilizing animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernasconi et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). Analysis of these stages of isolation, their interactions, and the evolutionary
        pressures they are under therefore has broad implications for comparative reproductive
        biology across these varied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        Finally, regardless of whether reinforcement has been a common pathway in speciation,
        its relevance may be increasing. Reinforcement is a possible outcome anytime <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that
        are capable of hybridization come into contact. Human activity is increasing the incidence
        of secondary contact by altering habitat and introducing invasive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. This contact
        often results in hybridization (reviews in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhymer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Simberloff</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mooney</ENAMEX> and Cleland
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). It is important to identify and understand the properties of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> pairs that make
        extensive introgression, extinction, stable hybrid zones, or reinforcement likely outcomes
        of such contact. If reinforcement has played a small role in the generation of current
        diversity, it may be because secondary contact itself has historically been a rare
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">occurrence</ENAMEX>. It is the frequency of reinforcement among incidences of secondary contact that
        will determine its importance in the near future.
      
    
  
