
  
    
      
        
        Throughout his career, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela Julesz</ENAMEX> created new scientific disciplines by remarkable
        combinations of seemingly disparate approaches. The selection of his major discipline,
        which would eventually be called visual neuroscience, may have been serendipity or
        choice.
        When the unexpected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> spurred his emigration to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela Julesz</ENAMEX>, with his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> doctorate in engineering, joined the
        numerous mathematical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> working at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T Bell Laboratories</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tukey</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Nyquist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Shannon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kelly</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the projects underway at the time was
        the creation of long random-number binary sequences that did not repeat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela</ENAMEX> told the
        story that he was assigned the problem of testing these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number generators</ENAMEX>; he decided to
        use the best pattern recognizer that he knew of—the human visual system. The random bits of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zeros</ENAMEX> and ones drawn from the random number sequences were plotted as sequential rows in an
        image. Any repeats, any correlations across space, would be instantly seen by the human
        visual system as patterns in the random dots. What caused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX> to choose this unusual
        approach to looking for patterns, combining computers and vision? His doctoral thesis
        research in network theory and television signals clearly influenced him, but it was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quintessential Bela</ENAMEX> to give himself a hand up into a new field by building on his base of
        knowledge, moving in a new and unexpected direction using mathematical and psychological
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>. He termed this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">talent “scientific bilingualism”</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julesz 1994).</ENAMEX>
        This success in exploiting the visual system, and the intellectual freedom intrinsic to
        the design of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Labs</ENAMEX>, provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX> with the opportunity to use these new random dot
        patterns to explore the visual system. Most of us know well that we can use the small
        differences in the images in each eye to see depth. Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Wheatstone</ENAMEX> showed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1838</TIMEX>
        that if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different perspective images were observed through a stereoscope so that each
        eye observed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> view, a startlingly realistic three-dimensional image occurred.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes</ENAMEX>, stereoscope <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX>, wrote of the experience that “the shutting
        out of surrounding objects, and the concentration of the whole attention, which is a
        consequence of this, produce a dreamlike exaltation…in which we seem to leave the body
        behind us and sail away into one strange scene after another, like disembodied spirits”
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes 1861).</ENAMEX>
        The basis of this three-dimensional perception was hotly debated between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheatstone</ENAMEX> and
        fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brewster</ENAMEX>. (Though it may seem odd for physicists to concern
        themselves with the physiology of optics, this was felt to be a natural extension of the
        study of the physics of optics.) Brewster opined that perspective was the source of the
        apprehension of an object's shape. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheatstone</ENAMEX> insisted that the images in the each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> had
        identifiable landmarks that were combined to assign depth to the landmarks. Bela read much
        of the literature of that time, and he must have seen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greats</ENAMEX> as wrestling without
        either finding the overwhelming hold to pin down the other. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than one hundred</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewster</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheatstone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela</ENAMEX> realized that his random dot patterns could be
        used to probe this question. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela</ENAMEX> did was create a pair of identical random dot
        patterns. When viewed binocularly through a stereoscope (i.e., fused), they would be seen
        as a single surface. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela</ENAMEX> took a central <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> from the right random dot pattern and
        displaced it minutely to the right. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Now</TIMEX> when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> patterns were fused, the central
        square was not seen double, but after a moment or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, eerily moved into depth, behind the
        surrounding region. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX>'s experiment with what eventually became known as Julesz
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> dot stereograms unambiguously demonstrated that stereoscopic depth could be computed
        in the absence of any identifiable objects, in the absence of any perspective, in the
        absence of any cues available to either eye alone. It was a perfect combination of
        psychological and mathematical insight and technology that solved this puzzle. (It is an
        interesting aside that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela</ENAMEX> sent his first report to the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of the Optical Society of America</ENAMEX> , where it was rejected; the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Labs Technical Journal</ENAMEX> holds the now classic paper [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Julesz 1960</ENAMEX>].
        The 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of the Optical Society of America</ENAMEX> published <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paper
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Julesz 1963</ENAMEX>].) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stereoscope</ENAMEX> had existed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125 years</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX> proposed in his book 
        Foundations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyclopean Perception</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>) that early in the vision
        process the two images from the two eyes were combined to form a single view, imbued with
        inherent depth information. The perceptual “cyclops within us” was proposed to analyze the
        visual world <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, before the motion, color, and contrast systems began their perceptual
        operations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX>'s book is full of powerful visual experiments that make this point
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irrefragably</ENAMEX>; from his psychophysical analysis, binocular vision forces unexpected
        constraints on the rest of vision, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.E.D. Foundations of Cyclopean Perception</ENAMEX> is still considered one of the
        classics of modern psychophysics and continues to have profound relevance to both those
        entering the field and established investigators—over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> after its publication.
        At the time of his death, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX> had begun working on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> edition.
        His success in determining the sequence of visual processing using random dot
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stereograms</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX> to propose that the anatomical hierarchy of the visual system could be
        understood in part through visual psychophysics—he termed this approach “psychoanatomy.”
        His ingenious use of the stereogram established a new approach in the field of vision
        research and presaged the now common use of carefully controlled computational techniques
        in brain science. By this time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela</ENAMEX>'s reputation was established, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, he received
        a prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthur Fellowship—the “genius</ENAMEX> award.” He used the funds for travel,
        including an annual peregrination to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Institute of Technology</ENAMEX>, where I first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">met Bela</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>.
        His seminars and lecture <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> were enthusiastically received and endorsed by
        countless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, post-doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainees</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, as evidenced both by his
        formidable reputation and through the numerous citations of his work. His approach to
        presenting his research was modest and gently self-deprecating. He always encouraged young
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>; his joy and passion in their science were transmitted both through his warm
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persona</ENAMEX> and his suggestions of directions for future study. His insights guided my
        development of random dot kinematograms (i.e., movies) to examine how motion could be used
        to construct three-dimensional form (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen 1988).</ENAMEX> He collaborated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fender</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Van Essen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Allman</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Institute of Technology</ENAMEX> on the
        combination of the computer, the psychophysical approach, and the physiological
        experiment.
        Bela was a fount of ideas, each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the prior</TIMEX>'s advance. His later passions were
        explorations of texture and attention, notably with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Victor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dov Sagi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX>'s
        appealing hypothesis that textons (putative elements of textures) are represented at a
        cellular level is now questionable (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julesz et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>). Bela was groping for an
        overarching computational theory for the representation of random geometry, but none was to
        be had. Nonetheless, the texton <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> served useful duty in the demonstration that there
        were two stages to early vision—an effortless phase preceding attention and a guided
        identification phase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sagi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julesz 1985).</ENAMEX> Many contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> examining
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX>, studying either perception or the activity of neurons, now incorporate designed,
        complicated, yet highly controlled stimuli that have evolved (knowingly or not) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX>'s
        original forays in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s and 1970s</TIMEX>. His continuing impact was recognized by his
        election to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy of Science</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX> retired from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Labs</ENAMEX> (by then he was a department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>) and joined the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of Psychology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers University</ENAMEX> to establish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vision</ENAMEX>
        Research. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bela</ENAMEX> continued investigating mechanisms of form, texture, and stereopsis; his
        presence led to numerous studies into the implications of his original findings as well as
        new investigations into computational vision. His collaborations greatly aided the
        establishment of neuroscience at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela</ENAMEX> wrote 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dialogues on Perception</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), a wide-ranging intellectual effort, in
        which he uses classic dialectics to question both his own successes and those of his chosen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>. In the book one reads of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> competing intellects, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bela</ENAMEX> who believes in his
        contributions to science and another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bela</ENAMEX> who is constantly belittling and judging his
        contributions.
        Throughout his career <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela Julesz</ENAMEX> was able to add language after language to his
        research imperative, becoming a true scientific polyglot. Although his arrival in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> was propelled by political events beyond his control, his intellectual
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> set out from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, his unique combination of mathematical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precision</ENAMEX> combined with deep biological insight had carried him to elegant solutions for
        seemingly intractable problems in visual neuroscience. Bela was always in dialogue, often
        with others, and often with himself. In the process, he would gently drive each of us, and
        himself, forward to our final destination of understanding the brain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bela Julesz</ENAMEX> died on
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31, 2003</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years to the day</TIMEX> after starting at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Laboratories</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
