
  
    
      
        
        Viruses are intracellular pathogens that are subject to intense selective pressures
        during their ongoing battles within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. To propagate successfully, they must exploit
        numerous machineries of the infected cell. Thus, studies of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">replicative cycles</ENAMEX> have
        yielded fundamental insights into eukaryotic biology. A prime example is the human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immunodeficiency</ENAMEX> virus (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>), which is a lentivirus that causes the acquired
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immunodeficiency syndrome</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>). Unlike simpler oncoviruses that rely exclusively on host
        cell machinery, lentiviruses code for additional accessory and regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that act
        as molecular switches at different stages of viral entry and exit from the infected cell.
        Studying the actions of these viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> has yielded understanding of diverse cellular
        functions such as the innate immunity against retroviruses, control of transcriptional
        elongation, export of macromolecules from the nucleus to the cytoplasm, and intracellular
        trafficking of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (reviewed in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]).
        The transcriptional transactivator (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tat</ENAMEX>) is a key regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>. It is
        expressed early after the virus integrates into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, and stimulates the elongation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA polymerase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> (RNAPII). This type of transcriptional control had not been previously
        appreciated; thus, work on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tat</ENAMEX> established a new paradigm in the field of eukaryotic
        biology. Moreover, these findings impacted greatly studies of cotranscriptional processing
        of nascent mRNA. To understand these processes better, we need to start with the basics of
        transcriptional control.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPII</ENAMEX> is the enzyme that transcribes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coding genes</ENAMEX> in eukaryotic cells. Elegant
        studies in vitro <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> suggested that the simple recruitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPII</ENAMEX> to transcription
        units was not sufficient for the copying of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and cotranscriptional processing of their
        transcripts. Rather, distinct steps could be defined, which began with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> of the
        preinitiation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PIC</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> clearance, pausing, and arrest, and ended with
        efficient elongation of transcription (reviewed in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]). The central component of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PIC</ENAMEX> is
        the general transcription factor (GTF) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TFIID</ENAMEX>, which contains the TATAbox- binding protein
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBP</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 to 15</NUMEX> TBP-associated factors (TAFs). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TFIID</ENAMEX> acts as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúlanding pad‚Äù</ENAMEX> for other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTFs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPII</ENAMEX> to nucleate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PIC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAFs</ENAMEX> serve as coactivators to a diverse
        set of activators. Both an ordered stepwise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and the recruitment of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100-plus</NUMEX>-subunit ‚Äúholoenzyme‚Äù have been proposed to be critical for the positioning of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPII</ENAMEX> at start sites of transcription.
        Next, the GTF TFIIH unwinds the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, opens the transcription bubble, and phosphorylates
        serines at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal domain (CTD) of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">RPB1</NUMEX> subunit of RNAPII
        (reviewed in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]). This phosphorylation is critical for the recruitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> that
        put a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-methylguanylate cap on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚</NUMEX>Ä≤ end of nascent transcripts. After the transcription
        complex clears the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>, the negative transcription elongation factor (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-TEF</ENAMEX>) is
        recruited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPIIa</ENAMEX> (reviewed in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]). It consists minimally of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,6</NUMEX>-
        dichloro-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-Œ≤-D-ribofuranosylbenzimidazole riboside (DRB)- sensitivity-inducing factor
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSIF</ENAMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>] and negative elongation factor (NELF) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. They bind and arrest RNAPII distal to
        the promoter cooperatively. Such arrested transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> have now been found on
        many inducible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in 
        Drosophila melanogaster (reviewed in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>].
        The transition to robust elongation depends on the positive transcription elongation
        factor b (P-TEFb) (reviewed in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> contains the cyclin-dependent kinase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CDK9</NUMEX>)
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> possible C-type cyclins. When recruited to stalled transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> phosphorylates serines at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTD</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>], the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Spt5</NUMEX> subunit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSIF</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>],
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX> subunit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NELF</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. These modifications result in heavily phosphorylated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPII</ENAMEX> (RNAPIIo), the recruitment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elongator</ENAMEX>, which contains splicing and
        polyadenylation machineries, and the conversions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSIF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NELF</ENAMEX> into elongation factors.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPIIo</ENAMEX> now copies the gene and directs the cotranscriptional processing, i.e., splicing
        and polyadenylation, of primary transcripts. Upon successful polyA addition, the CTD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphatase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FCP1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">dephosphorylates RNAPIIo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPIIa</ENAMEX> dissociates from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, and the
        transcription cycle starts all over again (reviewed in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> is unique among transcriptional activators in eukaryotic cells in that it functions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">via RNA</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter elements</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). It binds the transactivation response
        element (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAR</ENAMEX>) that forms a stable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> stem loop at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚</NUMEX>Ä≤ end of all viral transcripts.
        Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tat</ENAMEX> requires minimally the transcription of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TAR</ENAMEX> before it can stimulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        transcription from the long terminal repeat (LTR). Indeed, in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tat</ENAMEX>, RNAPIIa
        clears the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV LTR</ENAMEX> successfully but soon arrests, yielding predominantly short viral
        transcripts [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. Tat binds the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚</NUMEX>Ä≤ bulge in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TAR</ENAMEX> via its arginine-rich motif from positions
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49 to 57</TIMEX>, where a central arginine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">R52</NUMEX>) is key for this interaction. However, this binding
        is not sufficient for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tat</ENAMEX>'s function in vivo. Adjacent to the arginine-rich motif lie
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal core and cysteine-rich regions, which form the activation domain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        This activation domain binds cyclin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T1</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CycT1</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-TEFb</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> is CDK9 [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. As
        a consequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tat bind TAR cooperatively</ENAMEX>. The final proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> is the
        cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cofactor</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> came from studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> transcription in murine cells, where the
        introduction of the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CycT1 protein restores Tat</ENAMEX> function [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. The same effect can be
        achieved by substituting just the tyrosine with the cysteine at position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">261</TIMEX>, such as are
        found in murine and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CycT1 proteins</ENAMEX>, respectively [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tat and P-TEFb</ENAMEX> can also recruit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAF</ENAMEX>-independent transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV LTR</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>] (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Possibly, this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assembly</ENAMEX> reflects interactions between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CycT1</TIMEX> and the unphosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTD</ENAMEX> of RNAPIIa
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>].
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and disassembly of the complex between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEFb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TAR</ENAMEX> is a regulated
        process in vivo. Whereas the phosphorylation of CDK9 strengthens this complex [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>], the
        acetylation of the lysine at position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> in Tat weakens it [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. Upon this disruption,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acetylated Tat</ENAMEX> is liberated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> and recruits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p300</TIMEX>/CREB-binding protein‚Äì
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> factor (P-CAF) to the elongating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPIIo</ENAMEX>, most likely facilitating chromatin
        remodeling. In this issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology, Pagans et al.</ENAMEX> now demonstrate that acetylated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> is deacetylated by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SIRT1</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>] (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). In this way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> can reassemble with P-TEFb
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TAR</ENAMEX>.
        Clearly, P-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEFb</ENAMEX> plays a key role in the control of transcriptional elongation. Although
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> activator known that could recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> to initiating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPII</ENAMEX>,
        additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this group were soon identified. They include the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">androgen</ENAMEX> receptor,
        c-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myc</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> II transactivator (CIITA), myoblast determination <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MyoD</ENAMEX>), and
        nuclear factor Œ∫-B (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-Œ∫B</ENAMEX>). The last one is of great interest as it explains how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome</ENAMEX> can be transcribed before the synthesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tat</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> triggers
        the nuclear translocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-Œ∫B</ENAMEX>, where it binds the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV enhancer</ENAMEX>, leading to the
        stimulation of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transcription</ENAMEX>. It is not surprising that proviral latency, in which
        low levels of transcription or only short <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transcripts</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TAR</ENAMEX> are observed,
        would in large part reflect the absence of these activators. Indeed, in many of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">latently</ENAMEX> infected cells, the induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-Œ∫B</ENAMEX> or the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tat</ENAMEX> leads to the
        reactivation of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replication</ENAMEX> and spreading of the infection [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,21</NUMEX>].
        Recently, important aspects of the regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> have been revealed (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        Of interest, P-TEFb exists in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> in cells [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22,23</NUMEX>]. The larger measures
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500</TIMEX> kDa and contains the hexamethylene bisacetamide (HMBA)‚Äìinduced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> 1
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">HEXIM1</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7SK</NUMEX> small nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (snRNA) in addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,25</NUMEX>]. In this large
        complex, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cdk9</ENAMEX> is enzymatically inactive. HEXIM1 was identified as the inducible gene
        following the exposure of vascular smooth muscle cells to a potent differentiating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMBA</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]. 7SK <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snRNA</ENAMEX> is one of the most abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snRNA species</ENAMEX>, whose function remained a
        mystery for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a decade</TIMEX>. Of interest, targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HEXIM1 and 7SK</TIMEX> snRNA
        contributes significantly to the control of cell growth and differentiation. For example,
        growth signals liberate P-TEFb from the large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac</ENAMEX> hypertrophy
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, a disease characterized by the enlargement of myocytes due to a global increase in
        mRNA synthesis [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. Also, following stress, ultraviolet light, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of
        actinomycin <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRB</ENAMEX> to cells, the large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is converted to the small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> to
        stimulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">transcription</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22,23</NUMEX>].
        How central is P-TEFb to eukaryotic transcription? In 
        Saccharomyces cerevisiae , there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEFb</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CTDK-1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Bur1/2</NUMEX>. CTDK1-negative but not <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bur1/Bur2</ENAMEX>-negative yeasts still grow, albeit
        poorly and only on rich media (reviewed in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]). In 
        Caenorhabditis elegans , genetic inactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CDK9</ENAMEX> or CycT1
        and CycT2 resulted in the inhibition of all RNAPII transcription [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. Moreover, in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> melanogaster , following heat shock, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEFb</ENAMEX> is recruited
        upstream of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. Although no murine knockouts of subunits of P-TEFb
        have been reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRB</ENAMEX> and flavopiridol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> analogs that inhibit the kinase activity
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CDK9</TIMEX>, can inhibit nearly all transcription by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPII</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. Indeed, as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> is a coactivator of potent activators that mediate effects of enhancers and can
        itself activate transcription when placed on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> distal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter elements</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>], it
        might mediate many more signaling events than those of heat shock, ultraviolet light,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, and hypertrophy. Conversely, the inhibition of P-TEFb could explain the mode of
        action of some transcriptional repressors. Indeed, the global transcriptional repressor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PIE-1</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of embryogenesis in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> elegans , binds the histidine-rich stretch in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CycT1</TIMEX>, thus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decoying</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAPII</ENAMEX> and blocking the elongation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transcription</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>].
        These are exciting findings and suggest a plethora of future experiments, including the
        genetic inactivation of subunits of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> and isoforms of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEXIM1</ENAMEX> in the mouse. Of special
        interest are questions as to where to place this mechanism of transcriptional regulation in
        the hierarchy of competing or complementary processes. What roles do different P-TEFb
        complexes play in the transcription of specific genes? How central will the regulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>-TEFb be to cellular growth, proliferation, and differentiation, and what roles will it
        play in normal development and disease <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>? As to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>, how can we use our knowledge of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P-TEFb</ENAMEX> to slow down viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replication</ENAMEX> and/or to eliminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of proviral latency in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>? Obviously, we are only at the beginning of this journey, which promises to change
        radically our view of eukaryotic transcription.
      
    
  
