
  
    
      
        
        As the premier biological electron acceptor, molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) serves a vital role in fundamental cellular functions, including the
        process of aerobic respiration. Nevertheless, with the beneficial properties of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> comes the inadvertent formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX>, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superoxide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        ‚àí
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydrogen peroxide</ENAMEX> (H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ), and hydroxyl radical <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">(‚Ä¢OH</ENAMEX>); these differ from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> additional electrons, respectively
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Cells also encounter elevated levels of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX> when they
        are released by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> as a defense against detrimental organisms
        such as microbial pathogens. Reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen species</ENAMEX> can damage cells in many ways: by
        inactivating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, damaging nucleic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, and altering the fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> of lipids,
        which leads in turn to perturbations in membrane structure and function. The accumulation
        of this oxidative damage underlies the formation of many disease <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. It is
        postulated that tissue injury by these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX> accumulates over a long
        period of time and plays roles in the aging process and the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, chronic inflammatory diseases, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and several neurodegenerative diseases
        (Halliwell <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> have evolved strategies to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX> and repair
        damage, which have enabled them to prosper from the tremendous oxidizing potential of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> without succumbing to oxidative damage. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacteria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX>, and mammalian
        cells all induce the synthesis of global regulatory responses to survive oxidative insults.
        The consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">oxidative stress</ENAMEX> and the corresponding defense responses have been
        extensively studied in 
        Escherichia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coli</ENAMEX> . For ease of study in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>, the
        stress responses are often provoked by the external addition of chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxidants</ENAMEX> that
        specifically elevate the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX> within cells, or by the use of
        mutant strains that disrupt the normal ‚Äúhomeostatic mechanisms‚Äù for removing reactive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">oxygen species</ENAMEX> or the damage they do. While this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">primer</ENAMEX> focuses on a particular set of
        protective and regulatory protein modifications induced by oxidative stress in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> , it should be noted that many of the same mechanisms
        are present in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>; some specific examples from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> will also be
        described.
        The major target of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        ‚àí damage identified in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> is a class of dehydratase enzymes that
        utilize [<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4Fe‚Äì4S</ENAMEX>] clusters to bind their substrate (Imlay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Djaman et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). Since
        some of these enzymes function in the citric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> cycle (also called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krebs</ENAMEX> cycle) and
        in amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid biosynthesis</ENAMEX>, high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        ‚àí lead to a requirement for certain amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> in growth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> (Imlay
        and is well known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fridovich 1991).</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for its role in oxidizing thiol (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SH</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of cysteinyl amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>. Elevated levels of H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> also are associated with the oxidation of other amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, leading
        to the formation of methionine sulfoxide and a variety of carbonyls. Lastly, because of its
        extreme reactivity, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Ä¢OH</ENAMEX> targets all of the major macromolecules of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, and lipids. The extent to which membrane lipids are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> appears to depend on
        the presence of polyunsaturated fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> in lipids, which are not as prevalent in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> as they are in mammals.
        Many enzymes that protect against oxidative damage have been identified in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> (Imlay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002, 2003</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> superoxide dismutases, each of
        which contain a different metal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and show different expression patterns and
        subcellular localization, catalyze the dismutation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚àí</ENAMEX> to H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . While the superoxide dismutases eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        ‚àí , they also are a source of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endogenously</ENAMEX> produced H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> . The major enzymes involved in reducing H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> are catalase and alkyl hydroperoxide reductase. There is
        no enzymatic mechanism for decreasing levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Ä¢OH</ENAMEX>, produced from H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . Thus, levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Ä¢OH</ENAMEX> will be directly proportional to levels of H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , and accordingly, catalase and alkyl hydroperoxide reductase
        activities are critical to oxidative stress survival.
        Another component to the oxidative stress response is the reduction of oxidized thiols
        that arises through one of the mechanisms described below. The tripeptide glutathione and
        the thiol reductants glutaredoxin and thioredoxin are key to the restoration of thiols to
        their reduced state (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SH</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernandes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmgren 2004).</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> glutaredoxins that utilize the reducing
        power of glutathione to catalyze the reduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disulfide bonds (‚ÄìS‚ÄìS‚Äì</ENAMEX>) in the presence
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> and glutathione reductase. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> thioredoxins in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> that also function to reduce disulfide bonds. Reduced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thioredoxin</ENAMEX> is regenerated by thioredoxin reductase and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX>. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> is
        required to maintain the reduced state of glutathione and thioredoxin indicates that the
        response to oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> is coupled to the physiological status of core pathways that
        generate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Roles of Thiol Modifications</ENAMEX>
        As mentioned above, proteins‚Äîin particular, the thiols of cysteines‚Äîare the major
        targets of H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . The reaction of cysteinyl thiolates with H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> can lead to the formation of different modifications, such as sulfenic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid (‚ÄìSOH</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfinic acid (‚</ENAMEX>ÄìSO
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfonic acid (‚ÄìSO3H</ENAMEX>), as well as disulfide bond formation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">(‚ÄìS‚ÄìS‚Äì</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">glutathione conjugation (‚ÄìS‚ÄìGSH</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jacob et al. 2004; Poole et al. 2004</ENAMEX>) (Figure
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). These modifications often alter the structure and function of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. Recent
        progress in this field points to a common chemistry in the reaction of H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> with thiolates through the initial formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfenic acid</ENAMEX>. In the
        case of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that have a nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cysteinyl residue</ENAMEX>, a disulfide bond forms between the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sulfur atoms. The sulfenated cysteinyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> also can react with a cysteinyl residue
        on another <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> or with glutathione, leading to a mixed disulfide. If no cysteinyl
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residue</ENAMEX> is nearby, the sulfenated cysteine can be further oxidized to sulfinic or sulfonic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, or it can remain in the sulfenic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. All but the sulfinic and sulfonic acid
        modifications are readily reversible by reduction, using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> such as thioredoxin or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glutaredoxin</ENAMEX>; though sulfinic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> reductase activities have recently been identified in
        yeast and mammalian cells (denoted sulfiredoxin and sestrin, respectively) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biteau et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budanov et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        Given the reversible nature of most forms of thiol oxidation, it has been suggested that
        thiol modifications can play roles in signal transduction that are similar to protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">phosphorylation/dephosphorylation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sitia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molteni 2004).</ENAMEX> In support of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, there
        are several examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> whose activities are modulated by thiol oxidation and
        reduction.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of these examples is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyR</ENAMEX> transcription factor, which upregulates peroxide
        defenses in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> and a variety of other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">OxyR</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX>
        critical cysteines that are oxidized to form an intramolecular disulfide bond when cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">encounter peroxide stress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zheng et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aslund et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). Disulfide bond formation
        is associated with a conformational change that alters OxyR binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and allows the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> to activate the transcription of genes encoding enzymes, such as catalase and the
        alkylhydroperoxide reductase, that destroy H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . Once the H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration is decreased, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyR</ENAMEX> is reduced and the system is reset.
        The unusually reactive cysteine in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">OxyR</ENAMEX> that is oxidized by H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to form the sulfenic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid intermediate</ENAMEX> can clearly be nitrosylated and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glutathionylated</ENAMEX> in vitro (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hausladen et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim et al. 2002)</ENAMEX>, but the in vivo
        relevance of these other modifications is questionable (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mukhopadhyay et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other examples of redox-regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli chaperone protein Hsp33</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakob et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>) and the 
        Streptomyces coelicolor anti-sigma factor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RsrA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Li et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paget</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Buttner</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bae et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). For these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, the cysteine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>, which
        form intramolecular disulfide bonds, are in a reduced state when coordinated to a zinc ion
        (Zn
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc</ENAMEX> is released upon oxidation of the thiols. For both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>, oxidation and zinc release are associated with an opening of the protein
        structure. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Hsp33</TIMEX>, this structural change allows for dimerization and activates its
        chaperone activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graf et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). RsrA, on the other hand, dissociates from a promoter
        specificity factor of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an extracytoplasmic</NUMEX>-function-type alternative sigma
        factor) allowing the transcription of genes that permit recovery from the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Li et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bae et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). Among the target gene products is a thioredoxin, which reduces the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disulfide</ENAMEX> bonds that form within oxidized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RsrA</ENAMEX>. Presumably, reduction of the disulfide
        restores the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc</ENAMEX> and its inhibitory association with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sigma factor</ENAMEX>. Thus,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RsrA</ENAMEX> regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circuit</ENAMEX> provides another example, comparable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OxyR</ENAMEX>, in which the
        modification of a regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> thiol <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> can be linked to a change in the
        transcriptional output of genes that remediate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>.
        The peroxide-sensing repressor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OhrR</ENAMEX> from 
        Xanthomonas campestris pv. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phaseoli</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panmanee et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>) and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus subtilus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuangthong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmann 2002)</ENAMEX> can be
        inactivated by H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or by organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxides</ENAMEX> (ROOH) formed by the oxidation of a variety of
        organic molecules in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> or in the environment. The 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. subtilis OhrR</ENAMEX> transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">regulator</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a single</NUMEX>
        cysteine that forms a relatively stable sulfenic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> upon its reaction with H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxides</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuangthong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmann 2002).</ENAMEX> Oxidation of the
        single cysteine leads to the dissociation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OhrR</ENAMEX> from its DNA binding site and the
        derepression of the gene encoding an organic hydroperoxidase that eliminates the initial
        oxidizing insult.
        In this issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hondorp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) provide an example of a thiol modification
        that protects an enzyme activity during oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>. Their data suggest that when
        cells encounter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oxidative</ENAMEX> stress, a key cysteinyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> near the active site of
        methionine synthase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MetE</ENAMEX>) is glutathionylated. This modification blocks access of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substrate</ENAMEX> and prevents further synthesis of methionine. This finding is significant in that
        it presents a mechanism to reversibly preserve the function of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> during oxidative
        challenge. By glutathionylating a single cysteinyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is protected from
        further oxidation of that cysteinyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> to the irreversible sulfinic and sulfonic acid
        forms. Once the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> is removed, the mixed disulfide bond will be readily reduced, and
        access to the substrate restored.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevalence of Regulatory Thiol Modifications</ENAMEX>?
        As illustrated by the examples above, an array of chemical modifications obtained by
        oxidizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cysteinyl residues</ENAMEX> has been exploited in combating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">oxidative stress</ENAMEX>. Yet it is
        important to note that not all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cysteinyl residues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are readily oxidized by
        oxidants such as H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . We do not currently understand all of the features that determine
        the reactivity of a particular thiol to H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poole et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). The pKa of the thiolates clearly plays an
        important role, as thiolates are more reactive than their protonated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. In
        addition, the contribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> environment to the stability of the oxidized products
        is also known to be a factor, but is not well understood. Given that many of the thiol
        modifications do not appear to be in equilibrium with the redox state of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, the
        features of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that determine the rate at which the modifications are formed are
        another important parameter.
        The added complexity of the cysteine targets that compose part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zn</ENAMEX> binding site
        found for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Hsp33</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RsrA</ENAMEX> raises questions about the function of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc</ENAMEX>. Perhaps Zn
        binding provides some additional control over the reactivity of the cysteine thiols, or
        perhaps the loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc</ENAMEX> facilitates conformational changes. Recently, the oxidative,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">stress-induced thioredoxin-2</ENAMEX> from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> has also been shown to contain a H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -labile <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc</ENAMEX> site, although the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc</ENAMEX> does not change its
        reductase activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collet et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). Thus, the way this oxidatively labile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zn</ENAMEX> site
        affects thioredoxin function has yet to be established.
        The extent of thiol oxidation within the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> remains another open question. The variety
        of modifications that arise from treatment with H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and the experimental challenges associated with their detection has
        made it difficult to catalog all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that are modified and all the types of
        modifications that exist. In this issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leichert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jakob</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) report a general method
        for detecting cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> whose cysteinyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> were modified after imposing an
        oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>. Such an approach will greatly enhance our understanding of targets of
        oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>. The method described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leichert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakob</ENAMEX> also will be useful in
        detecting transient <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cysteine</ENAMEX> modifications.
        The importance of monitoring transient changes in cysteines is highlighted by the recent
        finding that oxidation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Yap1</NUMEX> activator of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antioxidant genes</ENAMEX> in the yeast 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Saccharomyces cerevisiae</ENAMEX> requires a peroxidase denoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gpx3</ENAMEX> or
        Orp1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaunay et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). In this case, H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> reacts with a cysteine in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Orp1</TIMEX>, forming an unstable sulfenic acid
        intermediate that then reacts with a cysteinyl residue of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Yap1</NUMEX> to form an intermolecular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disulfide</ENAMEX>. The disulfide undergoes an exchange with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> cysteine within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yap1</TIMEX> to form
        an intramolecular disulfide that locks Yap1 in a confirmation that masks the nuclear export
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wood et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). Thus, methods that allow the appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">thiol</ENAMEX> modifications
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> to be monitored kinetically will greatly enhance our understanding of how cysteine
        residues become oxidized.
        The examples mentioned here illustrate the versatile potential of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">thiol</ENAMEX> modifications.
        Given the reversibility of thiol oxidations and the wide range of structural constraints
        that can be imposed by the formation of a sulfenic or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfinic acid</ENAMEX> or a disulfide bond, we
        predict there will be many more examples of regulation by thiol modification.
      
    
  
