
  
    
      
        
        Recently 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> published our paper entitled ‚ÄúDesigning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equitable</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiretroviral Allocation Strategies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource-Constrained Countries‚Äù</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. We were
        disappointed to find that the editorial perspective written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> (WHO) ethicists regarding our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] was based upon a substantial
        misunderstanding of our novel quantitative analyses and our important results. Hence, they
        misunderstood the significance of the health-policy implications of our results. Thus, we
        wish to correct the record.
        Firstly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reis</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] misunderstood our quantitative analyses. They stated that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúWilson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blower</ENAMEX> developed a mathematical model that could inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX>'
        decisions regarding the optimal distribution of treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> to ensure equal access by
        all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>.‚Äù However, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> does not determine the optimal
        distribution of treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. As we clearly state in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] (and is also stated
        in the synopsis [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]), we developed a model that policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> can use to make decisions
        regarding how to achieve the optimal allocation of scarce antiretrovirals among the
        available health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> (HCFs) if the objective is to ensure treatment equity. We
        also calculated how the optimal allocation of antiretrovirals would vary if the number of
        HCFs utilized increased and/or the size of the catchment area that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCF</ENAMEX> services
        increased [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Thus, we took the treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFs</ENAMEX>) as given, and we used their
        specific spatial location in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> as inputs to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> in order to determine
        optimal antiretroviral allocation strategies under a variety of conditions.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reis</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] misunderstood our important results. They stated that
        ‚Äúapplying this tool to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KwaZulu‚ÄìNatal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blower</ENAMEX> were
        able to confirm mathematically the intuitive assumption that using a maximum number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>, at the least possible distance from most affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, would lead to the
        greatest fairness in the geographical distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ART</ENAMEX> [antiretroviral therapy].‚Äù We
        agree that if these had been our results, they would have been trivial and obvious.
        However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reis</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] did not discuss our actual results: we determined how to
        decide how many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to allocate to each of the available <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HCFs</ENAMEX> in order to achieve an
        optimal allocation if the objective is to ensure treatment equity. This is a very complex
        problem and the antiretroviral allocation strategies that we calculated (by using our
        model) to be optimal are very complex (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, which graphically shows
        the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that should be allocated to each of the available HCFs).
        Furthermore, we also determined what catchment area each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCF</ENAMEX> should service; specifically,
        we calculated that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCF</ENAMEX> should serve (if the objective is to achieve treatment equity)
        a catchment area of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40‚Äì60 km.</NUMEX> Thus, our results demonstrate (to our knowledge for the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> will have to travel extremely large distances (i.e.,
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-‚Äì60 km</NUMEX>) in order to receive antiretrovirals, if the objective is to achieve treatment
        equity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. We stress that currently it is unknown what the actual size of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">catchment</ENAMEX> area is around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. Catchment areas may in fact be very small.
        Thus, we suggested [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] that a primary goal should be to obtain empirical data of the
        distances that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> are willing (or able) to travel in order to receive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiretrovirals</ENAMEX>. We have been the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to provide a quantitative assessment of the
        necessary size of the catchment area, and our results have identified that there is an
        urgent need to collect these critical data for quantifying the size of the catchment areas
        around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFs</ENAMEX>. We have determined that the size of the catchment area will be a critical
        component in the ability to achieve treatment equity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. We also compared the
        optimal antiretroviral allocation strategies that we calculated with the current plan of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for allocating antiretrovirals [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>], and we determined that the
        current antiretroviral allocation strategies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> will not achieve treatment
        equity. Taken together, our quantitative results are novel and controversial, providing
        important quantitative insights into a complex public-health problem.
        We applaud the ambitious ‚<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Äú3 by 5‚Äù</NUMEX> WHO target for the antiretroviral rollout. However,
        the WHO has not yet devised a quantitative policy for determining how to allocate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiretrovirals</ENAMEX> in situations where the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> greatly exceeds the supply [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        Health-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will have to make these important and difficult
        decisions, and they will all make different decisions based upon what objectives they wish
        to optimize and prioritize. There are a multitude of factors to consider (these factors are
        well described in the recent 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Medicine</ENAMEX> report [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]). We stress that the alternative to a
        quantitative rational approach for allocating scarce resources is an ad hoc approach, which
        is how the scarce supply of antiretrovirals is currently being distributed in many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX>-constrained <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Our operations research modeling approach is based upon
        spatial heterogeneity in the distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> and the spatial
        heterogeneity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-infected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The most important ‚Äúreal world‚Äù result is
        that we show that what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is currently doing is inequitable. We
        show them how to achieve equity, if they wish to do so. We hope that our novel approach for
        deciding how to allocate antiretrovirals will be of use to the WHO and also to the relevant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in the many resource-constrained <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> who will soon have to make very
        difficult decisions as to who lives and who dies. Our analysis is to our knowledge the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> analysis to show how a rational and scientific solution can be reached for deciding
        how to allocate a limited amount of antiretrovirals, if the goal is to achieve treatment
        equity. Clearly, other goals must be taken into consideration (and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> can be
        modified to include these other goals); however, we hope that treatment equity will be a
        very high priority during the antiretroviral rollout that is just beginning.
      
    
  
