
  
    
      
        
        The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> that animal research is irrelevant for human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> are those who don't understand it or those who benefit from it. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>,
        clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>, and former animal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>, I know that though they are our closest
        genetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primates</ENAMEX> have failed as research models virtually whenever they have
        been used.
        As a partial list of failures, allow me to submit the notorious forced smoking
        experiments, which allowed cigarettes to be promoted widely for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>; the abject failure
        of a quarter-century of primate research on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> to provide any useful insights; the false
        leads and dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> produced during <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> research (verified by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Sabin</ENAMEX>,
        himself); the failure of primate studies to improve risks for birth defects and premature
        births; and the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> studies to identify nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug
        cardiovascular risk [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>].
        The 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> state in hopeful language that the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lassa fever</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> was successful in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>, and, thus, is a suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for human study [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>].
        Recall that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">VaxGen's AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> (AIDSVAX) showed great success in primate studies, but
        was an abject failure in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> human clinical trials, including a trial of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 2,500</NUMEX>
        injection <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>] and a multinational trial of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 5,000</NUMEX> high-risk
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>].
        Consider the fruitless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>-long effort to produce an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> in primates, the
        failure to produce even a single case of human <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in any primate studied, or the failure
        to identify even one useful <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> from primate studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetic</ENAMEX> and physiological
        imperatives dictate that no animal model, even higher primates, gives information
        applicable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Genome Project</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>] tells us that there is sufficient
        genetic diversity among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> that pharmacogenetic and pharmacogenomic techniques will
        have an increasing role in overcoming problems related to polymorphisms and other
        variations. We can't even apply scientific findings uniformly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> is now promoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> research?
        I am very disappointed that 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> has regressed to reporting animal research. It is
        discouraging that in this era of rapid biomedical advancement, and appropriate relegation
        of animal research to the historical dustbin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> has chosen to re-introduce an
        anachronistic, medically discredited, and unethical research tool to its reporting.
      
    
  
