
  
    
      
        
        Tyrosine kinases regulate signaling pathways that control cell growth, proliferation,
        motility, and other critical cellular processes. Mutations in tyrosine kinase genes can
        lead to abnormal kinase activity, and some tumors become dependent upon this activity for
        growth and survival. Thus, kinases are attractive targets for anti-cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Examples
        of new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase inhibitors</ENAMEX> include gefitinib and erlotinib, which have recently shown promise
        in treating non-small-cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, gefitinib and erlotinib work only in
        a subset of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and they can have severe side effects, albeit infrequently. So
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have been trying to find ways to predict who will benefit from therapy with
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and who won't.
        Following the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch et al.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N Engl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Med 350</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2129–2139</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paez et</ENAMEX> al.
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science 304</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1497–1500</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Pao</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have previously shown that the
        epidermal growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor receptor</ENAMEX> (EGFR), a tyrosine kinase, is often mutated in
        non-small-cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, and that tumors that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> such mutations are sensitive to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gefitinib</ENAMEX> and erlotinib.
        In this new study, they focused on a signaling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRAS</ENAMEX>, which functions
        downstream of many tyrosine kinases, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRAS</ENAMEX> gene is also often mutated in
        lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, but very few <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> have mutations in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRAS</ENAMEX> gene. To find
        out whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRAS</ENAMEX> mutations could help to predict which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> would respond to gefitinib
        or erlotinib, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> looked for mutations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KRAS genes</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> tumors for
        which sensitivity to either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> was known.
        They extended their earlier findings that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> mutations (which were found in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tumors</ENAMEX>) were associated with sensitivity to the kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, and found that tumors
        that had mutations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRAS</ENAMEX> (a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>) were refractory (i.e., did not respond) to
        either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>.
        These results need to be validated in larger and prospective trials that use
        standardized mutation detection techniques. If they are confirmed, knowing the mutation
        status of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRAS</ENAMEX> in tumors could help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> decide which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> should
        receive gefitinib and/or erlotinib. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inoue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nukiwa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspective</ENAMEX> that
        accompanies the article, “By combining all the factors that relate to response or
        resistance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who will benefit from treatment can hopefully be identified.
        Undoubtedly we have taken a great step forward in molecular therapy for lung cancer
        treatment.”
      
    
  
