
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Coronary heart disease</ENAMEX> (CHD) is the leading cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and mortality in
        developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and identifying and treating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> has an
        essential role in the prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>. Therapeutic lifestyle changes are important for
        general reduction of risk overall, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who are more likely to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>, or who
        have high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>, should be treated with statins. Statins inhibit HMG-CoA reductase‚Äîa
        key enzyme in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol synthesis pathway</ENAMEX>.
        Although we know that not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who may benefit from statins receive treatment,
        there is limited information on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are treated according to their estimated risk
        of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> may be classified as at low, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, or high risk of developing
        CHD according to the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>, some other medical conditions (for example,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>), and major risk factors including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> level, smoking, lifestyle, and
        family history. Jun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> analyzed data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Ambulatory Medical</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Survey</ENAMEX> and the outpatient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> component of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Ambulatory</ENAMEX>
        Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Survey</ENAMEX> to identify changes in treatment from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 to 2002</TIMEX>, and to identify
        current clinical practice. These surveys have been validated against other data sources,
        and used in past research on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> management.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> found that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1993 and 2002</TIMEX> the use of statins increased nearly
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-fold, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9% to 49%</NUMEX>, in ambulatory visits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>, but then
        declined to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Overall, the use of statins was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times more likely in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
        and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> at high risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> were more likely to use
        statins than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. However, among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> whose visit had a reported high
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 50%</NUMEX> of patient visits at high risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44%</NUMEX> of those at moderate
        risk were prescribed statins in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, well below the recommendations of current guidelines.
        Less than half the patient visits that arguably represent optimal opportunities for
        counseling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> received counseling about how they might change their lifestyle. The
        study also showed inequities in use of statins for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with different social and
        clinical characteristics, with lower usage in younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> cared for by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who are not cardiologists.
        As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> declare, the study was funded by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the statins, but the
        information acquired is of general interest. Persistent gaps in statin therapy suggest a
        need for improved identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who may develop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>, and treatment with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statins</ENAMEX> when indicated, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> say. A particular focus should be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who are at
        risk of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> should be aimed at improving the practice of
        physicians‚Äîabove all, those who are not heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">specialists‚</ENAMEX>Äîso that they adhere to
        evidence-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and published guidelines for cardiovascular risk reduction. In an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accompanying Perspective</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">DOI: 10.1371/journal</TIMEX>.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pmed.0020131</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiona Turnbull</ENAMEX> from the
        making treatment decisions based on single risk factors and instead use an approach based
        on absolute risk. ‚ÄúAn understanding of the concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äòabsolute risk‚Äô‚Äîthe</ENAMEX> probability of a
        patient developing a cardiovascular event over a specified time period‚Äîis crucial,‚Äù she
        says.
      
    
  
