
  
    
      
        
        What is the level of medical evidence that should be used to inform medical practice? At
        the bottom of the hierarchy of evidence are anecdotes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> opinion, case reports, and
        case series, and at the top is the systematic review of published (and sometimes
        unpublished) evidence. By necessity, systematic reviews come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> after hypotheses
        are first raised, and in the interim recommendations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> may sway back and forth.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example of this is the debate over the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> in heart disease, which has
        been going on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 50 years</TIMEX>. It started with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX> in the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annals of Internal Medicine</ENAMEX> that found higher serum uric acid
        concentrations in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">coronary heart disease</ENAMEX> (CHD) compared with controls. Since
        then, measurement of serum <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> has been suggested as a predictor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>. But many of
        the studies on serum <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> are epidemiologic studiesâ€”somewhere in the middle of the
        hierarchy of evidenceâ€”and have come to different conclusions about how useful measurement
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> is.
        Dissecting out the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> is further complicated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things: high levels
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> are associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> and being overweight (other risk factors for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>); levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> can be altered by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> such as diuretics that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with CHD
        often take; and finally, alteration of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal function</ENAMEX> can affect uric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> levels. Another
        problem is the type of studies that have been used to address the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX>'s
        role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>. Retrospective studies may be unable to control adequately for other risk
        factorsâ€”hence prospective, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideally population</ENAMEX>-based, studies would be the best to answer
        the question of whether there really is an association between high uric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Danesh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Icelandic Heart Association</ENAMEX>, report the single
        largest prospective study addressing the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> in heart disease. Further, their
        systematic review combines their findings with those of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> previously published prospective
        studies of serum uric acidâ<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">€”9,458</NUMEX> cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155,084</NUMEX> controls in all.
        The paper answers the question of the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> in prediction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> clearly:
        the risk ratio for prediction of disease was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.13</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.07â€“1.20</NUMEX>), but it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1.02</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.91â€“1.14</NUMEX>) in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> studies that had the most complete adjustment for possible
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confounders</ENAMEX>. What this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> does not do is directly address the question of whether or not
        serum <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> is involved in causing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> through intermediates; however, it does suggest
        that serum <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> levels are unlikely to be a major determinant of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>.
        Where does such a result leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>? Well, it is likely that improving diet, losing
        weight, and controlling blood pressure may all contribute to reducing both one's risk of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> and one's serum levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX>. The role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uric acid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> is now likely to be
        of interest only to those studying basic science; for now, the clinical question seems
        closed.
      
    
  
