
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Smith</ENAMEX>'s key suggestion [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] is that medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> “should stop publishing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trials”</ENAMEX> and concentrate on “critically evaluating them.” This bold and radical suggestion
        deserves wide debate. It's obvious that many medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are losing relevance as
        vehicles for scientific information, but it's unclear what will save them. Even as journals
        strive to better enforce their conflicts-of-interest disclosure rules, drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will
        strive to find or create other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication outlets</ENAMEX> that can communicate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>
        precisely what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> wish to communicate. In sum, an unanticipated effect of purging
        clinical trial reports from medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> might be an even larger proliferation of frank
        advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> and messages that might more effectively catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' attentions.
      
    
  
