
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatz</ENAMEX>'s statement, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">“At least half</NUMEX> of the explanation for individual differences in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">susceptibility</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> is genetic” [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>], is, in my opinion, incorrect. As the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who led the team debating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortimer</ENAMEX>, whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> article [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] supports this
        statement, at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> conference on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> (“Challenging
        Views of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's Disease”</ENAMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], I think that the evidence that dietary and lifestyle
        factors explain the majority of the individual risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is very strong. My
        original paper in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>] found that total dietary fat and energy intake were the most
        important dietary risk factors, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal intake</ENAMEX> were the most important risk
        reduction factors. These findings have been generally confirmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drs. Luchsinger</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> and others. The reason I did my study was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honolulu Heart Study</ENAMEX> reported
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> times the risk of AD of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Japanese</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> times the risk of AD of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native Nigerians</ENAMEX>. If genetics
        were the primary risk factor, those living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> would have a risk of developing AD
        very similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> living in their ancestral home. The reason this is not
        the case is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> diet provides too much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, which is a particular problem
        for those genetically predisposed to AD.
      
    
  
