
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dietary</ENAMEX> and lifestyle changes during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX> have entailed an unprecedented
        epidemic of obesity and associated metabolic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, including type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">atherosclerosis</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> suffer simultaneously from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> of these
        conditions, and epidemiological studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, as well as studies in animal models,
        suggest that obesity-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> is a common pathogenic feature [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Indeed,
        insulin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> is the keystone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúmetabolic syndrome</ENAMEX>,‚Äù a major cardiovascular risk
        factor even in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">demonstrable glucose intolerance</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obesity</ENAMEX> and
        insulin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> are strongly associated with systemic markers of inflammation, and,
        indeed, inflammation may contribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Similarities</ENAMEX> and overlap
        between obesity and inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are emerging. Inflammatory cytokines such as tumor
        necrosis <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor Œ±</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF Œ±</ENAMEX>) and interleukin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> are produced by adipocytes as well as by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytes</ENAMEX> and macrophages, and they circulate at increased levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obesity</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,6</NUMEX>]. Moreover, bone-marrow-derived macrophages <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in on adipose tissue in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with obesity [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,8</NUMEX>], and adipocytes and macrophages may even be interconvertible
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. Furthermore, inflammation is increasingly recognized as a major component and
        predictor of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">atherosclerotic vascular disease</ENAMEX>, a major clinical consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        resistance [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. Hence, the interrelationships between obesity, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance, and
        atherosclerosis are of great scientific and clinical interest.
        We originally identified and characterized resistin as a circulating mouse adipocyte
        gene product that is regulated by antidiabetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>, resistin is derived
        exclusively from adipocytes [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,12</NUMEX>], circulates at increased levels in obese <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>],
        and causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dysregulated hepatic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> production, leading to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,14</NUMEX>].
        A syntenic gene exists in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, but is expressed at higher levels in monocytes and
        macrophages than in adipocytes [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,16</NUMEX>], raising questions about the relationship between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resistin</ENAMEX> and human metabolic disease. Recently, several studies have suggested that
        metabolic abnormalities are associated with polymorphisms in the human resistin gene
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,18</NUMEX>]. Furthermore, several studies, though not all, have reported increased serum
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resistin</ENAMEX> levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with obesity, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance, and/or type 2 diabetes
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,20,21,22,23,24,25,26</NUMEX>]. However, the mechanism and importance of increased resistin
        levels in human metabolic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> are not known.
        Here we show that the endotoxin lipopolysaccharide (LPS), a potent inflammatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulant</ENAMEX>, dramatically increases resistin production by inducing secretion of inflammatory
        cytokines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX>. This increase in resistin production is blocked by both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX> and
        rosiglitazone, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that have dual anti-inflammatory and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-sensitizing actions and
        have been shown to antagonize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-Œ∫B.</ENAMEX> Indeed, activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Œ∫B is sufficient to induce
        resistin expression, and loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">NF-Œ∫B function abolishes</ENAMEX> LPS induction of resistin.
        Resistin serum levels are increased dramatically by endotoxemia in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, and correlate
        with a marker of inflammation in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. Thus, systemic inflammation
        leads to increased resistin production and circulating levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. The increased
        level of resistin in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with obesity is likely an indirect result of elevated levels of
        inflammatory cytokines characteristic of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of increased adiposity. Hence, obesity and
        acute inflammation are both hyperresistinemic states associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        resistance.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Differentiation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primary Human</ENAMEX> Macrophages
          following apheresis and elutriation. Greater than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monocytes</ENAMEX> expressed CD14
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DR. Cells</ENAMEX> were plated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well plates at a density of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> cells per well, allowed to adhere for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 h</TIMEX>, then washed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco's Modified Eagles Medium</ENAMEX> and further cultured in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s Modified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eagles Medium</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>) to promote macrophage differentiation. All experiments were performed after
          overnight equilibration with macrophage serum-free medium (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIBCO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States; Invitrogen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX>. Cells were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SN50</TIMEX>, and/or control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biomol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth Meeting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MG132</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PD98059</TIMEX>, SB20358
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calbiochem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). Neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, and
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1Œ≤</ENAMEX>, as well as control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX>, were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>. Adenovirus
          expressing activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IKK</ENAMEX> in pAD easy with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> and control vector was a generous gift from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Shoelson</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA Isolation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantification</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was isolated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNeasy Mini Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valencia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>),
          then subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> digestion followed by reverse transcription (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). mRNA
          transcripts were quantified by the dual-labeled fluorogenic probe method for real-time
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>, using a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Prism 7900</TIMEX> thermal cycler and sequence detector (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosystems, Foster</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real-time PCR</ENAMEX> was performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taqman Universal</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Polymerase Master Mix</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosystems</ENAMEX>). The primers and probes used in the real-time
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> were the following: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sense-Resistin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5‚Ä≤- AGCCATCAATGATAGGATCCA-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antisense-Resistin</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5‚Ä≤- TCCAGGCCAATGCTGCTTAT-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resistin Probe</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚</NUMEX>Ä≤-Fam-
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AGGTCGCCGGCTCCCTAATATTTAGGG-TAMRA-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>; Sense human 36B4 sense, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚</NUMEX>Ä≤-
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCGTGGAAGTGACATCGTCTTT-3‚Ä≤; Antisense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">36B4</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5‚Ä≤- CTGTCTTCCCTGGGCATCA-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">36B4 Probe</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5‚Ä≤-FAM- TGGCAATCCCTGACGCACCG-TAMRA-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosystems</ENAMEX>. The cycle number at
          which the transcripts of the gene of interest were detectable (CT) was normalized to the
          cycle number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">36B4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">detection</ENAMEX>, referred to as deltaCT. The fold change in expression of
          the gene of interest in the compound-treated group relative to that in the
          vehicle-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was expressed as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          ‚àídeltadeltaCT , in which deltadeltaCT equals the deltaCT of the
          compound-treated group minus the deltaCT of the chosen control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, which was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">normalized</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          Resistin concentrations, in cell media and human plasma, were assessed with a
          commercially available <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linco Research</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Charles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">normalized</ENAMEX> to cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. The average correlation coefficient for standards using a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-parameter fit was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.99</NUMEX>. Intra-assay and inter-assay coefficients of variance were
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.7% and 9.1%</NUMEX>, respectively. Direct comparison of standard curves generated by the Linco
          kit with those yielded by another commercially available resistin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> (Biovendor
          Laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX>) yielded high correlation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rho</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.99</NUMEX>, 
          p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.001</NUMEX>), except that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biovendor</ENAMEX> values were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 30%</NUMEX>
          lower than those determined with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linco</ENAMEX> assay. This appeared to be related to the
          standards used for calibration. Discrepant absolute values among different assays,
          including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biovendor</ENAMEX> assay, were recently described by others [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resistin</ENAMEX> levels in
          40 plasma samples were measured using both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biovendor ELISA kits</ENAMEX>, with moderate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correlation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rho</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.66</NUMEX>). Levels of soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> receptor 2 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sTNFR2</NUMEX>) were measured using
          a commercially available immunoassay (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>). Intra-assay and inter-assay
          coefficients of variance were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.1% and 9.8%</NUMEX>, respectively.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Endotoxemia Study</ENAMEX>
          Healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> (
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> female), aged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18‚Äì45</NUMEX> y with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 20</TIMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> and on no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>, were studied. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania Institutional</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Board</ENAMEX> approved the study protocol, and all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> gave written informed
          consent. Following screening and exclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with any clinical or laboratory
          abnormalities, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Clinical Research Center</ENAMEX> at the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> h stay. Serial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood samples</ENAMEX> were collected during
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> h prior to and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> h following the intravenous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of
          human-research-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endotoxin</ENAMEX> (obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health Clinical</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, reference endotoxin [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRE</ENAMEX>] [lots <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health Clinical</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center PDS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#67801</NUMEX>]) at a dose of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/kg given at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> AM. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plasma</ENAMEX> and whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood RNA</ENAMEX> (PAX
          tube isolators, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, and stored under appropriate
          conditions for subsequent assays.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Type 2 Diabetes Study</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> with type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> (
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">167</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> female), aged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35‚Äì75 y</NUMEX> and free from clinical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiovascular diseases</ENAMEX>, were recruited through the diabetes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Medical Center</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs Medical Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, to an ongoing study of cardiovascular risk factors in type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. The
          sample was composed of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasians</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were
          evaluated at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania General Clinical Research Center</ENAMEX> in a fasting
          study protocol, and all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> gave written informed consent. The patient
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> is described in more detail elsewhere [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>].
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Methods</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> are reported as mean and standard error of the mean (SEM) for continuous
          variables. Because of baseline variation in cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> between batches of primary
          human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monocytes</ENAMEX> isolated from multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, cell culture experiments were performed in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triplicate</ENAMEX> and data from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> experiments are presented. For cell culture
          experiments with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple</ENAMEX> treatments, analysis of variance (ANOVA) was used to test for
          differences in means across treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. When significant global differences were
          found, post hoc 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> -tests were used to compare specific treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to the control.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> from the human endotoxemia experiment were analyzed by repeated measures <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX>. In
          the type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spearman</ENAMEX> correlations of plasma levels of resistin with plasma
          sTNFR2 levels are presented.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resistin Gene</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Protein Expression</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endotoxin Treatment of Human</ENAMEX>
          Macrophages
          The regulation of resistin expression was studied in primary cultures of human
          monocytic cells. Immediately upon plating of elutriated primary human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monocytes</ENAMEX>, resistin
          gene expression was detectable but highly variable from experiment to experiment (data
          not shown). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> after plating, resistin gene expression remained detectable at low
          levels (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A</NUMEX>). Subjection of the cells to a protocol leading to differentiation
          along the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">macrophage</ENAMEX> lineage led to a modest, time-dependent enhancement of resistin gene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expression</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A</NUMEX>). In agreement with a previous report [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>], treatment of primary
          macrophages with the endotoxin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> led to a dramatic, dose-responsive increase in
          resistin gene expression (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1B</NUMEX>). We also determined that this effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> was
          paralleled by an increase in resistin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein secretion</ENAMEX> into the medium (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1C</NUMEX>). Of
          note, activated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse peritoneal macrophages</ENAMEX> harvested after thioglycolate treatment did
          not express detectable levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse resistin</ENAMEX>, even after treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (data not
          shown).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Endotoxin Induction of Resistin Is Delayed with Respect</ENAMEX> to TNFŒ±
          Induction of resistin gene expression by LPS exposure of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">macrophages</ENAMEX> began
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 6 and 24</TIMEX> h after treatment, with peak expression at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX>). This time
          course of resistin induction was delayed relative to induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> gene expression,
          which was detectable at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h and peaked 6 h</TIMEX> after LPS exposure (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2B</NUMEX>). The secretion
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> followed a similar time course (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2C</NUMEX>). By contrast, secretion of resistin
          did not increase until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">much later</TIMEX>, more closely following the pattern of the appearance
          of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sTNFR2</TIMEX>, a marker of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> action (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2C</NUMEX>) [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>].
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Endotoxin Induction of Resistin Is Blocked by Immunoneutralization of Multiple</ENAMEX>
          Cytokines
          Resistin gene expression was also induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> treatment of primary human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3A</NUMEX>) [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>], and resistin secretion increased in parallel (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3B</NUMEX>).
          Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> preceded the increase in resistin (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2C</NUMEX>), we
          hypothesized that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX>, or a similar cytokine produced early after LPS exposure, was
          responsible for the later induction of resistin. Indeed, neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> to TNFŒ±
          markedly attenuated the increase in resistin gene expression (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3C</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> treatment
          also induces other cytokines, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Œ≤</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>], and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> induces resistin
          modestly (data not shown) [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. Antibodies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Œ≤</ENAMEX> individually had minor
          effects on LPS stimulation of resistin (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3C</NUMEX>). However, the combination of
          antibodies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Œ≤</ENAMEX> markedly attenuated LPS induction of resistin (Figure
          3C). These data clearly show that resistin induction by endotoxin is mediated by a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cascade</ENAMEX> in which the primary event is secretion of inflammatory cytokines that, in turn,
          induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resistin</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Induction of Resistin Is Blocked by Anti-Inflammatory Insulin-Sensitizing Drugs</ENAMEX>
          That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target NF</ENAMEX>-Œ∫B
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse resistin</ENAMEX>, produced exclusively by adipocytes, is down-regulated by antidiabetic
          thiazolidinediones, including rosiglitazone [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. Consistent with an earlier report [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>],
          rosiglitazone down-regulated resistin gene expression (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>) in LPS-stimulated human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX>. Resistin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein secretion</ENAMEX> was also significantly reduced by rosiglitazone
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4B</NUMEX>). Hence, macrophage expression of resistin and its induction by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>-specific, but down-regulation of resistin by thiazolidinedione occurs both in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosiglitazone</ENAMEX> has marked anti-inflammatory effects on macrophages
          [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>]. This led us to examine the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX>, an anti-inflammatory compound that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">targets IŒ</ENAMEX>∫B kinase and has <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-sensitizing effects [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remarkably</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX>
          dramatically decreased endotoxin-induced resistin expression in a dose-dependent manner
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4C</NUMEX>). Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX> (via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IŒ</ENAMEX>∫B kinase) and rosiglitazone (via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARŒ≥</ENAMEX>) inhibit NF-Œ∫B
          [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31,32</NUMEX>], which is activated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>. Indeed, treatment of the macrophages with the
          proteasome inhibitor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MG132</TIMEX>, which prevents <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-Œ∫B activation</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>], abrogated
          endotoxin-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> of resistin expression (data not shown). Moreover, treatment
          of the macrophages with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SN50</TIMEX>, a cell-permeable peptide that specifically prevents
          activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-Œ∫B</ENAMEX> by inhibiting its nuclear translocation [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>], nearly abolished
          endotoxin-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> of resistin expression (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4D</NUMEX>). Thus, activation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Œ∫B is required for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> induction of resistin in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macrophages</ENAMEX>. Furthermore,
          constitutive activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-Œ∫B</ENAMEX> by adenoviral expression of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IŒ∫B kinase</ENAMEX> was
          sufficient to induce resistin in primary human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macrophages</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4E</NUMEX>). The magnitude of
          this activation was less than that caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, which is known to also activate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP-kinase</ENAMEX> (MAPK). Indeed, inhibition of either p42 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PD98059</TIMEX>, or p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> (using
          SB20358) partially blocked the induction of resistin by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4F</NUMEX>). Together these
          results show that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-Œ∫B activation</ENAMEX> is necessary and sufficient for resistin induction by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> activation increasing the magnitude of the response.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LPS Robustly Increases Circulating Resistin Levels in Healthy Humans</ENAMEX>
          Next, we asked whether our findings from ex vivo studies of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macrophages</ENAMEX> would
          translate into in vivo observations in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> were injected with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, using a protocol similar to that shown to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>]. Baseline
          circulating resistin levels were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml, and remained relatively constant
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> infusion (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5A</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remarkably</ENAMEX>, resistin levels rose
          dramatically because of endotoxemia, peaking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8‚Äì16</NUMEX> h after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5A</NUMEX>).
          The time course of hyperresistinemia paralleled the increase in circulating levels of
          sTNFR2, although the increase in resistin levels was more marked and sustained (Figure
          5A). The increase in resistin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels correlated with increased resistin gene
          expression in peripheral blood mononuclear cells following systemic endotoxemia (Figure
          5B).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Circulating Resistin Levels Correlate</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Inflammatory Marker sTNFR2</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Type 2 Diabetes</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance, many of whom are obese, have
          elevated levels of several inflammatory markers, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sTNFR2</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>].
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has been shown to induce acute <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>].
          Given that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> infusion increased resistin levels, we measured resistin in a cohort of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. Circulating resistin levels were significantly
          correlated with levels of sTNFR (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6A</NUMEX>). Thus, there is an association between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resistin</ENAMEX> levels and systemic inflammation in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        We have demonstrated that, in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macrophages</ENAMEX>, an inflammatory cascade with secretion
        of cytokines, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, is sufficient and necessary for the induction of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resistin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Insulin sensitizers</ENAMEX> that have anti-inflammatory properties, including a synthetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARŒ≥</ENAMEX> agonist as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX>, suppress macrophage resistin expression, as does direct
        inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-Œ∫B.</ENAMEX> Experimental endotoxemia in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, based on the
        well-established <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX>-negative bacterial inflammatory response in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38,39,40</NUMEX>],
        induces a dramatic elevation of circulating resistin levels. Hence, resistin gene and
        protein expression are increased by inflammatory stimuli both ex vivo and in vivo.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>, resistin is produced exclusively by adipocytes, regulates normal glucose
        homeostasis, and causes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance at high circulating levels [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,13</NUMEX>]. Translation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resistin</ENAMEX>'s metabolic effects from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> has been problematic because
        peripheral blood mononuclear cells and macrophages appear to be a primary source of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resistin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,16</NUMEX>]. This species difference in primary locus of expression is yet
        another example of the close and functionally overlapping relationship between adipocytes
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macrophages</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>]. Numerous studies have reported that circulating resistin levels are
        increased in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">obesity</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,25,26,41</NUMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,20,23,42,43</NUMEX>]. Our data suggest
        that, whereas hyperresistinemia in obese <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX> derives directly from adipocytes, human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resistin</ENAMEX> is indirectly regulated by the inflammatory internal milieu of obesity (Figure
        6B). Indeed, obesity is associated with elevated levels of cytokines whose systemic
        administration leads to impaired <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose homeostasis</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,44,45</NUMEX>], such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>,
        which we show here to mediate the inflammatory induction of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resistin</ENAMEX>. Thus, in both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, adipose tissue is an endocrine organ containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adipocytes</ENAMEX> as well as macrophages
        that regulates energy metabolism and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose homeostasis</ENAMEX> through secretion of multiple
        factors, including inflammatory cytokines [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>].
        Clearly the relationship between obesity, inflammation, and resistin expression is
        complex, and needs to be systematically studied in larger and varied patient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intriguingly</ENAMEX>, we found a strong correlation between plasma levels of resistin and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sTNFR2</ENAMEX>,
        the soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleavage product</ENAMEX> of the activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> receptor, in diabetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. A
        comparable correlation between resistin and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sTNFR2</TIMEX> (
        R = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.31</NUMEX>, 
        p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.001</NUMEX>) was found in a cohort of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">879</NUMEX> non-diabetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, in
        whom resistin levels independently correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">coronary atherosclerotic disease</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. P.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reilly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Lehrke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. L. Wolfe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Rohatgi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. A. Lazar</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. J. Rader</ENAMEX>, unpublished
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>).
        and Toll-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor 4</ENAMEX>, activating signal cascades involving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-Œ∫B</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>] and
        thereby inducing the transcription and secretion of early cytokines, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>]. We have shown here that these early cytokines are responsible for secondary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX> or enhancement of resistin expression in macrophages. Hyperresistinemia impairs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose homeostasis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49,50</NUMEX>], and inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        resistance [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>], which may serve as a physiological attempt to increase the provision of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> to the brain under stress conditions. Indeed, induction of acute inflammation by
        administration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> causes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>], and here we have
        demonstrated the concomitant induction of resistin. Interestingly, the peak in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-6</ENAMEX> levels after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> precedes a phase of prolonged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        resistance that begins <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 6 h</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>], closely
        approximating the time course of resistin induction. Hence resistin is a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with acute inflammation. Moreover, obesity is associated
        with activation of innate immunity [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>], including the inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> that induce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resistin</ENAMEX>. In this context it is intriguing that resistin levels are increased in obesity
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,26</NUMEX>] and that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin-sensitizing agents</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX> and rosiglitazone, with
        disparate primary molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, antagonize resistin induction. Indeed,
        thiazolidinedione suppression of resistin levels has recently been correlated with hepatic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin sensitization</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>]. Future work will be needed to better understand the
        relationship between circulating resistin levels and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> resistance characteristic
        of inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, including obesity.
      
    
  
