
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> has reached alarming proportions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. The magnitude of the
        epidemic is projected to exceed that of sub-Saharan <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. More
        than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Asians</ENAMEX> are currently infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 5 million</NUMEX> of whom
        are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepal</ENAMEX> has had a comparatively lower prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> compared to other countries
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seasonal</TIMEX> migration and sexual trafficking across a porous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> border
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>], fuelled by a bloody Maoist conflict (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sidebar</ENAMEX>), has raised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> prevalence
        to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.
        In this essay, we characterize the current <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> epidemic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, look at the ways in
        which the conflict may be fuelling the infection rate, and discuss the current local and
        international response from the health and development <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. We argue that there is
        currently a short window of opportunity to take action to control the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> epidemic in
        Nepal‚Äîand that inaction will lead to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> becoming the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> of the young and
        middle-aged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>.
      
      
        The Current <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV Epidemic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> was reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. Most cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-2</ENAMEX> was also recently reported [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2005</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for AIDS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STD Control</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> reported that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,755</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">856</NUMEX> confirmed cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. However, because of the
        poor surveillance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> and the lack of access to quality voluntary counselling and
        testing services coupled with antiretroviral treatment, these prevalence figures are likely
        to be a gross under-estimate [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>].
        A dramatically higher estimate comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNAIDS</ENAMEX>, which estimated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62,000</NUMEX> out of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24.1 million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> were living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15‚Äì49 years</TIMEX> are living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 30%</NUMEX> of those
        infected are female [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. WHO/UNAIDS estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">940</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> and
        that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 13,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were orphaned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> due to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2003</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. The
        prevalence in the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> may still be low, but it masks an increasing
        prevalence in several risk groups‚Äîthe prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> consistently exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">injecting drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, commercial sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
      
      
        High-Risk Groups
        Among injecting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">users‚</ENAMEX>Äîestimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 30,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal‚</ENAMEX>Äîabout <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. Needle sharing and risky sexual behaviour is common in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The
        figures are particularly alarming in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital city</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 68%</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">injecting drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. A subtype C virus with restricted genetic
        diversity is thought to have caused this epidemic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Concomitant hepatitis</ENAMEX>
        C infection is a contributing factor to the rapidity and severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> progression in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">injecting drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> have tested positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> C
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>].
        The predominant mode of transmission of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> is heterosexual contact with
        commercial sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> prevalence rates are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 4%</NUMEX> among sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the Terai
        regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1.5%</NUMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> (which is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than five</NUMEX> times the
        national average prevalence) [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 17%</NUMEX> of sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 25,000</NUMEX> sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>] and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 200,000</NUMEX> Nepalese
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothels</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 5,000 to 10,000</NUMEX> Nepalese sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are trafficked
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>], numbers that are likely to increase as a result of the conflict. One
        striking estimate is that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 70%</NUMEX> of sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> returning from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>].
        As in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, a major contributor to the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> has been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>'s mobile
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">truckers</ENAMEX> and migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX> of the estimated cases of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> are in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> highway <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> survey indicated that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">truckers</ENAMEX> surveyed had had sex with a sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> and that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 70%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">truckers</ENAMEX> had used
        a condom during their last sexual encounter [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> who have sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> still account for only a small proportion of those affected
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. But the recent detention and subsequent release of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> male transvestite
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Diamond Society</ENAMEX>, a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that provides sexual health,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, and advocacy services to sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, highlights the challenges faced by
        sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>].
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Role of Conflict in Fuelling the Epidemic</ENAMEX>
        Several factors contribute to the propagation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> in times of conflict (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>) [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>].
        While accurate numbers are hard to come by, the recent conflict may have contributed to the
        propagation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> by fuelling displacement [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. As the insurgency drags on, seasonal
        and long-term migration of labourers to neighbouring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, is becoming
        critical to the economic survival of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> ‚Äúen
        masse‚Äù for fear of execution and migrated to the high-prevalence areas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. UNAIDS
        estimates <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 10%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepalese</ENAMEX> migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are now infecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and others in many parts of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. By pushing rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> from war-torn areas to the capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, the
        conflict may have helped spread <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Some 200,000 to 400,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may have been displaced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> since the beginning of
        the conflict [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. Migrations within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and internationally, coupled with a
        general lack of awareness and knowledge about risk factors, is likely to have contributed
        to the propagation of the epidemic. The far western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, which are less
        economically developed and which are the hotbed of the current insurgency, are more prone
        to migration. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> have one of the fastest growth rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Migrants</ENAMEX> are more likely to practice high-risk sexual behaviour [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 8%</NUMEX> of
        migrant male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> returning from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai</ENAMEX> and examined in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> were infected with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. The epidemiological impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> has yet to be
        realized, as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 0.5%</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kailali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive, although <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 30%</NUMEX> had some form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STD</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>].
        Sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> have shifted their trade from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sindhupalchowk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuwakot</ENAMEX> in central
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepal to Rukum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolpa</ENAMEX> (the hotbeds of the insurgency) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-</TIMEX>west, taking undue
        advantage of the socio-economic conditions borne by conflict and violence. The low
        socio-economic status of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> along with the current conflict makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in this
        region particularly vulnerable [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. Save the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Children Norway</ENAMEX>'s recent study, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Impacts of Armed Conflict Pushing Women and Girls Into Sexual Abuse and Sex</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> , revealed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 19%</NUMEX> of female sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> stated they had entered the sex
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> directly because of the conflict [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>].
        While the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> infected has risen, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> prevention and awareness work has
        declined in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> as a result of the conflict. Save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's</ENAMEX> work in the Accham
        district of western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> has been hindered by fighting between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maoist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> and
        have been burned, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> are afraid to work [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M√©decins Sans Fronti√®res</ENAMEX> was
        forced to curtail its activities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jumla</ENAMEX>, one of the poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, due to the conflict. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> fear that the situation will continue to
        deteriorate if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGOs</ENAMEX> are not allowed to work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jumla</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in rural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> are desperate for care and support.
      
      
        Condom Use
        In a study of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 42%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> used a condom consistently
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. The vast majority of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80%</NUMEX>, who had sex with non-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">regular</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> felt
        they were not at risk of contracting any form of sexually transmitted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>].
        The reasons for non-use included fear of losing sexual pleasure, embarrassment over buying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condoms</ENAMEX>, and a belief that careful selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> offers sufficient protection [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>].
        Monitoring of behavioural trends has shown that condom use during the last sexual encounter
        as reported by female sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> has markedly increased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>].
        However, consistent use of condoms as reported by female sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54%</NUMEX>) still needs
        improvement [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. Many female sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and lack the power to
        negotiate safe sex [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. Many of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are considered free of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> by clients
        who see no need to use condoms. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> command a high price as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúvirgins‚Äù</ENAMEX> for brothel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> who do not want to disturb the situation by requiring condom use [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. Further, the
        weakening of traditional socio-cultural constraints in times of conflict makes the girls
        more prone to sexual abuse and exploitation and more likely to engage in high-risk sexual
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">behaviour</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local and International Response</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for AIDS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STD Control</ENAMEX> has received support from WHO, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNAIDS</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNDP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAID</ENAMEX>. But it lacks substantive funding to complete the necessary studies and
        interventions that are the key to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> control. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> efforts aimed at awareness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        are complicated by the ethnic diversity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 75</NUMEX> different ethnic groups
        exist, speaking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 50</NUMEX> languages.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGOs</ENAMEX> is now working on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. Local organisations
        are doing their best to reach out to those living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, but due to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX>-centric nature of most funding, funds available for the rural areas are scarce. Most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor representatives</ENAMEX> lack direct knowledge of the rural areas and rely on the instructions
        provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGOs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to dispense funds.
        Foreign aid, which accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 60%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>'s development budget, may have
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paradoxically</ENAMEX> contributed to lopsided development in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. While aid money has favoured
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> development and centralized power, the rural‚Äìurban gap has widened over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepal</ENAMEX>, weak linkages between urban and rural areas, and lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, communications,
        infrastructure, and appropriate skills among the rural poor mean that this urban bias has
        led to centralization of effective power on the one hand and maintenance of the economic,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX>, and political status quo on the other [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> biases inevitably play a
        deterrent role, discouraging poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> from seeking help. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> see very little of
        the aid money, since most of it is used for prevention, information, and awareness in urban
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centres</ENAMEX> rather than for care and support in rural areas.
        In our experience, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> care and support to be too expensive to
        fund, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> lacks the kind of infrastructure‚Äîclinics, district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, and
        distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units‚</ENAMEX>Äîneeded to provide effective antiretroviral treatment, and that
        antiretrovirals are a priority only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with a high prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> or
        more) in the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>].
        Harm-reduction interventions have been shown to slow the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> among intravenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> (IDUs) in many developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>], but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> the concept of harm
        reduction is still new. Few harm-reduction programs are government-supported or integrated
        into mainstream service delivery. Organisations such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lifesaving</ENAMEX> and Lifegiving
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGO</ENAMEX> established in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, have been providing education,
        counselling, and primary health care‚Äîas well as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bleach</ENAMEX>, sterile <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, condoms, and new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">needles</ENAMEX> and syringes‚Äîto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDUs</ENAMEX> to lower their risk of acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">blood-borne diseases</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>].
        The prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">IDUs</ENAMEX> who were in regular contact with the program
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1991 to 1994</TIMEX> was low, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.6%</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>].
        However successful, these programs have not reached the border zones with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection has risen dramatically among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDUs</ENAMEX>. This dramatic rise is not surprising since
        research has shown that cross-border drug-use patterns in areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> bordering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
        are particularly conducive to risky needle sharing [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>]. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDUs</ENAMEX> in other Nepalese
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">towns</ENAMEX>, very few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDUs</ENAMEX> in border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> belong to stable ‚Äúinjecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Sharing</ENAMEX> of
        contaminated injecting equipment in border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> is widespread, in part because of the
        makeshift arrangements in which the cross-border injecting takes place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> often share
        their small amounts of money to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Sexual intercourse with casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> occurs,
        with inconsistent condom use [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>]. Effective intervention would therefore require complex
        cross-border collaborative efforts [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> are stigmatized and face discrimination at all societal
        levels‚Äîin the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, at health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, and, most importantly, within the family
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>]. In a recent survey by CARE-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of those who came to the voluntary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counselling</ENAMEX> and testing centre at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doti District Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silgadhi</ENAMEX>, a
        conflict-affected area, during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">June‚</ENAMEX>ÄìJuly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> tested positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>, and almost all of
        those tested positive were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their twenties</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 60%</NUMEX> of them
        were breast-feeding their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>. These young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> faced rejection from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
        discrimination at work, and difficulty in coping with their life circumstances [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>].
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> important development in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has been within the area of condom promotion
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> prevention. A national research study found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76.6%</NUMEX> of retail outlets
        surveyed had never sold a condom in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population Services International</ENAMEX> began a
        national condom promotion program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2002</TIMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>] using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-pronged approach: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a
        national media campaign promoting condoms (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>); (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) increased widespread condom
        availability within the private sector to destigmatize condom use; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) targeted condom
        promotion to high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>]. The impact of such efforts on
        condom sales has been dramatic. Total sale of condoms jumped from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.9 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23.1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, and sales continue to climb [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>]. Creating long-term
        behaviour change and making condoms accessible in the private sector and affordable through
        subsidy to high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as female sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> appears to be increasing the uptake
        of condoms in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Window of Opportunity</ENAMEX>
        There is a window of opportunity to combat <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. If trends continue, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
        will be the leading cause of death among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15‚Äì49</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year-olds</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten years</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. 100,000
        to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> could be infected, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000 to 15,000</NUMEX> annual <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> deaths could
        occur in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten years</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. What steps must be taken to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> from being
        devastated by the infection?
        First, we must gather better data on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV seroprevalence</ENAMEX>, on sexual behaviour in the
        general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, and on sexual networking [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>]. We have argued in this essay that the
        extent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> will depend upon rates at which sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> are
        exchanged by commercial sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who regularly visit them, as well as the
        proportion of the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that has multiple and concurrent sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>.
        There are extensive migration patterns both within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and internationally, fuelled
        by the recent conflict, which provide the potential for considerable sexual networking.
        Better knowledge of this networking is crucial for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> control efforts.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must recognize and acknowledge the needs of high-risk groups‚Äîdrug
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, commercial sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who have sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Plans to
        create more behaviour changes are needed within these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2002‚Äì2006</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV/AIDS</ENAMEX>
        strategy proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>], which adopts a multisectoral approach focusing on
        prevention among vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, on control, care and support, and on voluntary
        counselling, hopes to address some of these issues.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, information campaigns should focus on changing attitudes that create barriers to
        regular use of condoms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Condoms</ENAMEX> should be readily available, and research should focus on
        the impact of mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> on perceptions of risk, negative attitudes toward condoms, and
        risky behaviour [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. A culturally specific approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> prevention is needed that
        includes education of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and brothel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> about condoms.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> involved in addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> and who are working in closely
        adjacent fields need to interact more and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with each other, and there needs to be
        greater inclusion of civil society in campaigns to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> awareness and reduce
        stigma.
        Finally, successful national programs that have the scale to alter the course of the
        epidemic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> should be expanded.
      
      
        Conclusion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is no longer only a health issue, it is also a development issue. Tackling the
        epidemic will require not only prevention and control of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection among vulnerable and
        risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, but a multi-sectoral approach addressing the lack of access by risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to
        health care and education and recognition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> at risk [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> living
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> should be brought to the forefront in the fight against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>].
        Family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, civil society <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, and the government
        all have their own important role to play [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>]. The status of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must change so that
        they are considered autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who can make their own decisions [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>].
        As with all international declarations on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, there is an absolute need to take a
        strong human rights approach to combating the epidemic. This approach includes recognizing
        fundamental rights such as access to health care and information, addressing gender equity,
        and a concerted effort to reduce sex trafficking. It further requires addressing the root
        causes of poverty and inequality, which give rise to the phenomenon of migration and
        trafficking as well as propagate violent uprisings. Only such efforts will prevail in
        mitigating the effects of both <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> and conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
