
  
    
      
        
        What holds cells together or connects them with the extracellular matrix—and what
        happens when these interactions break down—is one of the keys to determining how tumors
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metastasize</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of compounds—integrins—are a central part of these interactions. Not
        only do integrins play a part in cell–cell and cell–matrix adhesion, but they also are
        involved in signal transduction (the method by which a cell relays information from
        receptor binding to cellular response) and in triggering cell death by linking to other
        molecules. One such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">avß3</NUMEX> integrin, which is expressed
        on both the tumor cells and the new vasculature of various tumors, including melanomas.
        avß3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">integrin</ENAMEX> has a role in cell migration and extravasation, which occurs during
        metastasis, and also in angiogenesis—the development of new blood vessels that are
        essential for the growth of tumors. These blood vessels are the target for one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anti-cancer drugs—angiogenesis inhibitors</ENAMEX>. Molecules that bind to avß3 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">integrin</ENAMEX> have also
        been used to target therapeutic compounds to tumors: compounds that antagonize this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrin</ENAMEX> can lead to apoptosis (programmed cell death) of cells that express it.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haubner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of a paper in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , have previously developed a fluorine-labeled peptide, [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galacto-RGD</ENAMEX>, that has a high affinity for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">avß3</TIMEX> integrin. [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galacto-RGD</ENAMEX> has many of the features essential for a tracer: it is
        specifically accumulated by tumors that express avß3 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">integrin</ENAMEX>, it is efficiently eliminated
        by the kidneys, and it is stable in vitro and in vivo.
        In the research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haubner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> take the development of the
        compound further towards clinical application. First, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> with human melanoma they
        used highly sensitive positron emission tomography (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PET</ENAMEX>) scanning to show not only that the
        level of uptake of integrin was specific for the tumor, but also that the uptake was in
        direct proportion to the amount of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">avß3</TIMEX> expressed, thus potentially allowing quantification
        of receptor expression; however, larger tumors showed a poorer correlation, possibly
        because of the presence of necrotic areas that do not express the integrin.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, this picture was a little less clear; in a small study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        tumors including melanoma, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> found a good deal of difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in
        the uptake of the marker by tumor cells and the corresponding tumor vasculature. However,
        there was good correlation between the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tracer uptake</ENAMEX> and conventional staining for the
        integrin by immunohistochemistry—again suggesting that the marker is truly reflecting the
        in vivo level of the integrin.
        What do these results mean for clinical applications? As well as identifying tumors that
        express this marker, this approach might also offer a noninvasive way to assess the degree
        of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> formation in tumors. The approach could provide important information for
        planning and monitoring anti-angiogenic therapies targeting this integrin and could reveal
        the involvement and role of this integrin in metastatic and angiogenic processes in various
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
