
  
    
      
        
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Parliament</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> formed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">european</ENAMEX> and Developing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Countries Clinical Trials Partnership</ENAMEX> (EDCTP). The aim of this new funding body, which has
        a budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&euro</NUMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">400 million</NUMEX> spread over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, is a noble one: to fund research
        in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, that contributes to the development of
        affordable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prophylactics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, tuberculosis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>.
        Unfortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has not got off to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an auspicious start</TIMEX>. Its executive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piero Olliaro</ENAMEX>, was ousted from power at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first EDCTP</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> forum at the end
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. There have been rumblings of discontent among grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> who say that
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of grant assessments was administered poorly. And not-for-profit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> that would like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDCTP</ENAMEX> have been left in the dark regarding
        whom to speak to at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
        This omission is significant because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> is one of the key tenets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDCTP</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are slowly beginning to realize that they need to cooperate with
        each other if they are to be competitive with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The history of many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> is such that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> has much stronger ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> than does the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, so it makes political sense for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> to fund research that
        provides a springboard for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to compete effectively with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crucially</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDCTP</ENAMEX> was also set up to enable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to work
        together as equal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. There is increasing recognition that the paternalistic,
        colonial attitude that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pervaded “tropical medicine”</ENAMEX> in the past just will not do. The EDCTP
        hoped to change that by having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership Board</ENAMEX> that contains equal numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDCTP Assembly</ENAMEX>, which contains a representative
        from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each of 14</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> but none from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, has the power to veto the
        decisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership Board</ENAMEX>, which is supposedly the scientific decision-making
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>.
        Doing clinical trials in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> is far from easy. There are too few adequately resourced
        research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, and those that do consistently perform well are oversubscribed.
        Therefore, there is a clear need for "capacity building"—development of a research
        infrastructure, in terms of both equipment and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, that is capable of coping with
        the challenges of clinical trials. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDCTP</ENAMEX> hopes to contribute to this essential endeavor
        by funding clinical trials that are sustainable in the long term. In particular, it
        believes that the best way to train a new generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> is by teaching
        them on the job, that is, involving them fully in the planning and execution of the trial,
        rather than flying in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who leave as soon as the trial is finished.
        A commitment from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to be engaged for the long term is essential for
        the success of these projects. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> need to be brokered with national
        programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> to ensure that the new capacity can be sustained over time. The end goal
        is to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> of excellence that are run by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> doing internationally
        recognized research that conforms to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Clinical Practice guidelines</ENAMEX>. But this will only
        happen if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are treated as equal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and are allowed to be fully
        engaged in the projects that are taking place in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
        So can the EDCTP work, or is it doomed to failure? In many ways the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal going for it. Although the budget of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3400 million</NUMEX> spread over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> is tiny
        considering the combined burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, tuberculosis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, it is important to
        remember that it is the biggest single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> project for clinical trials in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. In
        many ways the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDCTP</ENAMEX> is a demonstration project: if some success can be achieved it is very
        likely that additional funds will follow. The project is certainly strengthened by the
        involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascoal Mocumbi</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mozambique</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> of the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mocumbi</ENAMEX> is highly respected by the global-health community
        and carries considerable weight with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Mobilization of political will
        within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> will be essential if research capacity is to be sustained for the long
        term.
        On the downside, it seems clear to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> that the management structure needs to
        be radically changed and partnership with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> needs to be improved. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDCTP Assembly</ENAMEX> met on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 28 and 29</TIMEX> to discuss these issues and to elect a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.
        At the time this editorial went to press, there was still no public announcement of the
        outcome of this meeting. In addition, the political infighting that pervades <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        politics at all levels needs to be controlled, or at least managed effectively. This might
        be a tall order, but it is essential if this worthwhile and high-profile project is to
        succeed.
      
    
  
