
  
    
      
        
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> is a sufficiently new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> that we are often doing
        something for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. This issue's “first” is the publication of a research article
        that reports data exclusively from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, more precisely from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> cynomolgus macaques
        used to test the efficacy of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lassa fever</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>. There is no question that animal
        studies are an important part of medical research, but which ones, if any, belong in a
        medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>? More to the point, which ones belong in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> ? Although our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>'s focus is on human studies, we have
        decided, on occasion, to publish animal studies that have important and proximal
        implications for clinical research, and maybe even practice.
        Lassa fever causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">serious morbidity</ENAMEX> and mortality in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Africa</ENAMEX>. The virus's natural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>, and as there is little chance for effective rodent control in the
        endemic areas, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> is the most feasible way to gain control of the disease. Several
        research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> around the world have worked on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> development—and their efforts have
        been boosted by the classification of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lassa</ENAMEX> virus as a Category A bioweapons agent—but to
        date no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> is available for either general or high-risk application in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Geisbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have developed and now report tests of a recombinant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> based on a replication-competent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">vesicular stomatitis</ENAMEX> virus (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOI</ENAMEX>:
        10.1371/journal.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pmed.0020183</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> shot of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> protected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        vaccinated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> against a lethal virus challenge, whereas the two control <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> died,
        making the vaccine a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for future application in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. Clearly many
        issues about this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> still need to be resolved, such as vector safety, duration of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>, and breadth of protection (there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lassa</ENAMEX> virus
        strains). Nevertheless, we accepted this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> because we and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> felt that the
        research was at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> where clinical questions, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> safety and design of
        early human trials, should inform any additional studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. The proper place for
        such a study is, we believe, a clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>.
        There are several other types of animal studies we consider appropriate for publication
        in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> . These include studies that explore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-label</ENAMEX> uses of
        approved medical interventions in validated animal disease models, again based on the
        studies' direct relevance to potential treatment of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. More often, we would
        publish human studies that also include experimental animal data, which typically explore
        molecular mechanisms suggested by the human data.
        Animal studies that are submitted to medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> can be broadly divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        groups—“animal clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trials”</ENAMEX> and exploratory studies. We will assess the former in a
        similar way to how we look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX> trials. This assessment will include not only the
        ethical conduct of the study and approval by the respective regulatory authority, but also
        the rigor of the methodology. Too often, animal clinical trials, i.e., prospective,
        hypothesis-testing studies that evaluate the effects of a health-related intervention in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, are not performed with the same rigor that has been developed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decades</TIMEX>
        and widely adopted by the clinical research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. In particular, animal studies often
        have inappropriate controls, are underpowered, involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> monitoring outcomes who
        are not blinded to treatment allocation, or lack proper statistical analysis.
        Exploratory studies, designed to yield <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insight</ENAMEX> into disease etiology, pathology, or the
        mechanisms by which a particular treatment affects a disease <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, are a crucial early
        part of the translation of basic research findings into clinical practice. However, by and
        large, they will not be appropriate for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> . Instead, we encourage submission of important advances
        from this early translational stage to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> , our flagship open-access biology journal
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plosbiology</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>).
        It would be foolish to deny the existence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sizeable “grey area”</ENAMEX> between these types
        of study. Between our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, we will try to provide open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> for any
        important study at this interface between biology and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, and will be happy to talk
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> on a case-by-case basis. In addition, we currently cross-reference studies
        between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> journals—and will do so even more when our new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> come on line. For
        example, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> has published a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspectives</ENAMEX> on research articles
        published in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> regularly highlights papers from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> on its home page. In this way, because all our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are
        open access, the difference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> between a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> published in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> and any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, is just a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rodent</ENAMEX> click.
      
    
  
