
  
    
      
        
        The immune system has a remarkable capacity for fending off infectious diseases, and it
        has become clear that these same defenses can recognize and destroy cancer cells. In fact,
        they do so on an ongoing basis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> develops only when immune surveillance breaks
        down. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with established tumors also mount an immune response against some
        antigens that are specific to, or enriched in, the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX>. This response, however, is rarely
        effective against the disease.
        The idea of enlisting the immune system to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> has been around for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>,
        and has led to the development of various cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> designed to alert the immune
        system to the presence of a tumor and to induce a response that, selectively and potently,
        will eliminate tumor cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Vaccines</ENAMEX> include whole tumor extracts or specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and
        peptides that are selectively expressed or enriched in tumors, by themselves or with a
        variety of adjuvants.
        There have been some spectacular successes, in particular with immune therapy to
        malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">melanoma</ENAMEX>, a tumor type that seems naturally to be more immunogenic than others.
        However, even in melanoma, success is usually restricted to a fraction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
        with no obvious explanation of why the strategy works for a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and fails in
        most others. The emphasis has consequently shifted from clinical outcomes to monitoring a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s immune response. What type of response is necessary and sufficient to eliminate
        tumor cells is still unclear, but the hope is that understanding the immune response in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> that show clinical benefit will answer that question.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> used state-of-the art technology to dissect the endogenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> response to vaccination with heteroclitic melanoma peptides, i.e.,
        melanoma-associated peptides that have been engineered to elicit a stronger immune
        response. They focused on cytotoxic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> lymphocytes (CTLs), and compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> clones from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        melanoma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-induced T cell responses and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">melanoma patients</ENAMEX> with
        spontaneous anti-tumor T cell responses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> analyzed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> CTL
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clones</ENAMEX> (to get a sense for the complexity of the responses in individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>) for T
        cell receptor variable chain beta expression, recognition efficiency, and ability to lyse
        target melanoma cells. Most T cells isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">vaccinated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> at tumor
        cell lysis compared with T cells from endogenous responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> suggest that the high doses of peptides administered in vaccinations and the
        increased binding capacity of heteroclitic peptides to major histocompatibility complex
        molecules—the very quality that makes them more immunogenic—induce many T cells with low
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> efficiency for the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX> they encounter on the tumor cells. Their
        findings also bring into question the ability to deduce the recognition efficiency and
        tumor reactivity of T cell responses from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISPOT</ENAMEX> and tetramer staining assays—the two
        standard measures of T cell responses to vaccines—which has implications for rational
        vaccine design in general.
      
    
  
