
  
    
      
        
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> announced the challenge to develop an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS Vaccine Advocacy Coalition</ENAMEX> (AVAC) has published
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> reports on the global status of the effort to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s deadline. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúAIDS Vaccine Trials‚ÄîGetting the Global House</ENAMEX> in Order,‚Äù officially ends
        the countdown. Saying that ‚Äúwe are on a long term mission,‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AVAC</ENAMEX> concludes that there will
        not be a safe and efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>, and that we need to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúfocus on the long haul
        and set an agenda for sustained and sustainable action that stretches well beyond <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2007.‚</NUMEX>Äù It
        is not that there are no vaccine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in clinical trials, but there is little hope
        that any of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will turn out to be a cheap and safe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> that
        affords long-term protection.
        Among notable developments over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 12 months</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AVAC</ENAMEX> report highlights the
        Global <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Vaccine</ENAMEX> Enterprise as an effort to improve coordination within the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
        vaccine field. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> was announced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2003</TIMEX> and now shares its scientific
        strategic plan with everyone affected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS pandemic‚Äîthat</ENAMEX> is, all of us‚Äîby publishing
        it in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">DOI: 10.1371/journal</TIMEX>.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pmed.0020025</NUMEX>).
        In its plan the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> presents itself as a global endeavor and emphasizes the need
        for integration and capacity <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> around the world. It is not ‚Äúa discrete organization
        with a pool of money‚Äù but a ‚Äúcoordinating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of individual funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that will
        support specific areas of research using their own mechanisms, according to their own
        practices and policies, and following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX>'s principles.‚Äù These principles
        include collaboration, standardization, and coordination among international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The plan focuses on specific scientific roadblocks that need to be overcome,
        but also looks ahead and mentions the need to build capacity for product manufacturing and
        clinical trials, and to address regulatory issues.
        These are noble goals, and the fact that they are stipulated jointly by many of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the field will generate excitement and expectations, even though much of what is
        said has been said before. The plan stresses collaboration and coordination; there are
        clear benefits from a concerted effort. But might a level of competition, rather than
        collaboration, be healthy, and, if so, what level of competition would work best? The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> seem to have wrestled with that question. The plan mentions an
        ‚Äúappropriate balance between productive competition and effective collaboration,‚Äù and
        suggests that certain incentives could be provided by ‚Äúthe funders with greatest
        flexibility.‚Äù As long as it remains unclear where scientific breakthroughs will come from,
        diversity and flexibility should be encouraged and not stifled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ho</ENAMEX>, in his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspective</ENAMEX> on the plan (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">DOI: 10.1371/journal</TIMEX>.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pmed.0020036</NUMEX>), mentions the danger of ‚Äúgroup
        think,‚Äù and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> must not fall into that trap.
        Notably absent from this initial plan is any mention of a timeline or milestones. The
        remit of the plan's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> was not to prescribe specific research but ‚Äúto stimulate both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and funders to explore new, more collaborative, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cooperative</ENAMEX>, and transparent
        approaches‚Ä¶in addition to continuing the productive, high-quality approaches already
        underway.‚Äù However, without a timeline, the plan fails to convey a sense of urgency. This
        is problematic, as any delays in developing a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> will increase the burden from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in the parts of the world that can least afford it. To accelerate vaccine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, the plan urgently needs to be supplemented with a list of specific tasks,
        responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, necessary resources, and allocated time.
        The next document from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> must provide specifics on project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,
        although one problem with putting a time frame on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> development is a fundamental
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>: we do not know whether it is actually possible to develop a safe and effective
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> assumes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> agree, though there is no explicit
        acknowledgement of this uncertainty in the plan.) Moreover, provided it can be done, it is
        impossible to predict when the necessary scientific advances will happen. That said,
        without a list of specific projects, project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and a time frame for achieving or at
        least evaluating specific goals, it will be impossible to define success and failure,
        review progress, and assure internal and external accountability.
        There is another reason why a best-guess timeline is essential: realistic expectations
        about an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> would stress the urgency of combating the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> pandemic over the next
        decade‚Äîand maybe longer‚Äîin the absence of an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>. The potential benefits of a
        vaccine cannot be overestimated, and its development has to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> top priority for the
        global scientific community. But its success cannot be taken for granted and will come too
        late for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>. Therefore, parallel efforts to prevent or reduce transmission and to
        treat infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> need to be accelerated now.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX>'s plan should be hailed as a crucially important outline for vaccine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, but the goodwill surrounding it won't last unless it is quickly followed up
        with a set of milestones, and a transparent process by which progress will be measured and
        course corrections implemented.
      
    
  
