
  
    
      
        
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Icelandic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is now a part of a unique epidemiological study, which has
        involved investigating the genetic heritage of many of them. The reason that this
        experiment can be done is because of the remarkable records that exist in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX>. Not only
        is there almost complete genealogical information dating back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> on all
        current (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">288,000</NUMEX>) and many previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icelanders</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 600,000</NUMEX> in total), but in
        addition the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has an almost complete <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> registry dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deCODE Genetics</ENAMEX>, was set up to mine health-care data in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX>, and to use it to assess
        the effect of genetics on health. Initially, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> attracted criticism, with some
        questioning the ethics of providing access to health-care data for many <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> projects to
        a for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has been supported by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Icelanders</ENAMEX> themselves,
        demonstrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Icelanders</ENAMEX> donating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood samples</ENAMEX> with informed consent for research on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple diseases</ENAMEX>, and now the project's scientific value is becoming apparent.
        One such analysis is the subject of a paper by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laufey Amundadottir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> that assesses how much genetic factors contribute to cancer
        risk across the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Icelandic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> looked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> (all those with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> cases)
        that had been registered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1955 and 2002</TIMEX> and analysed the frequency of close and
        distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> also having that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, or another kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
        showed significant “familiality,” and for some this risk even extended to distant (that is,
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>- to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>-degree) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">seven cancers</ENAMEX> with the highest increased familial
        occurrence both in close and distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> were breast, prostate, stomach, lung, colon,
        kidney, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">bladder cancers</ENAMEX>. And, interestingly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cancers—stomach, lung, and colon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cancer—were</ENAMEX> also seen more frequently in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, indicating a shared
        environmental risk factor. And for some <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> there was a familial association with other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with stomach, colon, rectal, or endometrial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> were more likely to have any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathryn Lewis</ENAMEX>, the academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> for the paper comments on the study's strengths.
        “This level of family relationship and clinical diagnosis is rarely available from
        interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The size of the study (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 600,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>,
        with 32,000 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases) and the high quality of data enables the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> to detect subtle
        effects across distant relationships.”
        How robust are these data, and what do they mean for the biological understanding of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>? As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> says, “Although the current study is impressive in its size and scope,
        even here, the sample size becomes an issue, with the most convincing results seen in the
        most common <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>.” Certainly not all the findings are surprising; some rare <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> are
        already known to be associated with particular genetic defects, and syndromes that
        predispose to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple cancers</ENAMEX> have been described, for example, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hereditary</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonpolyposis Colorectal Cancer</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> are more intriguing—the cluster of
        related <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> that include prostate, kidney, and bladder could possibly have a
        developmental origin, since all arise from the same part of the embryo.
        So, by highlighting these subtle links, the study's particular value may become
        apparent: deciding future avenues of investigation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> interrelationships that
        interact to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
