
  
    
      
        
        Epidemics of overt toxicity following widespread environmental contamination from
        commercial toxins heralded the discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s enhanced vulnerability to lead,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl mercury</ENAMEX>, polychlorinated biphenyls (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PCBs</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,2,3,4,5</NUMEX>] (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). Over the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have found that remarkably low-level exposures to these
        toxins are linked with less overt symptoms of toxicity‚Äîintellectual impairments, behavioral
        problems, spontaneous abortions, or preterm births [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14</NUMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,16,17,18,19,20,21,22,23,24,25,26,27</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28,29,30,31,32,33,34,35,36,37,38,39,40</NUMEX>]. Moreover,
        there is emerging evidence that decrements in intellectual abilities and low birth weight
        linked with lead or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> are, for a given increment of exposure, greater at lower levels
        than those found at higher levels [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,41,42,43</NUMEX>].
        The consequences of exposure to many other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> or mixtures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, such as
        insecticides‚Äîchemicals <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oftentimes</ENAMEX> specifically designed to be toxic‚Äîare largely unknown
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33,34,35,44</NUMEX>]. Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> or their metabolites are routinely found in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and body <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> of pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>].
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vulnerability to Environmental Toxins</ENAMEX>
        The developing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is particularly vulnerable to certain environmental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toxins</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46,47,48,49,50</NUMEX>]. Critical neurodevelopmental processes occur in the human central
        nervous system during fetal development and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three years</TIMEX> of life. These
        processes include cortical functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">differentiation</ENAMEX>, synaptogenesis, myelination, and
        programmed apoptosis [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s exposure to environmental toxins is insidious. Environmental toxins covertly
        enter a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> transplacentally during fetal development or by direct ingestion of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> dust, soil, and breastmilk and other dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> during early childhood
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51,52,53,54,55,56</NUMEX>]. Our ability to directly measure the actual levels of environmental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> in human tissues and body <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> using biologic markers (biomarkers) enables
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to more effectively link exposures to environmental toxins with disability or
        disease [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX>].
        Despite our increased knowledge of the toxicity of environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, testing for
        developmental neurotoxicity (DNT) and reproductive toxicity is rarely done. DNT testing
        uses animal experiments to provide information on the potential functional and morphologic
        toxicity to the fetal nervous system that results from the mother's exposure to toxins
        during pregnancy and lactation. Paradoxically, DNT testing of a chemical is seldom
        requested, and then typically requested only if there is pre-existing evidence that it is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotoxic</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prevalence of Diseases and Disabilities Linked to Environmental Toxins</ENAMEX>
        Based on parental reports, one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more
        developmental disabilities, from a subtle learning disability to overt behavioral or
        emotional disorders [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX>]. Exposures to environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toxins</ENAMEX> have been linked with higher
        rates of mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX>, intellectual impairment, and behavioral problems, such as
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,20,21,22,23,24,25,26,27,30,31,36,37</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38,39,40,41,42,43,59,60,61</NUMEX>].
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> is born preterm and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 5%</NUMEX> have low birth weight [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62,63</NUMEX>]. Preterm
        birth, defined as birth at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 37 weeks</TIMEX> of gestation, is a major determinant of
        infant mortality and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> throughout childhood [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62,63,64</NUMEX>]. Exposures to environmental
        toxins such as lead, tobacco smoke, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDT</ENAMEX> have been linked with an increased risk for
        spontaneous abortion, low birth weight, or preterm birth [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,9,10,13,14,15,28,32,65,66</NUMEX>]. The
        rate of occurrence for many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> or disabilities has been rising, as has
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62,63,67,68,69,70</NUMEX>].
        Multiple risk factors, including both genetic and environmental influences, interact in
        complex and often unknown ways to cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and disability in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But efforts can
        be undertaken to prevent or reduce environmental exposures linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> without full
        elucidation of the underlying mechanism [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX>]. Thus, conducting some sort of test to
        identify <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> and industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that could cause reproductive or
        neurobehavioral toxicity before the chemical reaches widespread use is essential to protect
        pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Origin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evolution</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNT Tests</ENAMEX>
        The process for testing potential developmental neurotoxins in laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>
        evolved out of a series of tragic epidemics. Widespread use of the drug thalidomide during
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX> led to an epidemic of phocomelia, an absence or deformity of limbs and other
        congenital defects in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> exposed in utero to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX>]. Subsequently, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>) developed the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teratology Guidelines</ENAMEX>. Because
        thalidomide induced gross defects in rabbits but not in rats, these guidelines called for
        toxicity tests in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. Moreover, these guidelines focused on gross abnormalities;
        they did not require testing for behavioral or DNT.
        Following the outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl mercury poisoning</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minamata Bay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> added behavioral (DNT) guidelines to their teratology requirements in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974 and 1975</TIMEX>, respectively [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73</TIMEX>]. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collaborative Behavioral Teratology Study</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBTS</ENAMEX>) was conceived to standardize and evaluate methods for DNT testing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">74</TIMEX>].
        The final report was issued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, and shortly thereafter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Kennedy</ENAMEX>, who was
        then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, supported the adoption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBTS</ENAMEX> recommendations. But the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> failed to implement these recommendations after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s departure.
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s exposure to environmental toxins is insidious
        
        neurobehavioral teratogens for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PCBs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl mercury</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, phenytoin, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>, methadone, and ionizing radiation) and developed rules
        for DNT testing in laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49,50</NUMEX>]. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Developmental</ENAMEX> Neurotoxicity
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Test Guidelines</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">OPPTS 870.6300</NUMEX>) had been established for use when submitting chemical data
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>]. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Research Council</ENAMEX> recommended that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNT</ENAMEX> data be
        included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s evaluations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>, which include classes of chemicals
        specifically designed to be toxic [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>].
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Precarious US Framework for Protecting Children</ENAMEX>
        Despite numerous attempts to upgrade the regulatory system, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBTS</ENAMEX>, the
        framework to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from environmental toxins is precarious. Under current
        regulations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> of commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> (excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>) are not required
        to supply any toxicity data before selling their products. Nor are pesticide manufacturers
        obligated to supply basic premarket toxicity and exposure data necessary to ensure that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be protected from exposure and potential harm from use of those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>.
        Indeed, the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> have not been tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNT</ENAMEX>. The most basic
        toxicity tests in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are lacking for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> highest production volume
        chemicals‚Äîchemicals for which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> production exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 million pounds</NUMEX> per year
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49,75,76,77</NUMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US EPA</ENAMEX> has entered into an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Chemistry</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>, to provide basic toxicity screening
        tests for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">high-production-volume chemicals</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">epa.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/chemrtk/volchall.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm</ENAMEX>), but this is voluntary.
        For new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> intended for use on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> crops‚Äîone of the areas in which regulations
        are most stringent‚Äîregulations require only that DNT testing be evaluated for substances
        already known or suspected of being toxins. Further, neurotoxicity testing need be
        conducted only in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> acknowledges that over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> registered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>
        are neurotoxic (i.e., specifically designed to act against pests by interfering with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotransmitters</ENAMEX> or other processes shared by mammals and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX>), but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has
        received DNT testing using validated protocols for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only nine</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49,75,76,77</NUMEX>].
        There is no general requirement that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> or other chemicals be tested for
        potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNT</ENAMEX> prior to their registration and use [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>]. For pesticides‚Äîwhich undergo more
        premarket testing than other chemicals‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has relied on a tiered system of toxicity
        testing. The assumption underlying this system is that positive findings on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, more
        basic tests of neurotoxicity in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> will ‚Äútrigger‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to request more
        extensive testing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, including tests in immature <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately,
        this tiered process has failed to result in appropriate DNT testing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, an internal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA Toxicology Working Group</ENAMEX> concluded that these triggers may not be sufficient to
        identify all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that have the potential to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNT</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75</TIMEX>]. Moreover, this tiered
        system discourages industry from conducting testing in immature <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> because the
        findings could necessitate further costly testing and hinder a chemical from reaching the
        market.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framework</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúREACH‚Äù</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> affirmed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s legislative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">framework</ENAMEX> did not provide adequate information about the adverse effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> on
        human health, and that when hazards were identified the regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were slow to
        assess risks and to introduce measures to reduce those risks [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78</TIMEX>]. Indeed, chemical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are not required to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúprove‚Äù that a chemical is safe before marketing it. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> proposed a new regulatory framework for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, REACH (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registration</ENAMEX>,
        Evaluation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authorization of Chemicals</ENAMEX>) [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78,79</NUMEX>] (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        Under REACH, chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> would have to assume a much greater burden for
        showing the lack of harm from use of their products. Specifically, REACH would require both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and non-European <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> doing business in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to submit more extensive
        toxicity data for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> on the market, including reproductive and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNT</ENAMEX> data
        for those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> produced in highest quantity. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemicals</ENAMEX> found to be hazardous would be
        subject to an authorization procedure to show that they can be used safely or that there
        are no safer alternatives. This registration process would not guarantee that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> are
        safe, but it is a step in the right direction.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Chemistry Council</ENAMEX> has objections to REACH, stating that ‚Äúthe proposed
        regulation is burdensome, costly, and impractical‚Äù
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accnewsmedia</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/site/</ENAMEX>page.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asp</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRACKID</ENAMEX>=<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">&VID</ENAMEX>=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>&CID=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">359</NUMEX>&DID=<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1256</TIMEX>).
        The pharmaceutical industry used similar objections to ward off regulations before the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">thalidomide</ENAMEX> epidemic ushered in requirements for pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to undergo extensive
        premarket testing in clinical trials [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>].
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Limitations of Existing Animal Tests</ENAMEX> for DNT
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US EPA</ENAMEX> has been slower than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> to adapt to the overwhelming evidence that
        low-level exposure to environmental toxins can be harmful. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> continues to rely
        heavily on data from animal (toxicity) testing conducted on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a single</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal species</ENAMEX>
        and in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> guidelines for a general developmental toxicity
        screening test typically examine only crude <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxicological endpoints</ENAMEX> such as death, body
        weight, or organ dysfunction. In contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNT</ENAMEX> includes tests of locomotor activity,
        acoustic startle, learning, and memory. But, as currently designed, the existing tests may
        miss important effects such as mood changes, impulsive behaviors, and attentional problems
        that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> have been shown to result from exposures to environmental toxins
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,27,30,37,40</NUMEX>]. While these effects might seem subtle, they can seriously interfere with
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s social and emotional well-being. It is also uncertain whether tests conducted
        under current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> guidelines will detect subtle deficits in key human skills such as
        reading.
        There are other problems with relying principally on adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> to signal the
        potential for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNT</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> and development of the cerebral cortex of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> commonly used in these studies differs markedly from that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX>'s
        effects on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of animal may differ from its effects on other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.
        In the case of thalidomide, high-dose fetal exposure had adverse morphologic effects on
        rabbits, but not rats; functional effects have only recently been described [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81</TIMEX>].
        Although there is some concordance of human and animal data for the adverse effects of
        lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PCBs</ENAMEX>, intake limits for these compounds established exclusively on the
        basis of rodent studies have not been sufficiently protective of human health compared with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epidemiologic</ENAMEX> studies [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>]. Indeed, there is compelling evidence from epidemiologic studies
        of widespread contaminants such as lead, tobacco, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PCBs</ENAMEX> that human studies are essential
        to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are not harmed by low levels of exposure
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,12,13,14,15,16,17,18,19,20,21,22</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23,24,25,26,27,28,29,30,31,32,33,34,35</NUMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,37,38,39,40</NUMEX>].
        From a scientific standpoint, data from epidemiologic studies represent the ‚Äúgold
        standard‚Äù for detecting subtle effects of environmental toxins on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. But
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epidemiological</ENAMEX> studies are expensive to mount, difficult to execute, and take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to
        complete. Using observational studies to disentangle the adverse consequences of a single
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> from other environmental influences and to promulgate regulations is a difficult and
        painfully slow process. There is also a financial disincentive for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">registrants</ENAMEX> to
        voluntarily fund such studies because a positive epidemiological study could lead to
        stricter regulations. More importantly, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> continues to rely on epidemiologic
        studies to evaluate the toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> only after they are marketed, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        will first be harmed.
      
      
        Steps to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Protect Children</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX> Toxins
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> must be better protected from both new and existing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that are known or
        possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">toxins</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>]. To protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from existing toxins, such as lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US EPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> need more authority and resources to regulate and reduce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> and exposures. Under our current system, efforts to enhance regulations to
        protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from confirmed toxins are costly and protracted. Indeed, countless
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> across the globe suffer from widespread environmental contamination. If there
        is any lesson from our experience with environmental toxins, it is that we need to identify
        environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that are toxic before they are marketed or widely disseminated.
        For new commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, toxicity testing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> should be required before they
        are marketed. For all new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>, extensive premarket testing
        should be required in multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal species</ENAMEX> of both sexes and at different developmental
        stages. These tests should be designed to have adequate statistical power to detect subtle
        differences within the ranges of exposure that occur in human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. If implemented,
        these testing requirements would represent a dramatic departure from existing regulations,
        while providing a powerful incentive for industry to develop less toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>.
        Toxicity testing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> is essential but insufficient to protect pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, uncertainties about the safety of a chemical for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> will
        persist even after toxicity testing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> is successfully completed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> additional
        safeguard that deserves further debate is whether prevalent environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> to
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> could be exposed should undergo more extensive testing in human trials
        before they are marketed. If done, these trials should examine exposure, uptake (using
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biomarkers</ENAMEX>), and adverse effects among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> only when the product
        is used as intended. For example, once animal toxicity testing of a residential pesticide
        is complete (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNT</ENAMEX> and reproductive toxicity testing), a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticide</ENAMEX> could undergo
        further testing in the home environment. Using an experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and a control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> would compare levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> found in settled dust, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s hands,
        and in their blood, urine, or hair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> would be followed, when indicated, to ensure
        that an excess of neurobehavioral problems or other relevant outcomes did not develop among
        those whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> were assigned to receive the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticide</ENAMEX> application.
        If such trials were undertaken, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> would need to be fully informed about the
        purpose, potential benefits, and risks of participating. The trials should be conducted by
        the federal government‚Äîor other independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that do not have any ties to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemical</ENAMEX> industry‚Äîand funded by an industry fee or tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Community representatives</ENAMEX> would
        need to be involved in the review and approval of such trials, and ethical standards would
        need to be established regarding, for example, the role of data safety and monitoring
        boards. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> would undoubtedly find it objectionable and would choose not to
        participate. Indeed, some products might never undergo testing if they failed to offer
        meaningful benefits to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, in which case the product would either be taken off the
        market or never reach the market.
        This type of trial sounds extreme, but it is quite rational when compared to the
        existing approach of disseminating a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s environments without
        any human data about exposure, uptake, or toxicity. Furthermore, under our existing system,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are neither informed nor given an option to decline involvement in what ultimately
        are experiments exposing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to potential toxins. Thus,
        we need to thoughtfully deliberate about whether these types of trials can be done in an
        ethical fashion. We also need to have further debate about whether it is ethical to
        continue to disseminate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> of unknown toxicity into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s environments or to
        allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to continually be exposed to prevalent toxins, like lead, despite
        considerable evidence that they are toxic [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">82</TIMEX>]. Too often, it is left up to a few
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> or community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to discover and quantify the adverse effects of toxins,
        and advocate efforts to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s exposure.
      
      
        Conclusion
        In contrast with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s proposed REACH program, which would require industry to
        conduct more tests or analyses to demonstrate that high-production <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> will not cause
        harm to fetuses or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has argued‚Äîin unison with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemistry Council‚</ENAMEX>Äîthat such regulations would harm industry [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83,84</NUMEX>]. It is time to
        acknowledge that the existing requirements for toxicity testing and regulations are
        inadequate to safeguard pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Until a formal regulatory system is
        developed to effectively screen and identify new and existing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that are toxic to
        pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, we are left to await the next epidemic to warn us about an
        environmental disaster. Unfortunately, by then we will have once again fouled our nest
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85</TIMEX>].
      
    
  
