
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Coronary heart disease</ENAMEX> (CHD) remains the leading cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and mortality in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and is associated with substantial economic cost [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Hyperlipidemia
        represents an important modifiable risk factor in the development and progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>.
        Estimates indicate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 100 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> have total blood cholesterol
        levels of greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">l</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 mg/dl</ENAMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> having levels greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.21</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mmol/l</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">240 mg/dl</ENAMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Identification and treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with hyperlipidemia play
        an essential role in the primary and secondary prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>.
        Currently, evidence-based practice guidelines focus on low-density lipoprotein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDL-C</ENAMEX>) as the primary target for risk reduction therapy and recommend that the
        intensity and target goals of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDL</ENAMEX>-C-lowering therapy should be adjusted to individual
        absolute risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. Absolute CHD risk is categorized as low, moderate, or high based
        on the presence or absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>, CHD-equivalent conditions, and major risk factors other
        than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDL-C.</ENAMEX> While therapeutic lifestyle changes are integral to general risk reduction,
        drug treatment proves necessary for selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> whose absolute risk is high and/or
        whose LDL-C is inadequately controlled with lifestyle modifications alone. Among existing
        drug therapies, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3-hydroxy-3-methyl-glutaryl</NUMEX> coenzyme A reductase <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, more commonly
        known as statins, provide a generally well-tolerated and effective option for lowering
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDL</ENAMEX>-C levels and decreasing the likelihood of subsequent CHD events [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,4</NUMEX>].
        Despite the compelling evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statins</ENAMEX>' therapeutic benefits, the literature abounds
        with documentation of wide treatment gaps in clinical practice [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5â€“10</NUMEX>]. Available research,
        however, offers only a limited understanding of how statin therapy varies by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> risk,
        particularly for statin-eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the moderate-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Also, national data
        are limited regarding recent changes in statin use.
        Using serial cross-sectional data from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 through 2002</TIMEX>, we tracked trends in statin
        use in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> during ambulatory visits categorized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> risk, with or without
        a diagnosis of hyperlipidemia. In addition, we analyzed the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> characteristics with statin use for insights as to how to target
        interventions to improve statin use.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Sources</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> data <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from1992 through 2002</TIMEX> were obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Ambulatory Medical</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Survey</ENAMEX> (NAMCS) and the outpatient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> component of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital</ENAMEX>
          provides complete descriptions of both surveys and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> data at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cdc</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/nchs/about/major/ahcd/ahcd1.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm.</ENAMEX> These surveys, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX>,
          have been validated against other data sources [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,12</NUMEX>], and have also been utilized in
          past research of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> management [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>].
          In brief, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX> captures health-care services provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>,
          while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> assesses services offered at hospital outpatient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. Both surveys
          utilize multistage probability sampling procedures, enabling the generation of nationally
          representative estimates. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1992 and 2002</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> participation rates among
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicians</ENAMEX> selected for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NAMCS</ENAMEX> averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX>, while the participation rate in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> by
          selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> with outpatient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX>. In our study, we combined NAMCS
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> data to obtain a wider range of outpatient settings and a broader
          socioeconomic spectrum of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> seeking ambulatory care.
          Standard encounter forms were completed for a systematic random sample of patient
          visits during randomly assigned reporting periods. Item nonresponse rates were mostly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
          or less in both surveys for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all years</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yearly</TIMEX> encounter forms varied slightly between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> and were revised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two years</TIMEX>. Our analysis focused on domains of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> that were consistently collected in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> for the time period
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992â€“2002</NUMEX>, including patient demographic and geography characteristics, reasons for visit
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to three</NUMEX>), diagnoses (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to three</NUMEX>), new and continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to five</NUMEX> in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992â€“1994 and six</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1995â€“2002</NUMEX>), and lifestyle counseling services provided or ordered at
          the visit.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
          
            CHD risk categorization
            We estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 20 y and older</TIMEX> based on risk factor counting.
            CHD risk was mutually exclusively categorized as low (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0â€“1</NUMEX> risk factors), moderate (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+
            risk factors), or high (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">atherosclerotic diseases</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>). The
            moderate-risk group included visits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> or equivalent but with at
            least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the following risk factors: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> (for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, ><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 y</NUMEX>; for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>55 y</NUMEX>),
            cigarette smoking, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>-reported diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately,
            family history of premature CHDâ€”were not captured in either data source. Also, neither
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> provided actual cholesterol measurements. Disease conditions were
            appropriate reason-for-visit codes that are specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX>. For instance,
            we identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> as having hyperlipidemia if their encounter forms contained an
            study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> whose encounter forms did not indicate the presence of a condition were
            assumed to not have that condition.
          
          
            Patient visit characteristics.
            Nonclincal characteristics included patient age, gender, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>/ethnicity, medical
            insurance, visit status, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> census region, metropolitan area status,
            physician specialty, and practice setting. Medical insurance was classified as
            private/commercial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>), or other (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>'
            compensation or self-pay). Visit status distinguished first-time visits from return
            visits to a practice. Physician specialty was available only from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX>, which
            contributed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 90%</NUMEX> of the total visits for each of the study <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. We
            categorized physician specialties as cardiology, internal medicine, general and family
            practice, or other.
          
          
            Measures
            Of primary interest were the rate of statin use relative to CHD risk and the
            relationship of statin use to patient visit characteristics. The rate of statin use was
            calculated as the proportion of patient visits where a statin was reported (i.e.,
            atorvastatin, lovastatin, pravastatin, simvastatin, or fluvastatin). Before its removal
            from the market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, cerivastatin was used scarcely (<<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> among visits by
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with hyperlipidemia) and therefore is not reported in this study. Measuring
            the rate of statin use by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> risk category provided a relative indicator of
            appropriate prescribing patterns, that is, the prevalence of statin use should be
            highest among high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, for whom secondary prevention is a priority.
            Variations of statin use by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> visit characteristics, if detected, would reflect a
            lack of equity in processes of care in that uniform practices are expected unless
            evidence-based guidelines recommend otherwise.
          
          
            Analyses
            Statistical analyses were performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX> for Windows software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS Institute</ENAMEX>,
            Cary, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX>-callable SUDAAN software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Triangle Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) to account for sampling weights and the
            complex survey design. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of analysis is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> visit. We report national
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> means of the rate of statin use by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> risk category and corresponding <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99%</NUMEX>
            confidence intervals for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1992 through 2002</TIMEX>. Ï‡
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> tests examined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of statin use with individual
            patient visit characteristics for combined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1995â€“2002</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> data. The
            independent effect of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> visit characteristic on statin use after controlling
            for all other characteristics was assessed with multivariate logistic regression.
          
        
      
      
        Results
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, visits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at moderate or high risk involved higher proportions of
        older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 65</TIMEX> y) than low-risk patient visits (mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 51</TIMEX> y), and
        consequently were more likely to be covered by public insurance, particularly Medicaid
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Moderate- and high-risk patient visits also were made up of more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and return
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. In addition, a greater percentage of high-risk patient visits (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX>) were seen by
        cardiologists than patient visits at low and moderate risk (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2% and 4%</NUMEX>, respectively).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internists</ENAMEX> and general and family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> played a dominant role in the care of
        moderate- and high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, accounting for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69%</NUMEX> of visits by moderate-risk patients
        and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX> of visits by high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Distributions by race/ethnicity, geographic
        region, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> area, and practice setting did not differ by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> risk. Overall, the
        majority of patient visits were return visits to office-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> made by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">non-Hispanic whites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> living within metropolitan statistic areas. Patient
        visits were distributed similarly across the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> geographic regions, with a slightly
        higher proportion from the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>.
        Throughout the study period, statins were primarily used among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> whose visit
        involved reported hyperlipidemia, representing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97%</NUMEX> of all statin use in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91%</NUMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statin</ENAMEX> use increased nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-fold from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99%</NUMEX> confidence interval: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%â€“12%</NUMEX>) of all
        visits with reported hyperlipidemia in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“55%</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, but then declined to
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“42%</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Of note, however, the annual rate of increase in
        frequency of patient visits with reported hyperlipidemia was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>,
        while it averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 12%</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The dominance of statins as lipid-lowering agents
        grew markedly from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47%</NUMEX> of all lipid-lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        Among available statins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovastatin</ENAMEX> remained the therapeutic choice through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, after
        which it was surpassed by other statins, particularly simvastatin and then atorvastatin
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Atorvastatin</ENAMEX> constituted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“56%</NUMEX>) and simvastatin <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“36%</NUMEX>) of all
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statin</ENAMEX> use in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.
        As expected, high CHD risk patient visits resulted in greater statin use, and the
        divergence in statin use among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> risk categories has grown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.
        Absolute increases in the rate of statin use were greatest for high-risk patient visits
        with or without reported <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hyperlipidemiaâ€”a 15 percentage-point</NUMEX> increase from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> of all
        visits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2002â</NUMEX>€”followed by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine percentage-point</NUMEX> increase (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2% to 11%</NUMEX>) for
        moderate-risk patient visits and a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 percentage-point</NUMEX> increase (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3% to 2.8%</NUMEX>) for
        low-risk patient visits (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statin</ENAMEX> use in the moderate-risk group peaked at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“17%</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Similarly, the rate of statin use in the high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> declined
        slightly from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001 to 2002</TIMEX>.
        Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> visits with reported hyperlipidemia, statins were used in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“19%</NUMEX>) of
        high-risk visits and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“14%</NUMEX>) of moderate-risk visits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. The high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statin</ENAMEX> use rate rose to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“71%</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> and was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“61%</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Likewise, the
        rate in the moderate-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> climbed to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“70%</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> and stabilized at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44%</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“57%</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. In addition, lifestyle counseling (i.e., regarding diet, exercise, or
        smoking cessation) occurred in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 43%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“53%</NUMEX>) of new and general medical examination
        visits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had moderate CHD risk and were diagnosed with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperlipidemia</ENAMEX>. Improvements over time in counseling rates were minimal.
        The increase in statin use with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> risk and with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of study persisted after
        controlling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>-reported hyperlipidemia, number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>, and nonclinical
        patient visit characteristics (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Moderate- to high-risk patient visits had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>-
        to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>-fold greater likelihood of taking a statin relative to visits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at low
        risk. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statin</ENAMEX> use was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately three</NUMEX> times as likely in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001 and 2002</TIMEX> as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Additionally, lower statin use was independently associated with younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>,
        female gender, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African American</ENAMEX> background (versus <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white), non-cardiologist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, and fewer total reported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Discussion
        Despite significant increases from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 to 2002</TIMEX> in use of statins associated with
        hyperlipidemic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> visits, the magnitude of increases is smaller than expected and the
        rate of use remains suboptimal according to the best available evidence. The underuse of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statins</ENAMEX> is most prominent among visits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at high or moderate risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> who do
        not have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>-noted diagnosis of hyperlipidemia but may nonetheless be eligible for
        lipid-lowering drug therapy. Previous research reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> are more likely to
        diagnose hyperlipidemia if laboratory reports show abnormal lipid levels [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]. However, the
        normal ranges of lipid levels on many laboratory reports do not take into account
        individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' absolute risk.
        When evaluating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">statin</ENAMEX> use across different CHD risk categories, the observed trends
        raise several issues. Both the rate of statin use and the absolute increases in the rate
        over time were positively associated with the level of CHD risk, which appropriately
        conforms to the notion of risk stratification. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> persisted after adjusting
        for potentially confounding factors such as a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hyperlipidemia</ENAMEX> diagnosis and nonclinical
        patient visit characteristics. Even so, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> after the publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adult</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treatment Panel III</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], statins were reportedly used in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 19%</NUMEX> of patient visits with
        established CHD or its equivalents, and the average rate was no higher than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> among
        high-risk visits where a diagnosis of hyperlipidemia also was noted. These data suggest a
        dramatic treatment gap. Another analysis based on national data estimated that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> would benefit from drug therapy to achieve the target <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDL</ENAMEX>-C
        goal of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">l</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 mg/dl</ENAMEX>) or less, assuming a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDL</ENAMEX>-C reduction with diet [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>].
        However, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 11%</NUMEX> of those eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> received lipid-lowering drug therapy,
        suggesting a gap of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89%</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. These obvious treatment gaps are disconcerting, especially in
        light of the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adult Treatment Panel III</ENAMEX> update[<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] that supports more intensive
        lipid-lowering drug therapy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at high and moderately high risk for a heart
        attack. Barriers to adequate treatment of high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> may stem from the patient
        (e.g., lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adherence</ENAMEX>, concern about adverse effects, inadequate knowledge of their
        hyperlipidemia, and drug cost), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> (e.g., lack of guideline awareness, failure
        to measure lipid levels, and overestimation of actual treatment), and the health-care
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> (e.g., lack of monitoring and follow-up and emphasis on acute medical problems)
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. If the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> continues, the observed treatment gaps are expected to
        persist or even widen.
        While statins deliver the greatest benefits when used for secondary prevention, evidence
        continues to accumulate that suggests an important role of statins in the primary
        prevention of cardiovascular events, particularly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at increased risk [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,17</NUMEX>].
        Our data show an increase in statin use from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of moderate-risk patient visits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, but without continued growth subsequently. Optimal proportions could not be
        determined because of the lack of detailed clinical data. Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutrition Examination Survey III</ENAMEX> data showed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38.5 million</NUMEX> adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
        without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more risk factors had an LDL-C level above the recommended <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.36</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mmol/l</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">130 mg/dl</ENAMEX>) and that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX> would remain eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> therapy even after a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
        decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDL</ENAMEX>-C with diet [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fedder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> found a doubling
        effect in the number eligible for primary prevention drug therapy by switching to
        Framingham risk scoring [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have reported that the proportions of
        treatment-eligible primary prevention <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who received no drug therapy reached as high
        as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,19</NUMEX>]. In our study, statin use was reported in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 44%</NUMEX> of moderate-risk patient
        visits for which a diagnosis of hyperlipidemia was noted, which is surprisingly low given
        that the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> would be expected to benefit from statin therapy. We also concur with
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> who have discussed the role that inadequate lifestyle counseling plays in
        the existing cholesterol treatment gaps [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,13</NUMEX>]. Our data show that lifestyle counseling
        occurred during <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 50%</NUMEX> of new and general medical examination visits by
        moderate-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, even though these types of visits arguably represent better
        opportunities for counseling services than return, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>-focused visits.
        It is intriguing to note that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> increases in statin use were not sustained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
        and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Studies using alternative data <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are needed to corroborate this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX>, and detailed market research is necessary for understanding the underlying
        causes of this unexpected decline in use. We speculate that the observed trends may be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">partially</ENAMEX> explained by discordant rates of increase in the diagnosis of hyperlipidemia
        versus the prescribing of statins. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> data released after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> will
        help determine whether the noted declines are due to random fluctuations in data
        reporting.
        Wide gaps between evidence-based lipid-lowering therapy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> practice were
        reported in many other western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as well. For instance, a survey conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 32%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> received
        lipid-lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. Likewise, in a population-based study from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, merely <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> eligible for lipid-lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> were actually
        treated [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>].
        In spite of being clearly underused, statins increasingly dominate lipid-lowering drug
        therapy, accounting for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92%</NUMEX> of all lipid-lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, which confirms
        the trends seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pharmacy</ENAMEX> dispensing data [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Also, in concert with
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>], we observed a shift in the leading statin prescribed over time,
        from lovastatin to simvastatin and then to atorvastatin, corresponding to their market
        entry. Atorvastatin accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of all statin use in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Even though most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statins</ENAMEX> share similar tolerability, some evidence shows that atorvastatin has greater
        dose-specific potency for lowering LDL-C and total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>].
        Additionally, our data add support to available literature documenting inequities in use
        of statins for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with different social and clinical characteristics [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23â€“26</NUMEX>]. Of
        particular note are the lower rates of statin use in at-risk younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-Americans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> cared for by non-cardiologists. These findings may be
        useful for guiding targeted interventions that aim to bring physician practice into
        agreement with published guidelines for cardiovascular risk reduction.
        Our findings must be interpreted in the context of data limitations. Although both NAMCS
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> are designed to produce nationally representative estimates, these estimates are
        not linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> but to patient visits. As a result, reported statin use may
        overestimate the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> prescribed drug therapy likely make
        more visits because of greater disease severity and/or the need of frequent follow-ups.
        Also, we are missing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with risk factors who have not been seen by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> or
        whose risk factors failed to be recorded. On the other hand, underestimation is also
        possible, for example, because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>' lack of awareness or incomplete reporting of
        patient medication uses. However, the failure to inquire or report an important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> such
        as a statin may be a clinical oversight in itself and contribute to therapeutic gaps. The
        degree of inaccuracy in our estimates is perhaps small, however, as suggested by the
        comparability of the current results to previous reports.
        Lack of detailed clinical data prohibits accurate risk assessment based on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX>
        risk scoring. While the risk factor counting algorithm that we used may simulate practical
        risk estimation by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, it precludes the assessment of appropriateness of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statin</ENAMEX> use in relation to the latest lipid-lowering guidelines. This creates difficulty
        interpreting the rate of statin use observed for the moderate-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. In particular,
        adequate information is not available to differentiate varying levels of absolute risk
        among the moderate-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. We likely misclassified some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> as moderate risk when
        they may have actually been high risk despite the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> or CHD equivalents. On the
        other hand, indications for statins might be marginal for some young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with modestly
        elevated risk factors. A final caveat is that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> captures patient
        compliance or outcomes, although these are perhaps separate issues from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> adherence
        to evidence-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>.
        Despite the acknowledged limitations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMCS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHAMCS</ENAMEX> cover a longer consecutive time
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">span</ENAMEX> and provide more complete information about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>-specific physician activities than
        many other national data bases, e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Expenditures Panel Survey</ENAMEX>, the National
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Assessment Nutrition Examination Survey</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health Interview</ENAMEX>
        Survey.
        In conclusion, persistent gaps in statin therapy suggest a continued need for improved
        CHD risk stratification of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and treatment with statins when indicated.
        Information technology and broader national policy around quality measurement and reporting
        are just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> potential strategies that could be used to improve current practice.
        Patient-centered interventions should strengthen patient education and improve patient
        access to different treatment options. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interventions</ENAMEX> should be targeted to at-risk patients
        whose drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regimens</ENAMEX> need to be reassessed and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, particularly
        non-cardiologists, whose practices need be improved. Guidelines for cardiovascular risk
        reduction treatment and determination of the specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who can benefit from statin
        therapy will continue to evolve. Indications for use in primary <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CHD</ENAMEX> prevention are likely
        to expand for statins. Given the observed practice shortfalls, drug therapy in
        moderate-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> remains an important priority for improvement.
      
    
  
