
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diabetic</ENAMEX> nephropathy (DNP) is a serious and common complication of type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and type 2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes mellitus</ENAMEX>, leading to end-stage renal failure in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 30%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. Early abnormalities of DNP affect glomeruli and include an increase in glomerular
        filtration rate, microalbuminuria, glomerular hypertrophy, and thickening of the glomerular
        basement membrane, followed by expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mesangial extracellular matrix</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glomerulosclerosis</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,2</NUMEX>]. As with most chronic degenerative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney diseases</ENAMEX>, the gradual
        decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal</ENAMEX> function at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later</TIMEX> stages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> is invariably associated with tubular
        epithelial degeneration (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX>), also called tubular atrophy, and interstitial fibrosis (IF),
        hallmarks of degeneration to end-stage renal failure [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. Pathomechanisms that may initiate
        and/or mediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> remain poorly understood. While glomerular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> consistent
        with human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX> have been described in various mouse models of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and IF have not
        been described in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mice</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>].
        Combining detailed renal phenotype analysis with gene expression profiling of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hyperglycemic</ENAMEX> mouse models of type 1 (streptozotocin [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STZ</ENAMEX>]) and type 2 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">db/db</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, we
        recently reported that decreased mRNA levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36</ENAMEX> in kidneys were strongly correlated
        with albuminuria [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. CD36 is a transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of the class B scavenger receptor
        family and is involved in multiple biological processes [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. CD36 is widely expressed and
        may interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple extracellular ligands</ENAMEX>, including thrombospondin-1 (TSP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>),
        long-chain free fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> (FFAs), modified (oxidized) low-density <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lipoprotein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>-LDL),
        advanced glycation end (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX>) products, and collagens I and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. CD36 mediates
        phagocytosis of apoptotic cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>-parasitized erythrocytes [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. Furthermore, CD36
        mediates antiangiogenic activity associated with endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> apoptosis induced by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TSP-1</ENAMEX> through p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> kinase (MAPK) and caspase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. Hyperglycemia-induced synthesis of
        CD36 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in macrophages has been associated with increased uptake of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>-LDL by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> and foam cell formation in atherosclerotic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,9,10</NUMEX>]. While diabetic cardiovascular complications are closely linked epidemiologically
        with albuminuria and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX>, a role for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal pathophysiology</ENAMEX> has not to our
        knowledge been described to date.
        Here we report a novel functional role for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">CD36</TIMEX> scavenger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX> and FFA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palmitate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>) in tubular epithelial apoptosis associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX>.
        Specifically, we show that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose stimulates CD36</ENAMEX> cell surface expression in proximal
        tubular epithelial cells (PTECs), and increased <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">CD36</NUMEX> renders PTECs susceptible to both AGE-
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEC</ENAMEX> apoptosis by mediating sequential activation of src kinase,
        proapoptotic p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>, and caspase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Based on these findings, we propose a new two-step
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metabolic</ENAMEX> hit model for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> in the progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>
          Kidneys were obtained from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28-wk</NUMEX>-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C57BLKS/J</ENAMEX>-lepr
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">db/db</ENAMEX> , STZ-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C57BL/6J</ENAMEX>, or STZ-treated 129SvJ <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and from
          age-matched control <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C57BLKS/J</ENAMEX>-lepr
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">db/m</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C57BL/6J</ENAMEX>, and 129SvJ <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> as described [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        
        
          Cell Culture
          Human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proximal</ENAMEX> tubular cell line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK-2</ENAMEX> and murine collecting duct cell line <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M1</NUMEX> were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collection</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manassas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and
          cultured according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>'s instructions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse proximal</ENAMEX> tubular cell line MCT was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>). Transfections were performed with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Fugene 6</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche Diagnostics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol. CD36-containing plasmid was
          a kind gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nada Abumhrad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUNY</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stony Brook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). Cells were
          also co-transfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Lakes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) to
          assess transfection efficiency. Cells were serum starved in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> serum containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>
          g/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">l glucose</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 24</NUMEX> h prior to stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGEâ</ENAMEX>€“bovine serum albumin (BSA),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX>, or FFA.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Quantitative Real-Time PCR</ENAMEX>
          Quantitative real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HPRT1</TIMEX>, and beta actin was
          performed as described previously [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. The following primers were used: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> CD36 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5â</NUMEX>€²
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGCTGGAGCTGTTATTGGTG</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3â</NUMEX>€² <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CATGAGAATGCCTCCAAACA</ENAMEX>, mouse beta actin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5â</NUMEX>€²
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACCGTGAAAAGATGATGACCCAG</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3â</NUMEX>€² <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGCCTGGATGGCTACGTACA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> HPRT1 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5â</NUMEX>€² TGTTGTTGGATATGCCCTTG
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3â</NUMEX>€² <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTGCGCTCATCTTAGGCTTT</ENAMEX>, human CD36 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5â</NUMEX>€² <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTCTGGGGCTACAAAGATG</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3â</NUMEX>€²
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAGGGAGAGATATCGGGCCT</ENAMEX>, human beta actin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5â</NUMEX>€² <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATGAGATTGGCATGGCTTT</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3â</NUMEX>€²
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CACCTTCACCGTTCCAGTTT</ENAMEX>, and human HPRT1 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5â</NUMEX>€² <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAAGGACCCCACGAAGTGTT</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3â</NUMEX>€²
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCAAGGGCATATCCTACAACAA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunostaining</ENAMEX> and Immunoblotting
          Primary antibodies specific for the following <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were used: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monoclonal</ENAMEX> mouse
          anti-CD36 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, clone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6â€“152</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunotech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fullerton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>), clone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMO</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgM</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>), rabbit polyclonal anti-CD36 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>), rabbit polyclonal
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">aquaporin1</NUMEX>, anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">aquaporin2</NUMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Na/K/2Cl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon, Temecula</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>), rabbit polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">phospho38/MAPK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse monoclonal</ENAMEX> p38 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Signaling</ENAMEX>
          Technology, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), rabbit polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX>-src (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y418</NUMEX>)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosource</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camarillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> monoclonal anti-tubulin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). Immunostaining was performed on frozen
          sections with FITC- and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Cy3</NUMEX>-labeled secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), or
          on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">paraffin</NUMEX>-embedded sections with immunoperoxidase, as described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
          Immunoblotting was performed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 Î¼g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> isolated from cultured cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Protein</ENAMEX>
          samples were resolved on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE and immunoblotted with primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> and
          revealed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> radish peroxidase (HRP)-conjugated anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgM</ENAMEX>, or anti-rabbit IgG
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Laboratory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bar Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). Immuncomplexes were detected by
          enhanced chemiluminescence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). The proximal
          tubular immunostaining was evaluated semi-quantitatively by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> independent pathologists
          who were unaware of the diagnosis; distribution and intensity of staining was scored on a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-point scale.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluorescence Flow Cytometric Analysis</ENAMEX>
          Cells were incubated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX>, scraped, and then
          washed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum. Cells were then exposed to monoclonal anti-CD36 IgG
          FA6 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>), or control mouse IgG1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 min</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> in the presence
          of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum then washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. This was followed by an incubation with
          phycoerythrin-conjugated goat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-murine</ENAMEX> secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Biotechnology</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 min</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. Cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Ã— 10</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ) were analyzed by using a SCAN flow cytometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Lakes</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), with appropriate gating. Flow cytometry data were analyzed
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cellquest</ENAMEX> (BD).
        
        
          Preparation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glycated Albumin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carboxymethyl-Lysine Albumin</ENAMEX>
          Briefly, to prepare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX>, essentially fatty-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-free and endotoxin-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">250</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/ml</ENAMEX>) was incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 5</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> wk with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D-glucose</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">500 mM</NUMEX>) in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX>-M
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX> buffer containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EDTA</ENAMEX>, ampicillin, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fungazone</ENAMEX>, polymixin B, and protease
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> preparations were treated identically except that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> was
          omitted. Carboxymethyl-lysine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML)â€“BSA</ENAMEX> was prepared as described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> with minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX> content (CMLmin-BSA) was prepared by incubation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.66 mM</NUMEX>)
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glyoxylic acid</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.15 mM</NUMEX>) in the presence of sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cyanoboronydrate</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">56 mM</NUMEX>) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
          mM sodium phosphate buffer (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.8</NUMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> Â°C under aseptic conditions. Finally,
          preparations were extensively dialyzed against phosphate buffer to remove free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>.
          Preparations were then tested for the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Quantitative Chromogenic</ENAMEX> LAL
          lower than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.07</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IU/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mg protein</ENAMEX> in all preparations.
        
        
          Preparation of FFA
          Palmitic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">P5585</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oleic acid</ENAMEX>, and FFA-free low-endotoxin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">A8806</NUMEX>) were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>. Palmitic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> was dissolved at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> mM in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX>
          fatty-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, sonicated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX>, shaken <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37 Â°C</TIMEX>, and sonicated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> again [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. For control experiments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acids</ENAMEX> was prepared,
          as described above. The effective concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> was determined using a commercially
          available kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wako Chemicals, Neuss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Apoptosis Detection
          In situ detection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fragmentation</ENAMEX> was performed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ApoTag TUNEL</ENAMEX> assay
          following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Purchase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>].
          Apoptotic nuclei were detected using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX> staining (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min) in cell cultures
          fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde, and analyzed via fluorescence microscopy to assess
          chromatin condensation and segregation. Caspase3 activity was detected by using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ApoAlert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caspase3 Fluorescent Detection</ENAMEX> system (BD) according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          protocol. Activity was normalized to total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> content. Z-DEVD-fmk, z-VAD-fmk,
          z-FA-fmk, and z-LEHD-fmk were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Kidney Biopsy Sample and Patient Characteristics</ENAMEX>
          Human kidney tissues (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> controls, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diabetic nephropathy</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> with focal
          segmental glomerulosclerosis [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSGS</ENAMEX>]) were obtained from archived kidney biopsy samples or
          from discarded nephrectomy specimens. All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diabetic samples</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
          biopsy-proven advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> with serum <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatinine</ENAMEX> ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/dl (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151</NUMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">444 Î¼M/l</ENAMEX>), heavy proteinuria (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>+ by dipstick or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3â€“6 gr/d</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>. All patients
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSGS</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with creatinine levels of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/dl (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151 to 435</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼M/l</ENAMEX>), heavy proteinuria (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>+ by dipstick), and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>. The diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSGS</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made on Periodic</ENAMEX> acidâ€“Schiff staining in the absence of immunodeposits on electron
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microscopy</ENAMEX>. The diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diabetic nephropathy</ENAMEX> was based on the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>,
          proteinuria, and the characteristic light microscopy findings. Institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Board</ENAMEX>
          approval was obtained for procurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney specimens</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Hospital</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Methods</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> are reported as mean and standard error of the mean (SEM) for continuous
          variables. All cell culture experiments were performed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> times and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summarized</ENAMEX>. Standard software packages (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPSS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Excel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>) were used to provide
          descriptive statistical plots (unpaired 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> -tests). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonferroni</ENAMEX> correction was used for multiple comparisons.
          Significance for the quantification of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD36</NUMEX> staining in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biopsy samples</ENAMEX> was
          calculated via the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wilcoxon Rank Sum Test</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Increased <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Expression of CD36 Specifically in Proximal Tubules of Human Diabetic</ENAMEX>
          Kidneys Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX>
          Using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microarray</ENAMEX>-based gene expression profiling on whole kidney <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> together with
          supervised clustering methods, we previously identified and validated gene expression
          patterns for molecular classification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mice</ENAMEX> with albuminuria and mesangial
          expansion [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. Reduced renal mRNA levels of the class B scavenger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor CD36</ENAMEX> were
          characteristic for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mice</ENAMEX> with albuminuria [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. Here we examined patterns of CD36
          protein expression in kidneys of non-diabetic and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. CD36 protein
          was detectable in the thick ascending limb of loop of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henle</ENAMEX> and in the collecting duct,
          and absent in proximal tubules in both control and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mouse kidneys</ENAMEX> (Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1Aâ€“1D</ENAMEX>).
          In contrast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> was detectable only rarely in individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proximal</ENAMEX> tubular cells in
          sections from non-diabetic human kidneys (controls) (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1E and 1H</TIMEX>), but was markedly
          increased specifically in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diabetic kidneys</ENAMEX> (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1F and 1I</TIMEX>). In
          addition, we did not observe increased proximal tubular CD36 expression in kidney biopsy
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSGS</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1J</NUMEX>), that were matched with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP samples</ENAMEX> for the
          severity of proteinuria (all in the nephrotic range) and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal insufficiency</ENAMEX> (all with
          elevated serum creatinine; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7â€“5.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/dl). Semi-quantitative analysis of the distribution
          and intensity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX>-positive PTECs (CD36 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEC</ENAMEX> score), which was performed by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pathologists</ENAMEX> in a blinded manner, demonstrated that mean CD36 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEC</ENAMEX> scores
          were not different between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSGS</ENAMEX> kidneys and normal human kidneys, but were significantly
          increased in DNP kidneys (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1K</NUMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Periodic acidâ€“Schiffâ€“stained</ENAMEX> sections of kidneys from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> exposed to type 2 diabetes
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">db</ENAMEX>/db <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 wk</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX>), or type 1 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> (STZ-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C57BL/6J</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wk</ENAMEX> (data not shown) demonstrated moderate to advanced mesangial expansion and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glomerulosclerosis</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX>). Tubular abnormalities were not detectable in either model
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX>). In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and IF were associated with moderate to advanced mesangial
          expansion and glomerulosclerosis on kidney sections of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2B</NUMEX>). These
          findings indicate that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upregulation</ENAMEX> of CD36
          expression in proximal tubules was associated with moderate to advanced stages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and
          IF. In contrast, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mice</ENAMEX> with albuminuria, mesangial expansion, and
          glomerulosclerosis, absence of CD36 expression was associated with normal appearance of
          the tubular epithelium and interstitial space. These findings suggest an association
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proximal</ENAMEX> tubular CD36 expression and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coincidence of Increased CD36 Expression and Increased Tubular Epithelial Cell</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apoptosis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human DNP</ENAMEX>
          CD36 has been shown to mediate apoptosis signaling induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TSP-1</ENAMEX> in endothelial
          cells [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>-LDL in macrophages [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]. We examined whether the strong upregulation
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36 protein</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX>, observed specifically in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>, was associated with tubular
          epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell apoptosis</ENAMEX> in vivo. TUNEL-positive tubular epithelial cells also stained
          positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36 protein</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2D</NUMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aquaporin1</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2C</NUMEX>), indicating that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> expression coincided in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>. In contrast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> was not
          detectable in TUNEL-positive PTECs in non-diabetic FSGS kidneys and in normal human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kidney</ENAMEX> (data not shown). Statistical analysis showed that the rate of TUNEL-positive
          tubular cells was significantly increased in kidneys of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX> compared with normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> human kidney (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2E</NUMEX>). In addition, tubular epithelial apoptosis was
          increased, but highly variable, in FSGS kidneys (data not shown). In contrast, tubular
          epithelial apoptosis rates were comparable between non-diabetic control and all diabetic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse kidneys</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2E</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mouse</ENAMEX> group included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24-wk</NUMEX>-old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">STZ-</ENAMEX>treated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">diabetic C57BL/6J</ENAMEX> or 129SvJ <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.23 Â± 0.1</NUMEX> TUNEL-positive cells per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> tubular cells)
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24-wk</NUMEX>-old lepr
          db/db <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.2 Â± 0.1</NUMEX> TUNEL-positive cells per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> tubular cells).
          Together, these findings indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> is associated with
          apoptotic events of proximal tubular cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> specifically in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>, but not in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSGS</ENAMEX> with matched functional and clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">abnormalities</ENAMEX>. These in vivo findings
          demonstrate a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>-induced CD36 expression and apoptosis in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>, suggesting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> may play a critical role in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> by mediating
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEC</ENAMEX> apoptosis in progressive human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          High <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ambient Glucose Induces CD36 Expression in Human</ENAMEX> PTECs
          High ambient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> has been shown to induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36 protein synthesis</ENAMEX> in macrophages
          [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. Because CD36 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was markedly increased in proximal tubules in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>, we
          examined the effects of high ambient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> mRNA and protein expression in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human PTEC</ENAMEX> line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK-2</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Exposure of cells to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-glucose for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX>, but not
          to control L-glucose, significantly increased levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3A</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> cell
          surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3C</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36 protein</ENAMEX> expression in cell lysates (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3D</NUMEX>). In
          contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were not detectable in the murine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEC</ENAMEX> line MCT at either
          normal or high ambient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose concentrations</ENAMEX> (data not shown). Interestingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          stimulation decreased <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD36</NUMEX> mRNA levels (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3B</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (Figure
          3C) in the murine collecting duct cell line <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M1</NUMEX>, consistent with our previously reported
          findings in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mouse</ENAMEX> kidney [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. Exposure of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HK-2</ENAMEX> and murine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1</ENAMEX> cell lines to
          defined preparations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA PA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> had no effect on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> mRNA and protein
          expression levels (data not shown). These findings demonstrate that high ambient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          causes upregulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> specifically in human, but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX>. Together with our in vivo observations, these results suggest that hyperglycemia
          may induce upregulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> and protein selectively in proximal tubules in
          kidneys of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>, but not <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mice</ENAMEX> with albuminuria.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML-BSA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA PA Induce Apoptosis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human PTECs</ENAMEX> via CD36
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complications</ENAMEX>, including tubular degeneration [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>] and tubular epithelial-to-mesenchymal
          transition [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX> albumin and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> are known to interact with CD36
          [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,20</NUMEX>]. However, it is not known whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> can activate CD36 signaling and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in tubular epithelial cells. Treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 5</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 wk</NUMEX> or with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX>-BSA induced a significant increase in the number of apoptotic nuclei in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX>-positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cells compared with control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BSA-</ENAMEX>treated or untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cells (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>). In
          contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML-BSA</ENAMEX> had no effect on the rate of apoptotic nuclei in
          CD36-negative murine MCT PTECs (data not shown). Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> glycated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> wk
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA5</ENAMEX>) induced robust apoptosis at concentrations <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 20</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 Î¼M</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>),
          we chose this preparation and concentration for further analysis in all subsequent
          experiments. AGE-BSA5-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apoptosis</ENAMEX> was blocked when cells were preincubated with
          neutralizing anti-CD36 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, while preincubation with control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG antibody</ENAMEX> had no
          effect (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>). These results were confirmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA laddering assay</ENAMEX> (data not
          shown).
          Among the most abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose-modified proteins</ENAMEX> detectable in the plasma of diabetic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>], which are typically present at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.6 to 2.3 Î</NUMEX>¼M
          concentrations in the plasma and urine of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diabetic individuals</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22,23</NUMEX>]. To use
          physiologically relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CML proteins</ENAMEX> in our in vitro experiments, we prepared
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMLmin-BSA</ENAMEX>, characterized by glycation of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 30%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lysine residues</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]. When
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK-2 PTECs</ENAMEX> at concentrations ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 to 10 Î¼M</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMLmin-BSA</ENAMEX> increased
          apoptosis rates significantly (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4B</NUMEX>). The proapoptotic effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMLmin-BSA</ENAMEX> was
          blocked by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, but not by control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4B</NUMEX>).
          CD36 has been shown to transport fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> in adipocytes [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>] and in muscle cells
          [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. Concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFAs</ENAMEX> may be substantially elevated, to levels of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 700 Î¼M</NUMEX>, in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> or obesity [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]. Thus, we examined the effects of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saturated FFA PA</ENAMEX> and monounsaturated FFA oleate on apoptosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK-2 PTECs</ENAMEX> in the absence
          or presence of anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX> neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> significantly increased rates of
          apoptotic nuclei in a concentration-dependent manner in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK-2 PTECs</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4C</NUMEX>). Anti-CD36
          neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, but not control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX>, blocked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apoptosis</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4C</NUMEX>). In
          contrast, oleate did not induce apoptosis, even at concentrations <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as high as 300</NUMEX> Î¼M
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4C</NUMEX>), neither did it prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apoptosis</ENAMEX> (data not shown). Of note, these
          experiments were performed using a total fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.6</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>, in order to
          closely model pathophysiologic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in which unbound FFA concentration is high [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>].
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML-BSA</ENAMEX>, as well as saturated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA PA</ENAMEX>, induce apoptosis in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTECs</ENAMEX> at
          concentrations previously observed in plasma and/or urine in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA Sequentially Activate</ENAMEX> src kinase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Proapoptotic</ENAMEX> p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>, and Caspase
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> through CD36 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Receptor</ENAMEX>
          CD36 has previously been shown to trigger the activation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p59fyn</TIMEX>, p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caspase</ENAMEX> 3 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneID</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">836</ENAMEX>) in response to thrombospondin in endothelial cells [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. Therefore
          we examined phospho-src, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">phospho-p38</TIMEX> levels and caspase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> activation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK-2</ENAMEX> PTECs
          treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> in the absence or presence of anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX> neutralizing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-BSA5</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> increased phospho-src levels rapidly (after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as little as 5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX>), and over a prolonged time interval (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 3</NUMEX> h) (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5A and 5B</TIMEX>). Phosphorylation
          of src kinase was blocked by anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX> neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5A and 5B</TIMEX>). This
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX> is consistent with previous findings demonstrating direct interaction between
          CD36 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p59fyn</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]; however, the involvement of other src <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> cannot be excluded. We
          also observed increased levels of phosphorylation of p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 to 2</TIMEX> h after
          treatment, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> was also completely blocked by anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX> neutralizing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5C and 5D</TIMEX>). These findings indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36 activates proapoptotic</ENAMEX> p38
          MAPK possibly via src kinase activation in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTECs</ENAMEX> when stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AGE-BSA5</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA. Chemical</ENAMEX> inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p38 MAPK</ENAMEX> prevented the increase in the rate of apoptotic
          nuclei induced by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-BSA5</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK-2 PTECs</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5G</NUMEX>), indicating that p38
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> function is required for apoptosis induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36 receptor</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> significantly increased activity of effector caspase <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 in human</TIMEX> PTECs
          (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5E and 5F</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caspase 3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> was blocked by anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX> neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>,
          but not by control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5E and 5F</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-caspase inhibitor z-VAD-fmk and the
          specific caspase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> inhibitor z-DEVD-fmk prevented apoptosis induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX>,
          while the specific caspase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> inhibitor z-LEHD-fmk had no significant inhibitor effect
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5G</NUMEX>). Together these findings indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36 receptor</ENAMEX> mediates sequential
          phosphorylation of src kinases and p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>, leading to activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase 3</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">PTECs</ENAMEX> exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> ligands. Interestingly, we did not
          observe phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Smad2</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p42/44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK MAPK</ENAMEX> under these conditions, as
          previously reported for AGE binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RAGE receptor</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>].
        
        
          CD36 <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Sufficient to Mediate Apoptosis Induced</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and FFA
          In contrast with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX>-positive human <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK-2 PTECs</ENAMEX>, we found that treatment of
          CD36-negative mouse MCT PTECs with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> had no effect on rates of apoptotic nuclei
          (data not shown). To test whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> was sufficient to mediate AGE-BSA-induced
          apoptosis, we transfected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX>-negative mouse MCT PTECs with a plasmid expressing human
          CD36 or empty control vector, followed by treatment with control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AGE-BSA5</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AGE-BSA5</ENAMEX> treatment had no significant effect on rates of apoptotic nuclei in MCT PTECs
          transfected with control vector (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> significantly increased
          apoptotic nuclei compared with unglycated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in MCT PTECs transiently transfected with
          CD36 expression vector (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). Nonglycated control albumin did not cause apoptosis.
          Thus, transgenic de novo expression of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX>-negative mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTECs</ENAMEX> was
          sufficient to mediate apoptosis induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Advanced diabetic nephropathies in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> are uniformly
        characterized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX>, or tubular atrophy, and IF leading to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal failure</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,30</NUMEX>]. Although
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and IF are the strongest predictors for progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>], mechanisms that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underlie TED</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> remain poorly understood. Based on our in vitro and in vivo findings we
        propose a two-step metabolic hit model for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX>. High ambient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, but not AGE or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX>, cause stimulation of CD36 expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> specifically in diabetic kidneys.
        Increased CD36 expression mediates sequential activation of src kinase, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proapoptotic</ENAMEX> p38
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>, and caspase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA PA</ENAMEX>, resulting in PTEC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proximal</ENAMEX> tubular epithelial apoptosis may be an initial mechanism for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX>.
        Our conclusions are supported by several key observations. First, we identify a new
        functional role for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> as an essential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> of proximal tubular epithelial apoptosis,
        inducible by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMLmin-BSA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA PA. Previous</ENAMEX> reports demonstrated a role for CD36
        in mediating apoptosis induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TSP-1</ENAMEX> in endothelial cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>-LDL in macrophages
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,14</NUMEX>]. In the present study, we show for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, to our knowledge, that CD36
        mediates apoptosis in differentiated epithelial cells that are exposed to AGE-BSA-,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CMLmin-BSA-</ENAMEX>, and FFA-induced metabolic injury characteristic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic milieu</ENAMEX>.
        Interestingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX> albumins and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX> are present in the urine of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>
        with albuminuria due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> and have been shown to bind proximal tubular epithelium
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22,32</NUMEX>]. While the presence or absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFAs</ENAMEX> in the urine of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diabetics</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> has not
        been determined to date, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFAs</ENAMEX> may cause tubular apoptosis [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>]. It remains to be determined
        whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> interacts with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD36</NUMEX> to activate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36 receptor</ENAMEX> signaling, or whether CD36
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mediates FFA</ENAMEX> uptake to activate src kinase and p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> signaling. Irrespective of the
        upstream mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">interaction</ENAMEX>, our results demonstrate very rapid
        activation of a well-characterized intracellular kinase cascade of proapoptotic signaling.
        Our finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE-BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> induce apoptosis through a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD36</NUMEX>-mediated and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p38</NUMEX>- and
        caspase-dependent mechanism in tubular epithelial cells, similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TSP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>-LDL in
        endothelial cells and macrophages, respectively, suggests that multiple, context-dependent
        extracellular stimuli of apoptosis may converge on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">CD36</TIMEX> scavenger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> to activate src
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proapoptotic</ENAMEX> p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> pathway. In the context of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diabetic milieu</ENAMEX> and
        diabetic complications, our findings provide new molecular insights into <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>-induced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX>-dependent injury of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal</ENAMEX> epithelial cells.
        Almost all TUNEL-positive apoptotic tubular epithelial cells showed increased expression
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX>, suggesting a strong correlation between upregulation of CD36 expression and
        increased apoptosis in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> specifically in human diabetic kidney in vivo. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Importantly,</ENAMEX>
        biopsy samples from cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSGS</ENAMEX> that were matched for degree of proteinuria, renal
        function, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> were characterized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX>, IF, and increased tubular epithelial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX>; however, proximal tubular CD36 expression was similar to that in normal human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> kidney. Therefore, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> is specifically associated with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetic condition</ENAMEX> and appears to be independent of degree of proteinuria and renal
        failure. Indeed, increased CD36 expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX> in vivo may be caused by
        hyperglycemia, as we show that high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose concentration stimulates CD36</ENAMEX> expression in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitro</ENAMEX>. It is intriguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD36</ENAMEX> expression was not detected in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mice</ENAMEX>
        with longstanding hyperglycemia in vivo, although underlying mechanisms for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species-dependent</ENAMEX> differential regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD36</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> in vivo and in vitro between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human</ENAMEX> remain unclear at this time. Comparisons of human 
        CD36 and mouse 
        Cd36 genes indicate a high degree of sequence and structural similarity
        in both coding and regulatory regions, suggesting that the mechanism or mechanisms that
        underlie our findings are likely determined by sequence-independent, epigenetically
        distinct response patterns to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diabetic milieu</ENAMEX> that differ between these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. It is
        also possible that dietary or metabolic factors account for the differences in CD36
        expression, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were maintained on standard mouse chow characterized by significantly
        lower fat and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> contents than typical western diets consumed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. However,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dietary</ENAMEX> or other unknown environmental factors cannot explain the differential CD36
        regulation by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> in human and mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTECs</ENAMEX>. Thus, we are exploring whether biochemical
        or functional differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTECs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose metabolism</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX>-induced signaling can be identified. However, current lack of understanding of the
        observed differential regulation between human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> does not diminish the
        translational research significance of our findings, with their clear therapeutic
        implications. Thus, the present study identifies a new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36-dependent</TIMEX> molecular signaling
        pathway that mediates tubular epithelial apoptosis, and may underlie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and IF, hallmarks
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> progression, specifically in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diabetic nephropathy</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, to our knowledge, our report provides the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> controlled study demonstrating
        increased apoptosis specifically in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTECs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and IF. These findings are
        consistent with a recent uncontrolled case series of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>], and with
        previous reports demonstrating tubular apoptosis in kidneys of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">STZ-</ENAMEX>treated diabetic rats
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,36</NUMEX>]. Interestingly, our study shows that tubular epithelial apoptosis was associated
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and IF in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>, while normal appearance of tubular epithelium and
        interstitium was associated with baseline apoptosis rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mouse</ENAMEX> models.
        Together, published observations from experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> models in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human DNP</ENAMEX>, and our own findings in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic mouse</ENAMEX> models and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>, suggest a striking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and tubular epithelial apoptosis. However, whether tubular epithelial
        apoptosis causes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX> will require further investigation. Interestingly, acute and
        chronic chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inhibition</ENAMEX> of caspase activity in a nephrotoxic serum nephritis model of
        chronic progressive glomerulonephritis with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and IF reduced tubular apoptosis and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX>
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>]. Decreased tubular apoptosis and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> were associated with significantly reduced IF and
        decreased collagen synthesis in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. This finding suggests that tubular epithelial
        apoptosis may trigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> and IF in this model of chronic glomerulonephritis in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>, and
        supports our conclusions that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>-induced tubular epithelial apoptosis may underlie
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX> associated with IF in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>.
        In conclusion, we report a new functional role for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">CD36</TIMEX> scavenger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> in tubular
        epithelial apoptosis associated with tubular degeneration and progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNP</ENAMEX>.
        Specifically, we show for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA PA</ENAMEX> induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTEC</ENAMEX> apoptosis
        through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD36</NUMEX>-mediated activation of src kinase, p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>, and caspase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Because high
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose stimulates CD36</ENAMEX> expression in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTECs</ENAMEX> and because CD36 expression is increased
        in apoptotic tubular epithelial cells in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>, we propose a two-step metabolic hit
        model relevant for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TED</ENAMEX>, a hallmark of progression of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNP</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
        
          Accession Numbers
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LocusLink</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ncbi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nlm</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nih</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/LocusLink/</ENAMEX>) accession numbers for the gene
          products discussed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are caspase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneID</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">836</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD36</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneID</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">948</ENAMEX>), MAPK
          (GeneID: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1432</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p42/44</NUMEX> ERK MAPK (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneID</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50689</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p59fyn</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneID</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2534</ENAMEX>), and Smad2
          (GeneID: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4087</ENAMEX>).
        
      
    
  
