
  
    
      
        
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 300 million</NUMEX> acute cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> globally, resulting in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a million</NUMEX> deaths. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of deaths due to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> occur in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> south
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sahara</ENAMEX>, and most occur in young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> types of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">malariaâ</ENAMEX>€”
        Plasmodium vivax , 
        P. malariae , 
        P. ovale , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. falciparum â€”</ENAMEX>
        P. falciparum <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> is most common in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, and it accounts
        for most of the extremely high mortality south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sahara</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Malaria parasites</ENAMEX> are developing unacceptable levels of drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>, and many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insecticides</ENAMEX> are no longer useful against <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX> transmitting the disease. Vaccine
        research has produced few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful candidates</ENAMEX>, and although <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> are poured
        into research, an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> away.
        One recurring theme in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> vaccine research has been the high frequency of the gene
        for sickle cell hemoglobin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HbS</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> endemic regions, which is believed to be due to
        a heterozygote (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HbAS</ENAMEX>) advantage against fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>. The mechanism behind the high degree
        of resistance conferred by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HbAS</ENAMEX> in severe and complicated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> is still unknown, but
        recent observations have suggested the mechanism might involve an immune component.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> reason that the best way
        to test whether <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> protection by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HbAS</ENAMEX> has a significant immune component is to see
        whether protection varies with age. They studied the age-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> pattern in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,054</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kilifi District</ENAMEX> on the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>. They argued that if
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> protection provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HbAS</ENAMEX> were innate, it should be independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>
        exposure and remain constant with age. However, if immune mechanisms were involved,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> should increase with age until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> become functionally immune, when
        additional immunological advantage should be lost.
        They found that overall <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HbAS</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 40%</NUMEX> protective against mild <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">clinical malaria</ENAMEX>.
        Protection varied with age, increasing from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20% to 60%</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first ten years</TIMEX> of life,
        and thereafter returning to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than ten years old</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> admit that this observation could be due to any factor that affects <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>
        risk and varies with age but state that accelerated immune acquisition seems the most
        likely explanation. They suggest several mechanisms for how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HbAS</ENAMEX> could accelerate immune
        acquisition; for example, immunity could be mediated by accelerated acquisition of
        antibodies to altered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host antigens</ENAMEX> expressed on the parasite-infected red cell
        surface.
        In discussing their findings the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> point out that their study focused on mild
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>. For accelerated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>-specific immunity to be relevant to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HbAS</ENAMEX> selection it
        would have to operate within a period of maximum risk for severe and fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>. They
        note that in a recent study, conducted by another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, protection
        against severe <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HbAS</ENAMEX> was only seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2â€“16 months old</TIMEX>, but that in that
        study, no analysis was presented that addressed the effect of age within that range.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> conclude that the relevance of their current observations on mild clinical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> to protection against severe and fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> are unknown, and that further work
        must be done to better understand the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HbAS</ENAMEX> in protection against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
