
  
    
      
        
        I am writing in response to an essay published in the most recent issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Hayden</ENAMEX>, entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúAlas, Poor Yorick: Digging Up</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead to Make Medical Diagnoses‚</ENAMEX>Äù [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of the 
        Science piece with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori B. Andrews</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hayden</ENAMEX> references, I am troubled
        by her comment on our article. Nowhere in that article, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúEthics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constructing Ethical</ENAMEX>
        Guidelines for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biohistory‚Äù</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>], do we suggest that genetic testing be done on deceased
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> for historically significant questions. In fact, we specifically highlight some
        of the ethical, legal, social, and scientific issues that such testing raises and recommend
        that guidelines be developed in order to monitor current research that is being undertaken
        in this area. The article does not advocate biohistorical research. This distinction is
        very important and one that is quite evident upon a careful reading of our article.
      
    
  
