
  
    
      
        
        Adverse side effects, viral resistance, and the high cost of antiretroviral therapies
        remain obstacles in the way of turning <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> into a manageable chronic disease.
        Structured treatment interruptions (STIs) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who have good viral control on
        therapy have been proposed as a strategy for overcoming these obstacles. The initial hope
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STIs</ENAMEX> would help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> achieve greater viral control has so far not been supported
        by data from clinical trials, but interrupting treatment has also been proposed as a
        strategy to reduce the cost of long-term therapy and drug-associated toxicity.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Montaner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> now report results from a randomized trial of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> on their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> regimen, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> on regimens containing
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 weeks</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> successive treatment interruptions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX>, followed
        by a final open-ended interruption for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        The study was designed to be able to detect a difference of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX> or greater
        between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for the time to viral rebound during the open-ended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interruptionâ</ENAMEX>€”the
        primary outcome. No difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> was seen (median time for the group
        on continuous treatment was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX>, and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks</TIMEX>).
        Secondary outcomes included serious adverse events (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> progression, acute
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retroviral syndrome</ENAMEX>, therapy failure, or opportunistic infections at any point in the
        study), changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD4</TIMEX> count on therapy, immune reconstitution changes (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD4</TIMEX> recall
        responses and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CD4 naÃ¯ve</ENAMEX>/memory T cell distribution), and detection of viral mutations There
        were no study-related serious adverse events in either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and no increase of therapy
        failure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. CD4 counts fluctuated between the start and end of each monitored
        treatment interruption, but levels recovered after resuppression of virus, with retention
        of recall responses throughout. Viral resistance was detected in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the continuous treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>), but
        it was more commonly detected (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> during the open-ended final
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interruption</ENAMEX>, even though all subjects suppressed virus upon reinitiating the same
        therapy.
        Possible risks and benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STIs</ENAMEX> remain controversial, but data from this and other
        published trials do not support short-term clinical benefits of treatment interruptions.
        However, because they do not see increased therapy failure and find preservation of immune
        function in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> conclude that, in light of the possibility of
        reducing costs and drug-related toxicity, additional trials of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STIs</ENAMEX> are warranted.
        Particularly important in the debate over the safety of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STIs</ENAMEX> is whether the detection of
        resistant mutants should be of concern. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> point out that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were
        able to resuppress the mutant virus when they resumed their previous drug regimens but
        state that it remains undetermined to what extent resistant mutations are a signal for
        future therapy failure. Moreover, viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replication</ENAMEX> and reboundâ€”which eventually occurred
        in all participantsâ€”is seen by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> as inherently detrimental, and these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> argue that treatment interruptions are unsafe and their use should be
        discontinued.
        What seems clear is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STIs</ENAMEX> have no place outside controlled clinical trials and that
        questions regarding long-term safety remain unanswered. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least a dozen</NUMEX> additional trials
        that examine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STIs</ENAMEX> are currently recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and will help answer these
        questions.
      
    
  
