
  
    
      
        
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> epidemic is continuing to grow, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations Programme</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> (UNAIDS), in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> there were more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living with the
        virus than ever before, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than ever before died of it. So,
        although in the developed world <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is a controllable <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, one with which a
        treated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> might expect to have a near normal lifespan, in much of the rest of the
        world <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is still a death sentence. Despite the fact that the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> has
        come down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $150</NUMEX> per year in the developing world‚Äîa much lower cost than
        previously‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are still unavailable to the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. What is more,
        every infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has the chance of infecting many others. Although huge sums of money
        have been poured into combating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/AIDS‚Äîaround <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">US$4.7 billion</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2003‚</NUMEX>ÄîUNAIDS estimates
        this amount is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> of what is required by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a quarter</NUMEX> of what will
        be required by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>, to mount a comprehensive response to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in low-income and
        middle-income <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the real dilemmas, therefore, of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> policy is
        deciding whether it is better to concentrate resources on prevention of infections or on
        treatment of infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Each approach has ramifications for the other, as shown
        by the experience in some developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, where an increase in availability of
        treatment has been accompanied by an increase in risk behavior.
        An analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Salomon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> suggests that trying to concentrate on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or the other of
        these alternatives is a false dichotomy, and that not integrating the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> approaches could
        have a catastrophic effect on the global toll of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>. In this theoretical
        paper the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> analyze the epidemic in sub-Saharan <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> (where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-fourths</NUMEX> of deaths
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> occur). With no change in current levels of prevention and care, it is predicted
        that there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.7 million</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV infections</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> dying of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in
        this region <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two decades</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> predicted that concentrating
        on prevention alone could decrease <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> infections by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, and that concentrating on
        treatment could decrease <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> infections by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>. However, combining both approaches could
        yield substantially greater benefits than the sum of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> alone‚Äîlowering projected new
        infections by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74%</NUMEX> and projected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> mortality by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. These percentages translate into
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 million</NUMEX> new infections and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> deaths averted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 2004 and 2020</TIMEX>.
        The challenge now is obviously how to put these policy suggestions into practice. The
        current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> treatment target of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on
        antiretroviral therapy by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2005</TIMEX> (the ‚<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Äú3 by 5‚Äù</NUMEX> objective) provides a yardstick for
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> part of the equation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> comment that the mobilization of communities
        that will be needed to achieve the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> objective should also be harnessed for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prevention</ENAMEX>, and that those who teach prevention must also be allowed to get care for those
        infected. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> say, only by doing so ‚Äúwill we at last move from slogans to
        impact.‚Äù
      
    
  
