
  
    
      
        
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several years</TIMEX>, there has been growing concern about selective publication
        of clinical trial results [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,2</NUMEX>]. The debate has intensified since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State Attorney</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot Spitzer</ENAMEX> filed suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GlaxoSmithKline</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2, 2004</TIMEX>, alleging that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was hiding data regarding the efficacy and safety of selective serotonin
        reuptake <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> in pediatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with depression [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>].
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most frequently suggested remedies for the selective reporting of clinical
        trials results have been to register all clinical trials and to make their results publicly
        available. Registries have been called for at least as far back as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> have in
        fact already been established [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. Shortcomings of registries include the fact that they
        are often not coordinated and that participation is often voluntary and‚Äîin cases where they
        are mandated by legislation‚Äîdifficult to enforce. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ClinicalTrials</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">registry</ENAMEX> authorized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Food and Drug Modernization Act of 1997</ENAMEX>, appears not to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> study found that, of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127</NUMEX> cancer protocols sponsored by pharmaceutical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that met criteria for inclusion, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 48%</NUMEX> were in fact submitted to the registry
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. Thus, one can check a number of registries and still have little assurance that all
        the relevant trials of interest have been included.
        Increasing the pressure on pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to include more trials in
        condition of considering a trial for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> will require its
        registration in a public trials registry [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. Further, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX>) Annual <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Meeting</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Delegates</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2004</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> called on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> to establish a comprehensive national registry. In
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2004</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustee</ENAMEX> testified in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> Congressional hearing,
        outlining elements necessary to make such a registry effective [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. Momentum for a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> clinical trials registry is also building internationally [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>].
        In this essay, I argue that a highly valuable but underused registry and results
        database for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> trials already exists within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>,
        specifically within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>).
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Drug Applications</ENAMEX>
        Before a pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can conduct a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> trial that it intends to use in support
        of a new drug application (NDA), it must first register that trial with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>. Because
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> forms the basis for marketing approval, it seems likely that the percentage of
        industry-sponsored trials that are registered with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> is very high. This registration
        trial protocol; protocols for additional studies within the same clinical trials program
        are submitted as amendments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IND. Later</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> has completed its clinical
        trials program and wishes to apply for marketing approval, it submits its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> then begins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> review process, during which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statistician</ENAMEX>,
        and a pharmacologist, among others, generate lengthy review documents [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. These reviews
        not only address the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>'s analyses of the data on pivotal studies, but they often also
        include reanalyses by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> using raw data obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>. These
        analyses are conducted in adherence to the statistical methods set forth a priori in the
        original trial protocols. (By contrast, with most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal publications</ENAMEX>, it is usually not
        possible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to verify whether what is presented as the main finding is
        consistent with the original hypothesis or whether it was a post hoc finding.) After the
        primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> have written their reviews, shorter reviews are written by their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superiors</ENAMEX>, with the process culminating in a decision about whether to approve the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> for
        the proposed indication.
      
      
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Semi-Public Database</ENAMEX>
        This process occurs entirely outside of the public domain. However, in the interest of
        making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> more ‚Äútransparent,‚Äù and in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Freedom of</ENAMEX>
        Information Act [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>], the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several years</TIMEX>, posted selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> reviews
        for approved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug‚Äìindication</ENAMEX> combinations on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accessdata</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fda</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/scripts/cder/drugsatfda/</ENAMEX>index.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cfm</ENAMEX>). These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> review
        documents are much more detailed than the resulting package insert and often more detailed
        than corresponding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal publications</ENAMEX>.
        For example, while the clinical trials section of the package insert is typically a few
        paragraphs long, the efficacy portion of the clinical review usually runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of</NUMEX> pages.
        Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> is made aware of all studies that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> plans to use in support of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> before they are conducted, and thus before there can be any selection based on
        outcome, these reviews cover not only studies that are positive (and more likely to be
        published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>), but also studies whose outcome was negative or indeterminate. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sidebar</ENAMEX> gives an example of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> review documents at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> give valuable information
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> paroxetine for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety disorders</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FDA Reviews for All Approved Drugs Should Be Made Public</ENAMEX>
        In the examples discussed in the sidebar, our having access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> review documents
        allows us to become aware of, and see beyond, apparent publication bias. It is in the best
        interest of the public health for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> to make as many reviews available as possible.
        According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> Web site, ‚ÄúAs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> continues to be one of the world's leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
        in its emphasis on openness and transparency, it is aware that making even more information
        available to the public will further the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>'s mission to protect and promote public
        health and improve its credibility. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has aggressively implemented the
        Electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom of Information Act‚Ä¶‚Äù [11</ENAMEX>].
        Unfortunately, the availability of review documents on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> is sporadic. To take
        additional examples from psychiatry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> reviews have been posted on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> for some
        approved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug‚Äìindication</ENAMEX> combinations, such as fluoxetine for pediatric <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aripiprazole</ENAMEX> and quetiapine for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> reviews for many other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug‚Äìindication</ENAMEX> combinations have not been posted: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac Weekly</ENAMEX> formulation of
        fluoxetine, clozapine for suicidal behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX> or
        schizoaffective disorder, and quetiapine for mania, among others. A review on paroxetine
        for pediatric <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot Spitzer</ENAMEX>'s suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GlaxoSmithKline</ENAMEX>, is
        not posted. This is probably because this drug‚Äìindication combination was not approved; in
        fact, it is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GlaxoSmithKline</ENAMEX> did not file an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> to be reviewed. However, I do
        not understand why, in cases where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDAs</ENAMEX> were both submitted and approved, such as the ones
        listed above, some reviews are posted while others are not.
        I therefore suggest that we increase access to the clinical trials registry and results
        database that already exist within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> could expand its implementation of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Electronic Freedom of Information Act</ENAMEX> and make all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX> reviews, at least for approved
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDAs</ENAMEX>, available in the public domain. The act is written into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Code</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Regulations</ENAMEX> as follows: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> will make the fullest
        possible disclosure of records to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, consistent with the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to
        privacy, the property rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in trade secrets and confidential commercial or
        financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">information‚</ENAMEX>Äù [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>].
      
      
        Obstacles and Limitations
        There would surely be obstacles. The pharmaceutical industry would vigorously invoke
        Exemption <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom of Information Act</ENAMEX>, the exemption for trade secrets and
        confidential business information [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA Freedom of Information Office</ENAMEX>
        already deals with confidential and proprietary information by redacting or editing it out
        of the review documents before making them available. Within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Office</ENAMEX>, staffing would need to be greatly increased. Some oversight might be
        necessary to ensure that the taxpaying public has been granted the fullest possible access
        and that unwarranted redaction does not occur. Unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom of Information Act</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">modified</ENAMEX>, access would still likely be limited to approved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDAs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> would remain
        unavailable for trials that did not lead to an approved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDA</ENAMEX>.
        It should be clarified that this resource does not compete with proposals by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> and
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for clinical trial registries‚Äîrather, it complements them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> has
        proposed the creation of a registry that is comprehensive in scope. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s registry and
        results database are restricted to those trials aimed at supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> marketing approval
        or a change in labeling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. While data from many studies conducted abroad are
        submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> for this purpose, this is not the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for which the sponsor
        has elected not to seek approval for marketing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. Nor does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> review data from
        Health, or by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>-initiated trials that are
        often not registered with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>.
        To make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> review data more accessible and user-friendly, simple formatting changes
        would be needed. For those (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">few</NUMEX>) reviews that are currently posted on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, one can
        determine the indication being evaluated only after opening the document and paging through
        it. (Descriptive titles would be helpful, and these could be linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ClinicalTrials</ENAMEX>.gov.
        Further, the trials reviewed could be identified with a unique international identifier, as
        promoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>].) Despite the fact that the reviews are
        created in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX> and converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDF</ENAMEX>, the versions that appear on the Web site
        are no longer in a searchable text format. While the reviews tend to be well organized, the
        posted versions are difficult to navigate because there is no hyperlinked table of
        contents. In addition to having these formatting issues addressed, clinicians and patients
        might benefit from brief summaries, the writing of which might require the addition of new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        Despite the limitations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s database, making it public is a strategy that could
        be implemented both rapidly and easily by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> upon existing infrastructure. While we
        await the creation of a clinical trials registry and results database that is truly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>, we already have at our disposal one that could serve as a trove of in-depth
        and unbiased information on many, if not most, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> currently marketed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
