
  
    
      
        
        The study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planche et al.</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] provides important new information addressing
        intracellular volume depletion in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with severe childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, but does not
        address the question of whether intravascular volume depletion (hypovolemic shock) is
        present. Using sophisticated methodology to determine total body water and extracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, they demonstrate a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.7%</NUMEX> deficit in total body water and an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.7%</NUMEX> deficit of
        intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, providing an important indication of the volumes of fluid that may be
        required to optimize hydration. The data, however, do not address the degree of filling of
        the intravascular compartment, nor should they be used to answer the question about the
        state of tissue and organ perfusion. Indeed, we believe that these new data present no
        conflict with our previously reported findings. Using methods to study critical illness
        physiology that are widely employed within pediatric intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> for
        interpretation of circulatory status, we have demonstrated evidence for hypovolemia in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with severe <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> complicated by metabolic acidosis [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        were younger, had longer capillary refilling times (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>3</NUMEX> s), lower central venous
        pressures (mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.9</NUMEX> cm H
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>) and higher creatinines (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">>80 µmol/l</ENAMEX>): all features of compensated
        hypovolemic shock. Furthermore, hypotension (systolic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX>) was present in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44%</NUMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with severe acidosis (base deficit <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>15</NUMEX>). These findings also indicate
        important baseline differences in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> studied. We agree that
        reconsideration of guidelines for acute fluid management is warranted, particularly when
        current recommendations await an adequate evidence base. Nevertheless, conflicting opinions
        on the question of volume status in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with severe <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> can be satisfactorily
        resolved only through prospective randomized trials that include both fluid resuscitation
        and control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. While the design and conduct of such trials will involve considerable
        challenges, optimal fluid management will never be resolved on the basis of theoretical
        consideration alone.
      
    
  
