
  
    
      
        
        The total projected spending on health care in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.79</NUMEX>
        trillion‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äî15</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.5%</NUMEX> of its gross domestic product [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. That amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,167</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, almost
        twice what most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> with comprehensive systems spend on care. Most policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
        agree that this level of spending should be more than enough to provide all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with
        high quality, comprehensive health care. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> falls far short of these
        goals. What are the flaws in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> health system that prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> from
        receiving value from this huge health care investment? And what are the options for
        improvement?
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Physicians</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health Program</ENAMEX>
        First, I should reveal my personal bias. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians</ENAMEX> should be well represented in the
        forefront of reform. As we look back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past half century</TIMEX> of failed health policy
        decisions, we see that the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX> (AMA), has opposed most reform measures that would result in
        an equitable, affordable system for everyone. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> has supported an agenda that
        promotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>' freedom to maximize their personal financial reward, even though those
        policies may deprive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> access to affordable care. The AMA
        agenda has contributed significantly to the current high costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> health care and
        to our failure to adequately address the mediocrity that characterizes health care in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">physicians‚Äîincluding myself‚Äîbelieve</ENAMEX> that the funding infrastructure should
        be redesigned to maximize heath care resource allocation for the primary benefit of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Because of the failure of organized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> on behalf of our
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, we decided that a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> was needed. We established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians</ENAMEX> for a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health Program</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pnhp</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>) [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,3</NUMEX>].
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uninsured and the Poorly Insured</ENAMEX>
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with no health care coverage, and not surprisingly, lack
        of insurance is associated with worse health outcomes [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 18,000</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> die
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> because they lack health insurance [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. The uninsured are less likely than the
        insured to receive the professionally recommended standard of care for their chronic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. And if you have a serious health crisis while
        you are uninsured, you risk major debt or bankruptcy.
        Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insured</ENAMEX> are inadequately covered. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who purchase
        coverage are rebelling at the high price of insurance premiums. To maintain competitive
        premiums, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> are designing products that reduce the benefits they pay out by
        increasing the out-of-pocket portion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are required to pay for services
        received. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Insured patients</ENAMEX> may have to pay cash for care until a designated amount is
        reached (the deductible)‚Äîwhich could be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are
        often required to pay a dollar amount (co-payment) or a percentage of the charges
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">coinsurance</NUMEX>) each time services are received.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Insurers</ENAMEX> may also exclude specified services from coverage, such as maternity benefits
        or mental health services. Most insurance plans now use lists of contracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, and impose severe financial penalties for using health care providers that are
        not contracted. All of these measures reduce the value of insurance by shifting costs from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who actually need care.
        Inadequate insurance coverage is making average-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> poorer. A recent study
        found that for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who had average or greater-than-average incomes and were
        continually insured, medical bills had caused significant financial problems [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. For those
        who were not continuously insured, the percentages were even higher. These financial
        barriers are impairing access to beneficial services. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> insurance market is
        now dominated by insurance plans that provide neither adequate health security nor
        financial security.
      
      
        Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Health Spending Mean Better Quality</ENAMEX>?
        There is a widespread belief that the high spending in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> means that high
        quality care is being delivered to the majority, who can afford both comprehensive coverage
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> out-of-pocket expenses. But international comparisons of industrialized
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> have shown that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is in the bottom quartile of population health
        indicators such as life expectancy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> mortality [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. And in regional comparisons
        within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, increased levels of spending have not produced a commensurate
        improvement in health care outcomes. In fact, a recent study found that in a state-by-state
        comparison, there is an inverse relationship between spending and quality outcomes‚Äîthe more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expenditure</ENAMEX>, the worse the quality [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>].
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> rated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in its health
        expenditures per capita, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37th</TIMEX> in its overall health system performance, below most
        its health care investment.
        Some contend that the poor performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> system is due to the funding
        of health care in the private sector, and that all would be well if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would
        just take over funding. But it is not quite that simple. The greater part of health care in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States‚</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Äî59%‚Äîis</ENAMEX> already funded by the tax system. On a per capita basis, the
        public, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>-funded health care expenditures alone total more than the health care
        spending of every other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s public and private funding combined (with the exception of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, in which total spending per capita equals our public spending alone) [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>].
      
      
        Flaws in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funding</ENAMEX> and Allocation
        How can the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> spend as much as it does and end up with such mediocre health
        care? Of the many reasons that exist, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are particularly important. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has
        a highly flawed system of funding health care and a flawed system of allocating its health
        care resources.
        In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, a multitude of private health plans cover the lucrative sector of
        society‚Äîlow cost, healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy families</ENAMEX>. But public programs must
        cover the higher costs of the elderly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with permanent disabilities, and some
        low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Since the uninsured are frequently unable to pay for the care they
        receive, the costs for their care are shifted to government programs or private plans, or
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, even if unintended. The costly administrative excesses of
        private health plans, especially when contrasted to government programs, have been well
        documented [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. This fragmented system of funding care places an even greater
        administrative and financial burden on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of health care. Although the exact
        amount is disputed, most policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> agree that replacing this fragmented system of
        funding care with a single, universal, publicly administered insurance program could
        recover <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 billion dollars</NUMEX> or more, which are currently being wasted on useless and
        sometimes detrimental administrative services [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>].
        And what is wrong with the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> allocates its resources? Many
        studies have confirmed that supporting a strong primary care base provides better outcomes
        at a lower cost [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. But in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, specialized, high-technology care is
        heavily marketed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of that high-tech care are rewarded more generously than
        primary care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. Yet studies show that these greater expenditures result in no
        additional benefit‚Äîand sometimes even in worse outcomes [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,13</NUMEX>]. Excessive resources are
        allocated to inappropriate expansion of high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and to training an excessive
        number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> to provide high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,13</NUMEX>].
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Reform</ENAMEX>
        What has been the response to these deficiencies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> health care
        system? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> attempted to introduce a comprehensive
        system of funding universal health care. The system would have used marketplace principles
        in a program of managed competition, but their complicated idea pleased no one, and it was
        never even brought to a vote. Because of this miserable political failure, policymakers
        decided that any comprehensive approach should be avoided, and that reform must take place
        in incremental steps. To date, with the notable exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Children's Health</ENAMEX>
        Insurance Program (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cms</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hhs</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/schip</ENAMEX>), the accomplishments of these incremental
        health reform measures have been unimpressive.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>, those interested in reform have been preoccupied with managed care
        measures and, more recently, with consumer-directed measures that increase costs to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> by requiring greater out-of-pocket spending. But these measures are designed more
        to control costs than to increase coverage and access. In the debate on universal coverage,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> general concepts have been put forward: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the expansion of our current system of
        public and private programs, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the establishment of a national health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> with
        government ownership of the system, or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the replacement of all current funding with a
        single, publicly administered, publicly funded program of social insurance that does not
        alter the existing ownership status of the delivery system.
        The greatest political support <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is for incremental expansions of our current
        programs, which, theoretically, would eventually result in universal coverage. There are
        innumerable variations of this approach. Most would increase the affordability of insurance
        premiums for private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and individual plans by providing financial assistance through
        tax policies and by modifying the benefits and coverage of the plans. Some policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
        recommend that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> be mandated to offer coverage to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. Others recommend
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> be required to purchase their own coverage. Since some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> would
        be left without coverage, a public program, such as the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> program for
        low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, would be used to cover everyone else. Many simulation studies have
        shown that these approaches could be effective in covering almost everyone, but they are
        the most expensive models of reform since they leave in place the administrative excesses
        of the fragmented system of funding care [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]. Also, to keep premiums affordable, these
        approaches may fall short on comprehensiveness of coverage and on the affordability of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">out-of-pocket</ENAMEX> component, especially for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with greater health care
        needs.
        In contrast, simulation of both the national health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and public social insurance
        models of reform have shown that they would provide truly comprehensive benefits for
        everyone, and that they are the least expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]. By integrating funding with
        the health care delivery system, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are well suited for the introduction of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> information technology system. Such a system would provide invaluable data to
        assist with decisions on resource allocation, enabling incentives to be established that
        would strengthen the primary care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>. It would also improve capacity planning for
        high-tech and specialized services, thereby ensuring appropriate access without excessive
        queues [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>].
        The political threshold for adopting a government-owned health service <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> is very high, since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> fear the specter of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúsocialized medicine</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        In contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program, an insurance program for the retired and for those with
        long-term disabilities, is very popular. There is an increasing public perception that we
        may need to accept a greater government role in health insurance if we are to adequately
        address the deteriorating status of our health care system. Correcting the flaws in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and then using the program to cover everyone may be a concept that can gain
        political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traction</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        Our political process is currently dominated by those who are enticed by the siren song
        of the market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> and turn a deaf ear to the health policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> who plead for
        health care justice. The debate needs to focus on defining the best role for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in
        ensuring that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> receive the best health care value. That debate needs to be guided by
        a thorough understanding and diligent application of sound health policy science.
        The continuing deterioration of affordability, coverage, and quality in health care
        makes it imperative that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> policymakers broaden their reform efforts beyond the
        ineffectual tinkering of incrementalism. A universal, single-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payer</ENAMEX>, publicly funded and
        publicly administered program of social insurance would ensure access to affordable,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>, high-quality health care for all. It should be the standard by which any
        other proposals are judged. If a better proposal can be crafted, now is the time to do it.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are dying while we delay.
      
    
  
