
  
    
      
        
        A link between high levels of homocysteine, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur-containing amino acid</ENAMEX>, and heart
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> was first suggested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, when it became clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with inborn
        errors of homocysteine metabolism were prone to develop severe cardiovascular disease in
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX>. Treatment with homocysteine-lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> such as folate,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitamin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B12</ENAMEX>, and betaine reduces the incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> in these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        This led to the hypothesis that mildly elevated levels of homocysteine might contribute
        to vascular disease. Subsequently, several studies have found higher mean homocysteine
        levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with coronary, peripheral, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cerebral vascular disease</ENAMEX>, particularly
        high low-density <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lipoprotein</ENAMEX> (LDL) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, or smoking. Several studies then
        sought to determine whether elevated homocysteine levels were a cause or effect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiovascular disease</ENAMEX>, and evidence for a causal relationship is accumulating. However,
        whether reduction in homocysteine levels translates into a reduction in heart disease is
        still an open question.
        “We are keenly awaiting the results from several ongoing trials. In the meantime, our
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> is trying to determine the risks and benefits associated with different
        homocysteine-lowering nutrients,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">”</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margreet Olthof</ENAMEX>. She and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wageningen Centre</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Science</ENAMEX> analyzed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> independent, placebo-controlled,
        randomized intervention studies that examined the effects of betaine, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">folic acid</ENAMEX>, and
        phosphatidylcholine on plasma homocysteine concentrations in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>. They
        combined blood lipid data from the individual studies and compared changes in blood lipid
        concentrations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> taking homocysteine-lowering nutrients and those taking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">placebo</ENAMEX>.
        They found that that betaine supplementation, while effective at lowering homocysteine,
        also increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LDL cholesterol</ENAMEX> and triacylglycerol.
        This raises the possibility that any potential benefits for cardiovascular health would
        be undermined by the adverse effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood lipids</ENAMEX>, and make betaine less suitable as a
        homocysteine-lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. The data on phosphatidylcholine were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inconclusive</ENAMEX>, but supplementation of folic acid—the most common way to lower homocysteine
        levels—does not seem to affect blood lipids. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> conclude that folic acid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“therefore</ENAMEX> remains the preferred treatment for lowering of blood homocysteine
        concentrations” in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
