
  
    
      
        
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> nestled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s largest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are reported to speak <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> different languages. Acculturation
        is difficult in the best of circumstances, but what happens when those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with limited
        or no proficiency in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> have a medical problem? Many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are
        required to provide some manner of interpreter services for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with limited English
        proficiency‚Äîbut do those services also bridge the cultural divide?
        Meeting the challenge of providing health care for a multicultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is now a
        major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> that is affecting health care in developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, principally the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> but
        also in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. Although the bulk of studies and commentaries on
        the subject began to appear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, the literature dates back much further, to
        articles written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s and 1970s</TIMEX> by medical anthropologists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>,
        mental health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, and others.
      
      
        Wake-Up Calls
        In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, the first major alert on this problem came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, when the 
        Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force on Black</ENAMEX> and Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX> was
        issued [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. (The ‚ÄúSecretary‚Äù was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHHS</ENAMEX>).) The report painted a bleak picture of the quality of health care afforded to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> and other racial and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade later</TIMEX>, reports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Institute of Medicine</ENAMEX> began to appear. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> reports, which spanned a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year</TIMEX> period, dealt with the need to greatly diversify the
        health professions work force‚Äîstill a somewhat unachieved goal. The most recent, considered
        a new wakeup call, was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> report 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unequal Treatment</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Confronting Racial and Ethnic Disparities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
        Care [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. It minced few words in describing the problems faced by racial and ethnic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> who sought health care: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThe conditions in which many clinical encounters take
        place‚Äîcharacterized by high time pressure, cognitive complexity, and pressures for
        cost-containment‚Äîmay enhance the likelihood that these processes will result in care poorly
        matched to minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' needs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minorities</ENAMEX> may experience a range of other barriers to
        accessing care, even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insured</ENAMEX> at the same level as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, including barriers of
        language, geography and cultural familiarity‚Äù (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        Soon afterward, another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency for Healthcare Research</ENAMEX> and
        Quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHHS</ENAMEX>, issued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other reports: the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Healthcare Disparities Report</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>] and the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Healthcare Quality Report</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>], with annual updates promised. The
        reports focused on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> clinical conditions, including <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, and mental
        health, and discussed the quality of care and differences in access to such care for
        special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population groups</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and the disabled.
        All of these reports make it clear that health care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and health systems
        need to change. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, in order to improve their lives economically or avoid war
        and/or famine, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have migrated from less to more developed areas of the world,
        changing the demographics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and a number of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>. Evidence that they and
        nonmigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> experience inequities in attaining quality health care is abundant
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        Studies also indicate that although genetics is involved in some health-related
        differences between racial and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, such as in the incidence of certain diseases
        and responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, it is probably not a major factor in explaining health
        disparities [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>].
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Era of Action</ENAMEX>
        A primary result of these reports on health disparities? A truly dizzying array of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, programs, and initiatives within the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHHS</ENAMEX> as well as in some of its
        major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health and the Centers for Disease</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control and Prevention</ENAMEX>, all designed to improve health care for racial and ethnic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> in one way or another. Some of these programs also fund grants to outside
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private, and coordinate with state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of minority
        health.
        And there are more activities devoted to reducing health disparities: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
        university-level institutes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and programs, such as those at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UMDNJ-Robert Wood</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson Medical School and Georgetown University</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>, such as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Endowment</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs within the various states, such as the very
        active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio Commission on</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) combinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiversityRx</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diversityrx</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>), an informational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> sponsored by the National
        Conference of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Legislatures, Resources</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross-Cultural Health Care</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Kaiser Family Foundation</ENAMEX>.
        All these efforts might suggest that there are no problems left to be solved, but this
        is hardly the case. Providing quality health care to those who differ from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
        majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in terms of language and culture (and often race) is a mammoth task
        that does not yield to easy or quick fixes, but rather to consistent and determined efforts
        at improvement.
      
      
        Cultural Competence
        The most common term used in this effort is ‚Äúcultural competence,‚Äù essentially defined
        as a respectful knowledge of and attitude toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from different cultures that
        enables health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> who work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from another culture to develop and use
        standard policies and practices that will increase the quality and outcome of their health
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>.
        With cultural competence as the centerpiece, social and behavioral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have
        started consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) train health care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> working in private and
        public health care settings (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>, managed health care plans) in
        cultural competence, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) propose as well as study the effects of such changes in these
        settings. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and managed health care plans have developed their own programs;
        examples that stand out are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.D. Anderson Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente</ENAMEX>
        health plans.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.D. Anderson Hospital</ENAMEX> established an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Institutional Diversity</ENAMEX>,
        which emphasizes the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with a variety of backgrounds and experiences to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">examine cancer</ENAMEX> and its impact on all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Educational forums, employee network
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, and the use of evidence-based hypotheses to design and implement pilot
        interventions are all part of the effort to improve care of culturally diverse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente's Institute for Culturally Competent Care</ENAMEX> selects and coordinates
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente</ENAMEX>'s several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers of Excellence</ENAMEX>, which each serve specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.
        For example, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> focuses on the diagnosis, treatment, and management
        of conditions prevalent among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sickle cell disease</ENAMEX> and prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Diversity Department</ENAMEX> emphasizes a diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> and has published
        a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' handbooks on culturally competent care for specific racial or
        cultural patient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Not to Be Left Out
        Pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have also discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">multicultural medicine</ENAMEX>. Many that offer
        continuing medical education <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> to help publicize their new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> now also offer
        courses on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> more prevalent in certain racial and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> than others (such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>/ Latino <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>). These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> include information on how to
        treat such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
        Interestingly, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> a clinical trial proved the effectiveness of the first drug
        specifically designed for the treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">congestive heart failure</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, a combination of fixed doses of isosorbide and hydralazine, may now be
        nearing the market. Despite the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Black Cardiologists</ENAMEX> was a
        cosponsor of the trial, the trial drew criticism on the basis that it allowed race to
        interfere with treatment decisions [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>].
      
      
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Issue</ENAMEX>
        The increased diversity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, with the expected stress on entrenched
        health care systems and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX> themselves, has led to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant-Friendly Hospitals</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mfh-eu</ENAMEX>.net), a ‚ÄúEuropean initiative to promote health and health literacy of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX> and ethnic minorities‚Äù begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2002</TIMEX>.
        With funding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Ministry</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Culture</ENAMEX>, a network of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> member
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> has been implementing and evaluating the effectiveness of three health care models
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are: the improvement of interpreting in clinical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>, the creation and distribution of migrant-friendly information and training
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and child care, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> training in cultural competence. Results of the pilot
        experiences were reported at a final conference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2004</TIMEX> and will form the basis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> recommendations on migrant-friendliness as a quality criterion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and on the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in promoting health and health literacy for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX> and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> mentioned above is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradford Hospitals NHS Trust</ENAMEX>, long
        active among a number of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> that strive to
        improve services for racial and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> in their areas.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> also has a multicultural society, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Centre for Culture and Health</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New South Wales</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> has an active program aimed at increasing cultural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competency</ENAMEX>, both among medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s medical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> at large (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://cch.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">med</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsw</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">edu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">au/</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX> offers graduate certificates
        and diplomas in public health (culture and health), as well as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health</ENAMEX>
        with a concentration in multicultural health, and a postgraduate research degree. It
        emphasizes the establishment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Area Health Services</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New South</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, grassroots <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. A number of research
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> also are underway. There are, for example, intervention strategies designed to
        reduce risk for cardiovascular disease in various cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and
        Farsi-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, and studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>'s basic medical needs do not vary greatly; they can be accommodated with
        appropriate understanding, awareness, and education. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and health care
        can only be enhanced and informed by the broadening of cultural awareness.
      
    
  
