
  
    
      
        
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ME-TRAP</ENAMEX>, which targets the pre-erythrocytic stage of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, was not effective at reducing natural infection rates in semi-immune <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, according to the report of a randomized controlled trial published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThis</ENAMEX> first field efficacy trial was an important
        milestone in the progression of new recombinant vectored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> to deployable products,‚Äù
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oxford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>), the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> of the
        study. ‚ÄúThe safety profile was excellent and the efficacy data provide a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> indication
        of the levels of cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">immunogenicity</ENAMEX> that will be required for preventing infection,‚Äù
        he says.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> used a heterologous prime‚Äìboost vaccination technique. They gave
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two vaccines‚</TIMEX>Äîa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA priming vaccine</ENAMEX> followed by a modified vaccinia virus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> (MVA) that acted as a booster. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MVA vaccines</ENAMEX> both had the same insert
        coding for thrombospondin-related adhesion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRAP</ENAMEX>; a pre-erythrocytic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>) and a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">string of T</ENAMEX> cell epitopes (called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ME for ‚Äúmultiple epitopes‚Äù</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> had previously shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ME-TRAP vaccines</ENAMEX> given in prime‚Äìboost sequence
        could induce large T cell responses in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> and could delay
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parasitemia</ENAMEX> in a sporozoite challenge test (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nat Med</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">729‚Äì735</ENAMEX>). The next step was to do a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">randomized</ENAMEX> controlled trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gambia</ENAMEX> to determine whether this vaccination strategy could
        provide protection against natural 
        Plasmodium falciparum infection.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gambian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> that were close to the
        alluvial flood plain and so were at high risk of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>. They randomly assigned
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">372</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> to receive either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> doses of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA ME-TRAP vaccine</ENAMEX> followed by a
        single dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MVA ME-TRAP</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rabies vaccine</ENAMEX>. This <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-dose schedule is
        similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization/United Nations Children's Fund</ENAMEX>
        Expanded Program on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunization</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks</TIMEX> before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> dose was given, all the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteers</ENAMEX> received antimalarial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to clear blood-stage 
        P. falciparum infections.
        The time to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> infection, the primary end point of the study, was similar in the two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, with an estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> efficacy of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 10%</NUMEX>. However, the effector T cell
        response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TRAP antigen</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T9/96</NUMEX>, measured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> vaccination, was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
        times higher in the DNA/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MVA</ENAMEX> vaccine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rabies</ENAMEX> vaccine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄúIt is absolutely crucial that results like these are published, since the failures, as
        well as the successes, need to be documented if we are to move towards rational strategies
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">optimizing malaria</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Smith</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss Tropical Institute</ENAMEX>, who was
        not involved in the study. ‚ÄúAt the same time, it makes sense to move on quickly without
        shedding too many tears, in a field that is moving much faster than it was before the
        recent injections of money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gates Foundation</ENAMEX>, but where it is still impossible to
        second-guess the results of field trials. This is partly because we do not have any good
        proxy measures of effective immunity in 
        P. falciparum , and partly because this is a fertile area for
        trying out new techniques, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA vaccines</ENAMEX>, where there is still a lot to learn.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> is planning to do further trials that address the important question of whether
        this type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> can prevent the symptoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> next step,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúis
        to assess newer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> regimes that employ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> viral vectors rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and to study
        prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> rather than infection.‚Äù
      
    
  
