
  
    
      
        
        On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15, 2005</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library of Science</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Accountability</ENAMEX>
        Project, a public interest legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that advises and supports whistleblowers
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whistleblower</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>), co-sponsored a private meeting near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol Building</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. C.</ENAMEX> In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the most high profile medical whistleblowers of
        recent times. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All four</NUMEX> have gone public with information about practices in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and
        medical research that they believe are risking the public's health or safety [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1–5</NUMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
        them was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate Director</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Food and Drug</ENAMEX>
        Administration's (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Drug Safety</ENAMEX>, whose research on rofecoxib (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vioxx</ENAMEX>) pointed
        to the serious cardiovascular risks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> was speaking in his own
        capacity and was not representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>. An anonymous <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> whistleblower—a research
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at a major drug company—participated by phone.
        The whistleblowers took turns to share their stories, including their accounts of
        retaliations they said they had faced from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> on raising their concerns, which
        led to lawsuits by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of the whistleblowers [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,3</NUMEX>]. The picture that emerged from
        these accounts—a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>'s inappropriate ties with the pharmaceutical
        industry—was deeply troubling.
        As the investigative medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanne Lenzer</ENAMEX> reports in her Essay for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>], the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whistleblowers</ENAMEX> spoke of public regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
        that are putting the interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> ahead of the safety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and of
        pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that allow their marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> to knowingly downplay
        serious side effects when promoting their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. And they spoke of the woefully inadequate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> offered to those in the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> who feel morally compelled to blow the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whistle</ENAMEX>.
        It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenzer</ENAMEX> who conceived the idea for the meeting. She believed that important
        lessons would emerge from having these medical whistleblowers, who come from very different
        professional backgrounds, together in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to share their experiences. It took her many
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of planning. In particular, she needed to gain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> of the industry research
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> could feel sure that anonymity would be preserved. But all
        of her planning nearly came to nothing. At the last moment the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> sponsor
        pulled out on the advice of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
        
          
            
              The picture that emerged from these accounts was deeply troubling.
            
          
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenzer</ENAMEX>'s phone call to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX>, enquiring whether we might step in, came just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> days
        before the event was due to happen. We took our own legal advice and then agreed to sponsor
        the roundtable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> was eager to support this event, and willing to accept any small legal
        risks, because we believe that the issues raised will be of huge interest to the medical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, to the press, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and to the broader <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. Further, the event fits
        well with our own public service mission of making all scientific and medical research
        results freely and publicly available, and with our belief that transparency in the conduct
        and publication of research is important for public trust. And the topic of the roundtable
        was in line with other articles we have published highlighting the many ways in which
        medicine has become tightly entangled with industry, to the great detriment of patients
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7–9</NUMEX>].
        The risks to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> in sponsoring such an event are, of course, much smaller than the
        risks that the whistleblowers at the roundtable faced in going public with their stories.
        Studies have shown that whistleblowers in both public service and private industry almost
        always experience retaliation from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, with those employed longer experiencing
        greater retaliation [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,11</NUMEX>]. They risk loss of earnings, intimidation, harassment,
        victimization, and personal abuse, and they traditionally receive little help from
        statutory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,13</NUMEX>].
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whistleblowers</ENAMEX>' stories illustrate these issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psychiatrist Stefan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kruszewski</ENAMEX> described how he was fired from his job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Public</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX> (DPW) after alerting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> to prescribing practices across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that he
        considered to be alarming and dangerous [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“I</ENAMEX> was fired in a demeaning manner,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">”</ENAMEX> said
        Kruszewski, who has sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPW</ENAMEX> over his firing. “My <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> were emptied and the contents
        of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> were put in the gutter.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">” David Graham—who</ENAMEX> testified at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Senate Finance</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> hearing on rofexocib (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vioxx</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merck</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>]—said that there was a
        conspiracy by senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> “to intimidate me ahead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
        testimony.” Both of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> contend that pharmaceutical industry influence over
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> (a state and a federal regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, respectively) played a part in
        the difficulties these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> faced in getting their concerns heard [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,2</NUMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenzer</ENAMEX>'s report will, we hope, spark discussion and debate about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">medicine—clinicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and medical journals—can disentangle
        itself from the influence of the pharmaceutical industry. In the past, medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> have played an important part in exposing the complex relationships between
        the pharmaceutical industry and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14–16</NUMEX>], including between industry and the
        medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> themselves [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> will continue to look critically at these relationships. A
        common theme at the roundtable was that, armed with information, the public too could have
        an important role in unpicking these ties. “The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pharma–FDA complex</ENAMEX> has to be dismantled,”
        said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>, “and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to insist on that, otherwise we're going to have
        disasters like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vioxx</ENAMEX> that happen in the future.” <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>, health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, and even
        the industry itself all surely stand to gain from disentanglement.
      
    
  
