
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Animal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> can play an essential role in guiding preclinical vaccine development,
        including in studies of preclinical vaccine safety, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> toxicity, and vaccine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunogenicity</ENAMEX>. Appropriate pathogen challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> can also provide the opportunity to
        perform preclinical tests of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> efficacy. Preclinical tests of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> efficacy
        are usually performed by exposing macaques to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">simian immunodeficiency</ENAMEX> virus (SIV), a virus
        that is closely related to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>. However, the viral inoculum sizes used to infect macaques
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIV</ENAMEX> vastly exceed the amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> are exposed to during a given
        exposure. Typically <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10â€“100</NUMEX> times the infectious dose at which <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> become infected (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ID50</NUMEX>). These excessive doses may not provide realistic
        preclinical tests of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> efficacy. Indeed, no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> has been shown to be effective in
        preventing infection by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIV</ENAMEX> (so-called sterilizing immunity) in such high viral inoculum
        trials. Now, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> published in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roland Regoes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> speculate that an
        alternative approach to trials in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> not only can mimic the human patterns of repeated
        low-dose exposure, but also can remove <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> for animal researchersâ€”the need to use
        very large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in experiments.
        What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> did was use statistical power analysis to compare a single low-dose
        challenge design, in which each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> is challenged only once, and a repeated low-dose
        challenge design, in which each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> is challenged until it is infected or a
        predetermined maximum number of challenges is reached. The statistical power of an
        experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">designâ</ENAMEX>€”a measure of the statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">qualityâ</ENAMEX>€”was assessed by simulating
        experiments, evaluating them, and then repeating the procedure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of times.
        What they found was that the experimental design using a single low dose of virus in
        each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> required unfeasibly large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>; even for the highest modeled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine efficacy</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> the single low-dose challenge design required <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX> animals
        per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to reach a statistical power of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>. However, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> modeled a
        protocol of repeatedly challenging the (virtual) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> with a challenge dose of one 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> , and allowing for a maximum number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> challenges of each
        individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">few as five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were required to achieve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 95%</NUMEX> of
        statistical power.
        Where do these results leave the design of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> trials? To begin with, the results should
        encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to develop animal models that reflect, to the fullest extent
        possible, what is known about the natural history and pathogenesis of the disease in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, rather than designing trials to fit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> models that are available. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have made available the programming script of their analysis so anyone can repeat
        it; it would be interesting to know whether preclinical trials assessing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> or
        treatments against infections by other pathogens could be usefully modeled in this way as
        well.
      
    
  
