
  
    
      
        
        Grant [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] describes as incorrect the statement that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least half</NUMEX> of the explanation for
        individual differences in risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> is genetic. He suggests instead that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dietary</ENAMEX> and lifestyle factors explain the majority of individual susceptibility to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX>.
        The basis for asserting a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> or greater role for genetics in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> risk
        comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> studies and from twin studies. In family studies, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree relatives
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> are at more than double the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX>
        compared to those with no affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,3</NUMEX>]. In twin studies, across different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> twin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">registries</ENAMEX>, estimates of heritability of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> range from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX>
        to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 70%</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>].
        Genetic risk undoubtedly represents the cumulative influence of many genes, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apolipoprotein E</ENAMEX> (APOE) and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> not yet identified. In particular, it appears that
        the magnitude of the genetic component of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> risk is similar across ethnic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, but that different genetic factors may contribute differently to that risk in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Latino</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APOE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">e4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">allele</ENAMEX> and high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>] or head injury [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>].
        Clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> is the outcome of multiple genetic and multiple environmental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">influences</ENAMEX>, operating additively and interactively. If genetic effects account for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of
        individual differences in liability, then environmental influences also account for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of
        the variation in susceptibility. From a public health viewpoint, it is vital to identify
        those influences that are modifiable. Controlling blood pressure and avoiding head trauma
        are examples. However, it is also important to appreciate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> bring
        differences in genetic risk to the table.
      
    
  
