
  
    
      
        
        Accurate staging of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> is one of the most important parts of the work up of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for both prediction of prognosis and determination of the most appropriate
        treatment. And an essential part of this work up is assessing whether or not there has been
        lymphatic spread. Current methods include surgical removal of nodes for examination and
        various types of imaging, ranging from ultrasound to newer technologies such as magnetic
        resonance imaging (MRI). All these methods have problems; some are very invasive, others
        are very time consuming, and none are completely reliable.
        However in one of the more exciting crossovers from chemistry into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        have developed nanoparticles to improve the diagnostic accuracy of MRI. The nanoparticles
        contain a central superparamagnetic iron oxide core and are covered by dextran, imparting
        long circulation times and biocompatibility. When injected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">intravenously</ENAMEX>, the nanoparticles
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">localize</ENAMEX> to lymphoid tissue, and are internalized into macrophages. There is then a
        decrease in signal intensity on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T2- and T2</TIMEX>*-weighted images, and when metastases are
        present there is a recognizably abnormal pattern on MRI scans.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Weissleder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
        described using these nanoparticles to assess lymphoid spread in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Now, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , they have gone further by extending the analysis to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and producing an algorithm that allows
        semiautomation of the procedure.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> developed the algorithm in a training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and then
        validated it in a group of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. The results are encouraging: the analysis showed a
        sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> confidence interval, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“99%</NUMEX>) and a specificity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>
        confidence interval, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX>%â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">€“96%</NUMEX>). The advantages of automating this procedure are substantial,
        not least because it can remove the problem of different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> assessing data
        differently.
        And what is more, once the data have been collected and assessed it is possible to
        reconstruct a virtual picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>, thus potentially allowing
        accurate surgical removal of the nodes.
      
    
  
