
  
    
      
        
        The case report by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nautiyal et al.</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] is an instructive reminder that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode
        of an acute painful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horner Syndrome</ENAMEX> should prompt imaging of the ipsilateral internal
        carotid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery</ENAMEX>, since carotid dissection (as well as other conditions, such as high-grade
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stenosis</ENAMEX>) needs to be ruled out. Unfortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> perpetuate the extremely common
        misconception that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enophthalmos</ENAMEX> accompanies ptosis and miosis in human <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Horner Syndrome</ENAMEX>. It
        is only an illusion of enophthalmos caused by the ptosis. This is evident in the left eye
        of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the case report.
        Actual measurement with exophthalmometry clearly demonstrates the lack of enophthalmos.
        As stated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loewenfeld</ENAMEX> ([<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 1139</ENAMEX>), “Animals such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> have
        enophthalmos on the side of the sympathetic lesion. But in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, the enophthalmos is only
        apparent. The small palpebral fissure makes the eye look sunken in on the affected side,
        but the position of the globe in the orbit remains virtually unchanged. This has been found
        by all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who have measured the supposed enophthalmos objectively.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">” Loewenfeld</ENAMEX> cites
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> supportive references.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> ([<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 964</ENAMEX>) provide <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> additional references that the
        enophthalmos “is apparent rather than real.”
      
    
  
