
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lymphocytes</ENAMEX> may have an important role in the pathogenesis of smoking-related
        emphysema, according to a new study by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. “We
        now know that T cells are not only present in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COPD</ENAMEX>],
        but are harmful,” comments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Shapiro</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Hospital</ENAMEX>
        , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Medical School</ENAMEX>, who was not involved in the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“We</ENAMEX> also now
        have a pathway that could be interrupted to prevent lung destruction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COPD</ENAMEX>.”
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrah Kheradmand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> took lung samples from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-smokers</ENAMEX> who had been
        admitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">resection</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had moderate to severe COPD as well as
        evidence of emphysema, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had none. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> isolated lung lymphocytes
        from the samples and used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-color flow cytometry to phenotypically characterize the
        cells. They found that lymphocytes taken from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with emphysema expressed more CCR5
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR3 receptors</ENAMEX>, which are associated with a particular type of T cell called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> helper
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Th1</NUMEX>), than did those from control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. By contrast, expression of CCR4
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX>, which are found on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T helper 2</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Th2</NUMEX>) cells, was very low in both control and
        emphysema <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        In a separate experiment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kheradmand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> showed that lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lymphocytes</ENAMEX> taken from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emphysema</ENAMEX> secreted more of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins—interferon gamma</ENAMEX>, monokine
        induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon</ENAMEX> (MIG), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interferon-inducible protein</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> (IP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>)—than control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. MIG and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> are known to be produced by injured epithelial cells and are
        ligands for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR3 receptors</ENAMEX>, which are expressed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        were also able to show that isolated peripheral lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">macrophages</ENAMEX> secreted matrix
        metalloproteinase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MMP12</NUMEX>), an enzyme that degrades <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">elastin—a protein</ENAMEX> important for lung
        elasticity—in the lungs, in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> and MIG. Together these findings, say the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, indicate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> cells, but not Th2 cells, are required for producing the
        elastin-destroying lung environment of emphysema.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> now intend to investigate the antigens that drive the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX>-based
        inflammation that underlies emphysema. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“Ultimately</ENAMEX>, we seek to understand the biochemistry
        of tobacco smoke that triggers inflammation in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, and whether such insight
        might explain other environmentally triggered lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">”</ENAMEX> explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kheradmand</ENAMEX>. “To
        understand such detailed immune mechanisms, we really need an improved experimental model
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, and this we are currently working on.”
      
    
  
