
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> (PLWA) face many forms of stigma and discrimination. This is
        the case in whichever <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they may live, as has been shown in a number of previous
        research studies. In addition to experiencing unfair treatment in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, and places of work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX> may encounter discrimination from health-care
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. This can interfere with effective prevention and treatment. Discriminatory
        practices in the health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> may also appear to legitimize other forms of
        discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Iacopino</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization Physicians for Human Rights</ENAMEX>, in
        collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Project–Nigeria</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for the Right to</ENAMEX>
        Health (also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>) investigated the problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>. With a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of roughly
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130 million</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> is home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 million</NUMEX> PLWA worldwide. Around <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adult Nigerians</ENAMEX> are thought to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive, and there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 310,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS</ENAMEX>
        deaths <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The indications are that infection rates will increase. Until now, little
        has been known about the nature and extent of discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>.
        Trained interviewers conducted a cross-sectional questionnaire survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,021</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX>
        health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
        Those sampled were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">324</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">541</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">133</NUMEX> midwives, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> health-care workers
        of unknown profession. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Fifty-four percent</NUMEX> of them worked in public tertiary care
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>. Many of the survey's results are worrying. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
        reported refusing to care for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> said they had refused a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> admission to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Fifty-nine percent</NUMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX> should
        be on a separate ward, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> believed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> status could be determined by their
        appearance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percent agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> should be informed when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive in order to protect themselves. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> percent believed health-care
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> should not be allowed to work in any area of health-care
        requiring patient contact. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Twenty percent</NUMEX> agreed that many with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> had behaved
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immorally</ENAMEX> and deserved their infection. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> percent felt that treating someone with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> was a waste of resources.
        Providers who reported working in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that did not always practice universal
        precautions against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> transmission were more likely to favor restrictive policies towards
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX>. In general, basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> needed for treatment and prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection were
        not sufficiently available. Providers who reported less adequate training in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
        treatment and in ethics were more likely to report negative attitudes towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. There was no consistent pattern of differences in negative attitudes and
        practices across the different professions surveyed.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> concluded that, while most health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> surveyed reported
        being in compliance with their ethical obligations, discriminatory behavior and attitudes
        towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> existed among a significant proportion. Inadequate education
        about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and a lack of protective and treatment materials appear to favor these
        practices and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX>. The findings of the study, in just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, cannot be
        generalized to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> as a whole and, although sampled systematically, it is possible that
        sampled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> may differ significantly from those that
        were not sampled in the study <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Concerns over a perceived lack of privacy in the
        interviews or about job status may have resulted in an underreporting of discriminatory
        behavior and/or an overreporting of “correct” practices or attitudes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> note that
        the health-care system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> is underfunded and suffers from fundamental problems,
        including material scarcity and inadequacies in infrastructure, both of which may
        contribute to discriminatory behavior. They call for targeted education of health-care
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and provision of adequate resources to health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, and for the
        introduction and enforcement of anti-discrimination policies.
      
    
  
