
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tram√</ENAMEX>®r provide a cogent argument in favor of the ethical use of placebo
        controls despite ‚Äúproven effective treatment‚Äù [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. However, they are wide of the mark
        citing the APPROVe trial in support of their position. Because there is no established
        treatment to prevent adenomatous polyps, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> would have any objections to the
        use of placebo controls in this study. Nevertheless, they are right to suggest that it
        would have been desirable to have included a placebo control in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIGOR</ENAMEX> study to provide
        a more rigorous assessment of safety. Whether, all things considered, a placebo control
        would have been ethical in this study of treatment for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">debatable</ENAMEX>.
        Another issue not discussed in this 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> Debate is the value of placebo controls in early ‚Äúproof of
        concept‚Äù efficacy trials, despite the existence of established treatment. The efficiency of
        seeking a rigorous efficacy signal before moving on to larger-scale trials (and exposing as
        few subjects as possible to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that might not work or turn out to be toxic) is a valid
        ethical reason for using placebo controls, provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are not exposed to undue risks
        of harm from withholding established treatment [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>].
      
    
  
