
  
    
      
        
        There is a much-quoted saying, attributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epidemiologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Rose</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúA large
        number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> exposed to a small risk may generate many more cases than a small number
        exposed to a very high risk.‚Äù This is true for many individual risk factors such as salt
        highway (linked to injuries and accidents). Does it apply to many other global health
        risks? The study by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> suggests that it does.
        To develop effective health policies, one must understand the existing health risks and
        disease burdens. On a worldwide scale, this is a tough challenge. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Burden of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disease Database</ENAMEX>, maintained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> (WHO), collects data from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> around the world on risk factors such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malnutrition</ENAMEX>, childhood abuse,
        unsafe sex, childbirth, and cholesterol levels, as well as on disease burdens, for example
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, blindness, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diarrhea</ENAMEX>. A large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> from all over the world
        has developed a framework to analyze these data. To compare different risks or burdens,
        they calculate disability-adjusted life-years, or DALYs‚Äîthe number of healthy life years
        lost because of a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> or risk factor.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> used data from the WHO database for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> risk factors and from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
        epidemiological subregions of the world to calculate the proportion of
        risk-factor-attributable disease burden in different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population subgroups</ENAMEX> defined by age,
        sex, and exposure level. For being underweight in childhood, for example‚Äîthe leading risk
        factor for global loss of healthy life‚Äîthey found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 35%</NUMEX> of the disease burden
        occurred in severely underweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the rest occurred in those only moderately
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underweight</ENAMEX>. The relative risks for the moderately underweight are much lower, but the
        number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in that category is so large that the total attributable burden amounted
        to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost two-thirds</NUMEX> of the total global burden of disease for that risk factor.
        The analysis confirms‚Äîand extends to a global level‚Äîprevious research showing that many
        major health risks are important across the range of exposure levels, not just among
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> exposed to high levels of risk. It also points to risk factors that are
        particularly prevalent among specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> and age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and for which highly
        targeted interventions could be effective.
        Despite numerous caveats and limitations of studies like this one, such analyses are
        essential aids in guiding the distribution of limited funds to lower the burden of life
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> lost to premature death and disability.
      
    
  
