
  
    
      
        
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last hundred years</TIMEX>, there have been major triumphs in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> related to
        public health, vaccination, and the introduction of new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>. However, over the same
        period, several diseases have increased in prevalence and/or severity. In some cases, the
        causes of the increase have become obvious‚Äîthe increases in lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, coronary artery
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, for example, are not considered to be a mystery. On the other
        hand, a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> related broadly to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúinflammation‚Äù have also increased. For
        these, a wide range of hypotheses about causation have been proposed. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Type 1 diabetes,</ENAMEX>
        rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, and inflammatory bowel <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> have increased since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Some
        analyses of the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> would suggest a similar time course, and
        this parallelism of the time frame has been taken to suggest that there could be a common
        cause. Indeed, there is a proposal that these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> are all related to some changes in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúcleanliness‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúhygiene‚Äù that have resulted in decreased activation of a common control
        mechanism. Specifically, this control has been ascribed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">regulator cells</ENAMEX>, which produce
        interleukin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>) or transforming growth factor-beta.
      
      
        Change <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">in Living Conditions</ENAMEX>
        The major changes in rural areas, tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> that could be
        related to the change in immune responses include: decreases in helminth infection;
        physical proximity to farm <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]; exposure to those mycobacteria that are commonly
        found in the soil; bifidobacteria colonization of the gut; as well as decreased prevalence
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hepatitis A</ENAMEX> infection [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. The implication in each case is that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> has increased
        secondary to an increase in inflammation or an increase of the allergic response that is
        closely associated. This assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> have increased
        in parallel, which is probably not true.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hay fever</ENAMEX> became a problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 1900</TIMEX>. Clear
        evidence for this view comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noon</ENAMEX>'s description of the development of immunotherapy
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>, the studies on <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever prevalence by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ratner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silverman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, and the recognition that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever was a major community problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. More recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Nelson</ENAMEX> analyzed all the studies on <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever published in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and found a prevalence of ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, with no convincing evidence of an
        increase since then (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Nelson</ENAMEX>, personal communication).
        If seasonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever was epidemic in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, then the subsequent increase in asthma has
        to be seen in a different light. The best estimates for the start of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> epidemic
        are around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> for such diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> as army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>], school
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. In each of these studies, the increase in asthma
        symptoms or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> has been greater than tenfold. However, the absolute values of the
        change have been dramatically different in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> (from ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2% up to 20%</NUMEX>)
        compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> (from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2% to 4%</NUMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. Furthermore, some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have experienced
        much greater increases in hospitalization than others. Clear evidence for increases in
        mortality has only come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with a high prevalence of symptoms and hospitalization.
        point, our questions about the increase in asthma are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Is an increase in allergy or hay
        fever a necessary precursor for the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>, a parallel event, or separate? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
        Why did the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> have such a consistent time course throughout the Western
        world in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where changes in infectious diseases have occurred very differently? and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> more common and more severe in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> than in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that
        have had an equal scale of increase (i.e., tenfold) over the same time course?
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Persistent Association</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specific IgE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total IgE</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asthma</ENAMEX>
        Long before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case control or prospective study, the association between allergy
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> was obvious in case series. These earlier studies reported skin testing with an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">amorphous</ENAMEX> extract called ‚Äúhouse dust,‚Äù but it was not until the identification of dust
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mites</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> was clarified [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. Indeed, as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late as 1978</TIMEX>, there were
        significant doubts that allergens played a role in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>. Using extracts of 
        Dermatophagoides pteronyssinus (dust <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mites</ENAMEX>), the strong
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> between this allergen and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> was established in many parts of the world,
        with odds ratios <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as high as 6</NUMEX> or even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,8</NUMEX>]. The possibility of a causal relationship
        was further supported by bronchial challenge studies and avoidance experiments [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cohort</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorset</ENAMEX> was, until recently, the only study with household measurements of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allergen</ENAMEX> and the results strongly suggested that exposure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was the
        primary determinant of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sensitization</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. Subsequently, studies from other parts of the
        world provided evidence about other indoor allergens, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cockroach</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,11</NUMEX>]. These studies showed that perennial exposure to allergens was an
        important cause of inflammation in the lungs and associated nonspecific bronchial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperreactivity</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). In most of the case-control and prospective studies,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sensitization</ENAMEX> to seasonal pollens has not been significantly associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>].
        This is an important issue; if allergy is associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> for genetic reasons or
        because of some common immunological feature, it is not clear why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> should be
        with perennial allergens only.
        Since assays for total serum <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgE</ENAMEX> became available in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, it has been clear that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> have, on average, higher total IgE than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hay fever</ENAMEX> or no
        allergy. Indeed, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> this was considered an established fact in textbooks of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunology</ENAMEX>. It was assumed that the increased total IgE related to allergen-specific
        responses. However, in some studies, the association between total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> was
        stronger than the association between asthma and specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgE</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burrows et al.</ENAMEX> went
        further and suggested that specific <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">IgE</ENAMEX> correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever, while total IgE
        correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. The implication was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgE</ENAMEX> has a complex relationship with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> that is not dependent on specific allergens.
        The strength of the association between asthma and total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgE</ENAMEX> raises questions that have
        not been resolved. Do specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgE antibody</ENAMEX> responses contribute to or even push total IgE?
        If so, do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> responses to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allergens</ENAMEX> have more effect than others? This
        question is relevant both to attempts to explain major differences in total IgE between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and to studies on acute <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>. In emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and hospital studies, the
        geometric mean total serum <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgE</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> is often greater than <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 IU/ml</ENAMEX>
        higher than values found in population-based studies. Recent work from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heymann et al.</ENAMEX> and
        Green et al. on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> hospitalized for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> has suggested that the interaction between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhinovirus</ENAMEX> and allergy occurs predominantly among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with total IgE > <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 IU/ml</ENAMEX>
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. Thus, the different properties of allergens could influence both the prevalence and
        severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>. However, the properties of the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allergens</ENAMEX> do not explain the
        overall increase in prevalence, which has occurred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with very different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>,
        climates, and traditions of domestic pet ownership.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Paradoxical Relationship</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cat Ownership and Sensitization: Significance</ENAMEX>
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prevalence or Severity</ENAMEX>
        Antigen exposure is considered to be a primary requisite for immune responses, and
        allergen-specific responses are no exception. There are many examples of allergens that are
        not significant in areas where the allergen is not encountered. For example, the pollen of
        olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> is not relevant in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, dust mite allergens are not significant
        in the northern part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scandinavia</ENAMEX> or the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and
        cockroach allergens are not significant in suburban areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dust mites</ENAMEX>, there is a wide range of evidence that increased exposure increases
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sensitization</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> have
        progressively higher concentrations of mite allergen and progressively higher prevalence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sensitization</ENAMEX> to mite allergens [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. But there is now evidence that increasing exposure to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cats</ENAMEX> does not lead to a higher prevalence of allergy [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,15,16</NUMEX>]. On a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> basis, the
        effect may be profound; sensitization to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> among school-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is generally ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>,
        while mite sensitization is often <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as high as 30%</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). This effect cannot be ascribed
        to inadequate exposure, since all estimates of the quantity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat allergen</ENAMEX> inhaled are
        higher than for dust <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mites</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, the quantity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat allergen</ENAMEX> found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or
        even in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> is sufficient to sensitize at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>].
        In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> raised in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> were less likely to be sensitized to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. Initially, it seemed possible that the effect was an example of reverse causation.
        However, the effect has been observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where a large proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
        keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, and very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> report choosing not to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> in the
        family. Furthermore, the presence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> does not decrease IgE
        antibody response to dust mites‚Äîin other words, tolerance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> can be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>-specific [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>].
        Understanding how the response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat allergen</ENAMEX> is controlled could provide an insight into
        how both the prevalence and the titre of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgE antibody</ENAMEX> responses in general are (or should
        be) controlled. It seems inevitable that the primary control is by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allergens</ENAMEX>. Indeed, there is already excellent evidence that injection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX> derived
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> allergen <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fel d 1</ENAMEX>, which give T cell responses, can be used for immunotherapy
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. Studying overlapping peptides of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fel d 1</ENAMEX>, we identified a striking response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        peptides at the terminal end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chain 2</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, both allergic and tolerant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> respond to these peptides by producing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interferon gamma</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. The
        implication is that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fel d 1</ENAMEX> inherently induces control, and that this control influences
        both allergic and non-allergic responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat allergen</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). In keeping with this,
        IgE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat allergen</ENAMEX> are not quantitatively as high as those to dust
        mites [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>].
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the central assumptions of the cleanliness hypothesis is that regulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> responses is, at least in part, non-specific. It is assumed that helminth infection,
        mycobacteria, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hepatitis A</ENAMEX>, endotoxin, and early-life infections can create a milieu that
        leads to a decrease in allergic responses in general. Likewise, we might expect that
        exposure to high concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat allergen</ENAMEX>, which can induce <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> producing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>,
        should have a general effect. There is some evidence for this hypothesis. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, the
        presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> tended to reduce allergy in general. In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, the presence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is associated with decreased sensitization to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat</ENAMEX>, and also to birch and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. However, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, the presence
        of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> has no effect on the prevalence or titre of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgE antibody</ENAMEX> to dust mites
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,17</NUMEX>]. Thus, it is clear that under some circumstances the tolerance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> can occur in
        highly atopic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>-specific. This phenomenon is not in keeping with any
        version of the cleanliness hypothesis. It has been proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> could
        have a non-specific effect because they shed or encourage endotoxin. However, recent
        studies on airborne endotoxin found that the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> had no effect, and that there
        were significantly lower endotoxin levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Possible Role of Lifestyle Changes</ENAMEX>
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last half of the 20th century</TIMEX>, there have been major changes in diet and
        physical activity. The most obvious result of these changes is an increase in obesity,
        which has reached epidemic proportions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, there have been
        multiple reports of an association between elevated body mass index (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>].
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, we suggested that changes in physical activity could be related to bronchospasm
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]. Thus, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct but strongly interrelated aspects of lifestyle that
        could be relevant to the prevalence and severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>: diet, physical activity, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obesity</ENAMEX>.
        It is much easier to document <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> than diet or physical activity, and although some of
        the obesity data are convincing, they are not consistent and certainly not comparable to
        the association between obesity and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> such as type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> in childhood. In a
        typical study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camargo et al.</ENAMEX> found that the prevalence of wheezing was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX> among the
        heaviest quintile and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> among the lowest quintile for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. Comparable values for type
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> diabetes would be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5% and 0.1%</NUMEX>.
        Studies using questionnaires have attempted to ask whether there is a relationship
        between wheezing and physical activity. However, the track record for questionnaires on
        this subject is very poor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westerterp</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have reported <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> observations:
        first, that general activity contributes more to energy consumption than ‚Äúaerobic exercise‚Äù
        does and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> who initiate an exercise program (such as a twice
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> visit to the gym) overcompensate so that they actually decrease overall activity
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. Recently, we have documented a decrease in activity among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age ~4 years</TIMEX>) in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United States Head Start</ENAMEX> program (a child-development program that aims to increase the
        school-readiness of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>) who have a history of wheezing
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. Although there are several possible explanations for this result, it seems clear that
        decreased activity can be present before elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>.
        The next question to ask is whether physical activity would have a beneficial effect on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fredburg</ENAMEX> concluded that full expansion of the lungs had a more potent effect on
        bronchial smooth muscle than isoprenaline [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Togias</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have shown that
        prolonged shallow breathing (=<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>) can lead to increased non-specific bronchial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivity</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]. It is obvious that expansion of the lungs is decreased during prolonged
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX> of sitting down. However, periodic expansion of the lungs occurs with sighs. Recent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> shows that ‚Äúsigh rates‚Äù while seated are very variable but are
        significantly lower when watching a video than while reading [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. Thus there is a real
        possibility that some forms of childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">behavior‚ÄîTV</ENAMEX>, videos, computer games, etc.‚Äîmight be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with sigh rates low enough to increase non-specific bronchial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperreactivity</ENAMEX>.
        A different explanation for the effects of physical activity comes from evidence that
        physical activity can be ‚Äúanti-inflammatory.‚Äù This evidence relates to several different
        models though not at present to the lungs. In some studies, obesity appears to be a risk
        factor for wheezing among non-allergic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. However, in most studies, the association
        between allergen sensitization and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> has been found in obese and non-obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        equally [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. Obviously, some obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are unfit and become breathless on
        exercise. In addition, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> may have sleep-disordered breathing. Thus, there
        are other conditions that are easily confused with exercise-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> or nocturnal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>. Taken together, there are excellent reasons for asking whether lifestyle changes
        have contributed to the increased prevalence or severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>. However, it seems
        unlikely that this effect occurs on normal lungs, so the hypothesis has to be that
        decreased physical activity in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who are allergic can allow persistent or increased
        severity of wheezing.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Although the explanation for the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> is not yet clear, it is possible to
        put forward a model that includes elements of each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main hypotheses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>
        raised in the tropics, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>, or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> such as those in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX>
        have exposure to endotoxin or infections sufficient to interfere with the development of
        allergen-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgE antibody</ENAMEX> responses. Once water supplies are clean, and major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">infectious diseases</ENAMEX> have been controlled, allergic diseases will appear.
        However, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> appears to be associated with perennial, i.e., indoor exposure, and may
        be more common or more severe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mites or cockroaches</ENAMEX> are the major source
        of allergens. Even with indoor allergen exposure, wheezing may remain transient or mild,
        provided prolonged outdoor play is normal. It is the combination of the control of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">infectious diseases</ENAMEX>, prolonged indoor exposure, and a sedentary lifestyle that is the key
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> epidemic and, in particular, the key to the rise in severity. Using this
        analysis, the severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> becomes much easier to explain.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX> indoors,
        have high exposure to mite, cockroach, and/or rodent allergens, and have very low levels of
        physical activity.
        In conclusion, it appears that these combined factors are the key to the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> epidemic
        and, in particular, the key to the rise in severity. We clearly need to develop ways to
        increase prolonged physical activity, both among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> and in the general
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. We also need to investigate whether prolonged moderate activity is beneficial
        in the treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> and/or is ‚Äúanti-inflammatory.‚Äù What is equally clear is that the
        current obsession of the medical profession with the pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>
        (as well as other lifestyle-related <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>) does not address the reasons why the disease
        has become so common and so severe.
      
    
  
