
  
    
      
        
        Mental health is perhaps the most neglected area of health policy and programming.
        According to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Report</ENAMEX>, “some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> suffer from a mental or
        behavioral disorder, yet only a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> of them receive even the most basic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treatment”</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 40%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have no mental health policy and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 30%</NUMEX> have
        no mental health program. Over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have no mental health policy that includes
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">behavioral disorders</ENAMEX> are estimated to account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> of the global burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, yet
        the mental health budgets of the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1%</NUMEX> of their
        total health expenditures [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. The relationship between disease burden and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> spending
        is clearly disproportionate.
        Those few who do receive services often fare just as badly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Disability Rights</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), a human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> dedicated to
        the promotion of rights of the mentally disabled, has documented how, in many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>,
        severely mentally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled individuals</ENAMEX> become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> of stigma, discrimination, and other
        human rights abuses. Routinely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> with mental disabilities are
        arbitrarily detained in psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, social care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, orphanages and other
        closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Out of public view, they are subject to the most extreme forms of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inhuman</ENAMEX> and degrading treatment experienced by any population (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, MDRI
        learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were raped in psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in plain view of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
        international humanitarian relief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paraguay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX> found people
        locked in cages [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,4</NUMEX>]. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> learned of a
        practice called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">“unmodified ECT”—the</ENAMEX> use of without any form of anaesthesia or muscle
        relaxants—a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> that is both painful and dangerous [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,6</NUMEX>].
      
      
        Defining a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Rights Approach</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Health Policy</ENAMEX>
        The starting point for the development of a human-rights based policy on mental health
        is that mentally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are full human beings who are entitled to rights. Although
        seemingly obvious, in practice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX> has found that the implications of these premises
        challenge predominant biomedical approaches to mental illness, as well as health services
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paradigms</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. In a rights framework, “mental health needs” are not analyzed (as they are
        in many studies) in terms of the application of given diagnostic criteria in isolation from
        the social context that leads to use of the mental health sector, and mentally disabled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> are treated as more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who need services [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,8</NUMEX>]. They have rights to
        exercise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in their own lives and to participate as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">societies</ENAMEX>, and these rights trump other concerns such as general attitudes toward risk
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">containment</ENAMEX> in society [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>].
        Thus, a human rights framework calls for changes that go beyond quality of care to
        include both legal and services reforms. Further, a human rights approach demands that we
        develop policies and take actions to end discrimination in the overall society that has a
        direct effect on the health and well-being of the mentally disabled.
      
      
        Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> and Accountability
        Suspicion of mental illness cannot mean untrammeled discretion to disregard due process
        concerns in detention. Whether or not ideological factors are at play, civil commitment
        laws must provide for minimum substantive and procedural protections that protect mentally
        ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>' fundamental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. This is often not the case. For example, MDRI
        found that civil commitment laws in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uruguay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> allow commitment upon medical
        certification of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">“mental illness</ENAMEX>,” which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX> found, in many cases, to be questionable.
        There are no requirements that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> be dangerous or in need of psychiatric treatment.
        These laws do not require a right to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> or a periodic review of commitment, as
        international law requires [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,12</NUMEX>]. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are found “mentally ill” can be
        deprived of their liberty indefinitely in these—and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">other—countries</ENAMEX>.
        Once mental health is construed in terms of human rights, all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are required, at a
        very minimum, to establish a normative framework consistent with international law [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>].
        Such a normative framework provides for procedural protections; it also provides for human
        rights oversight and remedies in the event of abuses. Mentally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled persons</ENAMEX> have the
        same right to redress for violations of their fundamental rights as other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,14,15</NUMEX>]. Recourse may imply judicial remedies but in some cases a human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ombudsman</ENAMEX>
        can be equally effective [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. As mentally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled individuals</ENAMEX> are often not in a position
        to avail themselves of remedies, proactive monitoring and enforcement is also necessary. In
        short, instituting legal reform, accountability procedures, and effective mechanisms to
        provide human rights oversight becomes a cornerstone of a human rights-based approach to
        mental health policy.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Reform</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Integration</ENAMEX> and Participation
        Treating mentally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as full human beings implies that they have rights to
        participate in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>. This, in turn, calls for community
        integration and service system reform instead of programs that merely rebuild segregated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. The WHO also recognizes that it is important to provide treatment in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, but its reasoning is largely utilitarian. The WHO argues that “community care
        has a better effect than institutional treatment on the outcome and quality of life of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with chronic mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shifting patients</ENAMEX> from mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> to care
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is also cost-effective” [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. From a human rights perspective, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
        entitled to live in and receive care in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> not because it is more efficient, but
        because all human beings develop their identities within social contexts, and have rights
        to work and study, as well as be with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> with mental disabilities are often denied the right to work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>,
          to marry or have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        
        A rights-based approach calls not only for the location of care in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, but
        also for the transfer of planning and decision-making power to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that the health system is supposed to serve. In this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and family
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> must be integrally involved in the policy-making and programming decisions
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,17,18,19</NUMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX> has repeatedly found that funds are misdirected toward rebuilding psychiatric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and orphanages. Further, international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> often undermine
        rights-based approaches to policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX> has documented how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>,
        development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and international humanitarian relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> fund projects to
        build new psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and orphanages throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, rather than focusing on community care [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>].
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Non-Discrimination</ENAMEX>: Within and beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Sector</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nondiscrimination</ENAMEX> is the most fundamental tenet in human rights. Under international
        law, discrimination need not be intentional nor de jure (in law) to constitute a violation
        of various relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">treaties</ENAMEX>, but merely needs to have the “effect of nullifying or
        impairing the equal enjoyment or exercise” of rights (paragraph <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> of [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX> has found that discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with mental disabilities is pervasive,
        and takes many forms. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>, for example, the public health insurance scheme does not
        cover mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. However, it is critical to recognize that discrimination
        outside the health sector also affects well-being. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDRI</ENAMEX> has seen that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with
        intellectual disabilities are denied equal access to education in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>. They are placed in
        programs that in effect warehouse them and assume that they are unable to learn [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. As
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with mental disabilities are often denied the right to work outside the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, to marry or have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, or to take part in the religious and social activities
        that define <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult members</ENAMEX> of society [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>].
        A human rights approach to mental health policy demands that special attention be placed
        on remedying such inequities—both within and beyond the health sector—which affect the
        physical, mental, and social well-being of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with mental disabilities [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. Such an
        approach depends upon multisectoral strategies including education, housing, and work, and
        establish that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with mental disabilities are full <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reflections</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> Steps
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MDRI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> through a human rights framework that links the improvement of mental health
        services with broader questions of social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> and nondiscrimination relating to the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> spectrum of rights set out in international instruments [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,14</NUMEX>]. As an immediate first
        step, all states—regardless of resources—can develop national mental health policies and
        plans of action with measurable targets, which provide for open public discussion [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,23</NUMEX>].
        Devising a national policy is a precondition to creating rights-based programs that address
        the multivalent problems faced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with mental disability [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Stakeholder
        participation in the process affirms that mentally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled people</ENAMEX> are rights-worthy
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,17</NUMEX>].
        Both international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> can play critical roles in
        policies [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,4</NUMEX>]. Bilateral and multilateral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> should encourage such rights-based
        policies through their funding prerogatives.
      
    
  
