
  
    
      
        
        In a compelling essay in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clarke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> Cochrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX>, lays down a challenge to clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and journal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. He argues
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> should do a study only if there is a systematic review that shows that the
        new study is needed. If no review exists, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> should do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> themselves before
        embarking on their research. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, he argues, should publish a study only if an
        updated systematic review is incorporated into the study, or published alongside it or
        shortly thereafter. How should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> respond to his challenge?
        First, we would argue that by the time a paper is sent to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, it is surely too
        late in the process to be insisting on systematic reviews. If a clinical trial report meets
        our criteria for originality, importance, and quality, it makes little sense for us to
        reject it just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> failed to systematically review the literature when
        designing their study. The time to mandate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> do a review is much
        earlier‚Äîwhen they apply for funding, register their trial, or seek ethics committee
        approval.
        There is no doubt that the best research builds on previous knowledge. But
        unfortunately, the current medical publishing system hides much of this knowledge behind
        subscription or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúpay per view‚Äù charges, which discriminates against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> who do not
        work for well-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, for example,
        recently told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depressingly</ENAMEX> familiar story of trying to search the medical literature in
        preparation for a research project [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]; access barriers got in their way. So our second
        response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s challenge is that it will remain difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>,
        particularly in resource-poor settings, to do systematic reviews unless the medical
        literature is made a freely available public resource.
        Many clinical trials, especially negative ones, remain unpublished, which prevents
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> from reviewing all the data on an important health issue. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main
        reasons why certain trials are not published: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is that the pharmaceutical industry has a
        long history of suppressing data that are commercially unfavorable and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is that
        medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and the popular media favor publication of positive over negative trials
        (after all, negative trials do not make for a provocative newspaper headline). While we
        support the recent announcement on trial registration by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Committee of</ENAMEX>
        Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal Editors‚</ENAMEX>Äîas a condition of considering a trial for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, member
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> will require registration of the trial in a public trials registry [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>]‚Äîwe believe
        that this policy addresses only part of the problem.
        The scientific literature will remain biased unless the publishing industry changes its
        practices and provides a place where the results from all registered trials can be
        published. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> is committed to publishing high-quality negative trials. In
        this issue, for example, we publish an important randomized controlled trial of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">372</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gambian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, which found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> was ineffective at reducing the
        natural infection rate.
        The internet makes it possible for every single clinical trial to be publicly and
        seamlessly tracked through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three tiers</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> tier is registration in a publicly
        available database. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is the publication of a peer-reviewed summary of every
        trial, regardless of its outcome, in a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> format, with annotations and
        critiques that help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> understand the trial's implications. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> is the
        deposition of detailed trial data in a structured, computable format that allows
        sophisticated searching and analyses across trials. This format will allow the development
        of better tools to help clinicians apply trial results to their practice. For trial data to
        be as useful as possible, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tiers</ENAMEX> must be publicly accessible. Assessment of each
        trial's validity is critical, but should not stop crucial information about all trials
        being placed in the public domain.
        Trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">registries</ENAMEX> exist, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ClinicalTrials</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Standard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Randomised Controlled Trial Number registry</ENAMEX>. Moreover, many trials are registered in a
        semi-public database maintained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>, and
        there are compelling arguments (which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX> articulates in an essay published online ahead
        of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> issue [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]) for making this a truly public resource. Publicly accessible
        trial databases (such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trial Bank Project</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://rctbank.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ucsf</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">edu</ENAMEX>) are under
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. And as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> committed to open access, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> will provide the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>,
        essential tier‚Äîjournals capable of peer reviewing and publishing an annotated report of
        every trial. Traditional medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, with their subscription-based model, are
        unlikely to be able to provide this service, because in order to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> they
        need to publish only the highest-profile trials. We believe that an open-access model‚Äîin
        which the research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funder</ENAMEX> pays a publication fee to recover the costs of peer review and
        for hosting the report on a secure server‚Äîis the best mechanism for creating such venues.
        We are working to make that happen.
        Returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s challenge, our final response is to say that we have a bold vision
        of a freely accessible online world of clinical trials‚Äîfrom registration to annotated
        summaries to trial databases. That world would be even richer if every systematic review
        were made freely available. We challenge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cochrane Collaboration</ENAMEX> to put the full text of
        all of its reviews into the public domain. We hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cochrane Collaboration</ENAMEX> will join us
        in the open-access revolution.
      
    
  
