
  
    
      
        
        The excellent article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan Paradise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori B. Andrews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúEthics</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Constructing Ethical Guidelines for Biohistory‚</ENAMEX>Äù [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>], neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> nor argues against
        biohistorical research; instead, it points out that such investigations are currently
        taking place without guidelines‚Äîethical, scientific, moral, or religious. The question
        remains: if such guidelines were to be established, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiners</ENAMEX>, family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intrepid biographers</ENAMEX> are to be given
        permission? Who is to decide what is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúhistorically significant‚Äù</ENAMEX>? Not to mention the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meta</ENAMEX>-question: who is to decide who is to decide? I apologize to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> if my brief
        comments [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] implied that they took a position on this issue.
      
    
  
