
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Dementia</ENAMEX> remains an incurable condition and its increasing prevalence is a deeply
        worrying aspect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">“graying”</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. An important question for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        is to establish whether dementia incidence, prevalence, and national history vary from one
        location to another. Incidence studies are particularly valuable for less biased comparison
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease occurrence</ENAMEX>, as well as being essential for policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. Many biases can,
        however, be introduced in such studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dropout</ENAMEX> and mortality are particular reasons for
        concern.
        Most of the numerous studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia incidence</ENAMEX> have been restricted to single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> have frequently attempted to assess whether rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given</TIMEX> study are similar to
        those obtained elsewhere. However, variations between studies in the methodology employed
        make such comparisons unreliable. Where within-country variations in incidence have been
        noted, as has happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, they have often been ascribed to methodological
        differences, but one cannot be certain whether this is the case.
        Risk factors for other chronic disorders common in old age (notably cardiovascular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>) do vary in their prevalence between and within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>,
        for example, the incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> is known to vary considerably across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. A
        high proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are thought to have a vascular component to their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dementia</ENAMEX>, and it has been assumed that dementia incidence could be reduced if vascular risk
        were better controlled. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to test this hypothesis is to compare sites with known
        variation in vascular risk to assess whether there is also variation in the incidence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Research Council Cognitive Function</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ageing Study</ENAMEX> (MRC CFAS) is a
        multi-site, population-based study in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years</TIMEX> and over living
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Diverse sites have been chosen, with varying
        exposures of potential importance in dementia. A two-phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-wave design has been
        employed, with the waves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> apart. A standard set of instruments for the diagnosis
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX> is used throughout. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFAS</ENAMEX> now publishes incidence estimates from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> sites,
        using likelihood-based methods to compare the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> waves of interviews.
        Predictably, incidence rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX>, for both sexes, were found to rise with age,
        from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.7</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> years at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 65–69 years</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">68.5</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> years at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 85</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and above. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> estimate that around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">163,000</NUMEX> new cases of dementia occur in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. However, there was no convincing evidence of variation across
        sites, and the incidence rates do not reflect the variations in the prevalence of possible
        risk factors in these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. We therefore cannot assume that action to reduce vascular risk
        will have a significant impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia incidence</ENAMEX>.
        Another issue addressed by the study is previous suggestions in the literature that
        dementia incidence rates might be lower in the oldest age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The limited number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> in these age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in previous studies made it impossible to test this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypothesis</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFAS</ENAMEX>, however, found no evidence of any such tailing off in incidence,
        which also has implications for policy and planning.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFAS</ENAMEX> is important because it provides the first multi-site comparison of incidence
        rates in ethnically homogeneous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> within a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, using
        identical methodology across sites. The methodological approach developed for the study
        will also be of value for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> undertaking other studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia incidence</ENAMEX>, and
        in other chronic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> studies involving a two-phase selection process.
      
    
  
