
  
    
      
        
        Acquired resistance to chemotherapy is a major obstacle to successful <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> treatment.
        Understanding the mechanisms by which tumors become resistant to a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is key
        to identifying new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or combination regimens.
        Kinases are signaling molecules that control many aspects of cell behavior, including
        cell proliferation, i.e., whether and how fast cells divide. Abnormally active kinases
        promoting tumor growth are found in many <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> and are a focus of rational <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> drug
        design. One target for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase inhibitors</ENAMEX> is the epidermal growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor receptor</ENAMEX> (EGFR).
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EGFR inhibitors</ENAMEX>, gefitinib and erlotinib, showed therapeutic benefits in a subset of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Recent work has helped us understand why some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> respond and some don't: responsive tumors usually harbor activating mutations in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> gene, which somehow make the tumors sensitive to treatment. Nearly all patients
        whose tumors initially respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, however, eventually become resistant to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and progress despite continued therapy.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Pao</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> examined tumors from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with non-small cell lung
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> who initially responded to gefitinib or erlotinib but subsequently relapsed. Tumors
        from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> carried activating mutations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> gene. In addition, in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
        out of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> cases, the resistant tumor cells carried an identical second mutation in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> gene. Whereas the activating mutation was present in tumor cells before treatment with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erlotinib</ENAMEX> or gefitinib, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mutation was not found in pre-treatment biopsies from
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, nor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 150</TIMEX> lung cancer samples from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had not been treated
        with either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. Additional cell culture studies supported the notion that the secondary
        mutation causes resistance to gefitinib or erlotinib. It is clear, though, that this is
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>, because in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other cases resistance occurred in
        the absence of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mutation. What caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> in those tumors is not
        known.
        All kinases share some common features, and a resistance mutation very similar to the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> identified here has also been found in other kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from tumors with acquired
        resistance to imatinib, another kinase inhibitor. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Gilliland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> point
        out in an accompanying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspective</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">DOI: 10.1371/journal</TIMEX>.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pmed.0020075</NUMEX>), the initial
        identification <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> of resistance mutations against imatinib led to the rapid
        development of alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase inhibitors</ENAMEX> that work even against tumors with the
        resistance mutation. Similarly, the results by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pao</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> should help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        develop <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> generation <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
