
  
    
      
        Preparing for Death
        How does one prepare for death? Those who have created a public persona must add to any
        spiritual ponderings about eternity the mundane chore of organizing their literary archives
        to protect any of life's secrets that seem worth the effort. That task involves choosing
        what diaries, letters, drafts, and laundry lists to donate to a university or to leave in a
        closet for legions of biographical ragpickers to quote, misquote, or variously interpret in
        as yet unimaginable contexts‚Äîor to burn.
        Many well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> contemplating their posthumous selves have been foiled in
        exercising control over their literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX>. Purposefully confounding future
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigmund Freud</ENAMEX> burned his early papers and admonished his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> to
        destroy their love letters. Instead, she bequeathed us this charming insight into the
        youthful exuberance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> of psychoanalysis, written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWoe to you, my
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess</ENAMEX>, when I come. I will kiss you quite red and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> you till you are plump. And if
        you are forward, you shall see who is stronger, a gentle little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who doesn't eat enough
        or a big wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> in his body‚Äù [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana√Øs Nin</ENAMEX>, whose voluminous diaries recorded her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life in exquisite, compulsively
        recorded detail, had better luck in choreographing her literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">afterlife</ENAMEX>. While alive, she
        published volumes of carefully edited literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX>. When someone at a seminar remarked
        to her that her life seemed more, well, racy than those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX> revealed, she smiled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mysteriously</ENAMEX> and said that after the death of all concerned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúunexpurgated‚Äù</ENAMEX> editions would
        be published. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several decades later</TIMEX>, companion volumes to the literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX> revealed
        passionate incest with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim Nin</ENAMEX>, an affair with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto Rank</ENAMEX>, and
        successfully bigamous marriages in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
        When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andr√© Gide</ENAMEX> revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX> had had sexual relations with a young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> boy
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Sherard</ENAMEX> lamented: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚ÄúHeavens</ENAMEX>! The task of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shooing hyenas</ENAMEX> away
        from the graves of the illustrious dead.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Sherard</ENAMEX> meant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grave‚</ENAMEX>Äîbut what
        about actual graves? What about history's corpus delicti?
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Line</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grave Robber</ENAMEX>
        How many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> and tyrants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlucky</ENAMEX> enough to have left body parts or ashes behind when
        they shuffled off the mortal coil could have imagined what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and medical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> of the future would do with their physical remains? Here, the line between
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> and the grave robber blurs, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> are exhumed and cremation urns raided
        to provide organic remnants for any number of curious purposes.
        Ethical debates about the appropriate care and maintenance of biological relics often
        begin at the autopsy table. Having removed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX>'s brain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey</ENAMEX> chopped it into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX> pieces and stored it in a cookie jar in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>, often
        shipping slabs (mailed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mayonnaise jars</ENAMEX>) to brain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> eager to count glia and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurons</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey</ENAMEX> lugged what remained of the brain cross-country to
        deliver it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Einstein</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> rumored to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> from an
        affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Boyd</ENAMEX> had tried to prove this paternity with his
        brain-chunk, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA proved ‚Äútoo denatured</ENAMEX> to decipher.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer driver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Paterniti</ENAMEX>, described getting his hands in the cookie
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">jar: ‚</ENAMEX>ÄúI actually feel as if I might puke. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are sealed in celloidin‚Äîthe pinkish,
        liver-colored blobs of brain rimmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> wax. I pick some out of the plastic container
        and hand a few to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn</ENAMEX>. They feel squishy, weigh about the same as very light beach
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>. We hold them up like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jewelers</ENAMEX>, marveling at how they seem less like a brain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than‚Äîwhat?‚</ENAMEX>Äîsome kind of snack <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, some kind of energy chunk for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> triathletes‚Äù
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pilferers</ENAMEX> cannot resist snipping body parts. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> was being autopsied, his
        ophthalmologist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Abrams</ENAMEX>, dropped by and filched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s brown eyes as a
        keepsake, storing them in a jar in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> bank <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX>. There were rumors that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>, a collector of body parts, offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several million dollars</NUMEX> for the
        eyes.
        
          Does confidentiality extend beyond the grave?
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>'s ears were hacked out and soon went missing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ren√© Descartes</ENAMEX>'s middle finger
        was stolen. (His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> was also separated from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> for shipping‚Äîa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX>'s
        in-joke, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Descartes</ENAMEX> introduced the mind/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> split into Western philosophy.)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>'s reputed penis went on a picaresque odyssey of its own, being displayed at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of French Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, auctioned, and finally ending up in the possession of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urologist‚Äîor</ENAMEX> so the story goes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef Haydn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> was stolen by phrenologists at his
        burial.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anunciada Colon</ENAMEX> presided over the opening of a golden trunk from the 16th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, containing ashes and bone fragments presumed to belong to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ancestor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, an event chronicled by a television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX>
        allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Granada</ENAMEX> to borrow the bones for a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> study. Being
        unsuccessful at extracting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from pulverized fragments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jos√© A. Lorente</ENAMEX> loaded
        the bones in a shoulder bag and flew them to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, where more sophisticated DNA
        tests (developed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the terrorist attack of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/11</NUMEX>) provided a
        disappointingly short and impure sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mitochondrial DNA</ENAMEX>. Remaining ashes and shards
        were inelegantly deposited on a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> storage shelf in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Styrofoam</ENAMEX> picnic basket
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">labeled ‚ÄúColon‚Äù</ENAMEX> in black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marker</ENAMEX>, awaiting better tests [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Ilyich Lenin</ENAMEX> remains the most visible deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, or what
        remains of it since his brain and other organs were removed, has been viewed by the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> who have passed by his open casket in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Square</ENAMEX>. A
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waterproof</ENAMEX> suit under his uniform holds in the embalming fluid. His hands and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bathed</ENAMEX> frequently. His microtomed (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31,000</NUMEX> sections) and dyed brain resides down the street
        from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Brain Institute</ENAMEX>, joining the brains of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tchaikovsky</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> who find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>'s public resting place a macabre
        embarrassment think his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> will only rest (and theirs with it) once he goes underground.
        But who can decree his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX>?
        When I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> found me exhuming a goldfish we had ceremoniously buried in
        the garden in a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> coffin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> before. How different, I wonder now, was my
        childish curiosity and wonderment at the mysterious process happening to my
        no-longer-swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> below the earth from that of grown-up exhumers? Consider Gira
        Fornaciari, who unearthed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medici</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to confirm various causes of
        death, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schubert</ENAMEX> dug up to transfer them to more
        secure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc coffins</ENAMEX> (borrowing both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> for a bit more measuring, and swiping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schubert</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">luxuriant</ENAMEX>, larvae-laden hair while they were at it). Archaeologists have braved curses and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biohazards</ENAMEX> to retrieve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mummies</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, however, were not allowed
        to take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tut</ENAMEX>'s mummy to sort out his genealogy; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supreme</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> of antiquities, after first agreeing, reversed the decision. A non-invasive
        x-ray of the mummy suggests a murder plot: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Tut</ENAMEX> may have been done in by a blow to the
        back of the skull.
      
      
        Guidelines for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bioethical Research</ENAMEX>
        When a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> was convened to decide whether specimens of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and bones
        should be tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> to discover whether he suffered from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Marfan syndrome</ENAMEX>, ethicists
        voted yes but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> vetoed the plan, claiming that the precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> should not be
        destroyed in case future tests would prove more effective [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,5</NUMEX>]. But what if they were even
        asking the wrong question? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> once told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Herndon</ENAMEX> that
        he had been infected with syphilis by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beardstown</ENAMEX> around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1835</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. What if a
        future test could prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> had spoken the truth? Imagine, if you will, a press
        most beloved of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> testing question spurred bioethicist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori Andrews</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Historical Society</ENAMEX> to join with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Institute of Technology</ENAMEX> to review
        existing ethical issues of biohistorical research. Their conclusion, after studying
        professional codes from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>: none contained guidelines for conducting
        biohistorical research and analysis [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. They recommend genetic testing for ‚Äúhistorically
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">significant‚Äù</ENAMEX> questions. But who is to define that loaded phrase?
        The newly dead are warm, soft, and somehow still human; by contrast, aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skeletons</ENAMEX> rising from the cold ground are the stuff of horror films, vampires and ghouls.
        While fascinating, they also unnerve. Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiners</ENAMEX> in fiction (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kay Scarpetta</ENAMEX>) and
        television (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr. Quincy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan Cavanaugh</ENAMEX>) capture wide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> with their gruesome and
        graphic dissection of putrefied, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maggot-ridden corpses</ENAMEX>, all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of solving some
        medical mystery.
      
      
        Respect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>
        Does confidentiality extend beyond the grave? Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> publish articles in medical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> about diagnoses that were confidential when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was alive? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Physicians</ENAMEX> have
        often raced to put pen to paper and reveal the signs and symptoms of their more illustrious
        deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Sexton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Wood Middlebrook</ENAMEX>, who used
        tapes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of therapy sessions given to her by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapist</ENAMEX> Dr.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Orne</ENAMEX>, the dead have no rights [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orne</ENAMEX> insisted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexton</ENAMEX> had given
        him permission to do what he thought appropriate with the tapes, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> howled that
        he had made a travesty of doctor-patient confidentiality, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexton</ENAMEX>'s wishes be damned.
        The long-dead are latecomers to the game of lobbying for rights. Who owns their bones?
        Who is to choose the right test, the right time, the appropriate question to ask? Who gets
        to decide whether they should be sliced, diced, dyed, pulverized, displayed, x-rayed,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographed</ENAMEX>, and subjected to the esoteric tests developed for forensic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> to
        reveal secrets they carefully took to their graves or urns? An interdisciplinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>?
        The law? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>? Should such decisions be made by bioethicists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, medical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, archaeologists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of the deceased? Where does simple respect
        for the dead play into this issue?
        The answers change over time and from place to place. The quagmire of ethical, legal,
        moral, and even aesthetic questions that surround the use (and misuse) of leftover body
        parts can only become more complex and contentious, not less.
        A word of warning, then, to the famous not-yet-deceased: consider the disposition of
        your physical remains as carefully as you consider the packaging of your archive.
        Swear your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> to posthumous secrecy.
        Be cremated.
        And have your ashes scattered to the wind.
      
    
  
