
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerberding</ENAMEX> outlines critical steps for arresting the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. She
        suggests moving ahead with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúABCs‚Äù</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">with ‚ÄúD‚Äù</ENAMEX> for diagnosis and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúR‚Äù</ENAMEX> for responsibility.
        These are good suggestions‚Äîwith increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> testing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> taking responsibility
        for their role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> spread, the epidemic might be slowed. We could continue to add
        incrementally to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alphabet soup</ENAMEX> of public health. But instead, we could choose to
        immediately implement the mainstays of public health‚Äîuniversal testing and contact tracing
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,3,4</NUMEX>]. Every sexually active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> at risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> deserves to
        know their <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> status. Thus, every HIV-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> must be called upon to be
        accountable for preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> transmission. Contact tracing should be instituted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        just as it is for other infectious diseases. Those who have been exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> have a
        right to know how to protect themselves and if they too are infected, to be offered
        treatment [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> testing has too often focused on testing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in a perinatal setting
        rather than universal testing in routine clinical care. Without universal voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        testing and contact tracing, we will see the continued tilt of the epidemic toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
        now at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV infections</ENAMEX> and in all likelihood at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì80%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 8 to 10 years</TIMEX>
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,7</NUMEX>]. For too long the debate has been that contact tracing will result in physical abuse
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Confining our definition of abuse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to physical abuse alone is to have too
        narrow an ethical focus‚ÄîHIV infection itself is an abuse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or of anyone else.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal HIV</ENAMEX> testing and contact tracing adds an essential comprehensive public health
        approach to the epidemic that will be successful in reducing the ever-escalating numbers of
        new infections.
      
    
  
