
  
    
      
        
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe that as societies advance economically they have higher levels of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiovascular disease</ENAMEX> (CVD) and other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">noncommunicable disease</ENAMEX> (NCD) risks. However, a more
        detailed analysis of how parameters of economic development are associated with health
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCD</ENAMEX> risk factors is needed to inform local and global health policies.
        Such an analysis might dispel prejudices about the “diseases of affluence” and stimulate
        policy approaches and research that appropriately target emerging risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> across the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX>, regardless of socioeconomic status.
      
      
        From Intuition to Data
        In a study in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ezzati</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have taken a close look at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> data available in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80 or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> on body mass index (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>, and
        hypertension [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. They looked at how these CVD risk indicators are predicted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> broad
        economic parameters: national income, average share of household expenditure spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>,
        and proportion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> living in urban areas. This cross-sectional analysis drew
        on published studies, reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> of health and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> from household surveys, demographic data, and centrally available economic indicator
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> to model the relationship between the selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVD</ENAMEX> risk factors and
        economic/demographic status.
        The overall results suggest that average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> increase with national
        income and then flatten out at higher incomes (or even decline), except in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX> and of leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> of the sedentary urban
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyle</ENAMEX> (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> and cholesterol levels do not flatten out with higher income).
        Not surprisingly, there is an inverse relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> and proportion of household
        income needed for buying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urbanization</ENAMEX> is associated with higher average income, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ezzatti</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> found
        that urbanization is associated with higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>. As urbanization progresses
        and food availability equalizes among both urban and rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, there is less of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> between increasing income and increasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>. However, some
        persistently agricultural economies with large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>)
        tend to retain the inequities that influence diets, leading to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-calorie deficiencies
        among those with lower income and increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> among those with higher income. Systolic
        blood pressure did not have as robust a relationship as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> to urbanization
        or national income.
      
      
        Looking Ahead
        Despite the limitations of multinational data and the broad brush approach used to
        interpret these data, there are some important lessons that emerge from this study
        regarding the population distribution of multiple CVD risk factors. These risk factors are
        systematically finding their way to low- and middle-income <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and the vulnerable
        populations therein that still suffer from childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> and high communicable disease
        burdens.
        This shift is already having an effect on the epidemiology of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVD</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCDs</ENAMEX>,
        particularly in middle-income <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. And we can predict that as low-income countries
        achieve economic growth, the disease burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCDs</ENAMEX> will be waiting for them as well.
        Effective policies can prevent some of this impact, if action is taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezzati</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' work provides a basis for planning such interventions.
      
      
        Planning for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>
        To target these interventions effectively, better data are needed on the prevalence of
        CVD risk factors in low- and middle-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of these
        risk factors with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCD</ENAMEX> health outcomes. CVD risk factor surveillance should be incorporated
        into national program planning and into best practices for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCD</ENAMEX> control supported by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> and other health development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Multinational agreements,
        such as the recently activated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Framework Convention on Tobacco Control</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX>who.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">int/tobacco/en</ENAMEX>), can create effective international cooperative efforts to stem
        the tide of global tobacco use. Global tobacco control should be a health and foreign
        policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> even for those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have not ratified the treaty.
        As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> assume more of an urban lifestyle, they should not be limited in their
        choices for healthy foods, suffer from lack of safe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, or lose opportunities for
        physical activity. These problems can be reduced through good urban planning, better food
        policies, improved environmental engineering, and better attention to healthy lifestyle
        practices in our growing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. Screening for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>, hypercholesterolemia, and
        nicotine addiction need to become a part of good clinical practices in low- and
        middle-income <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Of course, screening for these risks should then also be
        accompanied by better availability of low-priced secondary prevention therapies such as
        generic versions of anti-hypertensives, statins, and nicotine replacement therapies.
      
      
        Getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balance Right</ENAMEX>
        This is not to say that the big infectious disease <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> health problems
        should be ignored. Rather, we need to learn from the history of socioeconomic development
        that it is not simply affluence that permits the increased impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVD</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCDs</ENAMEX>; it
        is the risk factors for these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that spread across socioeconomic boundaries, causing
        the same illnesses regardless of the socioeconomic status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        Increased attention should be paid to these diseases not just in the developed world,
        but also in the developing world, where the unfinished agendas on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">communicable disease</ENAMEX> and
        childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> have drawn the most attention. Addressing CVD risk factors could best be
        accomplished through improved international cooperation, better understanding of the risks
        of globalization, and development of appropriate research and technologies that apply to
        low- and middle-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
