
  
    
      
        
        Current journal requirements forcing clinical trials to be registered [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] are
        insufficient and are unlikely to solve the problem of negative trials never even making it
        to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> consenting to clinical trials do so out of altruism. It
        is a great betrayal of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> to suppress clinical trial data. I suggest that
        institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review boards</ENAMEX> refuse to allow human experimentation unless the protocol is
        filed in a central (online) repository. The primary data should also be required to be in
        the public domain (say, within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1–2 years</TIMEX> after completion). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> obtained by appealing to
        altrusitic instincts, similar to money in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>, are not proprietary
        information, nor can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> cash out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. In reality, it is the
        pharmaceutical industry that stands to gain the most if data are made public as such data
        inform future research and help smaller, innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> avoid redundancy. Voluntarily
        sticking to higher standards of ethics will raise societal respect for the industry
        (currently being battered for greed) and attract a more talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, and may even
        help the current efforts to reform the tort law.
      
    
  
