
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Randomized</ENAMEX> trials and observational studies have conclusively shown a marked improvement
        in several cardiovascular risk factors when obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> lose weight, including
        decreases in blood pressure, and improvements in the lipid profile and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose metabolism</ENAMEX>.
        These results are closely consistent with observational data linking weight gain to
        worsening of these cardiovascular risk factors, and to their natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sequelae</ENAMEX>, clinical
        cardiovascular events. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obesity</ENAMEX> is also strongly associated with increased risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> at
        various sites. With such compelling evidence of the adverse effects of obesity and
        overweight [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1–4</NUMEX>], why has there been a continuing controversy about its association with
        overall mortality?
        In their paper in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaakio Kaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> conclude that “deliberate
        weight loss in overweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> without known co-morbidities may be hazardous in the
        long term” [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. Do the data really support such a conclusion? An examination of this paper
        illustrates several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> in approaching this seemingly simple question.
      
      
        Evidence from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemiological Studies</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemiologic</ENAMEX> studies of the relation between <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX> and mortality typically must
        address <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> principal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. First, in many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> tend to
        be leaner than nonsmokers. Because cigarette smoking is such a strong risk factor for
        mortality, failure to adjust for this adequately can lead to confounding, with the
        erroneous conclusion that leanness carries increased risk of death. Statistical adjustment
        for smoking is often insufficient to account for this difficulty. Smoking can lead to
        medical conditions, sometimes sub-clinical, that are associated with decreased body weight,
        such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. The presence of symptoms or diagnosed
        conditions may induce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> to quit. Moreover, the intensity of smoking is related to
        both risk of death and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> mass index. For these reasons, the best way to assess the
        impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX> on risk of mortality is simply to exclude current and past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' study differentiated only current smoker or nonsmoker. Thus,
        never-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> were included in the same category as past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>, regardless of how much
        the past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> had smoked or their reasons for quitting.
        A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> difficulty in some epidemiologic studies is the inclusion of intermediary
        factors as co-variates. Weight loss improves <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, so including these
        as co-variates would tend to attenuate the apparent benefit of weight loss. In the present
        study, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> appropriately excluded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, and adjustment for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hypertension</ENAMEX> appeared to have little impact.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and most difficult issue in studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX> and mortality is reverse
        causation, the impact of disease on body weight. This can occur either through the
        biological impact of a condition (diagnosed or preclinical) or as an inducement to attempt
        to lose weight as a means to improve health. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' keen recognition of this problem
        provides a significant strength to the present study. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> appropriately excluded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with a wide range of conditions to identify an apparently healthy cohort. This
        critical step is often ignored. Sometimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> also exclude deaths that occur in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first few years</TIMEX> after follow-up, to reduce the impact of reverse causation. Such lagged
        analyses can be helpful, but some chronic conditions of long duration, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>,
        chronic lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart failure</ENAMEX> (conditions that often may not reach the level of
        clinical diagnosis) can lead to lower body weight and higher mortality risk. Hence, that
        strategy (not employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>) may not fully avoid the problem.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Difficulties of Assessing the Effects of Intention to Lose Weight</ENAMEX>
        As a further step toward reducing the potential bias of the impact of disease on body
        weight, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with intent to lose weight. Unintended weight
        loss is well known as an ominous clinical sign, usually signifying a serious illness. Just
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a third</NUMEX> of the overweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaprio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohort</ENAMEX> had expressed intent to lose
        weight at baseline in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>. It is interesting to note that despite this intention, as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, the median weight change in the ensuing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> was a gain of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.33 kg</NUMEX>/m
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , almost identical to the weight change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that had not
        expressed intent to lose weight (gain of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.31 kg</NUMEX>/m
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ). Thus, this study cannot fairly be characterized as an assessment of
        intentional weight loss and its subsequent effect on mortality. Because the changes in
        weight are so similar in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, it is implausible to attribute the weight loss
        in the intent-to-lose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to that intention. These findings render the results
        particularly difficult to interpret.
        Other important limitations include the very small number of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">endpoints—only 268</NUMEX> total
        deaths in the cohort. When further subdivided according to intention to lose weight, and
        categories of weight change, the numbers are far from sufficient for reliable estimates.
        For example, the main conclusions are based on the subgroup of those with intent to lose
        weight who actually lost weight; this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> deaths, of which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> were violent.
        Another related difficulty is that this cohort, though <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX>, is not drastically
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obese</ENAMEX>. The median body mass index (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>) was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">26.7 kg</NUMEX>/m
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 10%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> greater than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. With such a
        narrow range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>, coupled with the very small changes in weight during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six years</TIMEX> of
        initial follow-up, even a very large study would not have sufficient power to detect
        plausible relative risks associated with weight change.
      
      
        What Advice Should Be Given?
        Given the well-known adverse metabolic consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX> and obesity, the
        strong links with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiovascular disease</ENAMEX> and several other serious illnesses, and the
        absence of any plausible adverse biologic consequences of maintaining normal weight (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
        to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>), it seems prudent to continue advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to seek to maintain a weight within
        that range. The results from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaprio et al</ENAMEX>, although they raise questions about the effects
        of weight loss, do not cast serious doubt on that advice.
      
    
  
