
  
    
      
        
        Postherpetic neuralgia (PHN) is a chronically painful condition that is a complication
        of shingles (acute herpes zoster), a recurrence of the varicella-zoster virus, which
        initially causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chickenpox</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shingles</ENAMEX> usually resolves within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>, some people
        continue to feel the pain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PHN</ENAMEX> long after the rash and blisters heal, because of nerve
        damage (neuropathic pain) caused by the shingles. Not everyone who has had shingles
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">develops PHN</ENAMEX>, although it is a common complication of shingles in older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.
        Despite advances in antiviral therapy during acute herpes zoster and the more recent
        introduction of vaccination against varicella zoster, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX> continues to be a significant
        clinical problem, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10‚Äì20%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> developing persistent neuropathic pain after
        acute herpes zoster reactivation. The nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX> pain is variable, which implies that a
        variety of mechanisms might be operating. This variability has led to the hypothesis that
        treatment plans could be optimised for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> on the basis of the individual
        pattern of their symptoms or the underlying mechanism of the pain.
        However, the current evidence base for therapies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX> is based on clinical trials of
        analgesics, which have examined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX> as a single disease <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, there is
        little evidence for the efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for specific sets of symptoms and no simple way
        to determine which pain mechanisms might be operating in an individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Rice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> reassessed the evidence base
        by doing a systematic review and meta-analysis of analgesic therapy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX>, which has
        fundamentally changed in the wake of several major new trials. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> searched the
        literature for trials of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX> and retrieved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> articles, of which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> were kept for final
        analysis.
        Their analysis confirmed several previous research findings, although they cautioned
        that the meta-analytic study design of collecting data from a range of trials had several
        inherent pitfalls, and it is difficult to directly compare treatments across different
        trials.
        However, they found evidence for analgesic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">efficacy</ENAMEX> in established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX> for orally
        administered therapies, such as tricyclic antidepressants, some opioids, gabapentin,
        tramadol, and pregabalin. Some topically administered therapies, such as lidocaine and
        capsaicin, were associated with analgesic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">efficacy</ENAMEX> in selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. However, it
        appeared that therapies such as oral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NMDA</ENAMEX> receptor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>,
        codeine, ibuprofen, lorazepam, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">5HT1 receptor agonists</ENAMEX>, and acyclovir were not efficacious
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX>.
        Altogether, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> conclude that the evidence base supports the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-line use of a
        tricyclic antidepressant for orally administered treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX>, reserving the
        gabapentinoids for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-line use. Topical treatments, such as lidocaine or capsaicin,
        should be considered as <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-line treatment if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> falls into the ‚Äúsensitised
        nociceptor‚Äù as opposed to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúdeafferentation‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub-group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        The role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intrathecal steroid</ENAMEX> is still not clear: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trial indicated that intrathecal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> were associated with benefits in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX>, but this therapy might be
        hazardous, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have concluded that further high-quality
        trials of this therapy are needed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> found little evidence regarding possible
        synergistic effects of the various treatments to support or refute the concomitant use of
        combinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
        They stressed that any treatment plan must recognise the importance of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biopsychosocial</ENAMEX> model of chronic pain and that any pharmacologically based management of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX> should be combined with advice on and management of psychological and social
        aspects.
        Finally, as there is no single pathophysiology that underlies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHN</ENAMEX>, they propose that
        future studies should use quantitative sensory evaluation to clearly categorise subsets of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> for better interpretation of treatment effects.
      
    
  
