
  
    
      
        
        Scientific truth is a moving target. In the process of peer review, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> work together to minimize the reporting of false results. However, even if one
        assumes no bias, wrongdoing, or ignorance on the part of any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
        involved—which is unrealistic, no doubt—chances are that some findings will turn out to be
        false. But is it inevitable, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ioannidis</ENAMEX> argues in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Essay</ENAMEX> in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">DOI: 10.1371/journal</TIMEX>.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pmed.0020124</NUMEX>), that the majority of
        findings are actually false?
        Although his calculations are based on assumptions about complex scenarios that we do
        not fully understand—as is true for most research projects—Ioannidis argues convincingly
        that many published findings will turn out to be false.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ioannidis</ENAMEX> is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to raise some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. Indeed, there are already
        initiatives under way that seek to address them. Increasingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> design
        individual studies, systematic reviews, and meta-analyses using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayesian</ENAMEX> statistics, in
        which the issue of pre-study odds is taken into account. And issues such as reducing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of bias when assessing evidence are addressed in the methodology used by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cochrane Collaboration</ENAMEX> in the production of its systematic reviews.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ioannidis</ENAMEX> doesn't define “findings,” but it seems important to attempt to separate data
        (“in this study <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> examined who lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1965–1970</NUMEX> developed
        lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> studied who lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anchorage”</ENAMEX>) from conclusions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">(“lung cancer</ENAMEX> rates are higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anchorage</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco”</ENAMEX>) and hypotheses (“cold
        weather exacerbates the consequences of smoking”).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hypotheses</ENAMEX> will inevitably change, as they depend not only on the study but also on the
        context of other relevant research and knowledge. Conclusions are also often based on
        current knowledge and assumptions, and, thus, subject to change. The data should be more
        robust; for instance, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> applying the same methods to study the same group
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at the same time should be able to generate the same data. However, research
        progress depends on conclusions being tested elsewhere. The major issue about the truth of
        research findings would therefore seem to concern the conclusions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ioannidis</ENAMEX>'s claim
        that most conclusions are false is probably correct. Is that a problem? Can it be
        avoided?
        The possibility that most conclusions are false might be an inevitable part of the
        research endeavor. That said, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and those involved in publication of research
        must do what they can to reduce false conclusions.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to do this is to delay publication until such a time when the chances that a
        conclusion is true are sufficiently high. If many published conclusions are false, we
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>) need to ask ourselves whether we are setting the bar too low. But
        what is the consequence of setting it higher?
        Research progress depends on dissemination of results, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> articles are the most
        effective tool we currently have to share them. The answer, therefore, cannot be that we
        wait until conclusions are proven beyond a doubt before we publish them. Publication of
        preliminary findings, negative studies, confirmations, and refutations is an essential part
        of the process of getting closer to the truth. Everyone involved in the generation and
        publication of research results needs to be open-minded, rigorous, and honest in designing
        experiments, analyzing results, reporting findings, peer-reviewing manuscripts, providing
        comments, and accepting that uncertainty exists in research.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ioannidis</ENAMEX> suggests how studies could be designed from the outset to increase their
        chances of producing true results. He also gives some corollaries that allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to get
        a sense of the extent of uncertainty for a particular study. He stresses that reliable
        evidence generally comes from several studies and from several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, and
        that what matters is the totality of the evidence.
        What can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> do? At high-impact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> such as 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , we see it as our job to select important articles. This
        means the conclusions reported should be more rather than less likely to be true. But
        better measures of importance are that a study should address a substantial clinical or
        public- health question, in as rigorous a way as possible, and the findings should be
        likely to have an effect on how other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> think about the question. In reporting
        studies, we ask that data are clearly delineated from conclusions, and conclusions from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypotheses</ENAMEX>. In addition to individual studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> should (and at 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> we do) ensure there is a place for articles that synthesize
        evidence from different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
        Too often <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> reward only the cleanest results and the most
        straightforward conclusions. At 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , we seek to create a publication environment that is
        comfortable with uncertainty. We encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> to discuss biases, study limitations,
        and potential confounding factors. We acknowledge that most studies published should be
        viewed as hypothesis-generating, rather than conclusive. And we publish high-quality
        negative and confirmatory studies.
        We also accept some responsibility for educating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of research about the
        research process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> also need to become comfortable with uncertainty, and
        understand the strengths and weaknesses intrinsic to every study conducted and published.
        Besides selecting papers and influencing how results are reported, we use the synopses and
        patient summaries to highlight uncertainties in research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. We also encourage
        contributions such as the essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ioannidis</ENAMEX> to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> section that will help
        research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to understand research findings in context.
      
    
  
