
  
    
      
        
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celiac disease</ENAMEX> can eliminate their symptoms—at a price: life-long
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adherence</ENAMEX> to a gluten-free diet. This means no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barley</ENAMEX>, and, until recently, no
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX>. Then some recent studies suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> did not cause the intestinal
        inflammation characteristic of the disease, and thus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> are now often included in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celiac disease</ENAMEX> diet. This is good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> coping with severe restrictions on what
        they can and must not eat, but a study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ludvig Sollid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> are not safe in all cases.
        Like other chronic inflammatory diseases, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celiac disease</ENAMEX> is caused by a complex
        Long believed to be a relatively rare disorder, it is now thought to affect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> worldwide. Clinical symptoms are present in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and vary
        considerably. Genetically, almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> predisposing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HLA</ENAMEX> molecules,
        which determine the context in which their immune system encounters foreign antigens,
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gluten proteins</ENAMEX> found in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereals</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with celiac
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, the immune system mounts an abnormal response to gluten, which is characterized by
        gluten-reactive intestinal T cells and by inflammation and compromised function of the
        small intestine.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludvig Sollid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> applied the current understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celiac disease</ENAMEX> and a
        range of molecular pathology tools to studying the response to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celiac disease</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were not a random sample: all of them had been eating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oats</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them had shown clinical symptoms after <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> ingestion. The goal of the
        study was to characterize the intestinal T cell response to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and to
        relate it to clinical symptoms and intestinal biopsy results. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were on a
        gluten-free diet and ate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> that were free of contamination by other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereals</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had reported problems after eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> showed intestinal
        inflammation typical of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celiac disease</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sollid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> studied intestinal T
        cells from these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who seemed to tolerate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> also
        had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX>-reactive intestinal T cells. Functional study of these T cells showed that they
        were restricted to celiac-disease-associated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HLA</ENAMEX> molecules and that they recognized two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX> derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oat avenin</ENAMEX> that are very similar to peptides of gluten.
        Taken together, the findings show that intolerance to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> exists at least in some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celiac disease</ENAMEX>, and that those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have the same molecular reaction to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barley</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rye</ENAMEX>. However, identical reactions were
        also seen in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were clinically tolerant to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> suggest
        that these reactions could develop into symptomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> after some time delay, but
        there is no proof that the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX>-reactive T cells is an indicator of future
        symptoms or even of enhanced susceptibility to clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats intolerance</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Oats</ENAMEX> are not safe for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celiac disease</ENAMEX>, but future studies are needed to
        determine the frequency of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats intolerance</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
