
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> is the leading cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX> among the elderly and is
        characterized by accumulation of extracellular and vascular amyloid in the brain [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>].
        Amyloid deposits are composed of the amyloid-Œ≤ peptide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AŒ≤</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-kDa</NUMEX> peptide released
        during <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúamyloidogenic‚Äù proteolytic</ENAMEX> processing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer AŒ≤ precursor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (APP)
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> can also be cleaved by the nonamyloidogenic Œ±-secretases, a disintegrin and
        metalloproteinase <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-10</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-17</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], in a reaction that is believed to occur
        primarily on the plasma membrane [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>] and is known as ‚Äúectodomain shedding.‚Äù
        Œ±-Secretase-type ectodomain shedding divides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX>, thereby generating
        Œ±-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">secretase</NUMEX>-cleaved soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">APP ectodomain</ENAMEX> (sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> ) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. This reaction can be stimulated by activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphatase 1</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2A</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        Reports from retrospective analyses suggest that the statin class of
        cholesterol-lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HMGCoA reductase inhibitors</ENAMEX> may lower the risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX>
        by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 70%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,9,10,11</NUMEX>]. Studies in wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guinea pigs</ENAMEX> and in plaque-forming
        transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> have demonstrated that chronic statin treatment can attenuate cerebral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amyloidosis</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,13</NUMEX>], suggesting that statins may exert their risk-reducing effects, at
        least in part, by modulating APP metabolism. In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> culture, lovastatin and simvastatin
        decrease the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat hippocampal</ENAMEX> neurons [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,14</NUMEX>] while activating
        Œ±-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">secretase</NUMEX>-type ectodomain shedding [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,16</NUMEX>]. However, the molecular mechanisms by which
        statins modulate ectodomain shedding remain to be elucidated [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,18</NUMEX>].
        Statin effects on APP metabolism are, to some extent, attributable to cholesterol
        lowering, but statin actions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> may also involve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>-independent actions [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>].
        Reduction in synthesis of mevalonate leads to decreased generation of a number of
        isoprenoid lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">derivatives</ENAMEX>. Isoprenoids, such as farnesyl pyrophosphate and
        geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate, are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15- or 20-carbon</NUMEX> lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">moieties</ENAMEX>. Through the action of
        farnesyl transferases and type I geranylgeranyl transferases, isoprenoids are attached to
        the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid sequence Cys</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xaa (‚ÄúCAAX‚Äù</ENAMEX>) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">C-terminus of the Rho family</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTPases</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. These posttranslational lipid modifications are essential for attachment of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTPases</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cytosolic</ENAMEX> face of intracellular vesicles and/or to the cytosolic leaflet
        of the plasma membrane, thereby specifying subcellular targets for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTPase</ENAMEX> action(s).
        Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho GTPase</ENAMEX> family exert their actions through modulation of protein
        kinase activities. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best characterized is Rho-associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase 1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ROCK1,</ENAMEX>
        also called ROKŒ≤). ROCK1 is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">serine</ENAMEX>/threonine kinase with an apparent mass of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX> kDa that
        can be activated by either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RhoA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RhoB</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21,22,23</NUMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Structurally</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ROCK1</TIMEX> N-terminus
        contains the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase domain, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> has both a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rho</ENAMEX>-binding domain and
        a pleckstrin homology domain, either of which can modulate protein‚Äìprotein interactions. In
        the inactive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rho</ENAMEX>-binding domain and the pleckstrin homology domain form an
        autoinhibitory loop by binding and blocking the kinase domain at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> of the
        molecule. Activation of ROCK1 occurs when a Rho <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> binds to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rho</ENAMEX>-binding domain,
        causing a conformational change that opens the kinase domain for the phosphorylation of
        downstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">effectors</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. Once activated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX> phosphorylates several substrates,
        including myosin light <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> phosphatase, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIM</ENAMEX> kinases (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lin11</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Isl1</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mec3</ENAMEX>), and
        ezrin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">radixin</NUMEX>-moesin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,25,26,27</NUMEX>]. ROCK1 has recently been implicated in
        modifying the site of substrate cleavage by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> Œ≥-secretase [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>], perhaps acting via
        ROCK1-dependent phosphorylation of a component of the Œ≥-secretase enzyme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
        In the current study, we demonstrate that activation of sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding from cultured cells by atorvastatin or simvastatin involves
        isoprenoid-mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphorylation</ENAMEX>. Treatment of cells with a farnesyl transferase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibitor</ENAMEX> or expression of a dominant negative (DN) ROCK1 molecule led to enhanced sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding, supporting the notion that shedding is modulated by the
        isoprenoid pathway. Transfection with the cDNA for a constitutively active (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CA</ENAMEX>) ROCK1
        molecule led to inhibition of statin-activated sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding. These results raise the possibility that the apparent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beneficial</ENAMEX> effect of statins in the prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> could be, at least in
        part, mediated by isoprenoid modulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> metabolism.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Reagents
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal specific polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody 369</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>] was used to detect
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">full-length APP</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal fragments. Monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody 6E10</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1‚Äì16</NUMEX> of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dedham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) was used to detect human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holoAPP</ENAMEX> or sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> . Anti-ROCK1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chemicon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temecula</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). Streptavidin-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> HRP-conjugated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-Myc</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody 9E10</ENAMEX>,
          mevalonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arachidonic acid</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phenylarsine oxide</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). Atorvastatin was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Groton</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), and simvastatin was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LKT Labs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Paul</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). N2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supplement</ENAMEX> was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibco</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>). Sulfo-NHS-LC-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biotin</ENAMEX> was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>). CA and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Myc-tagged ROCK1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vectors</ENAMEX> were generated as previously described
          [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,31</NUMEX>] and were generous gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liqun Luo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fugene 6</ENAMEX> was
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Basel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>). Farnesyl transferase inhibitor <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (FTI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) was
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biomol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth Meeting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). Tumor necrosis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">factor Œ±</ENAMEX> (TNFŒ±) protease inhibitor <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27632</NUMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calbiochem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). Protein concentration assay kit was purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biorad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIVE/DEAD Viability/Cytotoxicity Assay Kits</ENAMEX>
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Amplex Red Cholesterol Assay Kits</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture Methods</ENAMEX> and Sample Preparation
          N2a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> neuroblastoma cells stably transfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> mutant form of APP
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">SweAPP N2a</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APP695</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">595‚Äì596</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KM/NL</ENAMEX>) (gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Thinakaran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Sisodia</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) were maintained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 Œºg/ml G418</ENAMEX> in the presence of penicillin and streptomycin [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]. For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> h
          prior to pharmacological treatments, the culture media were changed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">N2</NUMEX>-supplemented
          lipid-free medium. In some studies, cells were transfected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">N2-supplemented</TIMEX> FBS-free
          medium <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 h</TIMEX> before pharmacological treatments. Transfections were carried out using the
          performed in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Œ</NUMEX>ºM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mevalonic acid</ENAMEX>, unless otherwise specified.
          Cells were lysed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton-X/PBS</ENAMEX> buffer containing <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1 X</ENAMEX> complete proteinase
          inhibitor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>), sonicated twice for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> s, and centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>
          g for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein</ENAMEX> concentration in the supernatant was determined
          using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biorad Protein Assay</ENAMEX> kit, following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions. For the
          detection of holoAPP and sAPP
          Œ± , <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were separated in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5%</NUMEX> polyacrylamide gels, transferred to
          nitrocellulose, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> detected with either 369 (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> for holoAPP and
          C-terminal fragments) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6E10</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> for holoAPP or sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> ), followed by incubation of the transfers with appropriate
          secondary anti-rabbit or anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. For the detection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transfected</ENAMEX> ROCK1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were immunoprecipitated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Œºg</NUMEX> of anti-Myc <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, separated in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
          polyacrylamide gels, transferred, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> detected with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ROCK1</NUMEX> antibody
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:1,000 dilution).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cell-Surface Biotinylation</ENAMEX>
          Cells were plated in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100-mm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> √ó <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> cells/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX>. After treatment, media were harvested, and sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> levels were evaluated by immunoblotting as described above. Cells
          were washed twice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and then incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sulfo-NHS-LC-Biotin</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o C. Biotinylation</ENAMEX> reactions were terminated by one wash in Tris
          followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> washes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. Cells were lysed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton-X/PBS</ENAMEX> buffer containing
          protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitor cocktail</ENAMEX> as indicated above. Lysates were immunoprecipitated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 Œ</NUMEX>ºl
          of whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">369 antibody serum</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 Œºl</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> A beads. After washing twice with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton/PBS</ENAMEX>, and then twice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were boiled in sample buffer for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX>,
          separated in a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5%</NUMEX> polyacrylamide gel, and transferred to nitrocellulose. The
          biotinylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were detected using streptavidin HRP polymer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:10,000
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dilution</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viability/Cytotoxicity</ENAMEX> Assays
          Cells were plated in an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-well slide at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> √ó <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> cells/well. After treatments as indicated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIVE/DEAD</ENAMEX> assays were
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cholesterol Assays</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cholesterol</ENAMEX> levels in cell lysates were measured using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Amplex Red</ENAMEX> following the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>). We have previously demonstrated that
          standard doses of either simvastatin or atorvastatin reduce cholesterol levels in N2a
          cells by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì67%</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>].
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantification and Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          Quantification of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein bands</ENAMEX> was performed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UVP Bioimaging System</ENAMEX>, and
          statistical analysis was performed on paired observations using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX>'s 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">t</ENAMEX> test.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atorvastatin Activates</ENAMEX> sAPPŒ± Shedding at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subcellular Site Upstream</ENAMEX> of Endocytosis
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plasma Membrane</ENAMEX>
          We confirmed our previous observation [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] that atorvastatin produces an increase in
          sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding that is dose-dependent, reaching a maximum effect at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 ŒºM.</ENAMEX>
          The increase in sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding is accompanied by a corresponding increase in levels of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonamyloidogenic APP</ENAMEX> Œ±-C-terminal fragment (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C83</TIMEX>; data not shown).
          In order to refine our localization of the subcellular target of statin action, we
          evaluated the steady-state levels of cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">APP</ENAMEX> (csAPP) in the absence or presence
          of statins. After drug treatments, cells were subjected to the surface biotinylation
          protocol. Cells and media were harvested, and levels of sAPP
          Œ± , holoAPP, and csAPP were measured. Treatment with atorvastatin
          increased csAPP by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 1.6</NUMEX>-fold, similar to the effect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> on holoAPP
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), while sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding was increased by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 7</NUMEX>-fold (
          p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). Since csAPP levels were only slightly raised in the same
          statin-treated cells in which sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding was dramatically increased, we interpret this disparity to
          indicate that the effector of statin-stimulated shedding is probably intrinsic to the
          plasma membrane. In other studies, the plasma membrane has been proposed to be, or to
          contain, the statin target. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statins</ENAMEX> have been proposed to cause
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-localization of Œ±-secretase and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> within lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rafts</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,33</NUMEX>]; statins might also
          induce modification of the structure and activity of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in the plasma membrane
          Œ±-secretase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, perhaps in an action similar to how statins bind and ‚Äúlock‚Äù
          cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">integrins</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>].
          A pulse-chase protocol was also used to study post-transcriptional regulation of APP
          metabolsm by statins (data not shown). This protocol avoids any confound that might arise
          because of altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">APP</ENAMEX> transcription. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pulse-chase</ENAMEX> studies were performed using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-min
          pulse with [
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">35 S</ENAMEX>]methionine followed by various chase times from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0 to 120</NUMEX> min.
          Typical maturation and half-life of mature cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holoAPP</ENAMEX> were observed, as was
          subsequent release of sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,29</NUMEX>]. In the presence of either atorvastatin or simvastatin, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> course of maturation and release perfectly paralleled that observed in the absence
          of either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, except that the fractional content of cellular mature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holoAPP</TIMEX> was
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>-fold greater in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> (i.e., at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 or 75 min</TIMEX> chase, mature
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> in the presence of statin was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 310%</NUMEX> of the level of immature APP at 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> versus a control [vehicle treatment] of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150%</NUMEX> of the level of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immature APP</ENAMEX> at 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>; also, at 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min, the relative percent values for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> were
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">380% and 200%</NUMEX>, respectively). Fold increases in released sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> in the same experiments were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 3- to 4</NUMEX>-fold (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>
          arbitrary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5‚Äì8.0</NUMEX> arbitrary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">120 min</TIMEX> for atorvastatin and
          simvastatin, respectively). Secretory maturation toxicity is one possible mechanism for
          elevated levels of intracellular mature holoAPP and causes retarded conversion of mature
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holoAPP</ENAMEX> to sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> . This pattern was not observed following statin treatment,
          excluding maturation toxicity as a mechanism underlying the altered levels of mature
          cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holoAPP</ENAMEX>.
          Instead, the pattern that we observed raises the possibility that statins, presumably
          via isoprenoids (given the reversibility with mevalonate), as discussed in the next
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>, may alter sorting of cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holoAPP</ENAMEX>, diverting holoproteins away from terminal
          degradation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">endosomal</ENAMEX>/lysosomal pathway and into the constitutive secretory
          pathway that generates sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> . However, the fold effect on reduced intracellular turnover in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">endosomal/lysosomal</ENAMEX> pathway (or sorting out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">endosomal</ENAMEX>/lysosomal pathway and into
          the constitutive secretory/shedding pathway) is apparently insufficient to explain the
          fold effect on sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Œ±</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-fold for the former, vs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3- to 4</NUMEX>-fold for the latter),
          indicating a contribution from a downstream site in the processing pathway. When these
          results are taken together with independent work on regulated shedding of transforming
          growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor Œ±</ENAMEX> (TGFŒ±) [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,36</NUMEX>], a parsimonious explanation is that an important target
          for activation of ectodomain shedding is probably located at the plasma membrane or
          downstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> at the plasma membrane.
          The identification of the regulatory components of the ectodomain shedding machinery
          have been long-sought in other studies employing phorbol esters to stimulate shedding of
          sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> or TGFŒ± [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,35,36,37</NUMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Munc-13</ENAMEX> has recently been implicated as a
          phorbol <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> in regulated shedding [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>]. In our opinion, this molecule is rather
          unlikely to play a major role in shedding regulation, given the specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munc</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
          effects for phorbols and the generalization of the regulated shedding phenomenon to
          include activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphatase inhibitors</ENAMEX> and neurotransmitters. Neither of
          these would be predicted to act via the phorbol-binding C1 domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munc</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sisodia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>] demonstrated that arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> endocytosis from the
          plasma membrane by deletion of its 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPXY</ENAMEX> clathrin-coated vesicle targeting sequence [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,41</NUMEX>] can
          dramatically stimulate sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding, presumably by extending the half-life of co-localized
          Œ±-secretase and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> on the plasma membrane. In order to exclude the possible contribution
          of altered endocytosis to statin-stimulated shedding, we evaluated the effect of
          phenylarsine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PO</ENAMEX>), an inhibitor of endocytosis, on statin-stimulated shedding
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Treatment with either atorvastatin, simvastatin, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PO</ENAMEX> alone increased sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding, as expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-treatment of cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PO</ENAMEX> plus either
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">atorvastatin</ENAMEX> or simvastatin caused stimulation of sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding to levels greater than the maximal levels of shedding
          achievable with inhibition of endocytosis using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PO</ENAMEX> alone or with maximal doses of either
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statin</ENAMEX> alone (
          p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). The additivity of statin- and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PO</ENAMEX>-stimulated shedding is
          consistent with the hypothesis that statins act at or near the plasma membrane, prior to
          internalization of csAPP. Under all circumstances, stimulated sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding was completely blocked using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX> protease inhibitor <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, a
          standard Œ±-secretase/metalloproteinase inhibitor (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). We interpret this as an
          indication that the statin-induced Œ±-cleavage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> is probably mediated by one of the
          molecules usually associated with the phenomenon, i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-10</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-17</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>].
        
        
          Compounds that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Modulate Isoprenoid Levels Activate sAPPŒ± Shedding</ENAMEX>
          As discussed above, there is an established relationship between statins and
          isoprenoid-modulated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphorylation</ENAMEX>. We therefore tested the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FTI-1</ENAMEX> on
          statin-stimulated sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FTI-1</ENAMEX> increased the shedding of sAPP
          Œ± , but the combination of a statin plus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FTI-1</ENAMEX> increased sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding to levels greater than those achievable by using either
          compound alone (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>; 
          p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). In the same experiment, levels of holoAPP were modestly
          increased but, again, to an extent insufficient to account for the increase in shed sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
          To test whether statin-activated shedding might be attributable to a metabolite
          downstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMGCoA</ENAMEX> reductase, cells were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ŒºM</NUMEX> simvastatin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5 ŒºM FTI-1</ENAMEX>, and
          a series of concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mevalonic acid</ENAMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTI-1</ENAMEX> acts downstream of HMGCoA
          reductase, the stimulatory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FTI-1</ENAMEX> on sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding would not be predicted to be modified by mevalonate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supplementation</ENAMEX>. Low doses (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO"><1 ŒºM</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mevalonic acid</ENAMEX> did not affect statin-induced
          sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding, but complete inhibition of statin-activated sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding was achieved with higher doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mevalonic acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 ŒºM</ENAMEX>).
          As predicted, the shedding observed following treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FTI-1</ENAMEX> was not inhibited by
          any of the concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mevalonic acid</ENAMEX> tested (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). These data are consistent
          with a role for isoprenoids in statin control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> metabolism in cultured cells.
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK-Related Molecules Modulates sAPPŒ± Shedding</ENAMEX> in a Bidirectional
          Manner
          Since many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isoprenoid-mediated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rho</ENAMEX> effects converge on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">ROCKs</ENAMEX>, we next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">transfected</ENAMEX> N2a
          cells with cDNAs encoding either green fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (GFP) (control), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CA ROCK1</ENAMEX>, or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). Simvastatin caused a typical activation of sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding from GFP-transfected cells. When CA ROCK1 was introduced,
          however, shedding of sAPP
          Œ± from both untreated and simvastatin-treated cells was diminished
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> control). Conversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX> alone activated
          shedding of sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> . Cellular levels of holoAPP were not affected by transfection
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> control). In studies aimed at independent
          confirmation of the involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ROCK activation</ENAMEX> in sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding, we treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SweAPP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">N2a</ENAMEX> cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arachidonic acid</ENAMEX>, an
          activator of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROCK</ENAMEX>. As shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arachidonic acid</ENAMEX> reduced the shedding of sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> without altering levels of holoAPP. Based on this series of results,
          we concluded that both basal and activated sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding from cultured cells are controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROCK</ENAMEX> activity.
          In some experiments, cells were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-27632 (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 ŒºM</NUMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> that
          can inhibit ROCKs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y-27632</ENAMEX> showed no effect on basal sAPP
          Œ± release and blocked statin-activated sAPP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding (data not shown). This result was unexpected in light of
          the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX>. Given the internally consistent actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX> and CA
          ROCK1, as well as the results employing either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FTI-1</ENAMEX> or arachidonate, we concluded that
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-27632 result might be due to inhibition by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27632</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinases other than
          ROCK1 [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. The possibility was also considered that cytotoxicity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27632</NUMEX> for the
          central vacuolar pathway might explain the disparity between the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX> and
          those of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27632</NUMEX>, but neither impairment of intracellular APP maturation nor increased
          apoptosis as measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIVE/DEAD</ENAMEX> assay were apparent following <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-27632 treatment (data
          not shown). Ultimately, we were unable to document any explanation for the disparate
          results of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-27632 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The isoprenoid pathway involves lipid modification of various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rho</ENAMEX> family
        of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTPases</ENAMEX> by the addition of either farnesyl or geranylgeranyl moieties [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,42</NUMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isoprenylation</ENAMEX> serves to target the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTPases</ENAMEX> to the proper organelle membrane, where their
        actions often relate to cytoskeletal dynamics and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vesicle</ENAMEX> trafficking [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,42</NUMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROCKs</ENAMEX> are
        important downstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>), catalyzing the phosphorylation of effector
        phosphoprotein substrates [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. The foregoing data indicate that statin-induced activation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> shedding in cultured cells involves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho/ROCK</ENAMEX> pathway. More specifically, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ROCK1 activation</ENAMEX> blocks the effects of statins on APP ectodomain
        shedding, while ROCK1 blockade alone can mimic the effect of statins on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> shedding. By
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">extension</ENAMEX>, these data predict that application of statins to neurons might directly or
        indirectly inhibit ROCK1 activity. Evaluation of this possibility will be the subject of
        future investigation.
        The first evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> might be a substrate for ectodomain shedding was provided by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weidemann et al.</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>] who identified sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> in the cerebrospinal fluid and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. This aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> metabolism
        bears resemblance to the proteolytic signal transduction pathways involved in processing
        pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGFŒ±</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,36</NUMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notch</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>]. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notch</ENAMEX>, the process is set in motion by the
        binding of a ligand to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notch</ENAMEX> ectodomain, triggering its release (shedding). For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX>,
        intracellular signal transduction appears to be more important [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,29,45</NUMEX>]. In early studies,
        the existence of the shed ectodomain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> was used to deduce the existence of the
        proteolytic activity designated Œ±-secretase, which has the unusual specificity of cleaving
        its substrates at a proscribed distance from the extracellular leaflet of the plasma
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">membrane</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,39</NUMEX>]. Ultimately, the integral cell-surface metalloproteinases <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-10</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-17/TACE</ENAMEX> were found to underlie Œ±-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">secretase</NUMEX>-type ectodomain shedding [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,46</NUMEX>].
        Why is APP a substrate for ectodomain shedding? To answer this question requires
        contemplation of the physiological function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> is a type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">1 integral protein</ENAMEX> that
        is subjected to a host of post-translational processing events, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>- and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O-glycosylation</ENAMEX>, tyrosyl sulfation, phosphorylation, and proteolysis [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39,43,47,48</NUMEX>]. Most
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì80%</NUMEX>) newly synthesized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> is subjected to terminal intracellular degradation that
        generates no discrete fragments [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. A smaller fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">APP</ENAMEX> molecules (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 20%</NUMEX>
        in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PC12</NUMEX> cells under basal conditions [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]) undergoes ectodomain shedding catalyzed by either
        the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Œ±-secretase</NUMEX> (nonamyloidogenic) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Œ≤-secretase</NUMEX> (potentially amyloiodgenic) pathway. When
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> is activated, the stoichiometry of shed sAPP
        Œ± rises from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mol</ENAMEX> shed per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mol synthesized to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mol</ENAMEX> shed per mole
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synthesized</ENAMEX>. Most of this shedding is catalyzed by the Œ±-secretase pathway, but a trace
        amount (<<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>]) is catalyzed by <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Œ≤-secretase/Œ≤-</ENAMEX>site APP cleaving enzyme [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>]. sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> and sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ≤</ENAMEX> differ by the inclusion in sAPP
        Œ± of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AŒ≤</ENAMEX>. Unlike sAPP
        Œ± , which is generated at the plasma membrane, most sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ≤</ENAMEX> is probably generated by cleavage within the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trans -Golgi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and endocytic pathway vesicles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HoloAPP</ENAMEX> levels are
        likely limiting at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more sorting steps in the late secretory pathway, since activated
        sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding is apparently accompanied by diminished generation of sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ≤</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>].
        What is the function of shed sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> ? Again, from other molecules, we know that shedding can serve
        important cellular functions by releasing diffusible ligands from their membrane-bound
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precursors</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGFŒ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFŒ±</ENAMEX>) or by terminating intercellular signaling (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Notch</ENAMEX>). A
        popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> holds that sAPP
        Œ± may function as a neurotrophic and/or neuroprotective factor, and may
        promote neurite outgrowth [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>]. More recent evidence suggests that released <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">APP</ENAMEX> derivatives
        modulate efficacy of neurotransmission at the synapse [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>]. Targeted deletion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> has
        not revealed a striking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phenotype</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>], presumably because of functional redundancy
        supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> with double and triple null mutations in various
        combinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX>, APP-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein 1</ENAMEX>, and APP-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein 2</ENAMEX> are now being created, in
        search of evidence for a definitive function for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cao</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sudhof</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX>] have recently discovered that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal fragment generated
        by Œ±- or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Œ≤-secretase</NUMEX> is itself cleaved to release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> and an APP intracellular domain (AICD)
        that diffuses into the nucleus, possibly acting there as a transcription factor. The
        pathway leading to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICD</ENAMEX> must be initiated by ectodomain shedding: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holoAPP</ENAMEX> cannot directly
        give rise to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICD</ENAMEX>. Therefore, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> important function for Œ±- and/or Œ≤-secretase processing
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> may be the eventual generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICD</ENAMEX>. Our results suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho/ROCK</ENAMEX> signaling
        provides modulation of basal and stimulated Œ±-secretase activity. It will now be important
        to dissect pathways upstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho/ROCK</ENAMEX> signaling in order to identify the intracellular
        and intercellular events that participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho/ROCK</ENAMEX> regulation of Œ±-secretase under
        The potential role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Œ±-secretase-mediated</ENAMEX> shedding was discovered by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodovitz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX>] who used Œ≤-cyclodextrin to lower cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kojro et</ENAMEX> al.
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>] confirmed this observation, using not only Œ≤-cyclodextrin but also lovastatin to lower
        cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> proposed that elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-10</ENAMEX> activity and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels contributed to these effects. These basic observations dovetailed with
        emerging epidemiological evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of statins might lead to a diminished
        incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,9,10,11</NUMEX>]. Despite this, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statins</ENAMEX> and cholesterol levels with activated Œ±-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">secretase</NUMEX>-mediated shedding of the APP
        ectodomain was unexpected and not readily explicable by existing knowledge regarding
        regulation of Œ±-secretase activity. The best characterized regulation of Œ±-secretase
        processing typically involves <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphorylation</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,29</NUMEX>] or ERKs [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>] or protein
        dephosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphatase 1</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2A</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. We recently excluded the possibility
        that either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PKC</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ERK</ENAMEX> plays a role in statin-activated shedding [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>], raising the
        possibility that other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> phosphorylation signaling pathways might link statins and/or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Œ±-secretase activation</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maillet et al.</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX>] implicated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> pathway in modulation of Œ±-secretase activity
        while dissecting the activated shedding process that accompanies serotonergic signal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduction</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> discovered that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rap1</ENAMEX> acts through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rac</ENAMEX> to modulate
        Œ±-secretase processing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX>. Soon thereafter, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ROCK1</TIMEX> was discovered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhou</ENAMEX> et al. [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>] to
        modulate a downstream processing step in APP metabolism that involves
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">presenilin/Œ≥-secretase-</ENAMEX>mediated proteolysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal fragments <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C99 and C83</TIMEX>. These
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> discovered that activation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ROCK1</TIMEX> may account for how nonsteroidal
        anti-inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> specify the scissile bond within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> transmembrane domain that
        is cleaved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenilin</ENAMEX>/Œ≥-secretase to generate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus of AŒ≤</ENAMEX>. Based on these
        reports, we asked whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho/ROCK</ENAMEX> pathway might play a role in controlling shedding of
        sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> following statin application.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CA ROCK1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX> molecules yielded direct and complementary evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX> was
        indeed a candidate for modulation of statin-activated Œ±-secretase action. Further, we were
        able to demonstrate that Œ±-secretase activity could be modulated by molecules further
        upstream in the isoprenoid pathway (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FTI-1</ENAMEX>, an inhibitor of farnesyl
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transferase</ENAMEX> also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">744,832</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX>], mimicked and potentiated statin-activated
        shedding, presumably by blocking transfer of isoprenoid moieties to a Rho <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> by
        farnesyl transferase, and thereby decreasing Rho activity. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FTI-1</ENAMEX> treatment can
        also increase the level of geranylgeranylated isoforms of certain Rho <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, e.g., the
        inhibitory geranylgeranylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RhoB protein</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>]. In further support of a role for
        isoprenoids, we were able to demonstrate that supplementation of cells with mevalonate
        abolished statin-activated shedding (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Statins block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMGCoA</ENAMEX> reductase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of mevalonate from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-hydroxy-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl-glutarate</ENAMEX> (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). Therefore, the
        addition of mevalonate would be predicted to antagonize statin action via the isoprenoid
        pathway, by relieving statin-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mevalonate deficiency</ENAMEX>. As predicted by this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, we
        observed that statin-activated shedding was abolished by adding mevalonate. Taken together,
        these results suggest the existence of a reciprocal relationship between
        isoprenoid-mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho/ROCK</ENAMEX> signaling and sAPP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œ±</ENAMEX> shedding, i.e., activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ROCK1</ENAMEX> blocks <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">basal</ENAMEX> and stimulated
        shedding while ROCK1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhibition</ENAMEX> apparently relieves a tonic negative influence exerted on
        shedding by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ROCK1</TIMEX> activity.
        As in PKC- and ERK-activated shedding, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ROCK1</NUMEX> substrate effector molecule or
        molecules that regulate proteolysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ADAMs</ENAMEX> remain to be identified. The cytoplasmic
        domains of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-17</ENAMEX> have been evaluated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for important targets of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphorylation</ENAMEX> during the regulated shedding process, but neither ‚Äúsubstrate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activation‚Äù</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúenzyme activation‚Äù</ENAMEX> appears to explain the phenomenon, i.e.,
        phosphorylation of neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-17</ENAMEX> dramatically increases the efficiency of
        Œ±-secretion [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61,62</NUMEX>], indicating that activation is more indirect.
        Our data using statins and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PO</ENAMEX> localize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> of statin-activated shedding to the
        plasma membrane, upstream of endocytosis, as appears to be the case for PKC-activated
        shedding [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,63,64,65</NUMEX>]. Similar conclusions were drawn by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosenberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>] who
        used streptolysin-porated cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-ethylmaleimide</ENAMEX> to demonstrate that reconstitution of
        activated shedding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGFŒ±</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> does not require <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">membrane</ENAMEX> trafficking and
        apparently occurs on the plasma membrane. These results suggest that a tightly
        membrane-associated regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunit</ENAMEX> of the Œ±-secretase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is likely to be the key
        phosphoprotein that mediates Œ±-secretase activity as a function of its state of
        phosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> and perhaps also ERK and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ROCK1</TIMEX>. The molecular identity of this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphoprotein</ENAMEX> remains unknown.
        Œ±-Secretase activation is a potential therapeutic strategy for modifying cerebral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amyloidosis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX>]. This proposal is supported by recent evidence that
        either genetic modification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM-10/Œ±</ENAMEX>-secretase activity [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX>] or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of
        bryostatin, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activator</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX>], can modulate levels of brain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> in plaque-forming
        transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Œ±-Secretase activation may explain how statins lower the risk for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">69</TIMEX>], since atorvastatin diminishes AŒ≤ burden in plaque-forming
        transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. If Œ±-secretase stimulation is to be truly viable as a human clinical
        intervention, it will be essential to assess the possibility that enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APP</ENAMEX> ectodomain
        shedding might incur mechanism-based toxicity (analogous to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> currently
        surrounding Œ≥-secretase <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>). Along this line, extension of this work to other shed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> will be important to determine the impact of enhanced shedding via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADAM</ENAMEX>
        proteinases on other substrates of those proteinases, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notch</ENAMEX>, pro-TGFŒ±, pro-TNFŒ±,
        and CD44 [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>].
        Preliminary results from a pilot proof-of-concept using atorvastatin in a human clinical
        treatment trial are consistent with the proposed beneficial effects of this class of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">compounds</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX>]. Since atorvastatin has low blood‚Äìbrain barrier permeability [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX>], this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beneficial</ENAMEX> effect, if attributable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> lowering, must be due to altered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> metabolism in
        the periphery. Reduction in levels of free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> in the circulation has been demonstrated to
        lead to diminution in brain plaque burden following active or passive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immunization</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX>]. It
        is conceivable that, if statins lower circulating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AŒ≤</ENAMEX>, this effect could secondarily cause
        diffusion of central nervous system interstitial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AŒ≤</ENAMEX> down its concentration gradient and
        into the cerebrospinal fluid and circulation, from which it is cleared. To date, however,
        this mechanism is not supported by data from human clinical trials, where statin
        administration has shown no consistent effect on levels of circulating or cerebrospinal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluid AŒ≤</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73</TIMEX>].
        The results reported here point to several areas for additional investigation. As
        described above, the key substrate or substrates linking cytoplasmic protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> to intralumenal or cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protelysis</ENAMEX> remain to be identified.
        Nonetheless, Œ±-secretase activation has been validated as a viable therapeutic strategy for
        modulating cerebral amyloidosis [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX>]. Identification of the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho/ROCK</ENAMEX> pathway in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regulating Œ±</ENAMEX>-secretase provides a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> for its therapeutic activation, even though
        the potential relevance of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">atorvastatin-mediated</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">inhibition</ENAMEX> in neurons may not
        explain the apparent clinical benefits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. Still, if the reported
        disease-modifying effect of atorvastatin is confirmed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aging</ENAMEX>'s
        large, multi-center trial of simvastatin, one or more compounds of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> may be among
        slowing the progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer disease</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
        
          Accession Numbers
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ncbi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nlm</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nih</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/Genbank/</ENAMEX>) accession numbers for the proteins
          discussed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are ROCK1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">005397</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APP695</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">595‚Äì596</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KM/NL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">958817</ENAMEX>).
        
      
    
  
