
  
    
      
        
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20%</NUMEX> of all deaths in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> younger
        than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> are due to acute lower respiratory tract infections (LRTIs), with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX>
        of these deaths due to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX>. But despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRTIs</ENAMEX> being among the most frequent diseases
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first years</TIMEX> of life, the viral causes of these illnesses are not always clear.
        Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viruses</ENAMEX> are known to be involved, e.g., respiratory syncytial virus (RSV),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">influenza viruses</ENAMEX>, parainfluenza viruses, and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metapneumovirus</ENAMEX>, but none of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathogens</ENAMEX> is detected in a substantial number of cases.
        In a new article published in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lia van der Hoek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> investigate the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of acute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRTIs</ENAMEX> with human coronavirus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX>, a virus they recently
        described. They suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX>, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coronaviridae</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, is one of
        the most frequently detected viruses in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than three years old</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRTIs</ENAMEX> and
        that this virus is strongly associated with croup.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> analyzed samples from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRI</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DE</ENAMEX> study, a prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>-based study of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRTIs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> younger than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. They assessed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">949</ENAMEX> samples
        of nasopharyngeal secretions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRTIs</ENAMEX>.
        In all, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.2%</NUMEX>) were positive for HCoV<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-NL63 RNA</ENAMEX>. Viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was more prevalent
        in samples from outpatients (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.9%</NUMEX>) than hospitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.2%</NUMEX>), and co-infection with
        either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RSV</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">parainfluenza</ENAMEX> virus 3 was observed frequently. With an overall occurrence of
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.2%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> most frequently detected pathogen in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient group</ENAMEX> (RSV
        was the highest, found in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31.4%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX> in cases
        of respiratory disease where no other viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathogen</ENAMEX> could be detected in order to identify
        clinical symptoms associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX> infection. Samples in which only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HCoV-NL63 RNA</ENAMEX>
        could be detected had a significantly higher viral load than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> containing additional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">respiratory</ENAMEX> viruses. A strong association with croup was apparent: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43%</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with high HCoV-NL63 load and absence of co-infection had croup,
        compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX>-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Indeed, a significantly higher fraction
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17.4%</NUMEX>) of samples from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">croup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> than non-croup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.2%</NUMEX>) contained HCoV-NL63
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>.
        This study strengthens the evidence for the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX> in croup. Previous studies
        have shown croup to occur mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, with peak occurrence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second year</TIMEX> of life
        and predominantly in the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early winter season</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX> infection seems
        to follow these trends, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>.
        However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> warned that the high percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX>-positive samples could
        be due to a strong viral activity in the study year, and long-term studies are needed to
        determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX> infections occur in cycles peaking every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three years</TIMEX>, as
        observed for other respiratory viruses. But they noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX> has spread worldwide,
        with the virus found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. Thus, health
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> should add <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCoV</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-NL63</ENAMEX> to the list of pathogens that can cause numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRTIs</ENAMEX> in
        young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
