
  
    
      
        
        Many different things combine to cause epidemics of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. Among these factors are the
        characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">infecting organism</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, and, as is
        increasingly realized, climatic conditions.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>, the best known climatic disturbance, is caused by a warming of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean</ENAMEX>, which then affects the climate globally. Previous work has suggested that this
        recurring phenomenon can have a profound effect on the incidence of many <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>,
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dengue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diarrheal diseases</ENAMEX>.
        In a paper in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> from a climate research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX>
        and an infectious diseases <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> looked at the relation between climate and
        meningitis outbreaks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mali</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Africa</ENAMEX>, a region that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> and
        May sees devastating epidemics of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">meningococcal meningitis</ENAMEX> affecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
        The most important recurring climatic event in this region is a dry wind, known as the
        Harmattan, that blows throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>, causing a drop in humidity and the production
        of vast quantities of dust.
        What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> found was that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1994–2002, the week</TIMEX> of the onset of the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> meningitis epidemic came at around the same time as the peak of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> measure of the
        wind—the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixth week of the year</TIMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascual</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> say in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspective</ENAMEX> article on
        this study, “Sultan and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' study is exceptional in that it illustrates a clear
        relationship between an external environmental variable and the initiation of disease
        outbreaks.”
        How do climatic changes influence <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>? In some cases, such as the role of flooding
        in spreading a waterborne <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, the causes are perhaps obvious, but why should a dry
        wind affect disease incidence? Previous works have suggested that the climate can work in a
        number of ways, by influencing the life cycle of both <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> vectors and the
        disease-causing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>, and, as here perhaps, by affecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sultan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> speculate that the drying effects of the wind on the mucous membranes
        could increase the chances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> getting established in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. Whatever
        the causes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very useful feature of climate is that, once the patterns are understood,
        they can often be predicted.
        A way of predicting these meningitis epidemics could be enormously useful. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sultan</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> looked at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years</TIMEX>, but if these findings are confirmed over a longer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> period, they could make preparing for an epidemic much more efficient.
      
    
  
