
  
    
      
        PRESENTATION of CASE
        A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">43-y</NUMEX>-old white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2004</TIMEX> with pain in the left eye
        and left upper lid ptosis. She did not perceive any difference in perspiration between the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two halves</NUMEX> of her face. She was a nonsmoker and denied any history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> or neck trauma,
        or ocular, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac</ENAMEX>, vascular, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">neurologic disease</ENAMEX>. Neuro-ophthalmological examination was
        normal except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mm of left upper eyelid ptosis (drooping of the eyelid), miosis
        (constriction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupil</ENAMEX>), and mild <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">enophthalmos</ENAMEX> (recession of the eyeball into the
        orbit) consistent with classic left-sided <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Horner syndrome</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). There was no
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carotidynia</ENAMEX> (a neck pain syndrome associated with tenderness to palpation over the carotid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bifurcation</ENAMEX>) or carotid bruit. A chest radiograph obtained to rule out an underlying left
        apical superior <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sulcus tumor</ENAMEX> was normal. Magnetic resonance imaging/magnetic resonance
        angiography of the brain with cross-sectional imaging of the neck was obtained, which
        revealed extracranial left internal carotid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery</ENAMEX> dissection (Figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>). The
        patient was treated with unfractionated heparin and coumadin and made an uneventful
        recovery. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months later</TIMEX> and did not have any
        complications at follow-up.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DISCUSSION</ENAMEX>
        Horner syndrome—characterized by the constellation of miosis, ptosis, anhidrosis (lack
        of sweating), enophthalmos, and anisocoria (unequal pupil size)—is present in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 58%</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> carotid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery</ENAMEX> dissections [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> experience neck, facial, and head
        pain ipsilateral to the lesion because of ischemia or stretching of the trigeminal pain
        fibers surrounding the carotid arteries [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Ophthalmic manifestations have been reported
        to occur in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 62%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with internal carotid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery</ENAMEX> dissection [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Common
        findings in descending order of frequency are painful partial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Horner syndrome</ENAMEX> (due to
        disruption of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-order neuron oculosympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX>) as seen in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>,
        transient monocular vision loss, and permanent visual loss [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Bray et</ENAMEX> al. studied the prognosis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> cases of isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Horner syndrome</ENAMEX> due to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> carotid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery</ENAMEX> dissection [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. They found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91%</NUMEX> of cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Horner syndrome</ENAMEX> due
        to internal carotid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery dissection</ENAMEX> were painful. The risk of an early ischemic stroke
        within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 2 wk</TIMEX> was high (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 17%</NUMEX>) without initial antithrombotic treatment
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal</ENAMEX> carotid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery dissection</ENAMEX> is a potentially life-threatening condition and
        carries a substantial risk of disabling stroke [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. Carotid dissection is under-recognized
        as a cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Horner syndrome</ENAMEX> and can be missed [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. It is important to diagnose dissection
        because anticoagulation can prevent carotid thrombosis and embolism [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. The investigation
        of choice is magnetic resonance imaging and angiography scan of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and neck [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].The
        treatment advocated for dissection is anticoagulation for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3–6</NUMEX> mo [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
      
    
  
