
  
    
      
        
        If you are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX>, then losing weight is good for your health, surely?
        Unfortunately, the evidence on which an answer to this seemingly simple question might be
        based is at best equivocal, and at worst very controversial. Previous work has shown that
        weight loss in obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> improves risk factors associated with cardiovascular diseases
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, but studies are conflicting on the long-term effects of weight loss on
        mortality. A study in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaakko Kaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dataset</ENAMEX> adds
        more evidence to this debate, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> are divided on what can be concluded from it.
        The major difficulty in getting clear results on this question is that it is virtually
        impossible to do a controlled trial to answer it. Hence, the evidence accumulated has come
        mostly from epidemiological studies, but it is notoriously difficult to remove all
        confounding factors from these studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' study is another
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epidemiological</ENAMEX> study, but we should not simply dismiss the data as unreliable just because
        of the problems inherent to such a study design. Instead, we should consider their study in
        the light of all the other evidence available.
        Starting from a group of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,993</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> who have been studied since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> gathered data from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,957</NUMEX> overweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> who remained after they had
        excluded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pre-existing disease</ENAMEX>, and those with missing data. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> had
        been asked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> if they intended to lose weight, and then had information on weight
        collected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. Information on mortality was then collected over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 18 years</TIMEX>; the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> then analyzed mortality in relation to intention to lose weight and actual weight
        change.
        In total, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">268</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died. When the results were analyzed, the surprising finding was
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who intended to lose weight, and who did so, had a somewhat higher mortality
        than those who intended to lose weight but whose weight remained stable, or went up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
        who intended to lose weight, and who did so, also had a slightly higher mortality than
        those who did not intend to lose weight and whose weight was stable.
        The problems with such a study are outlined in an accompanying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspective</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOI</ENAMEX>:
        10.1371/journal.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pmed.002018</NUMEX>) by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meir Stampfer</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard School of Public Health</ENAMEX>, and
        there is no doubt that these results seem counterintuitive. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may take away the
        idea from this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that overweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should not be advised to lose weight, but
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stampfer</ENAMEX> cautions against that interpretation. Perhaps the safest interpretation of these
        results is that by the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX>, the health benefits of losing weight are
        not clear-cut. If there is one message therefore that should be taken from the paper it is
        this: in order to prevent the associated health effects of obesity, preventing obesity,
        especially in childhood, should be an overriding public health priority.
        The study leaves us with the question of how intentional weight loss could lead to
        excess mortality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> suggest that this could be due to the unavoidable loss of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">lean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body mass</ENAMEX>, which according to several other studies may increase mortality, and which
        may outweigh the beneficial effects of losing fat mass in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        therefore conclude that “the long-term effects of weight loss are complex, and they may be
        composed of oppositely operating effects with net results reflecting the balance between
        these effects.”
      
    
  
