
  
    
      
        Introduction
        The immunotherapy of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> holds promise in harnessing the host immune response to
        specifically target tumor cells without harming normal tissues. Strategies involve adoptive
        cellular therapy or active immune induction (commonly referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúcancer vaccination‚Äù</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> may consist of whole tumor cells or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor lysates</ENAMEX>, but identification of
        tumor-associated antigens (TAAs) over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> has made possible the use of specific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> or peptides as cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>. The anti-tumor potential of TAA-specific CD8+ T
        cells has been illustrated by the demonstrated capacity of adoptive T cell therapy to
        reduce tumor size [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. While endogenous anti-tumor <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ T cell responses may already exist
        in some <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>], vaccination with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TAA-</ENAMEX>derived peptides, and in particular
        heteroclitic peptide analogs, increases the frequency of TAA-specific T cell responses to
        detectable levels in many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,4,5,6,7,8,9</NUMEX>]. Heteroclitic peptide analogs are
        created by substitutions at anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> resulting in increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of peptide
        with the major histocompatibility <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (MHC) [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. Consequently, heteroclitic peptide
        analogs are predicted to be more immunogenic than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native counterparts</ENAMEX> because of more
        stable binding at the surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen-presenting cells</ENAMEX> (APCs). Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> capable
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor lysis</ENAMEX> have been isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> vaccinated with heteroclitic peptide
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,11,12,13</NUMEX>]. However, the presence of TAA-specific T cells elicited by vaccination often
        does not correlate with clinical responses [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,14,15,16,17</NUMEX>].
        Various reasons for the paradoxical coexistence of cancer cells and TAA-specific T cells
        within <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have been proposed [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,19</NUMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility is that elicited TAA-specific T
        cells are not optimally functional in vivo [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,18</NUMEX>]. Another possibility is that T cells
        inefficient in tumor recognition or lysis are induced by vaccination [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. It is becoming
        recognized that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-specific T cells may have substantially different requirements for
        cognate peptide (the peptide that is recognizable to a specific T cell clone) for efficient
        target <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lysis</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,21,22,23</NUMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúRecognition efficiency‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>) (also known as ‚Äúfunctional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">avidity‚Äù</ENAMEX>) is a measure of the sensitivity of a T cell to different peptide concentrations
        for stimulation [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,25,26</NUMEX>]. We hypothesized that high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen densities</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">APCs</ENAMEX> resulting
        from vaccination with heteroclitic peptide may paradoxically drive T cells of predominantly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">low RE</ENAMEX>, which are not efficiently activated by the endogenous expression levels of native
        peptides on tumor cells. Consequently, such T cells would be ineffective in tumor cell
        destruction. Support for this notion is emerging: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells with low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> are predominantly
        expanded in vitro with high peptide concentration [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. Moreover, in vitro stimulation of T
        cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy donors</ENAMEX> with heteroclitic peptides results in expansion of cells with a
        wide range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. A similar phenomenon may occur in vivo, leading to TAA-specific T
        cells of low RE depending on the nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen stimulation</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>].
        While isolated T cell clones with low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> have indeed been generated from melanoma
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> following heteroclitic peptide vaccination, the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited T
        cell responses these cells represent in vivo is not clear. If predominantly high-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tumor-cytolytic T</ENAMEX> cells are generated, then a small fraction of low-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE T</ENAMEX> cells generated
        would be of little consequence. However, if predominantly low-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE T</ENAMEX> cells are generated,
        then this low proportion of high-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE T</ENAMEX> cells may be an important factor in the observed lack
        of clinical effectiveness of current <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> vaccination strategies. To address this
        important issue, we undertook a systematic examination of the complexity of T cell
        responses induced by heteroclitic peptide vaccination, and compared these responses to
        endogenous anti-tumor T cell responses which develop in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Typically, responses
        to vaccination are examined following in vitro expansion from patient samples, which may
        alter the composition of cells and consequently not reveal the proportion of cells in vivo
        having sufficiently high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> to lyse tumor targets. Although staining with peptide‚ÄìMHC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tetramers</ENAMEX> provides a direct estimate for the number of TAA-specific T cells present in
        vivo, and intensity of tetramer staining has been employed as a parameter for isolation of
        high-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>, tumor-lytic T cells [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>], staining intensity does not correlate well with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> or
        tumor-lytic potential [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28,29</NUMEX>], and cannot be considered a reliable indicator for the
        functional status of TAA-specific T cells.
        To analyze and compare T cell responses in melanoma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> on a single-cell level, we
        generated and examined a large number of cytotoxic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> lymphocyte (CTL) clones derived from
        post-vaccination or endogenous anti-tumor T cell responses. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clone</ENAMEX> was analyzed for T
        cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>) variable chain beta (VB) expression, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>, and ability to lyse melanoma
        targets. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, these clones were generated directly ex vivo through tetramer-guided
        sorting, which minimizes the selection bias that could be introduced by prior in vitro
        expansion. Therefore, data from these clones could be taken to estimate the complexity of
        the responses in vivo.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> and Samples
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had resected stage III or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> melanoma, as determined by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> modified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Joint Commission on Cancer</ENAMEX> staging system. They were required to have a magnetic
          resonance imaging or computed tomographic scan of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and computed tomographic scans
          of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis showing no indication of disease within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 wk</NUMEX> of therapy
          to verify that they were clinically free of melanoma. Eligibility criteria included age
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 y</TIMEX> or older, creatinine of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 180</NUMEX> Œºmol/l, bilirubin of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 110</NUMEX> Œ<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ºmol/l,</ENAMEX>
          platelet count of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> √ó <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9 /l</ENAMEX> or more, hemoglobin of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g/l</ENAMEX> or more, and total white blood cell
          count of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX> √ó <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9 /l</ENAMEX> or greater. Tests for human immunodeficiency virus, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> C
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> B surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> were required to be negative, and all
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HLA-A2 antigen</ENAMEX> positive by a microcytotoxicity assay. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were
          required to comprehend and sign an informed consent form approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Cancer</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles County/University</ENAMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern California Institutional Review Board</ENAMEX>. Analysis of the patient samples was
          approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Review Board</ENAMEX>. Peripheral blood
          mononuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> (PBMC) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> after vaccination with the
          heteroclitic peptides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MART</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26‚Äì35</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">27L</NUMEX>) (ELAGIGILTV) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp100 209‚Äì217</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">210M</NUMEX>) (IMDQVPSFV)
          at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Southern California Norris Cancer Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>). Clinical-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX> used were provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer Therapy</ENAMEX>
          Evaluation Program of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX> under an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investigational New Drug</ENAMEX> application BB <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6123</TIMEX> held
          by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunizations</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mg of each peptide emulsified with incomplete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjuvant</ENAMEX>) were administered every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> wk for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> wk, then <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">every 4 wk</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> wk, and then once
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 wk later</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PBMC samples</ENAMEX> were collected <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 wk</TIMEX> after the final immunization and stored at
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">‚àí130 ¬∞C</NUMEX>. Samples were thawed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before an experiment for overnight culture in CTL
          medium. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, viable cells were isolated by ficoll density
          centrifugation, washed, and resuspended to the appropriate concentration in a solution of
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iscove</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Modified Dulbecco's Medium</ENAMEX> (IMDM) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum (FBS).
        
        
          Flow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytometry Analysis</ENAMEX>
          For isolation and detection of peptide-specific T cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> PBMC <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stained</ENAMEX> and analyzed by fluorescence-activated cell sorting (FACS) as previously
          described [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Briefly, cells were stained with anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD8‚àí</ENAMEX> fluorescein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isothiocyanate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caltag Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlingame</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and
          CD19-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CyChrome</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD Biosciences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abs</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-A*0201/peptide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tetramer‚Äìphycoerythrin</ENAMEX> (PE). The final staining dilution of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX>
          was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/200 and 1/80</NUMEX>, respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tetramer‚ÄìPE</ENAMEX> was titrated for optimal staining, usually
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1 and 10 Œ</TIMEX>ºg/ml. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VB</ENAMEX> typing, cells were divided in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> aliquots and
          stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD8 PerCP-Cy5.5</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD Biosciences</ENAMEX>), tetramer‚ÄìPE, and a panel of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
          different anti-VB monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abs</ENAMEX> labeled with fluorescein isothiocyanate, allophycocyanin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX>), or both. Cells were incubated at room temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, washed, then
          analyzed using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-laser, four-color <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACSCalibur</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Lakes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) or sorted using a FACSVantage flow cytometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>).
          Lymphocytes were identified by forward and side scatter signals, then selected for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+
          and tetramer positive. Up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one million</NUMEX> events were acquired and analyzed using FlowJo
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TreeStar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Carlos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          CD107 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobilization Assays</ENAMEX>
          
            Target cells
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA</ENAMEX>-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0201</TIMEX>-positive melanoma lines <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Malme-3M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A375</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">T2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> line were
            purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manassas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and maintained according to
            instructions provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA</ENAMEX>-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0201</TIMEX>-positive melanoma line <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">mel526</NUMEX> was
            obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surgery Branch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Malme-3M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mel526</ENAMEX> express both
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MART</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp100</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A375</ENAMEX> does not express <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MART</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp100</ENAMEX> and served as a negative control.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Expression</ENAMEX> (or lack thereof) of these antigens by each cell line was further confirmed
            by immunohistochemical staining. Cells were trypsinized using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trypsin/EDTA</ENAMEX> solution
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIBCO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) before use. T2 cells were HLA-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A2.1</NUMEX>+ and
            were pulsed prior to assays with peptides indicated in the text.
          
          
            Effector cells
            Effector cells, which include clones, cell line, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PBMC samples</ENAMEX>, were frozen and
            analyzed in batches. The cells were thawed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before an experiment for overnight
            culture in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> medium. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, viable cells were isolated by ficoll
            density centrifugation, washed, and resuspended to the appropriate concentration
            (usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7 /ml</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> medium.
          
          
            Experimental procedure
            All assays were done at least twice, with duplicates for each condition. The
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">effector</ENAMEX> to target (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>) ratio used was generally <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:2</TIMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> √ó <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> for clones or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> for the cell line and patient PBMC samples. To each well, the
            following was added in order: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Œºl</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM monensin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>) in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Œºl</NUMEX> of target cells, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Œºl</NUMEX> of effector cells, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Œºl</NUMEX> of
            CD107-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC Abs</ENAMEX>. The cells were mixed well using a multichannel pippetor. The plate was
            centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>
            g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX> to pellet cells, then placed into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> ¬∞C
            for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h.</ENAMEX> After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the incubation</TIMEX>, the plates were centrifuged to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>
            g to pellet cells, and the supernatant was removed. Cell‚Äìcell
            conjugates were disrupted by washing the cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.02%</NUMEX> azide
            and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, and mixed vigorously, then stained with additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abs</ENAMEX>.
          
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL Clones</ENAMEX>
          CD8+ T cell clones were derived by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACSorting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> tetramer-positive cells from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PBMC samples</ENAMEX> prepared for flow cytometry as described above. CD8+ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tetramer</NUMEX>-positive T
          cells were sorted under sterile conditions into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates, one cell per well, using
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS Vantage</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> contained <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Œºl</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL IMDM</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human AB</ENAMEX> sera, and penicillin, streptomycin, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-glutamine, supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
          units/ml <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX>. Sorted cells were expanded in vitro using standard protocols. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          irradiated feeder cells (JY cells and fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PBMCs</ENAMEX>) were added to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> containing the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sorted T</ENAMEX> cells, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates were incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> ¬∞C with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to allow for growth. Potential clones became visible around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 14</TIMEX>
          and were then transferred to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well plates containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
          units/ml <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> were selected based on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> confluency for expansion and further
          analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clones</ENAMEX> confirmed to be tetramer-positive were expanded in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-25</ENAMEX> flasks
          containing irradiated JY cells and fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PBMCs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> medium containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PHA</ENAMEX>.
          IL-2 was added to a final concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> units/ml on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 1</TIMEX> and then every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> d
          thereafter for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> wk.
        
        
          Cytotoxic Assays
          
            Target cells
            Target cells were as described above under CD107 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobilization Assays</ENAMEX>, and were
            labeled overnight with 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chromium</ENAMEX>, washed, and resuspended to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells/ml. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One hundred</NUMEX> microliters of target cells were incubated
            with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Œ</NUMEX>ºl <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> clones at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> ratio for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> h. Percent specific release of 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">51 Chromium</ENAMEX> from target cells was calculated from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-Œºl</NUMEX> cell-free
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatants</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            Determination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>
            Chromium-labeled T2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> were pulsed with a range of peptide concentrations,
            generally starting at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚àí7 M</ENAMEX> and decreasing by log steps to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">‚àí13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M. T</ENAMEX> cell clones were incubated with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T2</TIMEX> targets at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>:T
            ratios for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 h</TIMEX>, then chromium release was measured and percentage cytotoxicity
            calculated by standard methods. Prior to each cytotoxicity assay, clones underwent
            ficoll-hypaque centrifugation to remove dead feeder cells and were determined to be
            greater than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> CD8+ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tetramer</NUMEX>-positive T cells by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> ratio was based upon
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">live T</ENAMEX> and target cells. For each T cell clone, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> cytotoxicity was plotted
            against peptide concentration. The peptide concentration at which the curve crossed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX>
            cytotoxicity was defined as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> of that clone [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>].
          
          
            Microcytotoxic assay
            Cells were isolated directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMCs</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> 422 by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> as described above.
            Cells were collected in microfuge tubes containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMDM</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>. Collected cells were washed and resuspended to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83,300</NUMEX> cells/ml in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMDM</ENAMEX> with
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>. Targets were prepared as described above and resuspended to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,300</NUMEX> cells/ml in
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMDM</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,500</NUMEX> sorted cells (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 Œºl</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> target cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Œºl</ENAMEX>) were transferred to a microcentrifuge tube (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VWR International</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Chester</ENAMEX>,
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), centrifuged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
            g, and incubated <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 h at 37 ¬∞C</NUMEX>. Percent specific release of 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chromium</ENAMEX> was calculated from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 Œºl</NUMEX> of cell-free supernatant.
          
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VB</ENAMEX> Spectratyping
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted from clones and tetramer-positive cells using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIzol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and reverse-transcribed into cDNA using SuperScript
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II Reverse Transcriptase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> different <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚</NUMEX>Ä≤ primers
          that specifically amplify all functional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. Most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚</NUMEX>Ä≤ primers used have
          been previously described [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>]. These primers were used in combination with a common <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3‚</NUMEX>Ä≤
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX> based in the beta chain constant region, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BC63</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5‚Ä≤- GTGTGGCCTTTTGGGTGT-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>). As an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> control, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> for a section of the beta chain constant region was performed in
          parallel with VB-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCRs</ENAMEX> using the following primers: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">UpBC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5‚Ä≤-</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CGCTGTGTTTGAGCCATC-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LoBC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5‚Ä≤- TGCTCAGGCAGTATCTGGA-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>). All primer concentrations
          were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> nM. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed using an iCycler iQ thermic cycler equipped with a
          real-time detection system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QuantiTect SYBR Green PCR</ENAMEX> kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valencia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). PCR
          reactions were performed as follows: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX> ¬∞C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 min</TIMEX>, followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">94 ¬∞C</NUMEX> for
          30 s, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">58 ¬∞C</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">72 ¬∞C</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, followed by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">72 ¬∞C</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min. Specific
          amplification was determined relative to constant region control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>. For spectratyping,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCRs</ENAMEX> were performed as described above with the following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">VB14- and VB17</TIMEX>-specific <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚</NUMEX>Ä≤
          primers: VB14m (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5‚Ä≤- ACCCAAGATACCTCATCACAG-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">VB17</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5‚Ä≤- GACAGGACCCAGGGCAAG-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>),
          followed by a run-off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> with downstream VB-specific primers: VB14 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5‚Ä≤-</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GGGCTTAAGGCAGATCTACT-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">VB17m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5‚Ä≤- TTTCAGAAAGGAGATATAGCT-3‚Ä≤</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">FAM6</NUMEX>-labeled BC63
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3‚</NUMEX>Ä≤ primer. Run-off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed as described above except that only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> were run with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> ¬∞C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">annealing</ENAMEX> temperature and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QuantiTect Probe PCR</ENAMEX> kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>).
          Labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> fragments were run on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABI Prism</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">377</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA Sequencer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosystems</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and analyzed using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GeneScan</ENAMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosystems</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          A standard software package (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SigmaPlot 5.0</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systat Software</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>) was used to provide descriptive statistical plots. Barcharts were provided
          with standard errors on them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linear</ENAMEX> plots were provided with standard errors computed at
          each point. A linear regression (using least squares) of percent specific lysis on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> efficiency is shown in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5A and 5B</TIMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T Cell Responses</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAAs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with Melanoma
          To address the complexity of T cell responses against melanoma in vivo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine-induced</ENAMEX> or endogenous TAA-specific responses were selected. In recent cancer
          vaccine trials [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,4,5</NUMEX>], many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">melanoma patients</ENAMEX> who received heteroclitic peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>
          gp100 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209‚Äì217</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">210M</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMDQVPSFV</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G209‚Äì2M</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MART</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26‚Äì35</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">27L</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELAGIGILTV; M26</ENAMEX>) had
          measurable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">peptide</NUMEX>-specific T cell responses in PBMCs detected by peptide‚ÄìMHC
          tetramer staining. In addition, TAA-specific T cell responses could be detected in some
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> without vaccination, suggesting the existence of an endogenous anti-tumor T cell
          response in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. For the current study, we selected samples from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> melanoma
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> from these trials‚Äîfour with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited responses (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">patients 422, 476, 517,</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">520</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> with endogenous T cell responses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">132</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">461)‚</NUMEX>Äîfor detailed
          analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VB</ENAMEX> usage, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for the target peptide, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor cytotoxicity</ENAMEX>. The samples
          from these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> had peptide-specific T cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> detectable with
          G209‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äì2M</NUMEX>-tetramers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">422, 476</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M26</NUMEX>-tetramers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">517, 520</TIMEX>, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">461</NUMEX>) ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1% to 2.5%</NUMEX> of total <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ T cells (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A</NUMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vaccine-Elicited T Cells Are Functional Directly Ex Vivo but of Variable Tumor</ENAMEX>
          Reactivity
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Patient 422</ENAMEX> had the largest detectable TAA-specific CD8+ T cell response (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX>
          G209‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äì2M</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tetramer</NUMEX>-positive) and thus sufficient numbers for examination of lytic function
          immediately following isolation. To test whether <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptide-vaccine</ENAMEX>-induced T cell responses
          were functionally active directly ex vivo, T cells isolated by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G209‚Äì2M</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tetramer</NUMEX>-guided
          cell sorting from patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">422</NUMEX> were tested for lysis of peptide-pulsed and melanoma target
          cells in microcytotoxic assays (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1B</NUMEX>). The directly isolated tetramer-positive T
          cells from this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> specifically lysed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T2</NUMEX> cells pulsed with high concentrations (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Œºg/ml</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G209‚Äì2M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">G209n</NUMEX>) peptides, but not with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T2</NUMEX> cells pulsed with a
          cytomegalovirus-derived, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA</ENAMEX>-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0201</TIMEX>-restricted peptide (NLVPMVATV) or melanoma targets.
          This suggests that while a significant portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited T cells from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">patient 422</ENAMEX> may be functional in vivo, they did not have significant tumor lysis
          activity.
          To assess the functional status of the smaller TAA-specific CD8+ T cell responses in
          the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> patients‚Äîwhich were too small for direct cytotoxicity assays after
          sorting‚Äîwe utilized a novel FACS assay for degranulation based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD107</TIMEX> mobilization
          [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> TAA-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> exhibited robust functional responses ex vivo, as
          measured by percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G2090‚Äì2M-</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M26</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tetramer</NUMEX>-positive cells that mobilized CD107
          and/or downregulated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">CD3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> upon incubation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T2</NUMEX> cells pulsed with cognate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptides</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%-99.6%</NUMEX>). In response to melanoma targets mel526 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Malme-3M</ENAMEX>, which
          both express gp100 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MART-1</ENAMEX> and are HLA-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0201</TIMEX> positive, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> endogenous
          TAA-specific responses (samples from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">132 and 461</TIMEX>) also exhibited robust
          functional responses directly ex vivo (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36.8%‚Äì87%</NUMEX>), and these responses were
          specific as they had little response to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A375</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA</ENAMEX>-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0201</TIMEX>-positive melanoma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> that
          does not express gp100 or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MART-1</ENAMEX> and served as a negative control for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-specific
          killing (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.7% and 3%</NUMEX>). In contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited responses exhibited
          much lower reactivity to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">mel526</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Malme-3M</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23.8%‚Äì32.5%</NUMEX>). These data
          demonstrate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all six</NUMEX> TAA-specific CD8+ T cell responses were functional ex vivo, but
          there were significant differences in reactivity to melanoma targets between endogenous
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited responses.
          To substantiate the generality of these findings, we analyzed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> additional patients
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited responses. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> responded to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">G209‚</NUMEX>Äì2M only (patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">722</NUMEX>), one
          to M26 only (patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">713</NUMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to both G209‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì2M and M26</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">721 and 735</TIMEX>).
          Similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> vaccine-elicited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
          TAA-specific responses in total) exhibited variable reactivity to melanoma targets,
          ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13% to 49.6%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vaccine-Elicited T Cells Have Varied Capacity to Lyse Melanoma Targets</ENAMEX>
          To confirm and further investigate the differences in tumor reactivity between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> and vaccine-elicited responses, we reasoned that analysis of a set of clonal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CTL</ENAMEX> lines that represented the tetramer-positive population would provide an accurate
          estimate of the complexity of the TAA-specific T cell response in each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. A large
          number of clonal CTL lines (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 200</NUMEX>) were generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> of individual G209‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äì2M</NUMEX>-
          and M26-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tetramer</NUMEX>-positive cells directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PBMC samples</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX> of sorted
          cells expanded in various sorts (data not shown). Randomly selected expanding clones and
          the tetramer-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from which they were derived were examined for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VB</ENAMEX>
          expression using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VB</ENAMEX>-specific monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abs</ENAMEX> and VB-specific primers in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>. Diverse
          cells expressing different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VB</ENAMEX>, while the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two endogenous</NUMEX> responses were less diverse.
          All but one clone derived from patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX> expressed VB17, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dominating T cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">476</NUMEX> expressed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">VB14 and VB17</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). The clonality of the
          dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was evaluated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> fragment length analysis
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>). Identical length fragments were demonstrated in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> selected clones from
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">476 BV14</NUMEX>+ and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">476 BV17</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. Identical length fragments were also demonstrated in
          all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">BV17</NUMEX>+ clones from patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX>. Furthermore, analysis of sorted tetramer-positive
          cells from patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">476</NUMEX> demonstrated single fragment sizes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BV14 and BV17</TIMEX>, which were
          identical to the fragment sizes generated from the selected clones, arguing for clonality
          of these dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>).
          Peptide specificity and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD8</ENAMEX> expression of each clone was confirmed by staining with
          G209‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äì2M</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M26</NUMEX>-tetramers and anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> (data not shown). To obtain an
          accurate reflection of the total T cell population detected with tetramer in each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, we decided to rigorously examine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> representative clone for each
          subpopulation expressing a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>). Multiple clones were analyzed to
          determine dominating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">132, 517</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">461</NUMEX>, for which fewer clones
          were generated, all clones were included in the analyses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>).
          To determine the effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor lysis</ENAMEX> by the different TAA-specific T cell
          clones that were propagated, clones were analyzed for their ability to lyse melanoma cell
          lines <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mel526</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Malme-3M</ENAMEX>. A375 cells served as a control for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-specific killing.
          In addition, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> clone was examined for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-specific lysis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T2</NUMEX> cells pulsed
          with high levels (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1Œºg/ml</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G209‚Äì2M</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M26</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúEfficient lysis‚Äù in these
          experiments was defined as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> or greater specific release of radiolabel from the target
          cells; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> or less specific release was categorized as ‚Äúlow or no lysis,‚Äù and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10% to 40%</NUMEX>
          was termed ‚Äúintermediate lysis.‚Äù All but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> clones elicited from endogenous
          anti-tumor responses (from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">132 and 461</TIMEX>) exhibited ‚Äúefficient lysis‚Äù of both the
          mel526 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Malme-3M</ENAMEX> melanoma cell lines (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). In contrast, only a few clones from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited responses (from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">422, 476, 520</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">517</NUMEX>) efficiently lysed
          melanoma cells. The majority of clones examined from these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited responses
          either failed to lyse melanoma targets altogether or lysed them with intermediate
          efficiency (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). This lack of efficiency in melanoma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysis</ENAMEX> was not due to
          cellular dysfunction, since each clone efficiently lysed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T2</NUMEX> cells pulsed with high levels
          of relevant, but not irrelevant, peptide (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Overall, the majority of clones
          derived from endogenous anti-tumor responses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">132 and 461</TIMEX>) lysed both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mel526</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Malme-3M</ENAMEX> melanoma target cells more efficiently than clones from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited
          responses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">422, 476, 520</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">517</NUMEX>) (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). These findings suggest that
          TAA-specific T cells elicited by heteroclitic peptide vaccination have different
          tumor-cytolytic potentials from those which develop endogenously to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heteroclitic Peptides</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T Cells</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Endogenous</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaccine-Elicited Responses</ENAMEX>
          We hypothesized that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> clones that did not efficiently lyse melanoma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> may be
          incapable of recognizing the relatively low surface densities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native peptide</ENAMEX> present
          on tumor cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> clones selected for analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor lysis</ENAMEX> were also assessed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>
          for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> and heteroclitic peptides via a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-log range of dilutions. This is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illustrated</ENAMEX> with clones <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">132.1 and 476.105</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>). There were considerable
          differences in killing of peptide-pulsed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T2 cells</ENAMEX> by these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> clones. The differences in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">G209n native</ENAMEX> peptide displayed by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> clones highlighted in Figure 3A
          correlated with their ability to lyse melanoma cells: the high-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> clone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132.1</NUMEX> efficiently
          lysed melanoma targets, whereas the low-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> clone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">476.105</NUMEX> did not (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4B</NUMEX>). In contrast
          to the differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G209n</TIMEX> peptide, similar assays revealed little difference in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> clones for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G209‚Äì2M</ENAMEX> heteroclitic peptide (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4C</NUMEX>), suggesting that these
          clones recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> and heteroclitic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX> differently, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for the
          native, but not heteroclitic, peptide correlates with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX>-lytic potential.
          Similar RE assays were performed for the remaining clones from each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> selected
          for analysis. In order to compare REs of various CTL lines, each clone was assigned an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>
          score expressed as the negative log
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> value of the peptide concentration required for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> specific lysis
          at an E:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>. For clones <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">132.1 and 476.105</NUMEX>, these scores were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.1 and 8.3</NUMEX> for
          assays with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G209n</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.2 and 11.2</NUMEX> for assays with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">G209‚</NUMEX>Äì2M
          heteroclitic peptide (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4C</NUMEX>), respectively. We compiled the data on clones from all
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, which showed a correlation between tumor-lytic potential and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for native
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5A and 5B</TIMEX>). Overall, clones generated from endogenous anti-tumor
          responses had higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for the native peptide than clones generated from post-vaccine
          responses (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5C and 5D</TIMEX>). We estimated the composite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> of the overall TAA-specific
          response (composed of a heterogeneous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of T cells) in vivo by summing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE of</ENAMEX>
          each clone multiplied by its representation in the original mixture (the representation
          was estimated based on the proportion of TAA-specific cells expressing the same VB as the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clone</ENAMEX>). These composite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> values are represented in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">horizontal bars</ENAMEX> for each
          response. Clearly, the endogenous responses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">461 and 132</TIMEX>) had a higher overall,
          and more homogeneous, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for the native peptide than the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited responses
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">422, 476, 517</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">520</NUMEX>) (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5C and 5D</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clones</ENAMEX> also exhibited wide variations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> even for the heteroclitic peptide, compared
          to the endogenous responses (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5E and 5F</TIMEX>). This suggests that the variation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native peptides</ENAMEX>, and hence ability to lyse tumor cells, for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited
          responses is not merely a reflection of differential recognition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native</ENAMEX> and
          heteroclitic peptides by many clones. Rather, variations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> may be a function of the
          manner in which these cells were elicited in vivo via vaccination.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        To achieve maximal clinical responses, the majority of T cells elicited by vaccination
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> should be capable of responding to tumor targets. We have undertaken the
        most detailed analysis to date, on a single-cell level, of T cell responses elicited by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer vaccination</ENAMEX> and have compared these with endogenous anti-tumor responses. To
        evaluate the full spectrum of T cells elicited in each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> by vaccination, we utilized
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tetramers</ENAMEX> made with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine peptides</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heteroclitic M26</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G209‚Äì2M</ENAMEX>) to isolate such
        cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> clones were selected directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> PBMC <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> without enrichment in
        culture to closely reflect the composition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-specific T cell response in vivo
        at the time of isolation.
        Our data revealed that T cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> induced by vaccination were significantly
        different from endogenous responses: while some CTLs elicited by vaccination could kill
        melanoma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, most were inefficient in tumor cell lysis. In contrast, nearly all clones
        from endogenous responses were efficient at melanoma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysis</ENAMEX>. This difference was
        related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX>. Clones that did not lyse tumor cells required up to
        10
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> -fold higher concentration of peptide for similar levels of lysis of
        targets compared to T cell clones that were tumor-lytic. Side-by-side comparison of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> responses and vaccine-induced responses suggests that low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE TAA</ENAMEX>-specific T cell
        responses may be preferentially driven by heteroclitic peptide vaccination. Thus, high
        doses of peptide and/or the higher levels of expression of heteroclitic peptide on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APCs</ENAMEX> may
        induce and actively propagate predominantly T cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> too low for recognition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physiological</ENAMEX> levels of the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> present on tumor targets. These data suggest an
        inverse relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen density</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE of T</ENAMEX> cells elicited. This would be
        an important consideration in design of future vaccine strategies.
        Differential recognition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native</ENAMEX> and heteroclitic peptides by many T cells may also
        account for the induction of non-tumor-lytic clones by heteroclitic peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>, which
        has been suggested previously [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23,32</NUMEX>]. However, our data suggest that epitope density may
        be the dominant driving factor for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> in vivo. In all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited T cell
        responses, many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells generated were either of low or intermediate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> not only for
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native peptide</ENAMEX>, but also for the heteroclitic peptide, and exhibited no or intermediate
        lysis of tumor targets. In contrast, nearly all of the clones generated from the endogenous
        responses were of high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>. This suggests that the high dosage of peptides administered in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vaccinations</ENAMEX> and the increased binding capacity of heteroclitic peptides to MHC
        molecules‚Äîthe very quality that provides them with increased immunogenicity‚Äîdrive the
        induction of many T cells with low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for both heteroclitic and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native peptides</ENAMEX>.
        Another implication of this study is that the number of cells measured by current
        methods, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISPOT</ENAMEX> or staining with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> tetramers, may not correlate directly with
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> or tumor reactivity of T cell responses to vaccination. For example, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clones</ENAMEX> analyzed from patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">517</NUMEX>, none were efficient in tumor cell lysis, yet these cells
        were detectable by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> tetramer staining. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells with low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native TAA</ENAMEX> do not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">efficiently lyse tumor</ENAMEX>, and therefore are unlikely to have an impact on clinical outcome.
        Furthermore, it may be possible that low-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE TAA</ENAMEX>-specific T cells may interfere with
        elicitation of high-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE T</ENAMEX> cells, either by direct competition for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> on APC surface
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33,34</NUMEX>] or down-modulation of peptide‚ÄìMHC <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>.
        Our data support the notion that not only quantity, but quality, of the T cell response
        elicited by vaccination may be important for clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">efficacy</ENAMEX>. There are a number of
        strategies to increase the magnitude of T cell responses to peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>. These include
        using various adjuvants, such as incomplete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s adjuvant and immunomodulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>,
        such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>], anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CTLA-4 Abs</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>], or heat shock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>]. Thus far,
        none of these approaches have produced improved clinical outcomes. Our data suggest that in
        addition to driving higher numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>-elicited T cells, strategies to modulate the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relative RE of T</ENAMEX> cell responses are also needed. While the selective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> of high-
        versus low-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE T</ENAMEX> cells is relatively easy to manipulate in vitro via stimulation with
        limiting amounts of peptides, this may be more difficult to control in vivo. It is
        important to bear in mind that signals needed to drive a de novo na√Øve T cell response may
        be different from those required to drive further expansion of an activated T cell
        population [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>]. Thus, a complete vaccination strategy may involve an initial induction
        phase, followed by progressive shaping of the response to higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>. Although heteroclitic
        peptide vaccination may drive T cells of mixed high and low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>, such a strong stimulus may
        be needed to induce an initial de novo T cell response. Studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> suggest that once
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activated</ENAMEX>, effector <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ T cells may have an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 70-fold</NUMEX> compared to
        na√Øve cells [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38,39,40</NUMEX>]. Thus, na√Øve TAA-specific T cells, with inadequate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> to become
        activated by low densities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native peptides</ENAMEX> present on tumor cells, may become efficient
        in tumor lysis upon vaccination with heteroclitic peptide. This notion has support from
        studies in tolerized <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>: vaccination with a heteroclitic peptide analog recruited T
        cells, which were responsive to secondary stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native peptide</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41,42</NUMEX>].
        Therefore, optimized use of heteroclitic peptide to induce an initial peptide-specific T
        cell response, followed by selective expansion of the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RE tumor</ENAMEX>-lytic T cells may be
        needed for an effective strategy with clear clinical application.
        In summary, we have demonstrated that vaccination with heteroclitic peptide at high
        concentrations may drive T cell responses of variable tumor-cytolytic potential in cancer
        patients‚Äîand that the ability to lyse tumor cells correlates with the T cell's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native peptides</ENAMEX>. This represents an important‚Äîbut not sole‚Äîfactor in explaining the lack of
        correlation between immunological and clinical responses after vaccination for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, the situation is different in endogenous responses, in which cells are
        predominantly of high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>. This suggests that the manner in which T cells are elicited in
        vivo are different in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> settings and may underlie their differences in biology.
      
    
  
