
  
    
      
        Introduction
        With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 3.5 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> is home to one of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
        of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> worldwide [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV prevalence</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> has increased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> to an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.8%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Prevalence ranges
        from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2% to 14.9%</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Capital Territory</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. According to
        official estimates, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 3.6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> 310,000 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> deaths <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> alone [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], and these numbers are projected to
        increase <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, with the election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olusegun Obasanjo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>
        emerged from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 20 years</TIMEX> of military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> in which little governmental
        attention or funding was directed at addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> (PLWA) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> have been found to be subject to
        discrimination and stigmatization in the work place, and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,6</NUMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX> may also face discrimination from those employed in the health-care sector. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        Discriminatory or unethical behavior by health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX>, as
        documented in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7–11</NUMEX>], may create an atmosphere that interferes with
        effective prevention and treatment by discouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> from being tested or seeking
        information on how to protect themselves and others from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12–14</NUMEX>]. Furthermore,
        discriminatory practices and violations of international principles of medical ethics may
        serve to legitimize other forms of discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.
        Anecdotal information suggests that health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> may engage in
        discrimination against and stigmatization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,15</NUMEX>]. The prevalence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of, and
        factors contributing to these practices are, however, largely undocumented. To address
        this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians for Human Rights</ENAMEX> (PHR), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Project Nigeria</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for the</ENAMEX>
        Right to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX> conducted a survey of health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sites in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>. The
        study was designed to answer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> research questions. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Are there discriminatory
        practices in the health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> that affect the health and well-being of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) How receptive are health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and institutions to treating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>? And (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) what underlying factors may contribute to any discriminatory
        practices? The study was intended to inform ongoing policy discussions and development of
        effective interventions.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Sampling
          At the time of the study, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 120,000,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were living in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Capital Territory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. We conducted the study in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abia, Gombe, Kano</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oyo</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> were selected by dividing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> geopolitical zones into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sections—north and south—in order to capture geographical
          and other differences and then randomly selecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of three zones from each section.
          Within the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> selected zones, using health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> lists compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Ministry of Health</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>], we identified states that have a tertiary care
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> and randomly selected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> from each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">zone</ENAMEX>. To obtain a
          representative sample of health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proportionally</ENAMEX> sampled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, and midwives from the tertiary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and systematically selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and
          private secondary and primary health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Fifty-four
          percent of the health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> were sampled from tertiary care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. We
          determined the sample size based on local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>' estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of clinicians
          have discriminatory behavior and attitudes, a margin of error of ± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX>
          confidence (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> significance) level. The sample size required given these constraints was
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301</NUMEX> health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. However, our sample design included several levels of
          clustering, and we therefore assumed a design effect of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and thus the sample size
          needed was calculated to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 1,000</NUMEX>. Eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> were medical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> included in the published federal government database, which indicated that
          there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,585</NUMEX> health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. In each health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>,
          we systematically sampled from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, and midwives to acquire information
          about their knowledge, attitudes, and behavior. Eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> or
          certified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">midwives</ENAMEX> working in positions with direct patient contact. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> on
          the number of health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> were derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Ministry of Health</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, which indicated that these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 4,500</NUMEX> health-care
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survey Questionnaire</ENAMEX>
          The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX>-item health-care professional survey included questions on respondent
          demographics; practices regarding informed consent, testing, and disclosure; treatment
          and care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>; and attitudes and beliefs about treatment and care of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> including informed consent, testing, and disclosure.
          Treatment and care practices of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> were assessed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likert</ENAMEX>-type
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scales</ENAMEX> (e.g., the possible answers were “always,<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">” “most</ENAMEX> of the time,<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">” “sometimes,”</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“rarely</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">” and “never”</ENAMEX>). Attitudes and beliefs were assessed by a response of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">“agree”</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“disagree”</ENAMEX> with statements regarding testing, treatment, and care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.
          Using a separate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103</NUMEX>-item survey instrument, we obtained information about each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facility</ENAMEX>'s capacity, resources, and policies from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in charge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>.
          The questionnaires were written and interviews conducted in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> regional,
          human rights, and medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> reviewed the questionnaires for content validity. The
          instruments were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> tested among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lagos</ENAMEX> and suggestions regarding
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clarity</ENAMEX> and cultural appropriateness were incorporated.
        
        
          Interviewers
          After completing an intensive training program, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surveyors</ENAMEX> conducted the
          survey interviews. Interviewer training consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> d of classroom teaching and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">role-playing</ENAMEX> followed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> of field observation and ongoing supervision by PHR
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>.
          All interviews were conducted over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> wk in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2002</TIMEX>. Interviews
          lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 20–30 min</TIMEX> and were conducted in the most private setting possible
          within each health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. All questionnaires were reviewed for completeness and
          for correctness of recording after the interview by the interviewers themselves, by the
          Nigerian research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHR</ENAMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of each day</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Definitions
          In the surveys, informed consent was defined as ensuring that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> who is
          competent to make decisions is informed and consulted about his or her care. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Respondents</ENAMEX>
          were informed that this included the responsibility of the clinician to let the patient
          know about any procedure or medical decision, reasonable alternatives to it, and the
          risks, benefits, uncertainties, and possible consequences related to each alternative.
          The clinician must carry out the discussion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">layperson</TIMEX>'s terms, assess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s
          understanding along the way, and ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> understands the information and
          consents to it voluntarily [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> precautions were defined as the use of
          protective barriers such as gloves, gowns, aprons, masks, or protective eyewear, which
          can reduce the risk of exposure to potentially infective materials at all times
          regardless of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> or other status [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>].
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Subjects Protection</ENAMEX>
          This study was reviewed and approved by an independent ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review board</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with expertise in clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, public health, bioethics, and
          international <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and human rights research developed for this research project by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHR</ENAMEX>. In reviewing the research, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review board</ENAMEX> was guided by the relevant provisions of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 45 of the US Code</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Regulations</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>], and complied with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helsinki</ENAMEX>, as revised in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. The study was also reviewed for ethical and cultural
          appropriateness by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> convened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Project Nigeria</ENAMEX>. In addition,
          permission for the study and access to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> was granted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> Federal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of Health</ENAMEX>, state and local government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, and facility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>. There
          were no limitations placed on movement or surveying. Verbal informed consent was obtained
          from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, their names were not recorded, and only minimal identifying
          information was taken in order to preserve the anonymity of their responses. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
          did not receive any compensation.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          The data were analyzed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stata</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. To control for clustering and design
          effect, the sample was weighted by the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> selected with a tertiary facility
          from each of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> selected geopolitical zones, the number of local government areas per
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">location</ENAMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> selected from each local government area, and the
          response rate in each location. The study's principal objective was to describe
          health-care professional practices and attitudes towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, rather
          than to conduct comparisons between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> or explore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between
          professional characteristics and different outcomes. However, we conducted bivariate
          analyses using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chi-square analyses</ENAMEX> and simple logistic regression to compare negative
          practices and attitudes among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> health specialties surveyed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midwives</ENAMEX>) and to test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between reported facility resources and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>'
          reported adequacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> training and reported negative practices and attitudes about
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Characteristics of Facilities</ENAMEX>
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">163</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> sampled, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> were no longer operational; for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> could
          not be established after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> attempts at the time of sampling; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> were not eligible.
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">118</NUMEX> eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> was established, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> participated in the
          study (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> of operational <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>). Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> were general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54%</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23%</NUMEX> were primary health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> of facility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> reported not having antiretroviral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. Moreover, the availability of other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> and
          dietary supplements was limited, and protective materials and other supplies and
          utilities were not always available (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Characteristics of Respondents</ENAMEX>
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,103</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> sampled, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> were not eligible, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> were not available
          after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> attempts at the time of sampling, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> were interrupted during the course of
          the interview, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> refused to participate. Consequently, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,021</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
          participated in the study (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93%</NUMEX> response rate). Although we did not gather information on
          nonrespondents, most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonrespondents</ENAMEX> who refused to participate cited lack of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> as the reason they were unable to participate (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">36</NUMEX>), with other nonrespondents citing
          other obligations (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>), fear of reprisal (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>), and opposition to the study
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>).
          
            Sociodemographic characteristics
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professionals</ENAMEX> were predominantly female (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX>) with a mean age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">y. Fifty-six</ENAMEX>
            percent were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> were certified midwives (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> training
            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> reported having some training on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Current
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">literature</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69%</NUMEX>), conferences (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52%</NUMEX>) were most
            frequently reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of this training. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> percent
            reported having no training on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> at all.
          
        
        
          Testing and Consent
          
            Practices
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Seventeen percent</NUMEX> of surveyed health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> reported that their facility
            had a written <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> testing policy (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Respondents</ENAMEX> indicated that the policies
            included requirements for informed consent (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX>), pre-test counseling (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX>), post-test
            counseling (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52%</NUMEX>), and post-test referral (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX>).
            Over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> reported obtaining informed consent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
            tests <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the time or less, including <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> who reported never obtaining consent for
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> tests (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Fifty-four percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> reported that, regardless of
            consent, routine <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> testing of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> scheduled for surgery always took place at
            their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> reported such routine <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> testing of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> attending
            antenatal care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>. Providers who reported that they lacked adequate training in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> treatment and ethics had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> higher odds of reporting that they failed to
            obtain informed consent for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> tests (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50%</NUMEX> of the time) compared to providers
            reporting adequate training in these areas (odds ratio (OR) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.53</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> confidence
            interval [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>] <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.17–2.01</NUMEX>).
          
          
            Attitudes
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
            should be informed when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive so they can protect themselves (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX>) agreed that there are circumstances when
            it is appropriate to test a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> without his or her knowledge or permission.
            Fifty-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> should be notified of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s status even without the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s consent. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> thought that the charts or beds
            of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> should be marked so that health facility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> know the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s status.
            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> percent believed that health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> should not be
            working in any area of the health professions that requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient contact</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX>
            percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> agreed that many of those who have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> behaved immorally
            and deserve the disease (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>).
            Providers working in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that did not always practice universal precautions
            (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX> citing lack of sufficient materials as the reason) were significantly more likely
            than those working in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that always observed universal precautions to agree
            that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> should not be employed in the health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> (OR <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.43</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1.09–1.74</TIMEX>) and should not work in areas that require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient contact</ENAMEX>. They also had
            higher odds of agreeing that under certain circumstances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> could be tested for
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> without their knowledge or permission (OR <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.63</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.14–2.33</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working</ENAMEX> in a
            facility that did not always practice universal precautions, being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> or midwife,
            and reporting inadequate training in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> treatment were all associated with
            agreeing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> should be on a separate ward in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> or
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nurses</ENAMEX> and midwives both had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than five</NUMEX> times the odds of agreeing that
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> should not be employed in the health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and that
            the charts or beds of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> should be marked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nurses</ENAMEX> and midwives also had
            almost twice the odds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> of agreeing that under certain circumstances it is
            acceptable to test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> without their consent or knowledge.
          
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treatment and Care</ENAMEX>
          
            Practices
            Among health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most important concerns about treating
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> were fear of becoming contaminated (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX>), contamination of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facility</ENAMEX>, materials, or instruments (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX>), and not having materials needed to treat
            them (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> reported that universal
            precautions were always practiced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in which they worked. Lack of
            materials—reported by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX> of professionals—was cited as the main reason for
            non-practice of universal precautions (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> reported refusing to care for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>,
            and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> indicated that they had refused a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> admission to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Sixty-six percent</NUMEX> had observed other health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> refusing to
            care for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43%</NUMEX> had observed others refusing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> admission to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> reported
            verbally mistreating a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> reported seeing others
            verbally mistreat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirty</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> reported giving confidential information to a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s consent, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX> had observed this
            behavior. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> reported giving confidential information to a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> not related to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> without consent, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> had observed this behavior
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>).
            Providers who reported inadequate training in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> treatment and in ethics were
            significantly more likely to have refused to treat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> than those
            reporting adequate training in those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas (OR <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.06</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.31–3.22</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Providers</ENAMEX>
            working in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that did not always practice universal precautions were not more
            likely to have refused care to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> themselves but were significantly more likely
            to report having observed other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> refuse to care for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
            (OR <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.09</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.01–1.45</NUMEX>). There were no differences among specialties in reporting
            having refused to care for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            Attitudes
            To prevent discrimination by health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87%</NUMEX>) indicated that health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> who engage
            in discriminatory practices should be educated and counseled. Health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> policies
            against discrimination were cited as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, and stronger
            laws against discrimination were suggested by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>).
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> to treat opportunistic infections may
            prolong the life of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> who is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 7</ENAMEX>). Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59%</NUMEX>) of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> should be on a separate ward in a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Forty-eight percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> expressed their belief that a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cannot be treated effectively in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> percent of
            health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> reported that it is possible to determine a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
            status by looking at him or her, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX> agreed that they could refuse to treat a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> to protect themselves and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> percent expressed
            agreement with the statement that treatment of opportunistic infections in patients
            with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wastes</ENAMEX> resources, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> agreed that treating someone with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is a
            waste of precious resources.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nurses</ENAMEX> had higher odds than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> of agreeing that treating opportunistic
            infections in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is a waste of resources (OR <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.14</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1.35–3.40</TIMEX>), but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> more likely than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> to agree that they could
            refuse to treat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> to protect themselves and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Respondents</ENAMEX> who reported inadequate training in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> treatment also were
            significantly more likely to agree it was acceptable to refuse to treat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> for
            these reasons (OR <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.34</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.31–3.22</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians</ENAMEX> had significantly higher odds
            than either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> or midwives of agreeing that there were circumstances under which it
            was appropriate to reveal a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> status to others without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s
            knowledge or permission.
          
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Most health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where the study was conducted appeared
        to be providing care to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive and complying with their ethical
        responsibilities despite their lack of training on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and their having insufficient
        supplies of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> needed for treatment and prevention in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> where they
        work. A significant number, however, reported engaging in discriminatory and/or unethical
        behavior. These practices are corrosive to the health professions as they taint all health
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and erode <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in them. They also represent missed opportunities for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prevention</ENAMEX>, positive living education, and treatment, thereby undermining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s
        concerted national efforts to address the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic. Our study findings suggest
        that there are several factors that may contribute to such discriminatory and/or unethical
        behavior by health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>.
        The vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> expressed an interest in additional information and
        suggested education as a way to address discriminatory behaviors by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. An
        immediate investment to ensure the education of all existing clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>,
        including modes of transmission, universal precautions, and the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX> would likely
        reduce the number of discriminatory practices towards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX> and may improve these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>'
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> and access to health services. This assertion is supported by previous studies that
        demonstrate the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> education of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> and other health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> on their
        attitudes and behavior towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> and elsewhere
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24–26</NUMEX>]. These studies also suggest that education about scientific matters is not likely
        to be sufficient to achieve change in practice and that educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> may also need
        to address attitudes and cultural beliefs.
        This study further suggests that the lack of protective and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> needed to
        treat and prevent the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> and related conditions contributes to discriminatory
        behavior. While the issue of access to affordable antiretroviral treatment is the subject
        of much debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,27</NUMEX>], many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in this study did not even have
        sufficient stocks of basic antibiotics to treat opportunistic infections. The lack of
        protective materials, documented in the health facility survey and cited also by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> as the main reason for not applying universal precautions, contributes to
        discriminatory behavior in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> lacking adequate protection may
        come to fear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX> and fear may lead to discrimination [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28–30</NUMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, lack of resources
        also results in differential treatment practices that may contribute to stigmatization of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX>.
        In order to do their jobs safely and effectively, health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> must be provided
        with adequate supplies of essential protective materials. Further, the lack of basic
        medications hampers the ability of health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> to provide appropriate treatment.
        Without these materials, it is unlikely that education of health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and
        implementation of anti-discrimination policies alone will have the desired impact on
        practice.
        It is likely that in other low-resource contexts, the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> needed to
        treat <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/AIDS-related illnesses, a lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> needed for protection of health
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and insufficient knowledge of health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> may contribute to
        discriminatory behavior towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. The role of these factors should be
        investigated. While addressing these factors may not eliminate all discriminatory behavior,
        these basic investments in the health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> are likely to result in improvements.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection is both a product of and a factor contributing to human rights violations
        [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. The documented marginalization of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and their increased risk for
        infection with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>], must be considered in light of this study.
        Misconceptions must be taken into account when developing education and training programs
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, one in which stigma and moral judgment appear to be attached to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>].
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Twenty percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> agreed that many of those who have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> behaved immorally
        and deserve the disease. As such, it is likely that governmental and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> policies and
        monitoring to reduce discriminatory practices in the health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> will be an
        important aspect of addressing these practices.
        Numerous international and regional human rights instruments, to which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> is a
        party [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>], protect the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX>. These include [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32–37</NUMEX>] the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African Charter on Human</ENAMEX>
        against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>], the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention on the Rights of the Child</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>], the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
        Civil and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Rights</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>]. Of these, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African Charter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Convention on</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child</ENAMEX> have been incorporated into the domestic law of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,38</NUMEX>].
        The above instruments set out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s obligations to protect the rights of PLWA
        including the right to life [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>], the right to education [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>], the right to marry and found
        a family [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>], the right to nondiscrimination [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>], the right to share in the benefits of
        scientific advancements [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>], the right to privacy [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>], and the right to freedom of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>].
        Several of the instruments to which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> include the right to health
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34–37,40</NUMEX>]. The right to health, was first elaborated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Covenant</ENAMEX> on
        Economic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cultural Rights, Article 12</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>], which states:
        
          
          
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> Parties to the present Covenant recognize the right of everyone to
            the enjoyment of the highest attainable standard of physical and mental health.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The steps to be taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> Parties to the present Covenant to achieve
            the full realization of this right shall include those necessary for:
          
        
        
          
          
            (a) The provision for the reduction of the stillbirth-rate and of infant
            mortality and for the healthy development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>;
            (b) The improvement of all aspects of environmental and industrial
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hygiene</ENAMEX>;
            (c) The prevention, treatment and control of epidemic, endemic, occupational and
            other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>;
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) The creation of conditions which would assure to all medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and
            medical attention in the event of sickness.
          
        
        responsible for interpretation and monitoring of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International Covenant on Economic</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>, and Cultural Rights, published General Comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right to the Highest</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attainable Standard of Health</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESCR Committee</ENAMEX> determined that fulfillment of the
        right to health means that access to health services must not be limited based on
        discrimination on a prohibited ground, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> status .
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">General Comment 14</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESCR Committee</ENAMEX> also set out the core obligations of a state
        party to protect the right to health, which include ensuring “the right of access to health
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>, goods and services on a non-discriminatory basis, especially for vulnerable or
        marginalized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,” the provision of essential <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs “as</ENAMEX> from time to time defined by
        WHO's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Action Programme on Essential Drugs</ENAMEX>,” and ensuring “equitable distribution of all
        health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, goods and services.” In addition to these and other core obligations,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESCR Committee</ENAMEX> also set out “obligations of comparable priority” , including a state
        party's obligation “to take measures to prevent, treat and control epidemic and endemic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">diseases,” </ENAMEX>to provide education and access to information concerning the main health
        problems in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, including methods of preventing and controlling them,” and “to
        provide appropriate training for health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, including education on health and human
        rights.”
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESCR Committee</ENAMEX> also stated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">General Comment 14</ENAMEX> that “any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> who is a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of a violation of the right to health should have access to effective judicial or
        other appropriate remedies at both national and international levels.”As a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> is bound by the provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International Covenant on Economic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cultural Rights</ENAMEX> and the authoritative interpretations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESCR Committee</ENAMEX>. This study
        finds that some PLWA have been excluded from access to health care because of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        status and that, at this time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX> have no access to judicial or other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">remedial</ENAMEX> processes
        to address this. The data further suggest that inadequate education of health personnel
        about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> along with a lack of protective and treatment materials likely contribute to
        these behaviors by health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. It is therefore likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> has not met
        its core obligations to fulfill and protect the right to health. The findings of this study
        suggest that, in order to fulfill its obligations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> should
        continue to address gaps in policy and legislation and work together with the international
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> to ensure that health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> receive the training, protective materials,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> they need to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PLWA</ENAMEX>.
        International principles of medical ethics and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> codes of conduct clearly provide
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> autonomy, i.e., the right to informed consent and confidentiality of patient
        information. In addition to representing violations of human rights, the denial of
        treatment and breaches of informed consent and confidentiality detailed in this paper
        contravene international principles of medical ethics and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> health professional
        codes of conduct. The 
        Rules of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Conduct for Medical</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Practitioners</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that “a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> shall preserve absolute secrecy on all he knows
        about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> even after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> has died, because of the confidence entrusted to
        him.” The binding rules also state that “practitioners…must always obtain consent of the
        patient or the competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>...before embarking on any special treatment procedures
        with determinable risks.”
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> also have a duty under these rules to report any
        unethical conduct by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Council of Nigeria</ENAMEX>. According to
        the rules, “every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> must be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keeper</ENAMEX>, with regard to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observance</ENAMEX> and indeed the enforcement of the rules and regulations which guide the
        profession. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> should expose without fear or favour, before the Medical
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Council of Nigeria</ENAMEX> either directly or through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Association</ENAMEX>,
        any corrupt, dishonest, unprofessional or criminal act or omission on the part of any
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>.” There is no indication that this may have happened in the case of the
        breaches documented in this study. At the time of publication, no specific medical ethics
        principles on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> have been articulated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Council of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>.
        
          Limitations
          The study was conducted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> with a total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
          million [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. It is possible that these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, though chosen at random from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with
          tertiary care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, may differ significantly from others in terms of resources and
          training provided to health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. Although sampled systematically, it is
          possible that sampled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> may differ significantly
          from those that were not sampled in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> study <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
          Although the findings of this study can not be generalized to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> as a whole, it
          is likely that, depending on resources and training available to the health-care sector,
          the level of discriminatory behavior may differ in other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
          The apparent discrepancy between reported and observed behavior may indicate under- or
          overreporting of discriminatory behavior or may result from health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
          within the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> having observed the same incidents.
          While this study focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, it is possible that health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
          also engage in inappropriate behavior toward or breach the confidentiality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
          other conditions. The health-care system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> is underfunded and suffers from
          fundamental problems including material scarcity and inadequacies in infrastructure,
          which may contribute to this behavior overall [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,42,43</NUMEX>]. We did not specifically ask
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinicians</ENAMEX> to compare their treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> with that of other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Even if health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> engage in breaches of confidentiality and
          other inappropriate behavior toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with other conditions, however, it is likely
          that the consequences of such actions may be worse for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> than for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with other conditions.
          Despite efforts to ensure privacy during interviews, the lack of privacy, or concern
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> job status, may have resulted in an underreporting of discriminatory behavior
          and/or an overreporting of “correct” practices or attitudes. Although interviewers were
          careful to explain that there would be no material gain or penalty to the respondent or
          his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> from participation in the study, the responses may have been
          inaccurate if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> judged it in their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> or political interest to exaggerate
          or conceal certain behaviors.
        
        
          Conclusion
          Despite these limitations, the study documents a significant proportion of health
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> as reporting discriminatory attitudes and
          engaging in discriminatory and unethical behavior toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>,
          including denial of care, breach of confidentiality, and non-consented <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> testing. The
          breaches of confidentiality and testing for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> without informed consent reported by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> are in contravention of international principles of medical ethics [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>], and
          are also breaches of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> code of conduct [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>]. The study identifies
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> factors that may contribute to this behavior: lack of correct information and
          education about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and prevention of infection, lack of protective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> needed
          for the practice of universal precautions, lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> needed to care for and treat
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, and prevailing attitudes about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLWA</ENAMEX>. This study suggests that
          adequately addressing these discriminatory practices and attitudes requires targeted
          education of health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and provision of adequate resources to health-care
          facilities combined with instituting and enforcing anti-discrimination policies.
        
      
    
  
