
  
    
      
        
        The term ‚Äúparasite‚Äù derives from a classical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> word that was used to refer to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> who comes to dinner and doesn't leave‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúa <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> who had meals at public
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expense‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clitodemus</ENAMEX>, in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Athenaeus Grammaticus</ENAMEX> , ca. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">378</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>). In modern usage, it
        refers to eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> that range from single-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protozoa</ENAMEX> to complex
        multicellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX>. The diseases caused by these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> represent some of the world's
        greatest health problems.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Malaria</ENAMEX>, for example, currently affects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 500 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and causes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3,000</NUMEX>
        deaths a day‚Äîmostly in sub-Saharan <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Schistosomiasis, caused by 
        Schistosoma spp. (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood flukes</ENAMEX>), affects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 250 million</NUMEX> people
        in the tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">world</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>], and a recent meta-analysis showed that the disease is
        significantly associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anemia</ENAMEX>, chronic pain, diarrhea, exercise intolerance, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undernutrition</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Almost a billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are infected with the nematode parasites: 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ascaris</ENAMEX> (roundworm), 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancylostoma</ENAMEX> (hookworm), and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trichuris</ENAMEX> (whipworm) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Why then have so few effective drugs
        been produced against these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>?
        The answer lies primarily in the fact that these are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> affecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
        poor and living in poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> of the world. They represent little or no viable market for
        the pharmaceutical industry, especially given the market requirements of the recently
        merged pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>. Given this reality, how can imaginative and effective
        strategies be developed to meet this challenge?
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Strategies</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiparasitic Drug Design</ENAMEX>
        At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> that hosts one of the largest international gatherings of basic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and
        tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>, several symposia highlighted efforts in antiparasitic drug
        design. What was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> a fairly dark vision of the future, now appears
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brighter</ENAMEX>.
        Several nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are now operating that are dedicated to this unmet
        medical need, some collaborative interest exists in industry, and philanthropies have
        backed new initiatives. There are also a number of new academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortia</ENAMEX> with novel
        strategies to address issues of target discovery and preclinical development.
        
        Strategy one: Developing a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that has both a commercial market in the west
        and an application against a neglected parasitic disease. This strategy is exemplified
        by the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Tidwell</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North Carolina</ENAMEX>. With funding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Gates Foundation</ENAMEX>, more
        than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>) are working
        in collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immtech International</ENAMEX> to manage the ‚Äúcross-over‚Äù development of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antifungals</ENAMEX> produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immtech</ENAMEX> as potential <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trypanosomiasis</ENAMEX>, also known
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> sleeping sickness. This approach takes advantage of drug development of a class
        of compounds targeting a viable commercial market for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immtech</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fungal diseases</ENAMEX> of the
        developed world). At the same time, academic- and nonprofit-institute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are
        targeting these compounds in parallel toward an ‚Äúunprofitable‚Äù major health problem‚ÄîAfrican
        sleeping sickness. Specifically, an analog of the antifungal pentamidine has been optimized
        as a trypanocidal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and is in clinical trials in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>.
        
        Strategy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>: An academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> gets federal support for pharmacokinetic
        and toxicology studies. This <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> strategy is exemplified by work under the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Krogstad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulane University</ENAMEX>. Here, without an
        industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krogstad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> are using in-house chemistry and computational
        assistance to modify chloroquine analogs in an effort to overcome the problem of
        chloroquine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> treatment. Their main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in this effort is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pharmacokinetic</ENAMEX> and toxicology studies by virtue of pre-existing contracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRI</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX> (an independent nonprofit research-and-development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Menlo</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> compound from this series is entering
        clinical trials.
        
        Strategy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>: An academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> uses a philanthropic gift to woo expertise
        from industry and build infrastructure for preclinical drug development. This third
        strategy is represented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> that I direct, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandler Center for Basic Research</ENAMEX>
        philanthropic support was used to build infrastructure for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>
        that mimics what might be found in a small- to medium-sized pharmaceutical company
        organized to carry out preclinical drug discovery and development. These core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>
        include computational support for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> discovery and chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> selection, X-ray
        crystallography, drug metabolism and toxicology <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, animal models of parasitic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, high-throughput screening, and synthetic chemistry.
        Initial work at this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> focused on a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug lead</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Chagas disease</ENAMEX> and was supported
        by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropical Disease Research Unit Program</ENAMEX> project grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allergy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Infectious Diseases</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>, now a drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, was originally
        synthesized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Palmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khepri Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>) as part of an industry
        search for anti-inflammatory and anticancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> focusing on cysteine proteases.
        Validation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> as an antiparasitic was carried out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rodent</ENAMEX> models of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and, next, supported, as in the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>, by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Development and Surveillance Group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> initially handed over further
        development of a drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for OneWorld Health</ENAMEX> (iOWH), one of the
        nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that has sprung up to meet ‚Äúdownstream‚Äù drug development needs for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">neglected diseases</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sidebar</ENAMEX>). iOWH facilitated tests of drug safety, minimum effective
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dose</ENAMEX>, and a formulation for large-scale <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Manufacturing Practice</ENAMEX> manufacture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drugs</ENAMEX>
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neglected Diseases Initiative</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dndi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>) has now become the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> for
        further development [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sandler Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> itself is now focusing on completing
        preclinical development of similar drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> targeting homologous enzymes in several
        other major global pathogens.
        There is another way in which this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> strategy represents a radical departure from
        the usual research paradigm of academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High-Throughput Screening Center</ENAMEX> has
        been established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sandler Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> upon the expertise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drs. Kip</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Williams</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>), who
        brought an industrial perspective to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. A recently completed screen used an
        assay that allowed robotic screening of a library of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of FDA-approved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and
        natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> for activity against 
        Trypanosoma brucei , the parasite that causes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> sleeping
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sickness</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhit list‚Äù</ENAMEX> from this screen is being made available on a Web site
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://itsa.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ucsf</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">edu/~schisto/fruit.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>) for those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> (such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neglected Diseases Initiative</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>], iOWH, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX>) whose missions
        include licensing, manufacture, and distribution. Similar screens are being set up for
        leishmaniasis, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Chagas disease</ENAMEX>, schistosomiasis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Drug Pipeline</ENAMEX>
        The success of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> unusual strategies, all originating within academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>,
        provides a new drug pipeline for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">parasitic diseases</ENAMEX> with no market value for the
        pharmaceutical industry (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The future is likely to see a number of academic or
        academic‚Äìindustrial collaborations supporting preclinical development in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortia</ENAMEX> like
        those described above.
        This prediction was already borne out at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2005</TIMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúDrug Development</ENAMEX> for
        Diseases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protozoa</ENAMEX>,‚Äù sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keystone Symposia</ENAMEX>. In the short time since the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene</ENAMEX> meeting, it has become clear that more
        academic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> are encouraged to pursue drug discovery and development avenues
        beyond research traditionally thought of as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX>. New <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortia</ENAMEX> modeled after the three
        described above are now functional or in late planning stages at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Dundee</ENAMEX>. In
        addition, significant help from some large pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, notably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tr√</ENAMEX>©s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cantos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GlaxoSmithKline</ENAMEX>, has fueled focused academic- and
        nonprofit-organization drug development efforts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drugs</ENAMEX>
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neglected Diseases Initiative</ENAMEX>, iOWH, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicines for Malaria Venture</ENAMEX>) are
        actively working to support various stages of the drug-development <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX>. Their efforts
        are particularly key to the ‚Äúdownstream‚Äù elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> manufacture and clinical
        trials.
        Finally, philanthropic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Gates Foundation</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandler Family Supporting Foundation</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison Foundation</ENAMEX> have contributed to these
        endeavors. Their continued support, and the recruitment of other interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, will
        be crucial to maintaining the momentum engendered by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> projects outlined here.
        
          Editorial Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PloS</ENAMEX> has received financial support in the form of a grant
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandler Family Supporting Foundation</ENAMEX>.
        
      
    
  
