
  
    
      
        
        As an intern, I took care of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco General</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX>, and so I grew up with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of my medical career. We struggled
        through the confusion about what was making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so sick, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each new day</TIMEX> brought a new
        discovery about the disease and its consequences. I went through that evolutionary process
        along with everybody else, and it shaped me in many profound ways. Before long, I
        recognized that this wasn't a disease of ‚Äúthose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over there.‚Äù This was a disease that
        could strike anyone, anytime. And as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, we had to adjust our thinking about our
        own vulnerability to occupational risk, and to emphasize prevention, because there wasn't
        going to be a cure for a long, long while. And not only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> had to rethink
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">things‚ÄîAIDS</ENAMEX> has reshaped society's very notions of the most basic human behaviors.
        I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, early in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic there. We knew then where that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">epidemic</ENAMEX> was going to go, absent an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> or cure, but few of us could have
        imagined that it would evolve so quickly without an end in sight. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> have achieved a huge amount in tackling <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, the
        epidemic is far from being under control on that continent and is spreading through other
        parts of the world with alarming speed.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis of Human Resources</ENAMEX>
        The theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International AIDS Conference</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> was ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ÄúAccess for All</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>, it has become increasingly apparent that a critical component of
        assuring access to care and treatment is human capital. Like fiscal capital, human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> are essential to ending the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS pandemic</ENAMEX>. I visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Health</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Thompson</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>, and we saw
        evidence of this critical need in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we visited. The miracles of modern science
        are meaningless without systems and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to deliver them to those in need.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> estimates that of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> worldwide infected
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 million</NUMEX> need immediate, life-sustaining antiretroviral therapy. Fewer than
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have access to such treatment (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,2</NUMEX>].
        There are too few skilled health care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to provide reliable delivery and
        administration of these life-saving therapies. According to a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Medicine</ENAMEX>
        health care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> is actually shrinking as they are lured to
        developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> by better pay and professional opportunities (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>) [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,3</NUMEX>]. Reversing
        this brain drain is essential over the long-term, as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> treatment and care will be
        required for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. In the short-term, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Medicine</ENAMEX> called for expanded
        efforts ‚Äúto bring qualified volunteer initiative medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> into both urban and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> areas to support prevention, care, and training programs‚Äù [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. I could not agree more
        that addressing the human resource needs will be essential as we move forward‚Äîand not just
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> programs, but for all aspects of public health and health care.
        It has now been shown, beyond any doubt, that even in resource-poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with the
        most basic health infrastructure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get the same benefit from treatment and prevention
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX> as those in the rich world [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. In fact, surveys in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kampala</ENAMEX>,
        Khayelitsha, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX> found rates of adherence to antiretroviral therapy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì94%</NUMEX>,
        compared with estimates of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> in developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,6,7</NUMEX>].
      
      
        When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Have Seen the Faces</ENAMEX>
        We hear the numbers‚Äîthe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> upon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> infected‚Äîand we grow numb. That is why we
        must go to the front lines‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and communities‚Äîand start focusing on each
        individual living with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>. I was at the dedication of an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>. It was
        raining, and we were waiting outside with our umbrellas. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in front of me
        turned around and leaned her head against my belly and said, ‚ÄúCould you take me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>?
        I need <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.‚Äù If you take that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s face and multiply it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand times‚</NUMEX>Äîthat is the
        memory I bring home from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and their asking, ‚ÄúWhy are so
        many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> dying? Why are we dying?‚Äù
        remote areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> where there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and it is impossible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come
        into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> centers to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> testing and other services. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>
        are working with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ugandans</ENAMEX> and community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in that area to deliver
        antiretroviral therapy. Some may think that the difficulties of delivering antiretroviral
        therapy into such a remote area are overwhelming‚Äîand some may question whether this is a
        sustainable intervention. But once you see firsthand what miracles are possible, your world
        view changes almost <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>.
        What we saw was the success of a wonderful home-based treatment and care program for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have access through other means. And when I say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚Äúhome</ENAMEX>-based care,‚Äù picture
        a hut without running <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or electricity, where only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX> are available to deliver
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step of the program is to provide clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coliforms</ENAMEX> and other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathogens</ENAMEX> in the water supply for the household are removed through an inexpensive water
        vessel fitted with a filter and through a chlorination process. In addition, a
        cotrimoxazole tablet is given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, which, in one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s words, changed his life
        because he began to feel well almost immediately. Not only do the cotrimoxazole prophylaxis
        and the water treatment improve diarrheal illness, but malarial parasitemia also drops. So
        that is a very positive, unexpected consequence of just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very simple and inexpensive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> also have tuberculosis and are put on
        tuberculosis therapy in addition to cotrimoxazole. As a result, they begin to feel better
        even before they begin antiretroviral therapy.
        We spent time with one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>-based care program. As she began to
        participate in these programs, tests became available to measure her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> count. She
        explained to me what her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> count was, what it meant, and how it improved when she started
        the cotrimoxazole and tuberculosis therapy. She had begun taking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> antiretroviral drugs
        and held up her pill box to explain her regimen in detail. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every week</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX> health aide
        delivered her supply of pills on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> and monitored her adherence to the
        treatment. Not only was she extremely reliable in taking her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>, but she also knew
        more about them and their side effects than most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> I treated at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
        General. She was also an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> prevention. I asked her, ‚ÄúWhat do you do to protect
        your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> from this infection?‚Äù She replied, ‚ÄúEvery day I take them by the
        hand, and I go out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and I say, ‚ÄòDo you see that mound of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>? That is your
        father‚Äôs grave. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> acquired this fatal infection through sex. Be careful.'‚Äù And
        then she talks to them about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúABCs‚Äù (‚ÄúA‚Äù</ENAMEX> for abstinence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúB‚Äù</ENAMEX> for being faithful, ‚ÄúC‚Äù
        for condoms).
        So when you see a story like that unfold in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, it's impossible not to
        be hopeful. And yet, it's also very sobering because we are reminded of our responsibility.
        The question is not what the international health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is accomplishing in these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> now, but what we could accomplish if we joined together to really fight this war
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. Such a story also inspires hope because you can see the multiplier effect that
        comes from taking on one problem and can see the way that effort can expand to encompass
        and address a much greater set of problems.
      
      
        Beyond ABCs‚ÄîDiagnosis and Responsibility
        When we think about successful prevention <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúABC‚Äù</ENAMEX> certainly stands out
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. However, at this point in the epidemic curve, other letters must also be considered.
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> transmission is accounted for by infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having risky sex with uninfected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Both in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, studies show that most infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> engaging in
        risky sex are unaware of their infection status, and that when their infection is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosed</ENAMEX>, they usually take steps to protect the others with whom they are having contact
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,10,11,12</NUMEX>]. So let's add the letter ‚ÄúD‚Äù for diagnosis. In fact, improving efforts to help
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose risk avoidance and to diagnose those who are already infected is the
        cornerstone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>'s new domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> prevention strategy. Diagnosis is extremely
        important in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, especially where the number of discordant
        couples‚Äîwhere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> is infected and the other is not‚Äîis high. Sadly, many couples
        ‚Äúbeing faithful‚Äù now do not realize that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> is already infected and are not being
        reached with diagnostic testing programs. So ‚ÄúABCD‚Äù is a concept that I would like to put
        out on the table as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for thought. Of course, there is another letter that we need to
        stress: the letter ‚ÄúR,‚Äù for responsibility: personal sexual responsibility is a critical
        component of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> prevention. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> become infected after being raped by men
        or because their social circumstances rob them of the power to refuse sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> must be held
        accountable for greater sexual responsibility and for ending sexual violence and
        degradation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> prevention programs need to emphasize responsibility,
        but not lose sight of the fact that responsibility can be practiced only with personal
        autonomy, which many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> simply do not have.
      
      
        Expanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Team to Meet the Needs</ENAMEX>
        The innovative programs and ideas emerging in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> can change the picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
        epidemic. The purchase of antiretroviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> is not the big challenge.
        Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> will improve in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. The real challenges are delivering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in a safe
        and effective way, monitoring therapy, and sustaining the pipeline of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> so that ongoing
        treatment can be guaranteed. In the example of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>-based program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, we have
        seen that these challenges can be overcome. Expanding access to prevention, care, and
        treatment services isn't going to be easy, but it is certainly possible. It will take
        unprecedented commitment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the public sector, the private sector, faith
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, and community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and perhaps most importantly, individual
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> who make up their minds to contribute in any way they can.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Peace Corps</ENAMEX> announced that it was activating programs in some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic, but this is
        just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of many steps that are being taken. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s Emergency Plan for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
        Relief will provide <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 billion</NUMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $10 billion</NUMEX> in new funds, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over five years</TIMEX>
        for international <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> assistance [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>], and I am part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that is charged with
        making this plan happen. I look forward to learning from others in the global health
        community how we can best expand our impact and collectively find a way to support the
        delivery of prevention messages and life-saving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> to everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa‚</ENAMEX>Äîand
        especially to that little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> who touched my heart.
      
    
  
