
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shah Ebrahim</ENAMEX> says, in his answer to my statement in our debate [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>], that plaque is so
        common that it makes sense to treat only those likely to have an acute event in the near
        future. Not everyone has a heart attack but everyone ages, nor can we be sure who will be
        lucky as they age and who will not. Anyone with a low-density lipoprotein level above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/dl</ENAMEX> is at risk [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Narrowing of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arteries</ENAMEX> must certainly contribute to health decline in
        aging. He says that most plaque is stable and does not rupture. The half-million <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
        have a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who have a stroke in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> alone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> would disagree. Waiting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> more for further studies will
        not help all those now succumbing to the disease, as long as all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> have
        already been well vetted, as they have been. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebrahim</ENAMEX>'s statement that “most [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plaques</ENAMEX>] are
        stable and unlikely to rupture” is based on his own study published in 
        Stroke [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has no data relating to how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> found
        to have increased intima-media wall thickness (IMT) or plaque actually had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>. It did find that intimal-wall changes were highly associated with ischemic heart
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>.
        It is correct that risk factors can predict <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> to some degree,
        though I have many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for whom that approach fails while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMT</ENAMEX> detects the risk
        otherwise missed. However, risk factor analysis is not enough. Changes in smoking, diet,
        weight, blood pressure, and such are all targets for treatment, but how do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> know
        whether they have controlled them adequately? If IMT increases, more control is required.
        If IMT stabilizes or reverses a little, then it means that control is at goal. Family
        history of premature coronary artery <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> is a major but underused risk factor. The
        causative factors have not yet been elucidated by research, so we do not know what the
        goals are. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMT</ENAMEX> provides a highly satisfactory parameter by which to judge the
        effectiveness of treatment in familial coronary artery disease: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMT</ENAMEX> stabilization and
        reversal are good, whereas progression is bad and requires more intensive measures.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemiology</ENAMEX> and public-health planning correctly look at policies to apply to large
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. However, the practice of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, accomplished in the
        face-to-face doctor–patient relationship. Policy can be useful as a resource, but each
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> should have the maximum individualized care and access that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> can provide.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> should be able to make their own informed choices and not be dictated to by
        policies meant for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. Shouldn't everyone with increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMT</ENAMEX> at least be informed of
        the options available to limit it rather than waiting until acute events or advanced
        narrowing occur? It would be best to start a healthy lifestyle from birth, but fortunately
        by adulthood there is still time to make an enormous difference in practical terms if we
        take action at the stage when intimal widening is detectable with the highly sensitive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ultrasound</ENAMEX> described in my original viewpoint [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>].
      
    
  
