
  
    
      
        
        Despite the significant progress in increasing our understanding of the immune
        mechanisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple sclerosis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>), in improving clinical classification and brain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imaging</ENAMEX>, and in developing new treatments, the factors that determine the course of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> are mostly unknown [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Currently, it is nearly impossible to predict the course of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>, its severity in terms of disability progression, or when a relapse will happen.
        The most commonly used disease-modifying therapies are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">interferon β</ENAMEX> (IFNβ) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] and
        glatiramer acetate [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,3</NUMEX>]. Despite initial excitement, these therapies have beneficial
        effects in some, but not all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,3</NUMEX>]. Because of the potential favorable effects of
        these therapies, it has been suggested that they should be initiated as early as possible
        to maximize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neuroprotection</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. Additionally, it has been recommended that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> should
        be monitored closely to determine whether and when it is necessary to modify treatment in
        order to maximize the benefit [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. The recommended monitoring is based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rate of
        relapses, neurological deterioration, and evidence of disease activity on brain magnetic
        resonance imaging scans. However, given the destructive nature of the disease, if we rely
        solely on clinical or radiological manifestations (such as a relapse or a new lesion on a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scan</ENAMEX>) to determine a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s response to therapy, we will probably be responding too
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX>.
      
      
        Gene <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Expression Patterns in Affected Organs</ENAMEX>
        The diagnosis and management of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> could be transformed thanks to the completion of
        the human genome project, the availability of sequence information for nearly every gene,
        and the advent of novel high throughput technologies (microarrays—see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glossary</ENAMEX>) that allow
        parallel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">profiling of thousands</NUMEX> of genes. By definition, nearly every aspect of a disease
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenotype</ENAMEX> should be represented in gene expression signatures of multiple genes in the
        affected organ. Indeed, studies that analyze affected tissues (mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>) clearly
        show that it is possible to predict prognosis, to identify new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, and
        potentially to determine response to therapy [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,7,8</NUMEX>].
        In diseases that do not require tissue resection for diagnosis or therapy, it is rare to
        obtain tissues for analysis. This problem is even more pronounced in diseases like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>, in
        which the target organ is the very inaccessible brain and spinal cord. Despite these
        limitations, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> used microarrays to analyze brain tissues obtained posthumously
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had MS and identified genes that characterized either acute or chronic
        lesions [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,10,11</NUMEX>]. However, although these studies identified some potential genes that may
        be involved in the local pathogenesis of the disease, they did not produce any information
        that could be used for identifying biomarkers associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> activity.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diagnostic Peripheral Blood Mononuclear Cell Gene Expression Signatures</ENAMEX>
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MS</ENAMEX>, looking for markers of disease activity in the much more accessible peripheral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> does not require a significant leap of faith. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> is an autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, and it is
        possible that some of the cells involved in the pathogenesis of the disease will be found
        in the bloodstream. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abnormal T</ENAMEX> cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> have repeatedly been observed in the
        peripheral blood of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,13,14</NUMEX>]. While these results supported looking at
        the easily accessible peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) for potential markers that
        reflect the disease, some doubts persisted. These revolved around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very strong
        arguments. The first argument was that if the signal comes from a minority of the cells
        within the bloodstream it will be too low to be detected. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> was that interpersonal
        variability, added to the inherent noisy nature of gene expression data, will make the data
        impossible to reproduce.
        Fortunately, recent observations suggest that these doubts are unfounded. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bomprezzi et</ENAMEX>
        al. [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>] determined that gene expression patterns can distinguish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MS</ENAMEX> from
        controls and suggested that at least some of the differences identified were derived from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activated T</ENAMEX> cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Achiron et al.</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] analyzed the expression of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in patients
        with relapsing–remitting MS. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX> expression patterns clearly distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> from controls as well as relapse from remission. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandel et al.</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>] compared patients
        with systemic lupus erythematosus and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>, and identified a common autoimmunity signature as
        well as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>-specific gene expression signatures. Interestingly, similar findings were
        recently described for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pulmonary arterial hypertension</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>].
      
      
        Could <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PBMC Gene Expression Signatures Be Used for Predicting Response to</ENAMEX>
        Therapy?
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weinstock-Guttman et al.</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>] analyzed the acute transcriptional response of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>
        in peripheral blood lymphocytes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNβ</ENAMEX>. They identified increases in known
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon</ENAMEX>-inducible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, and in genes involved in antiviral activity and interferon
        signaling. Using complementary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (cDNA) arrays, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sturzebecher et al.</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>] identified gene
        expression signatures that distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNβ</ENAMEX> responders from nonresponders.
        And now, in a new study published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology , Baranzini et al.</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>] provide compelling evidence that
        these PBMC gene expression signatures can be used to predict response to therapy (Figure
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). They studied the expression of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> selected for their presumed biological function
        in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>, followed up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two years</TIMEX> after initiation of IFNβ
        therapy. Instead of using microarrays that carry probes for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of genes, they chose
        to use real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>. This method is highly sensitive, specific, and reproducible across
        different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>. It is often used to verify microarray findings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baranzini et</ENAMEX> al.
        identified MX1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interferon-inducible protein p78</ENAMEX>), a known interferon-inducible gene, as
        the marker of treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNβ</ENAMEX>. They did not find overall differences between responders
        and nonresponders, but they did, using supervised classification methods, identify triplets
        of genes that distinguish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNβ</ENAMEX> responders and nonresponders.
        Interestingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> did not perform that well, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
        genes in a triplet were required for the highest accuracy (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80%–90%</NUMEX>). The minimal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">combinatorial</ENAMEX> number of genes that contains the most predictive information is not
        available since combinations of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> were not performed. Although the
        results were not tested on an independent dataset, as is frequently requested [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>], the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> applied an array of cross-validation strategies that convincingly suggested that
        the identified predictive signal was robust.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Implications of the Study</ENAMEX>
        What could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baranzini</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' findings mean? Clearly, the most obvious conclusion
        is that the lack of response did not result from the deactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNβ</ENAMEX>. The effect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNβ</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MX1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IFNAr1</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STAT2</ENAMEX> was observed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, suggesting that
        the response did not depend on IFNβ bioavailability. Considering that PBMCs represent an
        admixture of multiple cell types, the most plausible explanation is a simple lack of shift
        in subcellular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.
        However, the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baranzini</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' study lies not in its mechanistic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insights</ENAMEX>, but in its clinical relevance. The careful design of the experiment, the use of
        reproducible real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PCR</ENAMEX> instead of microarrays, the meticulous analysis, and the
        previous observations [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,16,17,19,20</NUMEX>] support the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMCs</ENAMEX> express clinically
        relevant gene expression signatures in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MS</ENAMEX> and probably in other organ-confined <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. To
        further prove this notion will require a significant investment in large studies that
        prospectively test the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> of these signatures in guiding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of MS. Only
        when direct evidence shows that therapy guided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMCs</ENAMEX> improves
        patient outcome will PBMC gene expression patterns take their place as biomarkers at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">center</ENAMEX> stage of monitoring MS progression and response to therapy.
      
    
  
