
  
    
      
        
        Medicine might not be the oldest profession, but the practice and the teaching of it
        certainly stretch far back into antiquity. In the developed world, medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are now
        thriving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> whose main aim remains to turn out sufficient numbers of well-trained
        medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>. But alongside this primary purpose, medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have become
        centers of excellence for research also, mostly basic scientific research. Certainly the
        medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at San</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSF)‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> closest to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS</ENAMEX> editorial offices‚Äîhave large research
        programs.
        Getting the balance right between understanding the research that will drive future
        medical discoveries, and providing training in clinical practice is obviously crucial in
        training <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. However, follow-up studies of those who graduate suggest that
        medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> may not be producing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who are happy with the profession, or who fit
        all the needs of medical services <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> striking observations
        came out of recent surveys. One is the difficulty in recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who want to become
        general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>, the primary care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who form the backbone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> health
        service. Whereas in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1980s 40</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì50%</NUMEX> of the qualifiers intended to enter general
        practice, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> the proportion was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20%‚Äì26%</NUMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">BMJ 326</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">194‚Äì195</ENAMEX>). But even more
        disturbing is the substantial proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in the same surveys who indicated that
        they regularly consider leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> altogether. Contrast these results with those of a
        survey from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, where the survival of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> was the most urgent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. From a
        cohort of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Makere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> had
        died over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following 20 years</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">BMJ 329</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">600‚Äì601</ENAMEX>). The most important cause of death was
        presumed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. But all of the surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> were in some form of medical
        work.
        What these figures show perhaps more than anything is the difficulties of generalizing
        about what are the top priorities for medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> across the globe. To provide a place
        for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to debate the issues that matter to them, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> is launching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Forum</ENAMEX>, a new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> section
        written by medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. An international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> has been elected
        that will help shape the content of this new section. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Forum</ENAMEX> recognizes the
        vital role that medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have in guiding the future of the medical profession.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Forum</ENAMEX> essay brings together <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> continents: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohit Singla</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Medical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>. They
        lay out some of their concerns, such as the need for medical education to distance itself
        from the pharmaceutical industry and the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> worldwide having unfettered
        access to the medical literature. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> also ask questions about their training,
        commenting that the ‚Äúreductionistic logic of medical education offers only false comfort,
        and only to those who content themselves with pathways and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        Perhaps surprisingly, this opinion is not far away from that of an established academic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinician</ENAMEX> and editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rees</ENAMEX>. In another essay in this issue, Rees
        similarly questions the overemphasis on basic research in medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, posing the
        question, ‚Äúwhy are our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> not fit for the purpose of improving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>'
        health?‚Äù
        Not an easy question to answer, but one that might also be relevant to the question of
        what a medical journal, especially one that wants to engage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, should publish.
        Should we follow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rees</ENAMEX>'s advice on what the composition of a medical school curriculum
        should be and have <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">no more than 20%</NUMEX> of our articles devoted to basic scientific research as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>? In this issue the balance of our research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> comes close to this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> paper on the differentiation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-producing cells from human
        neural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progenitors</ENAMEX>, and other papers throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> on topics as diverse as climate
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dengue fever</ENAMEX>, treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV genotypes</ENAMEX>, prescription practices, counterfeit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buruli</ENAMEX> ulcer, and health and human rights. But, perhaps like the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, we
        are not paying enough attention to other topics <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rees</ENAMEX> points out as important‚Äîoperations
        research, decision-making, informatics, and economics.
        In his lightning trip through medicine, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood and Guts: A Short History of Medicine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. W. Norton</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>), the
        late medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Porter</ENAMEX> wrote that ‚Äúthe biomedical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> can be myopic, searching
        ever more microscopically for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> but often omitting the wider picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>,
        environments and health.‚Äù In his description of the differing opinions on the role in 19th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of the new practice of laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, it becomes clear that
        the debate over what should be taught and what matters to medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> might not be
        new, but it is clearly as important as ever.
      
    
  
