
  
    
      
        
        
        Streptococcus pneumoniae is a common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX> that is present
        in the nasopharynx of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, where it causes no harm to its carrier
        but can be transmitted to others. If it moves beyond the nasopharynx, however, it can cause
        ear infections or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">invasive disease</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX> or meningitis. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Invasive disease</ENAMEX> from
        this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> occurs especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the elderly, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with weakened
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> systems.
        The protective effect of antibodies against bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX> has been appreciated
        since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, when it was shown that serum therapy‚Äîthe transfer of serum from an
        immunized animal to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with acute disease caused by the same bacterial strain‚Äîcould
        reduce mortality from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumococcal pneumonia</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. Subsequent development of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>
        based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX>'s polysaccharide capsule, which could protect against infection,
        confirmed that an endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> response can provide protection against invasive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>.
        One challenge for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> development has been the existence of many different serotypes
        (the same species of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> but with different composition of the polysaccharide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capsule</ENAMEX>). As protection usually doesn't extend to different serotypes, vaccination with
        capsule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> from different serotypes is necessary to ensure broad protection. Such
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> have been shown to be efficient and safe. They are now recommended in many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> and toddlers, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65‚</NUMEX>Äîthe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">invasive disease</ENAMEX> is most common‚Äîand for others who are at increased risk of pneumococcal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with heart, kidney, liver, or lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, or who have had a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">splenectomy</ENAMEX>).
        Even without vaccination, however, most exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> will never get invasive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. Instead, they develop natural immunity against the different serotypes, though
        this immunity gradually declines with old age. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Lipsitch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> wanted to
        understand the immunological basis of this natural immunity, and specifically whether it
        was due to anticapsular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>.
        If protection from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">invasive disease</ENAMEX> is due to acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anticapsular antibodies</ENAMEX> against
        each of the pneumococcal serotypes, they argued, this would lead to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> predictions about
        the age distribution of disease caused by the different serotypes in the non-vaccinated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. First, for serotypes that are more common and therefore encountered earlier in
        life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should develop immunity more quickly, causing disease from these types to
        drop off earlier in life than disease from the less common types. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, protection
        against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">invasive disease</ENAMEX> from a particular serotype should coincide with the acquisition of
        antibodies against that serotype, on both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> level.
        Neither prediction was borne out by the actual data the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> analyzed, suggesting
        that there is more to natural immunity against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumococcal disease</ENAMEX> than just anticapsular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. The study doesn't demonstrate what the additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> are, but
        additional research might not just teach us about our immune system but also provide clues
        for further vaccine development. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> say, ‚ÄúA better understanding of the
        mechanisms that underlie natural immunity to pneumococcus could pave the way for the
        development of more effective, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>-specific pneumococcal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
      
    
  
