
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Advances in transplant-based therapy for type 1 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mellitus</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] and a dearth of
        cadaveric pancreatic islets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langerhans</ENAMEX> have focused interest on developing renewable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of transplant-ready islet-replacement tissues. Pancreatic islets derive from
        embryonic endoderm, but display features of neurons, including a shared set of
        cell-autonomous developmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. Islets are the principal source of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, but in some invertebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, such as 
        Drosophila, brain neurons are the main source of circulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,4</NUMEX>]. The similarities between islet cells and neurons are further underscored by the
        demonstration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin gene transcription</ENAMEX> in the vertebrate brain [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>], although it
        remains unclear whether these vertebrate neurons produce or secrete <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin protein</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>].
        Moreover, recent studies also suggest that in some settings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> pancreatic epithelial
        cells can engender neuron-like cells [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,8</NUMEX>]. These and other findings [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] suggest that
        common, ancient developmental programs may govern the differentiation of islet cells and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurons</ENAMEX>. Methods promoting neural differentiation by embryonic stem (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ES</ENAMEX>) cells have been
        adapted [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,10,11,12,13</NUMEX>] to derive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (IPCs), but it remains unclear
        whether such <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPCs</ENAMEX> were derived from neural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progenitors</ENAMEX>, or whether a neural-based strategy
        can generate transplantable human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPCs</ENAMEX>.
        Neural cells derive from multipotent progenitor cells, and recently, clonal human neural
        progenitor cells that remained multipotent and karyotypically stable through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 15</NUMEX>
        passages were purified by flow-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">cytometry</ENAMEX>-based methods [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]. The availability of human
        neural progenitor cells allowed us to investigate whether inductive signals involved in
        normal pathways of islet development could direct these neural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progenitors</ENAMEX> to develop into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX>-responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>. Here we describe experimental strategies for developing IPCs
        directly from human neural stem cells.
      
      
        Methods
        All studies were performed in accordance with appropriate human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>' approval
        according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University Institutional Review Board</ENAMEX> guidelines.
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Lines</ENAMEX> and Culture Conditions
          The human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neurosphere</ENAMEX> (NS) cell lines (line numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1651, 1664</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1673</TIMEX>) were
          established following enrichment for AC133
          + cells, as previously described [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>], although none of the cell lines
          was expanded from a single cell, and they are therefore not clonal. The different cell
          lines were from distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and karyotypically normal. They gave comparable results,
          but line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1664</TIMEX> produced less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> by stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> in our protocol than the other cell lines.
          Following cell thaw, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSs</ENAMEX> were expanded in suspension culture, and in each case were used
          between passages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 and 7</NUMEX>. Undifferentiated human NS cells (stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) were cultured and
          expanded in medium containing <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>-VIVO15 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cambrex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walkersville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>),
          N2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supplement</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Œºg/ml</ENAMEX> heparin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          ng/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ml leukemia</ENAMEX> inhibitory factor (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon, Temecula</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX> epidermal growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>),
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml fibroblast growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>), and they were frozen after
          enzymatic dissociation. At stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, we thawed and cultured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells in medium made from a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1</ENAMEX> mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>-free DMEM
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-12</ENAMEX> medium (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> bovine serum albumin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">N2 supplement</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Œºg/ml heparin, 10 ng/ml leukemia</ENAMEX>
          inhibitory factor, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml epidermal growth factor, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml fibroblast growth
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-2</ENAMEX>. The final concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> in stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 mM.</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cultures</ENAMEX> were fed
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 2</TIMEX> wk. Cells formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSs</ENAMEX> during stages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 and 2</TIMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 wk</TIMEX>, we transferred
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40‚Äì80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NSs</ENAMEX> containing a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 2‚Äì4</NUMEX> √ó <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells to single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> in plates coated with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.005%</NUMEX> poly-L-ornithine
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 Œºg/</ENAMEX>ml fibronectin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). These were cultured for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 wk</NUMEX> (stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) in a
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:1</TIMEX> mixture of low-glucose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-12</ENAMEX> media containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 mg/l apo-transferrin</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">288 mg/l glucose, 73 mg/l</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L -glutamine</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.69</NUMEX> g/l sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bicarbonate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">25 Œºg/ml bovine insulin</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 ŒºM</NUMEX> putrescine, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> nM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">selenite</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">penicillin/streptomycin.</ENAMEX> Stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> medium was supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Œ</NUMEX>ºM all-
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trans</ENAMEX> retinoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and had a final glucose concentration
          of either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> mM. At stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>, cells were cultured in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">N2</NUMEX> medium [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>] supplemented with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM nicotinamide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM insulin-like growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>) for
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">d. Stage</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> medium included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17.3</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>. During stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 and 4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was
          changed every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX>. To examine the effect of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sonic hedgehog</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shh</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>),
          we added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse Shh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> every other day during stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>. To quantify neurite
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outgrowths per cluster</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shh</ENAMEX>-treated or control stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> IPC clusters were photographed
          under light microscopy, and digitized images were used to score neurites. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> are
          presented as the average ¬± the standard error of the mean. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-tailed 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> tests were conducted to determine statistical significance.
        
        
          RT-PCR
          Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was prepared by using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIZOL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RQ1</ENAMEX> RNase-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). For cDNA synthesis, random sequence primers were used
          to prime reverse transcription reactions and synthesis was carried out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thermoscript</ENAMEX> RT
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> were performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Platinum</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taq High Fidelity DNA Polymerase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). GAPDH expression was
          used to normalize input template cDNA to analyze relative gene expression. Primer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> and gene accession numbers are listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. To confirm their identity,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA products</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reactions were excised, cloned, and sequenced.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunohistochemistry</ENAMEX> and Morphometry
          Cell clusters were fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde, embedded in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HistoGel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard-Allan</ENAMEX>
          Scientific, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kalamazoo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), and then embedded in paraffin. We
          performed immunohistochemistry on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-Œºm tissue sections. We used primary antibodies at the
          following dilutions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guinea pig</ENAMEX> anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:200</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linco Research</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Charles</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse anti-Œ≤</ENAMEX>-tubulin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:500</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>); rabbit anti-C-peptide,
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:100</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linco Research</ENAMEX>); mouse anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nestin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:200</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon</ENAMEX>); mouse anti<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Ki67</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:100</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novocastra, Newcastle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>); rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">anti‚Äìcleaved caspase-3, 1:200</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Signaling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>); rabbit anti-glucagon, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:200</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dako</ENAMEX>,
          Carpinteria, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>); rabbit anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Glut-2</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:200</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>); mouse anti-proinsulin, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:500</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O. Madsen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hagedorn, Gentofte</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>); mouse anti-glucokinase, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:200</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Newgard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>); mouse anti-GFAP, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,000</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dako</ENAMEX>); mouse anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">MAP2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:500</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>); and rabbit anti<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Olig2</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,000</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Takebayashi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute for</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physiological Sciences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okazaki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>). Confocal immunofluorescence microscopy with an
          optical slice thickness of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.6 Œ</NUMEX>ºm was performed on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MRC1000</TIMEX>.
          Cell counting and point-counting morphometry were performed using standard
          morphometric techniques [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. To obtain representative results, all quantification of
          immunostaining was performed by counting numbers of positive-stained cells and dividing
          by the area of total tissues using a standard <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 √ó 10</NUMEX> microscope grid. For quantification
          of cells expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ki67</TIMEX>, Œ≤-tubulin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, or
          C-peptide, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NS-</ENAMEX>derived cell clusters were fixed, and sectioned to generate <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-Œºm-</NUMEX>thick
          tissue sections. Appropriately stained cells were counted in a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> random
          microscopic fields obtained from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least ten</NUMEX> cell clusters per condition.
        
        
          In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Situ</ENAMEX> Hybridization
          We used human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin cDNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">320 bp</ENAMEX>) cloned in plasmid <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pCR4-TOPO</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) as a
          template for in vitro transcription to produce riboprobes with a digoxigenin-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> labeling
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), performed hybridization with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> cluster
          sections as described [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>], and used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIG Nucleic Acid Detection Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>,
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Insulin C-Peptide Quantification</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Vitro Insulin Secretion</ENAMEX> Assay
          At each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX> or IPC clusters were handpicked, washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogenized</ENAMEX>; then intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptide</ENAMEX> content was measured with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-peptide ELISA</ENAMEX> kit
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Laboratory Products Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Stage 4</ENAMEX>
          IPC clusters were cultured in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.8</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> newborn calf serum (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 2‚Äì3</NUMEX> h. At the
          end of these washes, no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> was detectable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wash supernatant</ENAMEX> using an ELISA kit
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Laboratory Products Company</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifty</ENAMEX> IPC clusters were handpicked, transferred
          to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well plate, and incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 h at 37 ¬∞C</NUMEX> in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.8</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM sucrose. Supernatants were then harvested for enzyme-linked
          immunosorption assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ELISA)‚Äìbased</ENAMEX> quantification of released <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC Transplantation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physiologic Tests</ENAMEX>
          All animal studies were performed in accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University Animal Care</ENAMEX>
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Use Guidelines</ENAMEX>. Under general anesthesia, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9- to 10-wk</NUMEX>-old male NOD 
          scid <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bar Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>) were engrafted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> handpicked IPC clusters in the right and left
          subcapsular renal space (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> IPC clusters each) or received a sham transplant of saline
          solution. Transplantation of more IPC clusters in a renal graft site was not feasible
          because of the size of the clusters. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> cluster transplantation, we
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">subjected mice</ENAMEX> to an overnight fast. Then we measured serum human <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide before and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">intraperitoneal</TIMEX> injection with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> per kilogram of body weight using
          a human <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-peptide ELISA</ENAMEX> kit. When stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> IPC clusters were transplanted, tumors were not
          observed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> wk after engraftment, the maximum period of observation (
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). All data represent the average (from the indicated number of
          samples) ¬± standard error of the mean. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-tailed 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> tests were conducted to determine statistical significance.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glucose Restriction Initiates IPC Development</ENAMEX>
          Culture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> with high glucose concentrations have been useful for isolating and
          maintaining progenitor cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> from the central and peripheral nervous systems
          [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,17</NUMEX>] and for permitting differentiation by neurogenic cells [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. We routinely
          expanded NS cultures in medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, a level <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5- to 6</NUMEX>-fold higher than
          physiologic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> concentration. Isolated human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neural progenitors</ENAMEX> spontaneously
          aggregate in these conditions to produce a cell cluster called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì90%</NUMEX> of NS
          cells produce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediary filament</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestin</ENAMEX> (Figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX>), a putative marker of
          neural stem and progenitor cells [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Prolonged exposure to high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> levels can also
          severely reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> expression in pancreatic Œ≤-cells [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. Thus, we postulated that
          glucose reduction might blunt neurogenic programs by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSs</ENAMEX> and promote alternate fates,
          including development of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>. Therefore, we switched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX> culture conditions from high
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37 mM</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äústage 1‚Äù</ENAMEX>) to low <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 mM, ‚Äústage 2‚</ENAMEX>Äù; see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A</NUMEX>) to initiate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>.
          To assess developmental changes resulting from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> reduction and later culture
          modifications, we examined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX> cell composition, and expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene products</ENAMEX> known to
          regulate or define in vivo fates of embryonic neural or islet cells. A Œ≤-tubulin III
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isoform</ENAMEX> produced in differentiating neurons was not detected in stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells, whereas
          expression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ki67</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">S-phase</ENAMEX>-associated nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>, was expressed in the majority
          of stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Genes specifying transcription factors essential for in
          vivo differentiation of lineage-restricted neural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progenitors</ENAMEX> and their differentiated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progeny</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21,22,23</NUMEX>], including 
          En1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Hb9</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Isl1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Hoxc6</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRSF/REST</ENAMEX>, and 
          Nkx6<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> , were expressed at low or undetectable levels in stage 1 (see
          Figure 1B‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Äì1C</ENAMEX>), consistent with the reported multipotency of proliferating NSs grown in
          high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>].
          After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> wk at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NS-</ENAMEX>derived cells remained in clusters (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A</NUMEX>), but
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nestin and Ki67</TIMEX> were expressed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 35%</NUMEX> of cells (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), indicating
          possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">differentiation</ENAMEX> of cells toward lineage-restricted fates. Consistent with this
          view, we detected increased expression of 
          Nkx6<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRSF/REST</ENAMEX>, and Œ≤-tubulin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> (see Figures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1B</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). We also
          detected increased expression of 
          Neurogenin3 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ngn3</NUMEX>) (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1C</NUMEX>), a transcription factor expressed in
          differentiating neurons, and required for development of pancreatic islet progenitor
          cells [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,25,26</NUMEX>]. 
          Nkx6.1 and 
          ngn3 expression were never observed in NS cultures maintained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX> (see Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1B</TIMEX>; data not shown). These data suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> restriction
          initiates developmental programs known to promote differentiation of mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">neural</ENAMEX> and
          neuroendocrine cells. As shown below, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> expression in NS-derived cells required
          culture in low-glucose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, but we did not consistently detect <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          + cells by immunohistochemistry until stage 4.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA Promotes IPC Development</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> induces development of primitive endodermal cells from a subset of embryonal
          carcinoma cell lines, and is an endogenous signal that directs development of posterior
          organs like the pancreas from embryonic endoderm [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27,28</NUMEX>]. In vivo exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> is
          sufficient to induce ectopic development of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-expressing tissue in the anterior
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foregut</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. Moreover, stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NS-</ENAMEX>derived cells expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX>-Œ±
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR-Œ≥</ENAMEX> (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1C</NUMEX>), indicating competence for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> signals. To investigate whether
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> could stimulate development of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NS-</ENAMEX>derived cells toward an IPC fate, we measured
          expression of 
          Pdx1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cdx1</TIMEX>, and 
          FoxA3, transcription factors that regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gastrointestinal</ENAMEX> organ
          development [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,30</NUMEX>]. 
          Pdx1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cdx1</TIMEX>, and 
          FoxA3 expression was induced in ‚Äústage <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,‚Äù</NUMEX> when cell clusters were
          allowed to adhere to pre-coated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> at a density of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">40‚Äì80 NSs/cm</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and cultured in low-glucose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Œ</NUMEX>ºM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 wk</NUMEX> (see Figure
          1A and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1C</ENAMEX>). We then tested other concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and other plating densities. NS
          cells exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 40</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSs</ENAMEX>/cm
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and NS cells exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ŒºM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> at a plating density of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSs</ENAMEX>/cm
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> did not express these markers or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> at a later stage (‚Äústage
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4‚Äù</NUMEX>; Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3A</TIMEX>; data not shown). Thus, higher doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> of posterior
          fate in NS-derived cells, a dosage response like that seen during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> patterning of
          posterior gut development in vivo. Moreover, this response was sensitive to plating
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX>, revealing that additional cell-non-autonomous factors may regulate this
          response. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mesoderm</ENAMEX> develops in close association with gastrointestinal endoderm both in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vivo</ENAMEX> and in vitro [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31,32</NUMEX>]. Thus, detection of gut markers like 
          Pdx1 and 
          FoxA3 in NS-derived cell cultures raised the possibility that
          mesodermal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> might co-develop. However, we did not detect expression of known markers
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mesoderm</ENAMEX> formation, including 
          brachyury, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flk-1</ENAMEX>, myosin light <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and 
          Œ≤-globin, at any stage in our cultures (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1B</NUMEX>). By contrast,
          mesoderm development invariably accompanies endoderm development in embryoid bodies
          derived from human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ES cells</ENAMEX> or embryonic germ cells [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31,32,33</NUMEX>]. In stage 3 cultures,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nestin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ki67</ENAMEX> expression was nearly extinguished (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), while expression of 
          En1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ngn3</TIMEX>, and 
          Hb9 increased (see Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1B and 1C</TIMEX>). While their numbers increased
          slightly during stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX>, Œ≤-tubulin III
          + cells composed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 10%</NUMEX> of cells in NS-derived clusters (see
          Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), suggesting that the majority of differentiated cells had acquired non-neural
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fates</ENAMEX>. Consistent with this interpretation, we also did not detect expression of
          homeodomain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins Hoxc6</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Hoxb9</NUMEX> (see Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1B</TIMEX>; data not shown), which are induced by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> in spinal cord neuronal precursor cells [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>].
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> can activate signaling through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedgehog</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hh</ENAMEX>) pathway, and recent studies show
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hh</ENAMEX> signals control development of embryonic pancreatic islets in vivo [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,34</NUMEX>]. To
          elucidate the mechanisms underlying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-induced expression of markers like 
          FoxA3 and 
          Pdx1, we examined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hh</ENAMEX> signaling during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> development. We detected
          expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedgehog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patched</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ptc</ENAMEX>) and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smoothened</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smo</ENAMEX>) at all stages (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3B</NUMEX>), consistent with the
          possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NS-</ENAMEX>derived cells are competent for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hh</ENAMEX> signaling. However, we did not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">detect NS</ENAMEX> expression of genes encoding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hh</ENAMEX> ligands like 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shh</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3B</NUMEX>), similar to previous studies [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Increased 
          Ptc transcription is a known consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shh</ENAMEX> signaling, but we did
          not detect changes of 
          Ptc expression during stages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1‚Äì4</NUMEX>, consistent with the absence of
          detectable expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hh</ENAMEX> ligands. To test directly whether the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hh</ENAMEX> signaling
          was required for expression of endodermal or islet markers, including 
          FoxA3, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pdx1</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, we added <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> to stage 4 cultures,
          which do not express 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shh</ENAMEX> or genes encoding other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hh</ENAMEX> ligands like 
          Desert hedgehog or 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> hedgehog (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3C</NUMEX>). At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM, a dose used to induce
          neuronal development in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ES</ENAMEX> cell cultures [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shh</ENAMEX> produced a significant increase in
          neurite outgrowth in NS-derived cells (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3D and 3E</TIMEX>; see Methods), and resulted in
          increased 
          Ptc expression (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3F</NUMEX>). Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shh</ENAMEX> treatment during stage 4
          eliminated expression of 
          Pdx1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FoxA3</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3F</NUMEX>). These data are reminiscent of
          prior studies demonstrating that excess endodermal Shh signaling disrupts pancreas
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> in vivo [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,34</NUMEX>]. Thus, in contrast to the response of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ES</ENAMEX> cells [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NS-</ENAMEX>derived cells does not stimulate endogenous Hh signaling. The lack of Hh
          signals in NS-derived cells blunts neural differentiation and permits differentiation
          toward endocrine-like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell fates</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insulin Expression</ENAMEX> by IPCs
          
          ngn3, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pdx1</TIMEX>, and 
          Hb9 are essential factors for mammalian Œ≤-cell development [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>], and
          their expression in stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX> suggested the potential for deriving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>. Insulin expression
          has not, to our knowledge, been reported in NS-derived cells [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,35</NUMEX>]. Moderate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperglycemia</ENAMEX> is a potent stimulus for Œ≤-cell differentiation and expansion in vivo and
          in utero [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>], so we tested whether exposure of stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> cells to elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> levels
          could induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> expression. Semi-quantitative RT-PCR measures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> mRNA
          expression showed that exposure of cultures grown in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 to 17</TIMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> at stage 4 induced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> expression (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3A</NUMEX>). Growth of cells at stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> followed by exposure in stages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 and 4 to 17</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> also resulted in
          insulin expression at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>, but at lower levels. By contrast, no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> was expressed
          by cultures maintained in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> throughout stages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2‚Äì4</TIMEX> (Figure
          3A). Thus, reduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> in stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> growth medium followed by a later increase in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> at stage 3 or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> was essential for development of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>. Insulin-like growth
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-1</ENAMEX> may promote <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX> and prevent apoptosis of Œ≤-cells in vivo [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>], and
          addition of this factor at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX> reduced apoptosis <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 10-fold</NUMEX> (see Figure
          1A; data not shown). Nicotinamide, which can stimulate in vivo pancreatic endocrine cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>], did not affect cell survival, but did increase <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide
          expression <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 1.5- to 2</NUMEX>-fold (data not shown). Thus, simultaneous exposure to
          high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> levels, insulin-like growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-1</ENAMEX>, and nicotinamide optimized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          expression at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>. Comparable results were obtained with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> independently derived
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NS</ENAMEX> lines.
          Coinciding with the onset of high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> expression levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse islets</ENAMEX>, 
          ngn3 expression is virtually extinguished [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>], while expression of 
          Pdx1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FoxA3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Isl1</TIMEX>, and 
          Nkx6.1 in islet Œ≤-cells is maintained or increased [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. Similarly, we
          noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> maturation from stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 to 4</TIMEX> was accompanied by increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          expression, reduced 
          ngn3 expression, and increased or maintained levels of 
          Isl1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FoxA3</TIMEX>, and 
          Pdx1 expression (see Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1B and 1C</TIMEX>). Thus, tissues derived from
          neural progenitor cells express <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, 
          Pdx1, and 
          FoxA3, markers typically co-expressed in foregut-derived tissues.
          Expression of these markers suggests differentiation of some neural progenitor cells
          toward an endoderm-like fate. We were unable to detect expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Pdx1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FoxA3</ENAMEX> using
          immunohistochemical methods in stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>, (data not shown). We also did not detect
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nkx6.1</ENAMEX> or islet amyloid polypeptide, markers of mature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pancreatic</TIMEX> Œ≤-cells
          (see Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1C</TIMEX>; data not shown). Thus, the sequence of gene expression accompanying
          formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSs</ENAMEX> was similar but not identical to that described for
          differentiating pancreatic Œ≤-cells, and further molecular studies are required to
          determine the degree of endoderm-like differentiation of cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>.
          We detected expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin protein</ENAMEX> by immunohistochemistry in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> of stage 4
          cell clusters (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). An average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX> of cells in stage 4 clusters were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+</ENAMEX> , and appeared healthy, with abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cytoplasm</ENAMEX> and a well-defined
          nucleus delineated by the nuclear stain 7AAD (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>). Of the cells composing stage 4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clusters</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX> were Œ≤-tubulin III
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+</ENAMEX> , none of which contained <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> (Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5A‚Äì5C</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Insulin</ENAMEX>
          + cells showed little or no co-expression of neural stem cell markers
          like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestin</ENAMEX> (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), or other markers of neural lineages known to develop from
          human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neural progenitors</ENAMEX>, like MAP2 (differentiated neurons; Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5D‚Äì5F</ENAMEX>), Olig2
          (multipotent precursors, bipotent glial precursors, and oligodendrocytes; Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5J‚</NUMEX>Äì5L;
          see [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>]), or myelin basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (data not shown). Occasional rare <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          + cells expressed detectable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GFAP (a marker</ENAMEX> of astrocytes; Figure
          5G‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Äì5I</ENAMEX>). Thus, while we cannot completely rule out the possibility that some neural cell
          types expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, these data suggest that nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">+ cells</ENAMEX> produced in stage 4 cultures were non-neuronal.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclei</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          + cells were not stained by an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to Ki67 (see Figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and
          4B), suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          + cells at stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> are post-mitotic, like mature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pancreatic</TIMEX> Œ≤-cells.
          Immunostaining with specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> revealed proinsulin and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide, an internal
          portion of the proinsulin translation product, in the cytoplasm of all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          + cells (see Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4D‚Äì4G and 4O</TIMEX>), supporting our conclusion that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin protein</ENAMEX> was produced in stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>. In situ hybridization with antisense
          riboprobes specific for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin mRNA</ENAMEX> labeled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì30%</NUMEX> of stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> cells (see Figure
          4H‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Äì4J</ENAMEX>), providing further evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> production. We observed only rare <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          + cells stained by antibodies specific for activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase</ENAMEX>-3
          (<<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX>; see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4K</NUMEX>) or TUNEL assay (data not shown). In stage 4 cell clusters we
          did not consistently detect expression of glucagon (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4L</NUMEX>), pancreatic
          polypeptide, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">somatostatin</ENAMEX> by immunohistochemistry. The absence of glucagon gene
          expression in our IPC cultures was further confirmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> (data not shown). Thus,
          like in pancreatic islets, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> was the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>. However,
          the composition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> was distinct from that of pancreatic islets, and further studies
          are required to determine the basis for this difference.
          To quantify <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>, we used a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4P</NUMEX>). By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX>, we did not detect <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide in stage 3 or stage 4
          culture media, which contained supplementary bovine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>. Thus, use of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> did not detect medium-derived bovine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> in measures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPC insulin</ENAMEX> content
          [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>]. C-peptide levels at stages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1‚Äì3</NUMEX> were low or undetectable (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4P</NUMEX>), consistent
          with the lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">immunostainable insulin</ENAMEX> (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) in cells at these earlier stages.
          Similarly, in cultures maintained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> during stages <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1‚Äì4 (‚ÄúHHHH‚Äù</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide
          levels were not detectable (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4P</NUMEX>). In cell clusters exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> in
          stages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2‚Äì3</NUMEX> then switched to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> at stage <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 (‚ÄúHLLH‚Äù</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide levels
          were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.36 fmol</NUMEX> per cluster, and the average number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide
          + cells per cluster was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>. Thus, we estimate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0018</NUMEX> fmol <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide
          per NS-derived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX>. A single Œ≤-cell contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 0.6 fmol</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>], so we calculate that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptide</ENAMEX> content in one stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> is approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX> of the level in isolated human Œ≤-cells. Collectively, these experiments confirm that
          IPCs transcribe and translate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, and rule out that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> measured in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> is
          derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, as shown in another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>].
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">IPCs Are Glucose Responsive</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glucokinase</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> transporters like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Glut-2</ENAMEX> are essential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          responses in pancreatic Œ≤-cells, and expression of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> in stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          + cells (see Figures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1C</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4M</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4N</ENAMEX>) suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> could sense
          and respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>. To test whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> respond appropriately to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulation</ENAMEX>, we measured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> release in static batch in vitro assays. We found that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPC insulin</ENAMEX> release increased markedly following a step increase of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.8</NUMEX> to
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25 mM</TIMEX> (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Q</NUMEX>). To examine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> are similarly responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          stimulation in vivo, we performed a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grafting</ENAMEX> experiments in
          immunocompromised recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks</TIMEX> following engraftment (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> IPC-containing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">clusters/mouse</ENAMEX>), recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and sham-transplanted controls were fasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide levels measured. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> was undetectable in mouse sera prior to
          glucose challenge, or following <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">glucose</ENAMEX> challenge of sham-transplanted controls (see
          Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4R</NUMEX>). In contrast, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> after intraperitoneal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> challenge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>
          we detected <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6.1 ¬± 1.2 pmol</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/l human C-</ENAMEX>peptide (
          p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 0.5</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì1%</NUMEX> of serum <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide levels observed
          following engraftment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> human islet equivalents in a prior study [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>]. Thus, IPCs
          respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> challenge in vivo by releasing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide. Analysis of IPC
          graft sites <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 wk</TIMEX> after transplantation revealed nests of transplanted cells without
          obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> formation. Histologic analysis and immunohistochemical detection revealed
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide-expressing cells persisted in the graft site (see Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4S and 4T</TIMEX>). Thus,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engrafted IPCs</ENAMEX> remained differentiated and survived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to a month</TIMEX> following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transplantation</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        There is widespread interest in developing tissue replacement strategies for treatment
        of human disorders like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mellitus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson disease</ENAMEX>. While much attention has
        been focused on the promise of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ES</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> for tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX>, recent work suggests that
        neural stem cells, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ES</ENAMEX> cells, may have an unusually broad differentiation potential.
        For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gage</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> demonstrated the conversion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> neural stem cells to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">endothelial</ENAMEX> lineage, indicating that plasticity is a bona fide property of cultured
        neural stem cells [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>]. These results were also unexpected because endothelial cells and
        neuronal cells normally derive, respectively, from mesoderm and ectoderm, distinct
        embryonic germ layers. Here we show that human neural stem cells have a similarly broad
        differentiation potential, and that specific in vitro culture conditions can divert neural
        stem-derived cells from neural lineages toward a fate with endocrine and endodermal
        characteristics.
        Our study shows that application of endogenous signals governing pancreas development to
        human neural progenitor cells can generate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>-responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>. Systematic variation of
        the identity, concentration, and sequence of these signals led to discovery of methods
        culminating in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPC</ENAMEX> formation. However, there are limitations to our findings that should be
        noted. First, our molecular analysis of differentiating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> showed that they remain
        distinct from mature pancreatic islet Œ≤-cells; in other words, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">+ cells</ENAMEX> derived by our methods are not mature Œ≤-cells. For example,
        combination of gene products that approximate those expressed in developing pancreatic
        islet cells. However, the temporal sequence of expression of some of these products, like
        glucokinase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Glut-2</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pdx1</ENAMEX> does not precisely recapitulate that observed in the
        embryonic pancreas (reviewed in [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]), and transcription of other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> typically expressed
        in Œ≤-cells, like 
        Nkx6<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>, was not detected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> stage IPCs (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Thus, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">+ cells</ENAMEX> derived in this study are not bona fide Œ≤-cells. Further
        experimentation may elucidate the basis for these differences, revealing the extent of
        neural progenitor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell development</ENAMEX> toward an endocrine cell fate. Recent studies suggest
        that neural cells can be derived from adult pancreatic epithelium [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,8</NUMEX>], adding to a
        growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of data demonstrating numerous similarities in neural and pancreatic endocrine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> (reviewed in [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>]). In light of these similarities, we speculate that methods
        leading to the production of Œ≤-cell factors like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nkx6.1</ENAMEX> in stage 4 clusters may enhance the
        Œ≤-cell-like qualities of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">neural-progenitor</ENAMEX>-derived <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        + cells, and thereby permit differentiation of tissues that more closely
        resemble endoderm-derived islet cells. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, our immunohistochemical analysis shows that
        stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-expressing cells do not express markers like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestin, Œ≤-tubulin III</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MAP2</TIMEX>,
        or Olig2, suggesting that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        + cells are non-neuronal, but we cannot formally rule out the alternate
        possibility that our methods produced neural cells capable of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">secreting insulin</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, we
        have not demonstrated fully that the stimulus‚Äìsecretion coupling apparatus in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> is
        similar to that in pancreatic islets. While <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> release by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> produced here appears
        to be <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose-sensitive</ENAMEX>, both in vitro and in vivo, future work should elaborate whether
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPC insulin</ENAMEX> is stored in dense-core secretory vesicles, and whether secretogogues or
        secretion potentiators other than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> (like amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> or sulfonylureas) stimulate
        insulin release by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>, like in pancreatic islets. Lastly, we have not ameliorated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
        regulation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic animal</ENAMEX> models with the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">IPCs</ENAMEX> described here. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serum</ENAMEX> levels of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">insulin C-</ENAMEX>peptide expression achieved following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> transplantation in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>-challenged
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1%</NUMEX> of normal (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Thus, we did not attempt IPC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transplantations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">overtly diabetic animals</ENAMEX>, since prior studies suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        production at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of normal (or greater) may be required to improve glucose regulation in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diabetic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and animal models [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,41</NUMEX>]. Additional studies to test the impact of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transplanted IPCs</ENAMEX> in animal models of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> therefore await production of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPCs</ENAMEX> capable
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion at levels higher than achieved here.
        Nevertheless, compared to other methods for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> development from human stem cells
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,44</NUMEX>], our methods produced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> at the highest levels yet achieved from an
        expandable, human stem-cell-derived tissue. Multiple experimental approaches were taken to
        demonstrate that these IPCs transcribe, translate, and secrete <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, and to rule out the
        possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> measured in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPCs</ENAMEX> derived from the culture media. In vitro studies
        demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> release <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>-responsive manner, like islets.
        Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX> transplanted into <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> remained differentiated and released circulating
        human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>-dependent manner. Thus, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, we demonstrate
        moderately efficient production of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose-responsive IPCs</ENAMEX> from an expandable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of
        human stem cells. Current islet transplantation methods require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 5</NUMEX> √ó <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 to 10</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> Œ≤-cells per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>]. From <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> cells at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, we produced an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200‚Äì400</NUMEX> clusters with
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> cells per cluster; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 25%</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+</ENAMEX> and release <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5</NUMEX>%‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äì1%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> secreted by Œ≤-cells. Based strictly
        on these yields, we would need to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPC</ENAMEX> production <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 10</TIMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> -fold to meet the need for one transplantation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Undifferentiated</ENAMEX> NSs
        can be readily expanded through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a dozen</NUMEX> passages [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>], suggesting sufficient cell
        numbers could be generated to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúscale up‚Äù this protocol for transplant-based therapies.
        We did not exhaust all possible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> combinations in our study: we speculate that
        further method refinements may improve the efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX> conversion into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPCs</ENAMEX>, as well
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IPC insulin synthesis</ENAMEX> and stimulus‚Äìsecretion coupling, the hallmark functions of mature
        Œ≤-cells. If so, then human neural stem cells may serve as a valuable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> for elucidating
        the mechanisms and factors that regulate neuroendocrine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell differentiation</ENAMEX>. For instance,
        addition of glucagon-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptide-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Œ≤ ligands, or other factors that potentiate Œ≤-cell
        maturation, growth, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46,47,48</NUMEX>] may improve the methods described
        here. Because our method is based solely on extracellular factor modulation, in the absence
        of genetic manipulations, it could serve as the basis for developing replacement islets
        from a wide range of human stem cells, including neural stem cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ES</ENAMEX> cells.
      
      
        Supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
        
          Accession Numbers
          numbers for the genes and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene products</ENAMEX> discussed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brachyury</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">AF012130</NUMEX>), 
          Cdx1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">000209</ENAMEX>), 
          Desert hedgehog (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">021044</ENAMEX>), 
          En1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">001426</ENAMEX>), 
          flk-1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">AF035121</NUMEX>), 
          FoxA3 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">004497</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">002046</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFAP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">002055</ENAMEX>), glucokinase
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">M90299</NUMEX>), 
          Hb9 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">005515</ENAMEX>), 
          Hoxb9 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">024017</ENAMEX>), 
          Hoxc6 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">004503</ENAMEX>), human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin cDNA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">J00265</NUMEX>), 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> hedgehog (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">002181</ENAMEX>), 
          Isl1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">002202</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MAP2</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U01828</NUMEX>), myelin basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">M13577</NUMEX>), 
          myosin light <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>-2 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">X57542</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">006617</ENAMEX>), 
          ngn3 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">AF234829</NUMEX>), 
          Nkx6<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">006168</ENAMEX>), 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRSF/REST</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U13879</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Olig2</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">005806</ENAMEX>), 
          Pdx1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">000209</ENAMEX>), 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ptc</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U59464</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR-Œ±</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">000964</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR-Œ≤</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">BC060794</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR-Œ≥</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">000966</ENAMEX>), 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shh</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">L38518</NUMEX>), 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smo</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">AH007453</NUMEX>), 
          Œ≤-globin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">000518</ENAMEX>), and Œ≤-tubulin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">BC000748</NUMEX>).
        
      
    
  
