
   
   
      
         
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> putsch watch has resumed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>' appetites have been
whetted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) ever-louder grumbling among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
leadership botched the fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on disaster relief and the budget; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
an anonymous "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Colleague</ENAMEX>" letter urging a no-confidence vote on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) a demand by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s birthday) that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> caucus halt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>'s drift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>'s failure to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. The most serious
breach so far is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX>'s declaration that he isn't bound by the budget
agreement since he wasn't one of the "big shots" who negotiated it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
made a show of unity on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/18</NUMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX> rabbis
have been charged with laundering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> drug money
through a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> and a yeshiva. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neighbors</ENAMEX> think the rabbis didn't
know the money was drug-related, since <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are reviled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> think they did. Angered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> angle,
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasidim</ENAMEX> offered semantic rebuttals ("everybody in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rabbi"</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmudic</ENAMEX> hairsplitting (the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">culprit</ENAMEX> wasn't a real rabbi
because he didn't head a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX>), and angst (who will tell the bad news to
the aged chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>?). (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/18</NUMEX>)
            

            Book
'em: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> suspected of driving the getaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> air
base bombing has been deported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. He has
agreed to help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> in exchange for reduced charges. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> accused of mowing down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> has been turned in by anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghans</ENAMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> offered a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> bounty for him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Einhorn</ENAMEX>, the peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> who was convicted in absentia of murdering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> 16 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, after hoodwinking his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and jumping bail, has been captured in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and will be extradited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/18</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> is in turmoil. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Genocidal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>-turned-guerrilla-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX> reportedly has surrendered after being hunted down by his own former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX>, who will run against
each other in elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, are vying for the allegiance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> and are building well-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival armies</ENAMEX> of "bodyguards." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bodyguards</ENAMEX> got into a deadly turf skirmish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, which bodes ill for the
elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>'s demise but regrets that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crooks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schemers</ENAMEX>, and butchers evidently will continue to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/18</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> responded by calling off settlement talks
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, the IRA's political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> lamented that the atmosphere
of new hope created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s election has been ruined. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX> as "a puppet of the IRA's hard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>." However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> implored the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> to "keep the
negotiating talks rolling at all costs." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/18</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> appointed an advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and gave a speech to promote
racial reconciliation . The coverage praised the theme but doubted the
practical results, noting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s toning-down of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> speech drafts and
his failure to propose solutions other than affirmative action and more money
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</ENAMEX>. "Few <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">See How Clinton Effort</ENAMEX>
Will Bring Results," scoffed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> theorized that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is triangulating back to the left after tacking to the right on welfare
reform and the budget deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> doubted the sermonizer but loved the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sermon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, while accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of
defending "quotas," complained they were underrepresented on the advisory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/16</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing trial is over (the jury sentenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX> to
death), and the conspiracy-theory frenzy is underway. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense attorney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Jones</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> not to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> to death, saying: "We don't
want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Harvey Oswald</ENAMEX> here. We don't want an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> movie." Then Jones
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">titillated 60 Minutes</ENAMEX> with hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> were involved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jurors</ENAMEX> and law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> confirmed they
suspect other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> are at large. The Internet is percolating with
theories that an "electromagnetic pulse weapon" destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> did it and wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>, etc. An <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legislator</ENAMEX> has mustered enough signatures for a grand-jury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> to root out
the uncaught <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> has called on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> to cough up their "secrets" or shut up. Meanwhile, appellate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dershowitz</ENAMEX> predicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> will fire his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and base his appeal on
their incompetence. Cynics surmised that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dershowitz</ENAMEX> is already chasing the
paddy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/16</NUMEX>)
            

            News
from abroad: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX> has evidently coasted to
re-election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> expressed regret at voting "irregularities" and at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX>'s autocratic nationalism, but consoled themselves with reports that he
is dying of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. A senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of England</ENAMEX> instructed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> to quit the throne or dump his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>, since "we are
not going to have a confessed adulterer as supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> affirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> will not be prosecuted in the corruption scandal that has dogged him
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has its own 
                  Primary Colors
               --a novel curiously
reminiscent of the recent scandal that ruined a top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authorities</ENAMEX> have responded by banning the novel and arresting its putative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distributors</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/16</NUMEX>)
            

            Sports
updates: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Utah Jazz 4</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to win their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Basketball Association</ENAMEX> title in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> reaffirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX>
star <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s divinity and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Malone</ENAMEX>'s mediocrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detractors</ENAMEX> argued that his choking performance proved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> had been foolish
to give him its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Valuable Player</ENAMEX> award. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> argued that the award
was what had caused him to choke in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Sportswriters are already
forecasting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX>' imperial decay with morbid delight. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> golfer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie Els</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX> but got less attention for winning it than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX> got for losing it badly. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/16</NUMEX>)
            

            The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rent-decontrol apocalypse</ENAMEX> has been averted. Rent control will
remain for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another six years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> of rent deregulation, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>, relented in exchange for a compromise plan that will
gradually raise rents by regulating the existing regulations. Among the
mind-numbing details reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "Second-generation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> could remain in regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> provided they were willing to pay
the vacancy bonus." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> swallowed the plan <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> after
calling it "laughable" and "absurd." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> called it the
culmination of "a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-month</TIMEX> game of political <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take on
the issue, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "Such a
Deal" and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" it sparked.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/16</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> played regular-season games
against each other for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the sport's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120-year</TIMEX> history.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of interleague play believe it will ignite local rivalries (e.g.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX>) and showcase the sport's stars in more
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, thereby boosting attendance and merchandise sales, which, in turn, will
enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to satisfy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>' skyrocketing salary demands. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Traditionalists</ENAMEX>
complain it will dilute ancient rivalries, screw up the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-to-year</TIMEX> continuity
of statistics, obliterate the quaint differences between the two leagues
(principally, the designated-hitter rule), and spoil the climactic, virgin
mystique of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>, which, until now, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX>' only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intercourse</ENAMEX>. Results so far are uneven: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets-Yankees</ENAMEX> series opener sold
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as many seats as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Padres-Angels</ENAMEX> series. "Already, [interleague
play] has restored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s grandest traditions: the passion for
arguing about the game," observed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> . Things could be
worse: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reports that, thanks to the popularization
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bats</ENAMEX> have "emerged as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> of choice for hooligans,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thugs</ENAMEX>, [and] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">extortionists</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/13</NUMEX>)
            

            Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> faces possible charges for secretly
delivering and abandoning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> such case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. First, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were charged with killing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> in a
motel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and dumping it in the trash. Then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> gave
birth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> at her high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prom</ENAMEX> and dumped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in the trash,
where it would later be found dead. (She then checked her makeup in the mirror,
went back to the dance floor, and asked the disc jockey to play a heavy-metal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unforgiven</ENAMEX>"--for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>.) Moral indignation over the incident was
almost overshadowed by disbelief that nobody had noticed her condition. The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> declared it the latest sign of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> moral
apocalypse littered with condoms, fear of school prayer, hysteria over Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Ralston</ENAMEX>, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mapplethorpe</ENAMEX>'s bullwhips." Now comes the third
case, in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> gave birth in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and left the baby
there. Again, family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> say they had no idea she was pregnant.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/13</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Basketball Association</ENAMEX> fined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>
Rodman <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> for insulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormons</ENAMEX>. This doubles the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s previous
record fine, also earned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>, for kicking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> earlier this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>'s first offending remark, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>: "It's
difficult to get in sync because of all the [expletive] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormons</ENAMEX> out here." His
follow-up remark, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10</TIMEX>: "Mormon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't like me either, right? That's a
given, right? So what the hell." His apology, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX>: "If I knew it was like a
religious-type deal, I would have never said it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bulls coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Jackson</ENAMEX>
explained: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">To Dennis</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX> may just be a nickname for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>. He
may not even know it's a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> or sect or whatever it is."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/13</NUMEX>)
            

            The
Dow Jones industrial average roared past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,500</NUMEX> and closed above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,700</NUMEX>.
It has now risen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year and a half</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> cited
the usual factors: strong profits, low inflation, expectations of a sound
budget agreement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have become so blasé about Dow milestones that they
hardly noticed this one. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , while warning that a
recession is inevitable, acknowledged that such warnings have lost almost all
credibility: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economists</ENAMEX> "worry that the news is too good to last--and then it
does." Related headlines: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economists See Rosy Long-Term U.S. Future</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10</TIMEX>); "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Golden Age"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Glassman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10</TIMEX>). (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/13</NUMEX>)
            

            Miscellany: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> bought control of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>'s cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>--"a merger of the
sacred and profane," cracked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kelly</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> resort-hopping in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to evade rape charges
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, was finally convicted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s state pardon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> threw out the conviction of former Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Hunt</ENAMEX>--who had appointed
them--on charges of diverting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> from a tax-free inaugural fund to
personal use. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly passed--again--a constitutional
amendment to ban the desecration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
Rep.-turned-gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Kennedy</ENAMEX> raised eyebrows by speaking in
favor of the amendment. Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> praying at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Wall</ENAMEX>
were doused with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX>, trash, and feces--by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX>
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>," "whores," and "goyim," evidently because
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were praying together. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/13</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
