
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">update: 1</ENAMEX>) Having refused to negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> or to ease sanctions, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> offered to ease sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> oil sales if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> lets
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspectors resume their work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> cried appeasement. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
rejected the offer and insisted that the world accept <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s conditions for
resumption of inspections. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> said that it has worked out a deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, but didn't say what's in the deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> objected that the deal
reportedly would include a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> pledge to cut short its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>-inspection
program. The charitable view: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is playing good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> , while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> plays bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>. The uncharitable view: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is selling us out.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> accelerated the backspin against military
action with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> piece criticizing "facile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> commentary" that
exaggerates the ease of deposing or crippling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.
(
                  Slate
                gives you "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/19</NUMEX>)
            

            A
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> banned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX> from seeking
re-election, concluding that he was involved in a scam to launder union money
into his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign. Editorialists bemoaned the fall of an idol (see

                  Slate
               's assessment), arguing that his legacy of reforming the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> transcends his personal lapse. Left-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wingers</ENAMEX> complained that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">right-wingers</ENAMEX> would use the ruling to tar the whole labor movement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Right-wingers</ENAMEX>, led by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , obliged them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX>
pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> hadn't murdered anybody (unlike past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>),
and rationalized his scam as a "desperate" response to the threat posed by his
more corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James P. Hoffa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reformers consoled</ENAMEX> themselves with the
hope that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> will likewise throw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffa</ENAMEX> off the ballot for campaign
violations. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/19</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terrorists</ENAMEX> massacred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>. None was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> were shot, hacked, and mutilated. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s biggest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist faction</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Group</ENAMEX>," claimed responsibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>
suggested a further escalation of violence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> linked
the massacre to similar bloodshed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> and blamed it on poor security.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s neglect of social and economic
inequality. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/19</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
is considering whether to replace school textbooks with laptops .
Arguments for the switch: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) With lower laptop prices plus volume discounts, it
will be cheaper than new textbooks. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Laptops will make it easier to update
the curriculum. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> learn more on computers. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It'll give poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
access to technology. Best argument against it: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> will lose their laptops.
Bottom line: The question is when, not whether, the switch will happen.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/19</NUMEX>)
            

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to plead for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> unity. The inside spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Non</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are
furious at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> who are
denying state recognition to non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. The conflict--in
addition to anger over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s management of peace talks with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>--is affecting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX>' donations to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s
message: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX> are "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>" with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in resolving this conflict,
and there are no "second-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>." The outside spin: Why isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> during his visit<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "Good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> has
earned this snub," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> , noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s rocky relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> were screwing up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/17</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> predict that an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will be named to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investigate Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX> . This is likely, according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , because the dispute over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX> traded
a decision on an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>-casino license for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>-campaign money involves
facts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> can't resolve in its allotted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>. An
independent probe of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX> would include examination of top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX>, possibly
leading to a wholesale investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fund raising, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
have hoped. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/17</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX> was released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and exiled to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. The first-day spin: It's a triumph for human rights and a
vindication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s constructive-engagement policy. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-day
backspins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX> brought his punishment on himself by thumbing his nose at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s offer to exile him was old news. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has
thereby rid itself of an irksome "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>" and his influence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> are still in jail. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Trading nuclear technology and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX> for him at the recent summit was a lousy deal. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/17</NUMEX>)
            

            Former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teacher Mary Kay LeTourneau</ENAMEX> was sentenced 
               to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> in jail
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of treatment for having sex--and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>--with a 13-year-old
student. She had pleaded guilty to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> counts of second-degree <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> rape. She
was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> and married with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at the time. Controversy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> asks whether it was rape or, "as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>
to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and talk radio programs suggest, the answer to every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">schoolboy</ENAMEX>'s dream." Corollary: Should the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LeTourneau</ENAMEX> and the boy
still "love" each other count against her (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> insist) or for her?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> says: "I don't feel that this is a crime. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> does not feel
victimized." Controversy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: Did she get off lightly because she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>,
whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are jailed longer for similar crimes? The respectable rejoinder:
She's a first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX>. The naughty rejoinder, offered by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> just want to punish her because "she is attractive." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/17</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> killed payments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the year</TIMEX>. The reason: an abstruse quarrel over
abortion funding. The payments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> were already overdue.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> called the decision "utterly boneheaded" because
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> needs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> support against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> needs the
promise of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> financial support to help quell financial panic in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>.
Another end-of-session deal will allow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a million</NUMEX> illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but tighten controls on future
illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Immigrant spokesmen</ENAMEX> welcomed the relaxation but said it was
unfair to future comers and favored some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicaraguans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX>) over
others. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/14</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mastermind</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing were
convicted. They face life sentences. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> were convicted in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>; another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> escaped, probably to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The remaining mystery is
whether some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> funded and orchestrated the
bombing. The sunny spin: We nailed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. The ominous spin: The
terrorists nailed us <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, more are coming, and there are too many to keep
track of. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> ended its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800 plane
crash, leaving mechanical failure as the only theory under investigation.
Editorialists labored to connect the two contrary outcomes. (Various sites,
among them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> video of the reconstruction of the crash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/14</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
reported more evidence of the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> plot to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
elections. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> intelligence files indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hsia</ENAMEX> has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable</ENAMEX>" reports say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> gave a
classified document to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> while in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
can't confirm this. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fragmentary</ENAMEX> intelligence" suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> wanted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s campaign. The spin: Why didn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
Department get this information <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> didn't get
it and give it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> investigation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX> until his
hearings had ended. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> called it another blow to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s credibility and
another reason to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/14</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
