
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>
landed a robot on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> and began exploring the surface. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> are
steering the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-foot</NUMEX> long, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23-pound</NUMEX> robot by remote control (from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119 million</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> away) and downloading the video and geological data it collects. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX>'s purpose is to study rocks, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> are more fascinated by the
unmistakable evidence of ancient flood <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>--which might now be frozen at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">poles</ENAMEX> or beneath the planet's surface--and by vivid photos. The mission's
official Web site has reportedly surpassed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 million</NUMEX> hits, making it one of
the most popular sites in the history of the Internet. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

            
Upheavals abroad: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s ruling party lost control of the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assembly</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 70 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> celebrated it as the
advent of true democracy. The story was almost overshadowed by the news that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lord</ENAMEX> died as a result of plastic surgery that was
supposed to hide him from the cops. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
staged a successful coup against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, wrecking
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s experiment in democracy and its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost</NUMEX>-completed peace pact with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victors</ENAMEX> celebrated by looting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rioters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, threw <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grenades</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, and hijacked and burned
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 230</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> marched through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> neighborhoods.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> finally relinquished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> found excuses to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> there, playing up the possibilities
of political confrontation and violence (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> oafishly sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to show everyone who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>) before conceding that nothing was going
to happen. Poorest excuse for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s travel expenses: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> Ponders
Meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Record Rainfall</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> agreed that
capitalism will continue to flourish there even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> doesn't: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Friedman</ENAMEX> noted that replicas of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goddess of</ENAMEX>
Democracy" (erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>), which were
being peddled by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>, were "Made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
hearings on the campaign-finance scandal are set to open. Best leaks
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Documents indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>'s real-estate holding
company funneled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> money into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> campaigns ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> );
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> personally lobbied the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>'s finance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> wistfully
alluded to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> and regretted that the
current scandal doesn't measure up. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> was disqualified during his latest championship boxing match for biting
off part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evander Holyfield</ENAMEX>'s ear . The bite inspired a blizzard of bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">puns</ENAMEX> and rekindled the ancient debate over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> is inherently or only
sporadically barbaric. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> rated it the most disgusting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> in the history
of sports, surpassing the outrages perpetrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Alomar</ENAMEX> (spitting in
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpire</ENAMEX>'s face), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX> (kicking a cameraman in the groin), and
others. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX>, 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mitchum</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Kuralt</ENAMEX> died.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> contrasted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> (the idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>) with Mitchum
(the hard-living rogue) and juxtaposed both of them--"the last of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s golden era," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>-- with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
mediocre movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> paired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuralt</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> of virtue and the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> ceaselessly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glorified Kuralt</ENAMEX>'s television journalism. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martina Hingis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Sampras</ENAMEX> won the women's and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s tennis
championships at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> . Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> lionized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hingis</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wunderkind</ENAMEX> (she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>) and
Sampras as arguably the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> ever (he's on track to shatter the
record for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s grand slam titles). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s runner-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jana Novotna</ENAMEX> choked away
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>-set lead in the finals for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time but managed (unlike last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>) not to cry on the shoulder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kent</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

            Miscellany:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> decided to give domestic-partnership benefits to
gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> instead of letting them marry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX> announced its
purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop Grumman</ENAMEX>, completing the defense industry's consolidation
into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that recently
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won</ENAMEX> fame for cloning a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> is reportedly on the verge of deriving human blood
plasma from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>. A new scientific report claims that puberty begins
as early as the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> was charged with murdering
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> by whacking him with a computer keyboard. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
