
   
   
      
         
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9-0</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> can sue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> while
he's still in office, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> doesn't protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> from
civil suits unrelated to his official duties. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> instructed the
trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s official duties into account, which may allow him
to keep postponing the trial. Editorialists of all persuasions congratulated
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for reaffirming that no one is above the law--"the message is right,"
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> were amused that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> had suspended their usual worship of executive privilege.
Everyone agrees the decision puts a rude end to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> honeymoon,
though most accounts cited the coverage rather than the facts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contentions</ENAMEX> as the main problem. The case "plays into a public perception of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> under siege," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . Early political
wisdom is that here, as with his other scandals, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should cut his losses
(by settling the suit), but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> seem intent on dragging it out
instead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contrarians</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> actually won the decision, since it
comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> after his re-election. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/28</NUMEX>)
            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost World</ENAMEX>
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s sequel to Jurassic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> , shattered box-office records by grossing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$92 million</NUMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day weekend</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> estimate it could end up grossing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>, including
merchandise. They also agree that its poor reviews (for a weak plot,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, and dialogue) were overpowered by its shrewd timing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>
showed it because no other big movies were out), legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedigree</ENAMEX> (everyone
loved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX> ), and sure-fire premise (<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can't
seem to get enough of). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> called it "review-proof."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/28</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC Communications</ENAMEX> are discussing a merger. Valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, the deal would double the size of the biggest merger on record. It
would also reunite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX> already comprises
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> pried away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ma Bell</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>'
complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) This is what antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> get for showing their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impotence</ENAMEX> when they let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> merge with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYNEX</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The new telecom law
is a failure, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are merging, not competing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) An AT&T-SBC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">behemoth</ENAMEX> would hasten the merger trend by forcing other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecom companies</ENAMEX> to
combine to compete with it. The backspin from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX> is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> needs its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> to compete with other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' national
phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/28</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> rebuked the center-right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 30 percent</NUMEX> supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> in parliamentary
elections, raising the prospect that a leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialists</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greens</ENAMEX> will take control in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s runoffs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handicappers</ENAMEX> put
the left's chances at even money or better. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX>'s protégé, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alain Juppe</ENAMEX>, took the fall, and has said he will resign. Editorialists debated
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> were punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juppe</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) daring to privatize
and cut government functions (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) failing to
privatize and cut government functions (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ); or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>)
"on-again, off-again" weaving between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/28</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Congolese</ENAMEX> (formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zairian</ENAMEX>) rebel-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurent Kabila</ENAMEX> is being
downgraded from liberator to tyrant. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) He appointed himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and said
he won't schedule elections for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two years</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He scrapped the post of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> (sought by opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Etienne Tshisekedi</ENAMEX>) and stacked his
Cabinet with rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) He banned public demonstrations to prevent
Tshisekedi from staging a protest march. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) There are more and more reports of
mass graves that may belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> slaughtered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabila</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabila</ENAMEX> is too beholden to foreign-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tutsi</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX>, who may persecute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hutus</ENAMEX> and inflame ethnic tensions. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that "euphoria" in the capital is giving way to
"disillusion and dissent." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/28</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world. Good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly elected a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX>, who has promised more individual freedom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>
hailed him as a "moderate" and a sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> are fed up with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police state</ENAMEX>. Bad news: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> indicated he has no plans to improve relations
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> doubt that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> could reform the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
recalling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> deal with "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>." Cynics dismiss the term as an oxymoron. Good news: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> released a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who apparently
had been locked up because his reports offended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>. Bad news: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> human-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> accused the authority of widespread torture and
political oppression. Good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> 's armed forces are tightening
screws on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in order to safeguard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pluralism</ENAMEX>. Bad news: The fiercely authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taliban</ENAMEX> movement captured a key
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> , extending its dominion to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Good news: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> began fighting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/28</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: A series of twisters killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-devastating a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> hit by a tornado <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX>. Up-and-coming Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Molinari</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, will quit her job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> to anchor a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> news show. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , pointing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
Stephanopoulos, speculated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Molinari</ENAMEX> may use the TV job to advance her political
career. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dutchman Arie Luyendyk</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Indianapolis 500</ENAMEX> . Controversy
erupted over the final lap, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> sent mixed signals as to whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> were supposed to slow down because of a near-accident. The runner-up,
chronic hard-luck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">racer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Goodyear</ENAMEX>, complained the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mix-up</ENAMEX> had prevented him
from passing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luyendyk</ENAMEX>. The Dow Jones industrial average extended its
record-breaking run to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 7,400</NUMEX>. A new report suggests that studies on the
health risks of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast implants</ENAMEX> may be skewed because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who get the
implants are (among other things) more likely to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX>, more likely to
be promiscuous, and more likely to dye their hair. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/28</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> opened its case in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing trial . Its theory:
The real <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> was blown up in the explosion. The key evidence: A severed leg
not matched to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. Highlights of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiner</ENAMEX> enumerated detached body parts collected from
the scene and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>'s former chief medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiner</ENAMEX> recounted a
bombing case in which an extra penis found at the site turned out to be the
sole intact remnant of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had carried the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/23</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Lt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX> agreed to a "general" rather than an "honorable" discharge from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>. This will spare her a court-martial and possible jail time for
allegedly committing adultery, lying about it, and disobeying orders to end
that affair. However, the discharge will cost her her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>' and other
benefits. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Widnall</ENAMEX> refused to grant an honorable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discharge</ENAMEX>, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flinn</ENAMEX>'s alleged "lack of integrity and disobedience to order"
and warning that a special exemption would discredit the military-justice
system. Reports suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flinn</ENAMEX> cut her deal at just the right time, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>)
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were becoming skeptical of her "carefully orchestrated publicity
campaign"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) editorialists (e.g. the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> ) were growing more sympathetic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>'s case; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flinn</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> were beginning a counterattack on her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/23</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> accused the fashion industry of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glamorizing heroin</ENAMEX> .
After reading about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> who died of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin overdose</ENAMEX> after selling
pictures of emaciated, vacant-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> argued that such images have
encouraged young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to take up the habit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> protested that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the
heroin look faded from fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> use is far less
common than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> suggested; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) it's not fair to blame drug abuse on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. Still, many magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was right. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX> tried to say something or other about it.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/23</NUMEX>)
            

            More
miscellany: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> fired his top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> for resisting budget cuts and reforms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> regard this as a key
victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> over its military <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> dropped charges against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had left her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in
a stroller outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> while dining. The catch: She has to get out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX> introduced "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Share a Smile Becky</ENAMEX>," a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">wheelchair-bound Barbie companion</ENAMEX> doll. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX>, the "first <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>"
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, has died. Her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> book (reportedly ghosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>) has sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300,000</NUMEX> copies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Solzhenitsyn</ENAMEX> is in
the cardiac intensive-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> has agreed to
launch a daily TV talk show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX> has signed an
endorsement deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX>. The deal reportedly adds <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> to
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woods</ENAMEX> has already secured for similar contracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titleist</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuzzy Zoeller</ENAMEX> lunched with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> at a country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and has
evidently patched things up. There was no word on what they ate.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/23</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Sportscaster Marv
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> denied charges that he had assaulted and sodomized a female
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acquaintance</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, the press unearthed problems with his anonymous
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">accuser: 1</ENAMEX>) She faces criminal charges for allegedly threatening to kill her
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">co-worker</ENAMEX> has filed a complaint
accusing her of physical harassment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> stood by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>, announcing he will
continue to broadcast basketball playoff games. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> has retained the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Brown Simpson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> civil
case. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/23</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
