
   
   
      
         
            

            A federal appeals court
upheld <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> , which prohibits affirmative action
in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. A panel of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Circuit Court of Appeals</ENAMEX>
ruled that a lower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s obstruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 209</ENAMEX> (on the grounds that it
treated race-based discrimination differently from other kinds of
discrimination) perverted the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">14 th Amendment</ENAMEX>, trampled democracy,
and embarrassed the entire judicial system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> of affirmative action
will ask the full <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Circuit</ENAMEX> to reverse the decision. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> see
this as a war between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> that only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court can ultimately resolve. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> conceded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of
affirmative action will have to "find new ways to achieve the same objective."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            Election results: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Riordan</ENAMEX> crushed challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hayden</ENAMEX> with more
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> emphasized that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riordan</ENAMEX> won support from almost every ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (overcoming the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
reputation for racial conflict) and did better than any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayden</ENAMEX>'s meager tally a "hard slap"
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haitian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Bertrand</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aristide</ENAMEX> claimed victory in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and local elections. However,
all but a small fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haitians</ENAMEX> boycotted the vote .
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            Underplayed: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers University</ENAMEX> claim to have identified a chemical that causes female
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orgasms</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX>, known as the vasoactive intestinal peptide, appears
to trigger the orgasm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> in the brain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 paraplegic</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were able to achieve orgasm, evidently by receiving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> through the vagus nerve (which connects the brain directly to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cervix</ENAMEX>) rather than the spine. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> envision turning the chemical
into a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>, which they claim would be used for pain suppression. The director
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey Institute</ENAMEX> says that while he respects the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, it would
be hard to stabilize the chemical in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            Foreplayed: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will soon issue an apology from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government for the infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tuskegee</ENAMEX> experiment , in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
poor black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were deliberately left untreated for syphilis from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30</TIMEX>, comedienne <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen DeGeneres</ENAMEX> ' TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> will
confirm she is a lesbian, consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeGeneres</ENAMEX>' own (already well-known)
sexual orientation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scribes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are already reacting to both events,
although neither has happened yet. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> girls are
reaching puberty much earlier than previously thought. A study finds that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> begin developing pubic
hair or breasts by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 8</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> percent of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of white
girls begin acquiring these characteristics by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 3</TIMEX> (yes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). This contradicts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">textbooks</ENAMEX> and previous studies that placed the average age of puberty at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 or</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of the new study cite flaws in previous studies (they were done
long ago, were confined to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, and didn't include girls
younger than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>). But they concede that the new study might also be skewed,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who develop early sexual traits might be more likely to be
brought to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and hence included in the study. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Update from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese Seko</ENAMEX> to end the
war by resigning and leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The logistical problem here, as with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shah</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, is finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that will accept him in exile. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, while complaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> is too selfish and stubborn to quit,
have refused to let him into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> declared martial law
and ousted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Etienne Tshisekedi</ENAMEX>, who had seized
political control. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rebels</ENAMEX> in the east were said to have captured the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> may not turn out much different
from the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> report says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> have massacred <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. (For background on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zairian</ENAMEX> conflict, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>.")
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Celebrity rites of
passage: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">icons</ENAMEX> died. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beat Generation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsberg</ENAMEX> was remembered as a courageous and lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nut</ENAMEX> who spearheaded the
counterculture by letting it all hang out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> called him a third-rate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> but a first-rate self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>. (You can hear brief clips of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginsberg</ENAMEX>
reading from "" and ".") Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kent Cooke</ENAMEX> was remembered as
a voracious, colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rags</ENAMEX>-to-riches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> who built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dynasties (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Los Angeles Lakers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Redskins</ENAMEX>) while living a sumptuous life that
included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> successive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them too young to be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> , the nonflamboyant, noniconic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, punctuated his wedding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Mitchell</ENAMEX> with a pair of kisses
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> depicted as shockingly passionate.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            Update on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
fund-raising scandal: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , having criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> from fund-raising events, ran a front-page story implicitly
criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> for screening out an allegedly sleazy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latvian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> by supplying classified information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> have found no evidence "that any sensitive information was
improperly transmitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
Administration hastily abandoned a Web site it had created that allowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to check their earnings records and benefit entitlements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>,
fearing that snoopers could access the data, called it another illustration of
the Internet's threat to privacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> of the system argued that it's
cheap (saves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">money</NUMEX>), gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> an easy way
to access their own records, has never been abused, and is safer than the mail.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to host a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Camp David</ENAMEX>-like summit ,
the climax to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s proposed shortcut negotiations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said such a commitment might be "premature." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> before,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> had given a speech insisting that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> would not halt the rapid
construction of a controversial housing project in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> or make
further concessions to halt terrorism. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>
told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that negotiation was impossible as long as the construction
continued. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called his talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> "specific," "frank," and
"candid." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s translation: They had it out. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/7</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia/HCA</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s biggest medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>, is becoming the poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> of corporate
health-care greed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' principal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s policy of pegging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' investment returns to profits at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia/HCA</ENAMEX>-affiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>.
This is said to give the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>" an incentive not only to cut
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corners</ENAMEX> (the traditional HMO complaint) but also to send poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> while referring rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> affiliated
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> are investigating whether this is an
illegal conflict of interest, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Stark</ENAMEX> is leading a crusade to stop
the practice. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/7</NUMEX>)
            

            The latest health scare is
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX>-infected school lunches . A batch of frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberries</ENAMEX>
distributed through the federal lunch program caused <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis-A</ENAMEX> liver
infections in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 160</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. Similar batches
were sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, but no
infections have been found there. Early reports blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, whence the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strawberries</ENAMEX> came in violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ban on foreign ingredients in school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lunches</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> blames the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that processed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">berries</ENAMEX>. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> explained that this kind of risk is inherent in a complex
food-distribution system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editorialists</ENAMEX> demanded tighter regulation to make
sure it never happens again. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/4</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
