
   
   
      
         
            

            Update
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> investigation : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) A blood test indicates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX> had consumed anti-depressants as well as too much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police</ENAMEX>
confirmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was going at a speed of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 100 mph</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fayed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> claims photographs show the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> was dazzled by a camera flash before
the accident. The photos were apparently taken from a vehicle ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s last words after the crash were,
"Leave me alone, leave me alone." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> had been snapping
pictures "<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few centimeters</NUMEX> from her face." Bottom line: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> are
leaning toward blaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s speed and intoxication, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paparazzi</ENAMEX> could still be prosecuted for their behavior after the crash.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/10</NUMEX>)
            

            Late
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was eulogized and buried. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifty million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> got up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the wee hours of the morning</TIMEX> to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> on
television. The big story was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s slap at the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was
"someone with a natural nobility who was classless and who ... needed no royal
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> to continue to generate her particular brand of magic." For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, the
royals were scorned as stuffy brutes for failing to display grief in public.
When they relented and displayed their grief, they were likened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (for feeling others' pain) and scorned for pandering to public opinion.
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits belatedly</ENAMEX> conceded that they had covered the story
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obsessively</ENAMEX> based on their false intimacy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and their whitewashed view
of her character. They resumed covering the story obsessively based on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>'s false intimacy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and its whitewashed view of her character.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/8</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX> forced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Messinger</ENAMEX> into a
runoff in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> mayoral primary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 39 percent</NUMEX> in
the three-way race, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharpton</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> attributed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpton</ENAMEX>'s success to outrage over the Louima/plunger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>-brutality case.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX>'s embarrassing failure to win the primary outright means she has to
campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharpton</ENAMEX> without alienating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> she'll need in a
general election against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> concluded
that she's toast. (Also see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/10</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> authorized the constitutional endorsement of economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">privatization</ENAMEX>, and are considering political reforms that could gradually
extend elections from the local to the national level. Currently, privatization
is merely tolerated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> complained that instead of focusing on changes
in the system, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are gossiping about who's in and
who's out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> responded by gossiping
about who's in and who's out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/10</NUMEX>)
            

            Two
developments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> withdrew. They
wanted her to accept <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> and a vague statement from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--which means they'd get paid--but she's holding out for an explicit
apology. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chubb</ENAMEX>) are ending their coverage
of his legal bills and liabilities. This ends the plausibility of a monetary
settlement, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">henceforth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will have to pay out of his own pocket,
something his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> says he won't do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> look forward to embarrassing
depositions. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/10</NUMEX>)
            

            Sunbeam
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chainsaw</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX> sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX> to
make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> endorse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s health-care products exclusively for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> had proposed the endorsement scheme in exchange for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>
in royalties, but then backed out after being denounced for prostituting
itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> of "arrogance" for breaking the contract and
demanded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> in damages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> debated which of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> looks
worse. (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>.")
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/10</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Military Institute</ENAMEX> suspended a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadet</ENAMEX> for hitting a male
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upperclassman</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadet</ENAMEX> was among the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> under
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision. She struck the blow in response to ritual
verbal abuse by several upperclassmen. Civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> called for
scrutiny of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX> suspension, but agree that it's OK as long as the
abuse that provoked her was gender-neutral. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/10</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> also died. Reviews of her career were highly favorable.
Pundits paused to pay their respects before returning to the topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. The proximity of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s deaths inspired a flurry of silly
comparisons, which in turn inspired a backlash of equally silly commentaries
pointing out their differences. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zairian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese Seko</ENAMEX>
died, too. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> ended up being only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to
die during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, coverage of his demise was largely buried.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/8</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prodigy Venus Williams</ENAMEX> lost in the finals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX>. Because
she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> and black (her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> calls her a "ghetto Cinderella"), and because
she's been hyped for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (she got a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> contract at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>), she overshadowed the new men's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heartthrob</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rafter</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martina Hingis</ENAMEX>, who is a year younger than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and creamed her in the finals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> were set to anoint
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX>, but her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> screwed it up by calling her
semifinal opponent a "white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX>" and portraying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s collision
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> during a changeover as "a racial thing." Pressed about these
remarks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> parried, ducked, and fled her press conference. Critics
contrast her arrogance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX>' good manners. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> see a double
standard: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> don't blame white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steffi Graf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Pierce</ENAMEX>) for
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>' misbehavior, so why should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> be blamed for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s?
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/8</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is on
the hot seat in the campaign-finance investigation . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported that some of the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> raised in phone calls from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign ("hard" money) instead of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> ("soft" money). This removes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attorney General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s rationale for not appointing an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. The betting now is
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will be named, and will hound <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Scandal questions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upstaged Gore</ENAMEX>'s feel-good visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> hope that he
may get a real fight in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> primaries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX> are shifting from
defending his innocence to blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for corrupting him. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/8</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Photographs of:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Paul</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>), from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz/Reuters</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Mitchell</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> pool; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa by Joy Shaw</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venus Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martina Hingis</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sell</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
