
   
   
      
         
            

            Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">suicide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 150</NUMEX> at a
vegetable market in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> denounced the bombings,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> government
for freeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> "to prowl in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX>
"cannot continue with negotiations as long as such strikes take place, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> does nothing to stop them." A few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> who saw the
carnage dismissed the current "peace" as a bad joke and called for war against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/30</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> struck a budget deal .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had demanded tax cuts for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX> (as well as for the middle
class), while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> had demanded tax cuts for the upper-middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, and
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> had demanded more spending for their pet programs.
Thanks to the booming economy (and unspecified future spending cuts), all sides
got what they wanted. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> threw out proposed premium
hikes for wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. The consensus is that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have
once again fed us our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> (while telling us it's nourishing and fat-free)
instead of our spinach. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/30</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the campaign-finance hearings: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witnesses</ENAMEX> detailed how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Trie</ENAMEX>
laundered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> in foreign money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> check he handed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had been solicited by Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung</ENAMEX> explained, "I see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is like a subway: You
have to put in coins to open the gates." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stonewall Reno</ENAMEX>" for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) opposing
immunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nuns</ENAMEX> whose testimony might implicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) refusing to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX> testified against accusations that he laundered money
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> vouched that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbour</ENAMEX> was a swell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> of theirs and
that he had acquitted himself brilliantly. Reviews of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> so far:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>--fair and brave; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>--petty and partisan; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX>--honest and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constructive; Torricelli</ENAMEX>--servile and sanctimonious. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/30</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">co-founder Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> is about to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>,
according to various reports. This would complete the return and vindication of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s prodigal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, who had lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long-ago</TIMEX> power struggle with former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sculley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pessimists</ENAMEX> speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>' caustic perfectionism
would make it hard to hire a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimists</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> could supply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s immediate needs: strategic vision and a morale boost for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/30</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> tried <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> for genocide and sentenced him to life under
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> arrest. Editorialists denounced the trial as a "charade" on several
grounds: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He was tried by his own murderous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> instead of an
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>, evidently to gain credibility for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>
within and beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The "trial" consisted of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> of
pep-rally-style denunciations and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> response, without due process. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
There's no reason to think that the sentence will be enforced, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rouge</ENAMEX> refuses to hand him over to anyone else for a real trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX>
who saw video of the trial noted that the aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> didn't look like a man
who killed so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> single-handedly, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">henchmen</ENAMEX> who had helped him
do it are escaping justice, and that one of them (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX>) is on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to becoming the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/30</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cosby</ENAMEX> has taken a blood test to determine whether he is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autumn Jackson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cosby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Schmitt</ENAMEX>. The results are not yet in.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmitt</ENAMEX> said the purpose of the test is to end "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s trial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of
public opinion" by proving that he is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. Since paternity
cannot be established unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> is also tested, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmitt</ENAMEX> challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX>
to comply. This comes after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> was convicted of trying to extort <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/30</NUMEX>)
            

            Case
closed: Alleged "spree killer" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cunanan</ENAMEX> , who was being hunted by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> for the murder of fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX> and others, killed
himself. The premature anticlimax disappointed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, but they continued to
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> the story anyway. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> cleared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carroll O'Connor</ENAMEX> of slander for
calling his deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in murder." The pusher
portrayed the verdict as a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> portrayed it as
a defeat for scum. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reputed Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent "Chin</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigante</ENAMEX> reported to
prison after being convicted of racketeering and conspiracy to murder.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/28</NUMEX>)
            

            The
scandal over deaf <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> slaves widened. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> deaf
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> in "virtual slavery" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ); then similar
rackets were busted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> were smuggled
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, miserably housed, and forced to peddle <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 trinkets</NUMEX> (in
places like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>) to make money for their "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimps</ENAMEX>." The media bemoaned the
vulnerability of illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> (trapped by their fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> will
discover they're illegal) and congratulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayor Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> for rescuing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> slaves. Eventually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> conceded that the conditions
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, which these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> had fled and to which none so far want to
return, were just as bad. "In a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> and marginalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
the deaf are almost invisible," grieved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/28</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> resigned as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> to campaign for the job of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. He has been nominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but Sen.
has vowed to quash the nomination on the grounds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> is soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agree that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> guaranteed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> had almost no
chance of getting the job to begin with; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s caustic remarks about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of weeks</TIMEX> have further doomed his chances; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s
resignation won't help him. The subtle theory is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> knows he will lose
but is positioning himself for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential run in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The crude theory
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> just loves a good fight, particularly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/28</NUMEX>)
            

            DNA
evidence shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> were not our ancestors. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
argued that the research supports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> politically important theories: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Humans
have had so little time to diverge genetically that the differences between
human "races" are trivial, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) our common ancestors came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cro-Magnons</ENAMEX>) and drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>) to extinction. Why didn't
we interbreed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> when they were still around? Because they
were ugly, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/28</NUMEX>)
            

            Miscellany: Retired
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Brennan</ENAMEX> died. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> called him the
greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">jurisprudence</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> noted their
disagreements with him but remembered him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of principle and a truly
nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Fujimori</ENAMEX> is in deep trouble:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> are angry over his alleged illegal wiretapping and suppression of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and newly discovered documents indicate that he may have been born
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>, which would make him ineligible for his job. The
Army discharged a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> decorated veteran <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> before he would
have been eligible for retirement benefits, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> discovered
evidence of his homosexuality after an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arsonist</ENAMEX> torched his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Ullrich</ENAMEX>
became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclist</ENAMEX> to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tour de France</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/28</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
