
   
   
      
         
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, wounding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. This
was the worst clash between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> since the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> peace agreement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is increasingly provoking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> by helping <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biljana Plavsic</ENAMEX> wrest power from her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX>, who remains the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' de facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. Critics
worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s new activism against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karadzic</ENAMEX> will endanger its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and
trap them in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> quagmire. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> Gen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalikashvili</ENAMEX> rejected the idea of involving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in the arrests of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/29</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> withdrew his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. He explained
that if he had stayed in the race, the election would have focused on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">annulment</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s alleged fling with the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal focused on his annulment and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s
alleged fling with the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/29</NUMEX>)
            

            Eugenic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sterilization</ENAMEX> is the hot topic in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedes</ENAMEX> are outraged by reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden</ENAMEX> forcibly sterilized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62,000</NUMEX> "inferior" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the 1930s</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. Targets were evidently chosen by race as well as by mental
capacity. Meanwhile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> disclosed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> forcibly
sterilized retarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> law was used by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> to justify <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> policies. Similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sterilizations</ENAMEX> reportedly are still
forced on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> played up the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> eugenics program as the sick side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>'s
self-styled perfection. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/29</NUMEX>)
            

            Former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX> was indicted for soliciting favors from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> under his purview and then covering them up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> argued
that the favors he accepted (e.g., sports tickets and a crystal bowl) were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trivial</ENAMEX>, adding up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $35,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX> is the third
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to require an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> (along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Cisneros</ENAMEX>) and could soon be joined by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel O'Leary</ENAMEX>).
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/29</NUMEX>)
            

            Straws
in the wind: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boom in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> may be signaling the renewal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
optimism , according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of age discrimination in the workplace have the
same rights as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of race and sex discrimination. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> also endorsed a proposed study to settle the
debate over the benefits of medical marijuana. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> are up, reaching
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26-year</TIMEX> peak, but verbal scores remain low. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> noted that
grades assigned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are being inflated relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Million Woman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> , patterned on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Million Man March</ENAMEX>, is being
planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>. So far, it seems poorly organized.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> are counseling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> to stop eating squirrel brains, lest
they contract mad cow disease. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/29</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> made scores of fund-raising calls from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>,
according to newly released documents. Various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> put the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 70</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>. This updates the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> estimate (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">48</NUMEX>), which updated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s previous characterization ("a few occasions"). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> says
there's no logical inconsistency between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s description and the new
numbers, but the press agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has shown a pattern of fudging. Two
interesting notes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was asked to solicit money from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FedEx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Smith</ENAMEX>, and was briefed with a memo noting that the administration
"has been very responsive to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>." (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and money
mongering, see the campaign-finance-scandal update, below.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> evidently
didn't make this call. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ex-White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Quinn</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, also
made fund-raising calls from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX> isn't covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
excuse that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and veep are exempt from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hatch Act</ENAMEX>. Instead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX> claims his calls weren't fund-raising calls because he was thanking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributors</ENAMEX>, not soliciting them. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/27</NUMEX>)
            

            Abner
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louima</ENAMEX> plans to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie Cochran</ENAMEX> to represent him in a
half-billion-dollar lawsuit against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> brutality ,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> cops have been charged with
assaulting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Haitian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> and buggering him with a toilet plunger,
causing severe injuries. Other racial flash points: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> is considering
whether to court-martial accused sexual harasser/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abuser Sgt. Maj.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> has threatened to focus the trial on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s alleged
selective prosecution of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> for sexual harassment. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> state medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has suspended the license of a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who
had been touted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> as one of affirmative action's success stories.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/27</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> have found a genetic flaw in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ashkenazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> that
doubles the risk of colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> . The official optimistic spin:
Understanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of the flaw will lead to new methods of preventing
colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. The official pessimistic spin: Insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> might use
genetic tests to discriminate against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who carry the flaw. The unofficial
spin: Why are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ashkenazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> predisposed to so many <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examples</ENAMEX>: breast
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tay-Sachs</ENAMEX>, cystic fibrosis.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX>' best theory: too much
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inbreeding</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/27</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> defected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> exulted that he is their biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> catch ever and
could provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with loads of valuable intelligence about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> proliferation. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> responded by canceling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s talks
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, which were supposed to curtail <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>
proliferation. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/27</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the campaign-finance scandal: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> money scandal is converging
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> scandal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> reportedly is investigating
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX>'s campaign in
exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamster</ENAMEX> funding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
demanding a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> and promising congressional investigations. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> subpoenaed records to determine whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX> into giving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> to
then-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel O'Leary</ENAMEX>'s pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africare</ENAMEX>, in order to secure
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> meeting with her. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FedEx</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Smith</ENAMEX> sought favorable trade policies in a private meeting
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FedEx</ENAMEX> was contributing more than half-a-million
dollars to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> records indicate that a jewelry-fraud
ring used illegal third-party campaign donations to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
to pose in photos with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>. It then used the photos in promotional
literature to con <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/25</NUMEX>)
            

            A
federal election monitor decertified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX>'s election as president
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>, citing evidence of fraud and diversion of union funds to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> wasn't directly implicated; but his complicity wasn't
ruled out, either. The official delayed the announcement until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike
was settled, so as not to influence its outcome. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
points out that this decision influenced the strike's outcome. The election
will have to be rerun, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> may have the advantage because he triumphed in
the strike. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hoffa</ENAMEX> the younger, demanded that he step
down. Editorialists lamented that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s campaign against union corruption now
bears the taint of union corruption. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A More</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perfect Unionist</ENAMEX>.") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/25</NUMEX>)
            

            The
government will pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> not to train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> . This nationalizes a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400-million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state subsidy scheme that aims to reduce the surplus of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> argue that the subsidy is idiotic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> argue that it's
less idiotic than the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> policy of subsidizing physician
training, which has exacerbated the surplus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> scheme
had pointed out the unfairness of paying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> to undertake
cutbacks that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> elsewhere were undertaking at no charge. Instead of
equalizing things by scrapping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> payment scheme, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> decided to
equalize things by nationalizing it. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> are pointing out the
unfairness of subsidizing the reduction in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> while refusing
to do the same for other professions, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s
"Yes, We
Have No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians</ENAMEX>.") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/25</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX>
King swore off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson Foods</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> forever. This comes after: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) fecal
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> distributed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson's Nebraska</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> sickened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> obliged <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> to shut down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and undertake the biggest recall in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> history; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) investigators
cited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> for questionable record-keeping and safety practices. The
divorce cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> its biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and inaugurated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX>'s campaign
to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to continue eating its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Editorialists</ENAMEX> conducted the
usual food-scare protocol: calming the public and explaining that risk can
never be eliminated, while decrying ad hoc <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> responses and demanding
stricter laws. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/25</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> are giving up on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> peace deal
"has been undermined, perhaps fatally." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> says it was doomed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vagueness</ENAMEX> and naiveté from the outset. The latest escalation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> of preparing commando attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
territory--including an assassination attempt on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, according to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>--and urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s blockade of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> and its destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>
continued to defy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s demands that he round up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">militants</ENAMEX>. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, among other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> to halt
the spread of violence along their border. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/25</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
