
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> completed his summit with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
Clashes over human rights upstaged collaboration on other matters. First,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s human-rights record during a news conference with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters oohed</ENAMEX> and aahed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
"showed plenty of spine." Then, congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> grilled and lectured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> on the same subject. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, likened <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s liberation of the
slaves, and defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre as being necessary to
preserve "state security." Worst moment: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> asking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to move <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence Hall</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> so he wouldn't have to look at them. On the bright side, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>
promised to "open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> still wider to the outside world" and said that
"without democracy, there can be no modernization." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>
got prestige at home and around the world and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> as
the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy. Editorialists groused about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
persistent evils but grudgingly conceded that it was a good idea to make nice
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> in the hope of reforming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> over the long term.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/31</NUMEX>)
            

            The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nanny Murder Trial</ENAMEX>" ended in a conviction . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">au pair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> was found guilty of second-degree murder for causing fatal injuries to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>-area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. The inside spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s defense,
headlined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX>, blew it by refusing to offer the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> the option of a lesser manslaughter conviction. The cultural spin: This is
what can happen when you leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in the hands of a mysterious au <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>.
The political spin: Should the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> continue sponsoring the
importation of au pairs? The backspin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> should stop working and stay at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, instead of hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nannies</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/31</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
stopped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> from entering its territory. This
once again violates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> resolutions that put <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s military under
international supervision. Both sides will now replay their old game: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> will seek international support for sanctions and perhaps a
military strike, probably to be thwarted by a last-minute <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retraction</ENAMEX>.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of thought: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> once again is proving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">taunting</ENAMEX> and frustrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> once again is proving his
idiocy by galvanizing the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> against him, which had been
disintegrating. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/31</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the campaign-finance scandal: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX>
appeared before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> and denied allegations that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> reversed its decision on an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> project in order to
please <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babbitt</ENAMEX> explained that he had probably lied to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> about being pressured in the matter by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
Ickes, but that he (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX>) was not now lying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> about having lied to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> called it "the closest [thing] to a
quid pro quo " in the scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babbitt</ENAMEX>'s troubles, like
those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, on the corrupting influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> episode is seen as a prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for triggering an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, who could then investigate everything else. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Documents show that two
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> received political help from
an independent conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> secretly funded by conservative moguls. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> agreed to schedule a vote on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> bill in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> cheered. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/31</NUMEX>)
            

            A
consensus is forming on why the stock market pulled out of its nose
dive. The antidote to a crash, as summarized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , is confidence. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> are confident that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy is
stronger than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokers</ENAMEX> and mutual funds handled "sell" orders more
quickly and willingly than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. This reassured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> that they could
get out at a time of their choosing and therefore, that they needn't rush to do
so. Corollary: The "circuit breakers," which suspended trading, backfired.
(What are circuit breakers, and how do they work? See 
                  Slate
               's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>.") <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The
remaining problem is lack of confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> is now putting up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in loans in the hope of
solving this problem, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has agreed to backstop loans to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> . (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/31</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
are debating where the markets will go next . The conventional, feel-good
view is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market withstood its plunge valiantly and will resume
forging ahead. The contrarian view is that the rally happened too soon, that
the market hasn't bottomed out yet, and that it needs to do so in order to
"wash out" its fears--i.e., it needs to finish puking before it can start
eating again. In any event, no one thinks this is a bear market. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX> speculated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the correction would scare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> sufficiently
to cool off the economy, so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> won't have to raise interest rates and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> rally would restore global confidence and fuel recoveries in other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' markets. Sure enough, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that the "salutary" plunge will slow consumer spending nicely and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
overseas markets rebounded. Even hard-hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> rose by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX>. (For
more on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s madness, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Motley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fool</ENAMEX>.") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/29</NUMEX>)
            

            A
western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> allegedly has infected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> , and perhaps many
others, with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> . According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, he seduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> by
lurking around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and had sex with them despite knowing he had
the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>. The youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> is up in arms because he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evidently</ENAMEX> had sex with many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> there as well. The story is igniting two
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">controversies: 1</ENAMEX>) Can the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> be convicted of a crime? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX>
plans to charge him with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> counts of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree assault, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> says "he should be prosecuted for attempted murder." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
confidentiality laws too strict? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authorities</ENAMEX> had to get an unprecedented court
order to allow the release of his name so that they can find, warn, and test
his sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and their subsequent sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, who may number in the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/29</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Basketball Association</ENAMEX> hired its first female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">referees</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX> said they should be prepared to be patted on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">buttocks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX> announced his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX> Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Capps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, died of a heart attack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' lawyers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subpoenaed Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> . The federal deficit fell to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22.6 billion</NUMEX>, the
lowest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tried to make a big deal about it, but
everyone was distracted by the stock market. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> with the West in order to avoid a "fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>." Tests show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> was sober when he died in a plane crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/29</NUMEX>)
            

            About
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Million Woman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>. The main
themes: the status of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, family unity, repentance, and renewal. Other
topics: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, homelessness, and civil rights. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Million Man March</ENAMEX>,
this event was organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphians</ENAMEX> unconnected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX>.
The closest thing to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> figure was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heroine</ENAMEX>-turned-villainess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie Madikizela-Mandela</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Conyers Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine Waters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, whose demand
for a probe of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> drug-peddling in black neighborhoods--unsubstantiated by any
evidence--was played up by march <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>. There was also a pitch for
racially segregated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Parks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coretta Scott King</ENAMEX> declined to
attend. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> saw the march, along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Million Man</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> rally, as a sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are giving up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and are organizing to solve social problems themselves.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/27</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Marlins</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> . They became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> wild-card
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> and the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">club</ENAMEX> (they were founded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>) to win the
Series. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Sentimentalists</ENAMEX> cheered the triumph of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Leyland</ENAMEX>,
who had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33 years</TIMEX> without a championship ring, but lamented the
defeat of the plucky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, who haven't won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49 years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> complained of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX>' sloppy play but applauded the epic <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Game</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlins</ENAMEX>, down to the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outs of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their season</TIMEX>, eked out
the tying run and won in extra innings. Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> anointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baseman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Fernandez</ENAMEX> the goat for missing a ground ball that ended up
deciding the game--forgetting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernandez</ENAMEX>'s previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-RBI single was the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were still in the game. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>
discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX> in a 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>.")
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C. United</ENAMEX> won its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League Soccer</ENAMEX> championship.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/27</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> dumped his
longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viking</ENAMEX>, and is seeking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $17 million</NUMEX> for his new
book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> see this as a milestone in the publishing industry's descent
into the madness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> free agency , which has already overtaken
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> compensation, and professional sports. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Patterns: 1</ENAMEX>) Loyalty is
dead. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> is demanding more money than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can possibly
earn from his services. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) All it takes is one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>--and there are plenty of
them--to pay him the money anyway, thereby accelerating the madness. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superstar</ENAMEX> expects the industry to justify his compensation by finding new
revenue streams. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX> are eating up all the available money and
crowding out new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/27</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
