
   
   
      
         
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> banned federal funding of research on human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloning</ENAMEX> .
He also urged privately funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> not to clone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. A bill was
filed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> to ban human cloning outright. Contrary to the traditional
objection to birth control--that it permits sex without reproduction--critics
of cloning are increasingly objecting that it permits reproduction without sex.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/7</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Underplayed : A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> announced that he has made <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>
behave like quails by replacing their embryonic brain cells with quail brain
cells. The media, consumed by the frenzy over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">cloning</TIMEX>, have largely ignored the
brain-transplant story. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> point out that transplanting animal
tissue into human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryos</ENAMEX> is far more imminent than human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloning</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> are already implanting fetal pig cells in the brains of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> raised the specter of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
socially unacceptable behavior being forced to undergo brain surgery."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/7</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rebels</ENAMEX>
holding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> broke off talks
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. They claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are preparing to storm the building
by digging a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tunnel</ENAMEX>-digging story is plausible, but that if it's true, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fujimori</ENAMEX> doesn't know about it. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/7</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Flooding 
               along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio River</ENAMEX> has killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, driven many
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> from their homes, and destroyed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $400 million</NUMEX> worth of
property from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/7</NUMEX>)
            

            A panel
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> conceded that a planned robot mission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> might bring back
harmful alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">microorganisms</ENAMEX> . But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> said it's very unlikely
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX> germs could do much damage here, since they probably can't compete
with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s own germs. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/7</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX>
announced that they have ruled out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">half-brother</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> in her murder, evidently because both were out of town
when the crime was committed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Locals</ENAMEX> are said to be increasingly suspicious of
the refusal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to be interviewed separately by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.
Material collected from under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s fingernails--possibly tissue scraped
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>--is reportedly being examined by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/7</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund-raising scandal is closing in on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
made private phone calls (some from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>) soliciting donations. The
report prompted further calls for an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, on the grounds that a
high government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>) had violated the law by making political calls
from a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Editorialists</ENAMEX> derided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s response that the law
doesn't apply to him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> suggested that their end (getting
re-elected and thereby helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) justified their means (using
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to raise money). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> also released records showing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> had used his official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> for a reception for
high-dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> are bewailing the shattering of
their faith that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Honest Man</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. The betting
now is that he's in for a stiff primary challenge in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5</NUMEX>)
            

            New
disclosures in the scandal: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> was paid far more money in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> after his
resignation than had been previously thought, much of it from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> endorsed a project in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> that was
financially important to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riady</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> just after a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riady</ENAMEX>-controlled company
put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> on its payroll. Whitewater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subpoenaed White House</ENAMEX> records, evidently to find out whether the
Riady-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo Group</ENAMEX> paid hush money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> to prevent him from
cooperating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>'s chief of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>--from an alleged "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">hustler</ENAMEX>" deeply embroiled in the scandal.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/7</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the investigation: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> decided that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> fund-raising
probe will cover congressional as well as presidential campaigns, but will
concern itself with only "illegal activities," not soft money. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Attorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> concluded that laws prohibiting political fund
raising in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> apply only to direct campaign contributions,
not to soft money. This lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> off the hook, which, in turn, reduces the chances <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> will
authorize an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Intelligence Committee</ENAMEX> announced
an investigation of possible efforts by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to influence
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s elections. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> called the scandal "much bigger
... than <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> a hypocrite, since he was
recently reprimanded for unethical fund raising. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/7</NUMEX>)
            

            Echoes
of the scandal abroad: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> replied to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> criticism of its
human-rights abuses by accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of corruption for letting its
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> sell face time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
Party is demanding an investigation of a report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX>
orchestrated an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX> donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tories</ENAMEX> from a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> welcomed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and
criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>.
out the carpet" to enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s prestige and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) sending <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> a warning
not to screw up the peace process by provoking further conflict. News accounts
agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> has finally shed his image as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> and is now being
honored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> not only as a virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of state but as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">indispensable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the peace process. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5</NUMEX>)
            

            The
balanced-budget constitutional amendment failed--as expected. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66-34</NUMEX> in favor of it, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote shy of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority needed.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> reported that "confidential defense reports" show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX> confessed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing. The document in
question appears to consist of notes taken by a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> during an
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> indicated that his team
had faked the putative confession in order to persuade a witness to talk to
them, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> has now confirmed that the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> told him of the fake confession <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. The executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> dismissed the fabrication theory as ad hoc damage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5</NUMEX>)
            

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX>, pressured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>,
rushed 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> through naturalization <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and ended up
granting citizenship to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>--if not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>--of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who should have
been rejected because of past felony convictions. Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is
at the center of the controversy. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> indicate that the pressure came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and was driven in
part by hopes of registering new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> have identified
another obesity gene . The gene creates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">UCP2</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that determines
whether an animal burns calories or stores them as fat. The next step is to
develop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to influence the gene and thereby treat obesity. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/3</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
