
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> concluded his summit with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, and nearly everyone declared it a success. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> agreed
to reduce nuclear<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-missile warheads</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> acquiesced to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> accepted an expanded
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-cynical view is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> hasn't made its
peace with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion, but is just too weak to stop it. The completely
cynical view is that there is no reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should care about
this distinction. (For a primer on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>.")
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> is back in the spotlight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund-raising
scandal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX>
paid Hubbell <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100,000</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riady</ENAMEX>'s having spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX>
visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riady</ENAMEX> had also met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> supplants last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s scandal poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Tamraz</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> and
accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embezzler</ENAMEX> with past ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCCI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamraz</ENAMEX> got into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
events after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> enlisted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to try to
dissuade a national-security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> from keeping him out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24</NUMEX>)
            

            Other
news on the scandal: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that documents
released by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> show that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> set explicit fund-raising
targets for coffees with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> descent waged a
proxy battle over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy by funneling campaign contributions to
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Pressler</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX> is returning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22,000</NUMEX> in campaign donations, mostly from
Lippo-connected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> fund-raising hypocrisy watch: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) A former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> , who is chairing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> investigation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> money scandal, threatened to deny him access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> because he failed to satisfy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s demand
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> in campaign money. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> hit up investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>
contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> shortly after working on financial-deregulation
legislation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> released documents indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> sold
big political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> meals with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/19</NUMEX>)
            

            Zairian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese Seko</ENAMEX> returned home from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in a last-ditch
attempt to salvage some part of the power he once held. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> see no real
future for him: He is gradually dying of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> and has no leverage
because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> are getting whipped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, who are expected to roll
through the capital sometime soon. Instead of a military victory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> now
seems to be angling for some kind of coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, playing off his
chief political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> against the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the rebel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The general consensus is that the rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> holds all the aces. (For
            

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> "gave a green light for attacks" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamas</ENAMEX> took credit for a suicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> who killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystanders</ENAMEX>
and wounded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> more. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> dampened criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s
refusal to halt an inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">settlement</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, and
stepped up pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> to crack down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24</NUMEX>)
            

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> recommended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> mammograms for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in their
40s. This contradicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Cancer Institute</ENAMEX> advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s recent
recommendation that the benefits to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40s</NUMEX> didn't necessarily
justify the cost, and that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should decide for themselves whether to
undergo the test. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>, under heavy political pressure, is expected to
reverse that recommendation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. The prevailing wisdom now is that the
"decide for yourself" advice was too confusing, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> need to be told
exactly what to do. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
may soon get its hands on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> air-base bombing .
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have detained a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> suspected of driving either
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> or the getaway car used in the bombing, which killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and wounded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> others. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Abdel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahim Sayegh</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite Muslim</ENAMEX> possibly connected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>-supported
terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX>, which they suspect is responsible for the bombing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sayegh</ENAMEX> deported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for
questioning, thereby circumventing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> who have frustrated the
efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to investigate the bombing.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> basketball tournament : The Final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> are set. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spoiler</ENAMEX>, having ousted tournament favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> and the only remaining
dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX>, which was led by the memorable point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> God
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shammgod</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, the defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>, has staggered through despite
injuries that have reduced its roster to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outsider</ENAMEX>, getting its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Final Four</ENAMEX> berth ever after having been denied an
invitation to the tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> is the comeback
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>, redeeming itself after having lost its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> conference games this
season. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passed the partial-birth-abortion ban , as expected. The vote was
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">295-136</ENAMEX>--better than a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority--which means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the
ban must once again depend on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to sustain a presidential veto.
Despite all the hoopla over a pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>'s confession that he had lied
about the circumstances under which the procedure is generally used, only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> switched their votes from "no" to "yes." (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abortion Apostate</ENAMEX>" on
the partial-birth abortion debate.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/21</NUMEX>)
            

            The
tobacco industry suffered a potentially catastrophic defection. The
smallest of the major tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liggett Group</ENAMEX>, agreed to a
settlement with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> who had sued to recoup money
spent on health care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>. The media focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liggett</ENAMEX>'s admissions of
the obvious--that cigarettes are addictive and cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and heart
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX>--and its agreement to pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> a quarter of its (relatively
small) pretax profits for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 25 years</TIMEX>. The more important concessions,
however, were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liggett</ENAMEX>'s admission that the industry had consciously marketed
tobacco to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> (which will increase congressional support for stiff
regulation of the industry) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) its release--temporarily blocked by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--of documents from strategy meetings among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
biggest tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, which industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> believe will prove a
conspiracy of deceit. Also, the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> who told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> they
didn't consider nicotine addictive might now be prosecuted for fraud and
perjury. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liggett</ENAMEX>'s motive, industry and financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> speculated
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liggett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> hoped to make the marginally profitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> a more
attractive merger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> by eliminating its exposure to possibly huge jury
awards. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/21</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> nominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Tenet</ENAMEX> to become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> replaces the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Lake</ENAMEX>, who withdrew
earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>'s reasons: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s demands for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files,
new questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s role in the foreign-money scandal, and further
unpleasant hearings on top of the pounding he's already taken. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> had gone "haywire" and worn out his patience and dignity. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
noted the echoes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>'s suicide note, but weren't buying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">martyrdom</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>'s case. Their reactions: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> had shown poor ethical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX> and would have been lousy at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> job anyway. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX> for
succumbing to a couple of right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">punks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Shelby</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inhofe</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> pose is pretentious and self-serving. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nominee</ENAMEX>-stoning
is what the two-party system and separation of powers are for. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
are reaping what they sowed (after torturing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tower</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fault for creating the foreign-money
scandal and thereby bringing suspicion and scrutiny on everything <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> did. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>)
Once again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> failed to "go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX>" for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> in trouble. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-nominee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Herman</ENAMEX>, who was closer to the fund-raising mess,
will now be confirmed easily because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is satisfied with having killed
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/21</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
News <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Westin</ENAMEX> is the latest star in the network news soap
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> implied that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX>'s predecessor, the legendary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roone Arledge</ENAMEX>, is being kicked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is losing the ratings war
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>. The rap on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX> is that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> who has no
news experience. The counter-arguments are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) neither did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arledge</ENAMEX> (he came
from the sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arledge</ENAMEX> will tutor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX> for a while. The
substantive issue at stake is hard news vs. soft news: Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is accusing
the others of going soft in pursuit of ratings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westin</ENAMEX> says he wants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> to get
back to hard news. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are swarming over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX>'s alleged
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherrie Rollins</ENAMEX>, who not only was his direct
subordinate but is still married to multiply disgraced political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollins</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/19</NUMEX>)
            

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> announced that a new strategy for treating tuberculosis
could save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> lives over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>. The treatment, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOTS</ENAMEX>,
consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> drugs taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> under meticulous supervision. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> calls it "the biggest health breakthrough of this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/19</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
