
   
   
      
         
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> released videotapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s coffees with
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. The tapes were made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> (i.e.,
recorded in the open) and cover only <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first few minutes</TIMEX> of each coffee
(i.e., introductions and small talk). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> says the tapes show
nothing illegal. Questions: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Why is the audio missing from the most important
clip--the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> allegedly made an introductory pitch for
campaign contributions? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> calls this "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Mary Woods</ENAMEX>
problem," referring to the infamous <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18-and-</NUMEX>a<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-half-minute</TIMEX> gap on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>'s tape. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Why were the tapes turned over only after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> specifically asked for videotapes--and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only hours</TIMEX> after Attorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> cleared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of alleged campaign-finance
violations--despite previous congressional subpoenas demanding all records
relevant to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fund raising? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> now are raising the possibility
of obstruction of justice and demanding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> reconsider her decision to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clear Clinton</ENAMEX>. Regardless of the tapes' content, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are looking forward to
another orgy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> comparisons. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/6</NUMEX>)
            

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assembly</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>;
confess their selfishness and sexual sins; and take leadership in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of advocating a
return to patriarchy. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> showed up, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> applauded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for promising "to reassume their responsibilities to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s buildup to the assembly focused on gender
controversies--but the assembly focused more on racial reconciliation, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> behaved humbly, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> forswore political plans or motives.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> finally acquitted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> of the charge that they are
divisive and leveled the more serious charge that they are boring. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> was at the rally--check out his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch</ENAMEX>."
Also read this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Stodghill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marci McDonald</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/6</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
botched an assassination attempt on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> . According to various
reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) infuriated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> by infiltrating that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and staging
the attack there; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) infuriated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> by forging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
passports for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) bungled the attack, leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>'
arrest; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) was forced to release the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> (who was serving a life
sentence) and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> and to supply an
antidote for the lethal nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> used in the attack, in order to assuage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s anger; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) aroused such fury at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> reportedly will have to release the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> he has
rounded up and reopen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Domestic and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> and added that
the attack was so stupid and potentially calamitous that he's lucky he screwed
it up. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/6</NUMEX>)
            

            Now
they tell us: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s diary tapes (not to be confused with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tapes) show him admitting that he "blew it" when he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">picked Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> as his running mate, according to a new book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was referring to how the selection was managed, not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> himself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The same book says that at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican convention</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>: "I have strong reservations about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>. I'm
concerned about turning the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> over to him." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) According to another book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tapes (not to be confused with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tapes) indicate he suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> of complicity
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s assassination but feared that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military response
would trigger nuclear war. (To listen to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> tapes, click here.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that he showed no signs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> during his presidency. The alternative explanation for his
mental lapses: indifference to detail. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) At a forum on mental illness this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX> said he shouldn't have dumped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Eagleton</ENAMEX> from
his ticket in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/6</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">atrocity</ENAMEX> watch : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Militants 1</ENAMEX>) decapitated or cut the throats of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) similarly massacred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) slaughtered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) attacked a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> and killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, some of whom were shot through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/6</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> is launching a campaign against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> , alleging "a strange type of monopolistic practice" that controls
"content and innovation" rather than price. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott McNealy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Reback</ENAMEX> will speak at an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> conference
organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, is threatening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
with hostile legislation or obstruction of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX>' license renewals
unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> adopts the new sex-and-violence ratings system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX> is
offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $1,000</NUMEX> for news tips, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> says it's OK because
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> (not "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of stories or anyone connected to them")
are eligible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> says bowling is all the rage in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/6</NUMEX>)
            

            Paint
traces may indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> collided with a black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX>
just before the fatal crash. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signal</ENAMEX>-light fragments found at the scene also
bolster the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-car theory, coinciding with eyewitness testimony that a car
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>, possibly carrying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>, weaved in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> just before the crash. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> who survived the crash has recovered
partial memory of events before the crash, but evidently can't answer whether a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX> struck <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> say he might eventually recover his memory of
the crash itself. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/3</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> announced plans to block imports of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with weak food-inspection systems. Consumer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> said the measures are too weak (they don't set the same standards
abroad that apply here). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Free-trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> said they are too strong (they
may prompt retaliatory measures from affected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> said they
are driven by political rather than safety concerns (the plan may garner votes
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fast-track trade negotiating proposals among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> fearing
influxes of contaminated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is expected to welcome the measures.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/3</NUMEX>)
            

            
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> are taking charge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX>
accepted financial support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutherford Institute</ENAMEX>, which has assisted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> in various legal fights. At <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rutherford</ENAMEX>'s recommendation, Jones
also hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that has defended pro-lifers, student prayer, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> sodomy law. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> see this as bad news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the
settlement front (since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> seem eager to go to trial) but good
news on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> front (since it plays into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> line that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is a
puppet of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> noted that in her press conference,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> spoke only when given permission by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX>. (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>.")
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/3</NUMEX>)
            

            Bosnian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muslims</ENAMEX> reportedly are arming for an overwhelming assault on Bosnian
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "The question no
longer is if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> will attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX>, but when," and that
"the only way to prevent such an attack ... is for the peacekeeping mission to
extend its mandate" beyond the deadline by which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are supposed to
pull out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> leaked the bad news
to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> not to pull out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also concluded that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy of equipping and training <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> may not be such a
bright idea. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/3</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott</ENAMEX>
Krueger, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> fraternity pledge, died of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> poisoning after a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. This has rekindled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> and outrage sparked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>
by the similar death of a pledge at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana State University</ENAMEX>. The high-minded
spin: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases underscore an epidemic of binge drinking in frats and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> in general. The naughty spin: How could this have happened at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>,
where, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are supposed to be smart? (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/1</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Catholic Conference of Bishops</ENAMEX> called for acceptance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> said homosexual orientation "cannot be
considered sinful," because it "is experienced as a given." The catch: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gays</ENAMEX>
must remain "chaste," which means avoiding "genital sexual involvement" with
same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> called their position old news, but gay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>
found the shift in emphasis significant. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/1</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> proposed to amend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>-Feingold bill to
ban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> from funneling dues to political activity without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' explicit
consent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agreed that he's using the amendment to make the bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unpalatable</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> so they'll kill reform and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> will be on their
hands. Editorialists admired and reviled his diabolical shrewdness. Critics
argued <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> can quit a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> if they don't like its political activities and
that any debate about regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> money should be taken up separately.
Even if enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> join <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to kill the amendment, more would be
needed to defeat the filibuster that has already been promised. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s
take, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chronicle of a Death Foretold</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>.)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/1</NUMEX>)
            

            More
miscellany: Capitalizing on frayed relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Telecom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>,
WorldCom outbid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BT</ENAMEX> by offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy" McCaughey Ross</ENAMEX> switched from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were glad to get rid of her. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> gave her only a
perfunctory welcome. Ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Rose Oakar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, will plead guilty
to evading campaign-finance laws. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hooters</ENAMEX> settled a discrimination
lawsuit by shelling out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.75 million</NUMEX> and agreeing to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--as support
staff, not as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX>, thereby preserving the tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hooters Girls</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/1</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX>-art icon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> died . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obituaries</ENAMEX> generally celebrated him for countering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">texture</ENAMEX> and esoteric expression with irreverence and ironic wit, and for being
an all-around nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> said he "made the vulgar
chic" and "the ersatz ... authentic." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/1</NUMEX>)
            

             

         
      
   
