
   
   
      
         
            

            Update
on the campaign-finance scandal hearings : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn.</ENAMEX>, disclosed that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> check that scandal figure <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX>
handed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was funded by a
transfer from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> called the news "an apparent direct hit."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Brownback</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>, summarized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>'s compensation package at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> as "No raise money, no get bonus." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownback</ENAMEX> used no accent and
immediately said that he had meant "no slight." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownback</ENAMEX>'s
remark "completely racist." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>,
announced that he had evidence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> plot to infiltrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, but couldn't say more because the evidence is top secret. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> is considering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>'s offer to testify in exchange for partial
immunity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> pronounced the hearings "a cultural bust."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> agreed: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Partisan Fencing Draws No Blood</ENAMEX>." For
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/11</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> arrested a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> war criminal and killed another who resisted
arrest. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> arrests will follow. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>
speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> wants to gauge the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX>' reaction (e.g., possible
assaults against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>) before deciding whether a full-scale roundup
of war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> is worth the risk. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> coverage was generally
enthusiastic, with several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> celebrating the bust as an overdue
outburst of courage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> managed to get credit for it without
risking a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> provided logistical
support. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is only picking at the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> because
more senior war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are too well guarded. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/11</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>
landed a robot on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> and began exploring the surface. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> are
steering the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-foot-long</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23-pound</NUMEX> robot by remote control (from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119 million</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> away) and downloading the video and geological data it collects. Evidence
of ancient flood <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (which might now be frozen at the poles or beneath the
planet's surface) and signs of repeated melting and crystallization of the
planet's crust indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> is much more like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> than was previously
thought. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s reaction: "It's going to be a bummer if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> turns out
to be like us." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/11</NUMEX>)
            

            Best
story from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> summit : In a chat with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX>, an
open mike caught <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Chr√</ENAMEX>©tien ragging on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chr√©tien</ENAMEX> said: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> policies are
motivated by domestic politics, not statesmanship (specifically, pushing to
include the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baltic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in order to win ethnic votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Chr√©tien
has a "policy" of defying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. He boasted that this is great domestic
politics in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. Specifically, he said he enjoyed defying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policy
against commerce with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chr√©tien</ENAMEX> helped resolve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
dispute over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> confided, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX>, you saved my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bacon</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> emulated their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, "all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> would be in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, because they sell their
votes." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> found the remarks "funny," but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> demanded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chr√</ENAMEX>©tien apologize to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/11</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> confirmed the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> known case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
transmission 
               through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> kissing . The report explained that
although <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX> is a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> of the virus, in this case both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">gum disease</ENAMEX>, which evidently allowed blood-to-blood transmission. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
voted to dismantle the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX> , but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the
margin was a single vote, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> has more support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will veto the bill if necessary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also rejected a clause in the
big tobacco settlement that would restrict the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to regulate cigarettes . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> wondered whether this will
kill the deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Shabazz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> pleaded guilty to deliberately
setting the fire that burned her to death. Since he's just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years old</TIMEX>, the
maximum sentence is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX> in detention. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ValuJet</ENAMEX> is escaping its past by
marrying another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> and changing its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AirTran</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Amelio</ENAMEX> resigned , prompting several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to ask whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is headed for extinction. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/11</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> staged a successful coup against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. The victors began looting, and hunting down
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of whom have already been executed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> foresee <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible outcomes: brutal tyranny (the optimistic
scenario) or bloody civil war. This follows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s history of: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) massive
genocide; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a decade-long civil war; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in foreign aid
to restore democracy, which now seem to have been wasted. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/9</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s ruling party lost control of the national assembly for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68 years</TIMEX>. It was the longest-reigning political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the
world. Reasons for the defeat: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> were sick of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s lousy
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) they were sick of the ruling party's tradition of rigging
elections; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) this time, the ruling party neglected to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the election.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernesto Zedillo</ENAMEX> executed one of history's most impressive
post-election spin jobs, portraying his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s defeat as proof of the climate
of freedom and democracy he has fostered. Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has lost its grip,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> foresee a wave of opportunistic defections by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, as happened
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Democrats</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/9</NUMEX>)
            

            Boxing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> revoked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX>'s license to fight and fined him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
million for biting off part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evander Holyfield</ENAMEX>'s ear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> can apply for
reinstatement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimists</ENAMEX> called the penalty stiff and predicted that
it would restore some standard of decency to the sport. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pessimists</ENAMEX> pointed out
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> gets to keep <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27 million</NUMEX> he earned from the fight and can take his
services overseas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> rated the bite the most disgusting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> in the
history of sports. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/9</NUMEX>)
            

            Sports
news: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Indians</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Alomar Jr.</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s All-Star
Game for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> with a two-run, seventh-inning home run in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martina Hingis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Sampras</ENAMEX> won the women's and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s
tennis championships at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> . Sportswriters lionized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hingis</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wunderkind</ENAMEX> (she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>) and
Sampras as arguably the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> ever (he's on track to shatter the
record for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s grand slam titles). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s runner-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jana Novotna</ENAMEX> choked away
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>-set lead in the finals for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time but managed (unlike last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>) not to cry on the shoulder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kent</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/9</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Doctors</ENAMEX>
reported that fenfluramine and phentermine, a popular diet pill
combination, may cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">severe heart-valve disease</ENAMEX> . The story is all over
front pages and the TV news because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> are prescribed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20 million</NUMEX>
times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> is sending warnings to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. The news cycle on drug scares has become so fast that the backlash
(accusing the new report of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-hyping the heart-disease link and ignoring the
benefits of reduced obesity) is already underway. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/9</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> finally relinquished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> agreed that
capitalism will continue to flourish there even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> doesn't: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Friedman</ENAMEX> noted that replicas of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goddess of</ENAMEX>
Democracy" (erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>), which were
being peddled by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>, were "Made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>." The first bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">omen</ENAMEX>: On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> said textbooks must
remain neutral in their descriptions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

            More
Miscellany: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> formally admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> successfully pressured its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> to postpone a
similar decision on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovenia</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. The investigation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s alleged affair with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> is being
dropped because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> won't cooperate. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> decided
to give domestic-partnership benefits to gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> instead of letting
them marry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX> announced its purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop Grumman</ENAMEX>,
completing the defense industry's consolidation into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that recently won fame for cloning a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> is
reportedly on the verge of deriving human blood plasma from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>. A
new scientific report claims that puberty begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as the age of 6</TIMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> was charged with murdering her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> by whacking him with
a computer keyboard. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/9</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX>,

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mitchum</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Kuralt</ENAMEX> died. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contrasted Stewart</ENAMEX> (the idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>) with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchum</ENAMEX> (the hard-living
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rogue</ENAMEX>) and juxtaposed both of them--"the last of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> era," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>-- with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s mediocre movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> paired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuralt</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> of virtue
and the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> ceaselessly glorified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuralt</ENAMEX>'s
television journalism. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/7</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
