
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX> was found guilty on all counts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX>
bombing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX>, having exaggerated the defense's options and prospects
for dramatic effect throughout the trial, finally conceded that the contest had
never been close. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Editorialists</ENAMEX> congratulated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for proving
(in contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>) that the criminal-justice
system works. While proclaiming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has finally lost its
virgin naiveté about domestic terrorism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> scratched their heads over why
the trial didn't mesmerize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> cases
did. Next, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> will consider whether to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> the death penalty.
Having milked the trial for pathos, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> applauded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for
instructing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> not to manipulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s emotions. The early line
on the coming trial of alleged co-conspirator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> is that he'll be a
lot harder to convict because he was home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> went off in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/5</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> commenced settlement talks through
the media. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> camp's spin: She wants her good name back. The threat: to
focus the trial on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s relations "with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>" and make him spend
the rest of his presidency being hounded about his privates instead of showing
off his public service. Settlement demands: his admission that she told the
truth, plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> in damages, and compensation for her emotional pain. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp's spin: She and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are in it for the bucks. The threat:
"to put her reputation at issue," dredging up old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>. Settlement
proposal: a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> donation to her chosen charity, plus some part of her
legal costs, but "no apology" and "no admission of misconduct." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization for Women</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for stooping to the old tactic of bringing up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>'s sexual
history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> urged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "quit besmirching
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> and settle the case, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stop seeing him as a likable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rogue</ENAMEX> and start seeing him as an unlikable rogue." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/5</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> held a parliamentary election. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Chrétien</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrist Liberal Party</ENAMEX> retained its majority. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberals</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
seats. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) they won a mandate for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal</TIMEX> austerity program, sort
of. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can only admire an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> readier than their own to
administer a bitter but necessary medicine," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .)
Meanwhile, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>-separatist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> won big in the West and
became the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Chrétien nearly lost his seat to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quebec</ENAMEX> separatist. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> lost seats overall. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX>, confused by the results, accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of confusion and warned
that regional conflicts within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> could destabilize its relations with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> blamed the weak showing of
economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> in recent elections--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--on those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' insufficient economic conservatism. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/5</NUMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethics-commission</ENAMEX> report solicited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will recommend that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> be allowed to clone human embryos for experiments, according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . However, the report recommends a ban on
implanting these embryos in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and developing them into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>. Pro-lifers
attacked the proposal for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) inviting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to toy with human life and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
then requiring them to abort it. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> argued that if human-embryo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cloning</ENAMEX> remains legal in the private sector but illegal in government-funded
research, unsupervised quacks will control it. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> decided
not to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to ban human-embryo cloning outright, reportedly because
they trust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> even less than they trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. Related updates:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Chromosomes Transplanted Into Mice</ENAMEX>" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>); "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rush Is on for Cloning of Animals</ENAMEX>" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3</TIMEX>).
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/5</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, will block the nomination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Weld</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had hoped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s nomination would foster bipartisan harmony. Instead, it has fostered
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> disharmony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> cited conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' quarrels with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>
(who favors medical marijuana and abortion rights) as evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> isn't
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> quality." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> and try to remove the thorn from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paw</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/5</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> booted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> out of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> and
put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX> in power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greens</ENAMEX>, and other leftist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> won a majority of seats, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Chirac</ENAMEX>'s center-right
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalition</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> its seats. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> agreed that, unlike the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Labor Party</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialists</ENAMEX> won on an unreformed welfare-state
platform: creating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350,000</NUMEX> government jobs without raising taxes, and cutting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> without cutting salaries. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> Reject
Austerity in Favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>," asserted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' headline. But
few thought that an available choice. The most common view was that the
election was a huge blow to the global spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-led fiscal austerity and
privatization. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ironists</ENAMEX> noted that, as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, "liberal" has
become a dirty word in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>--but in the sense of classical liberalism, i.e.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conservativism</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/2</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> swished a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX> at the buzzer to carry the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> past the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
Jazz in the opening game of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Basketball Association</ENAMEX> finals.
Jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Malone</ENAMEX>, who edged out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s vote for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Valuable Player</ENAMEX>, gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> the game-winning opportunity by
bricking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> free throws with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine seconds</TIMEX> left. Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX>
"choked" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ), and regretted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MVP</ENAMEX> vote can't be
reconsidered. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for a recount," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Chronicle</ENAMEX> .
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/2</NUMEX>)
            

            The
homicide rate fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. The media
called it an "impressive" decline (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> raced to take credit for their creative and diligent
law-enforcement efforts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminologists</ENAMEX> cited other factors: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Baby boomers</ENAMEX>
have passed their crime-committing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) A lot of would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> have
been killed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> are sick of all the murders and don't want to add to the
body count. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> have sorted out many of their territorial disputes.
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> observed that serious dog bites have
increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> did not connect the two phenomena.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/2</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> won redemption at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX> awards . The show, which had
been faulted and ridiculed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, won the award for best musical, plus the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other categories in which it had been nominated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
called this "sweet vindication." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> actually won more awards (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>),
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> were less impressed, since it had been expected to do well.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Night</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballyhoo</ENAMEX> won the award for best play, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Doll</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> won for best revival of a play. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/2</NUMEX>)
            

            The
controversy over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> escalated. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX> was found murdered, reportedly after having sold an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> said they had arrested an armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> in the process of abducting an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> land <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>, evidently
for execution. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> has fingered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
security-agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> in the previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> executions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
says human-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are calling attention to "the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
death <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squads</ENAMEX>," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> public
supports the executions. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/2</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: The new health scare is a staph germ that is becoming immune
to the antibiotic of last resort. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">germ</ENAMEX> has appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and the
question is how long it will take to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The new
bioethical controversy is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> should obey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who want to
freeze the sperm of their deceased loved ones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yankees</ENAMEX> finally
signed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star pitcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hideki Irabu</ENAMEX>. Baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, having hyped Irabu
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, began questioning whether he's been overhyped. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> is
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> with a chest infection. News <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> declared it "potentially
fatal" but acknowledged in the fine print that he'll probably come out fine.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Sealfon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> won the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th National Spelling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bee</ENAMEX> . The media construed her histrionics and rudeness as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> charm.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/30</NUMEX>)
            

            Overseas update:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> 's ruling party overwhelmingly won re-election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>
credited the victory to a near-totalitarian patronage system. Military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX> (primer--it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west Africa</ENAMEX>) ousted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s first
democratically elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in a coup. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> then sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to
challenge the coup, evidently to restore the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and repair <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s
corrupt image abroad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> began backing away from his pledge to
remove <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>, which had replaced his previous
pledge to remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1997</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> for a day of photo ops, obliging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> to point
out once again how similar the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/30</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
