
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> announced that he will pay his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> ethics "assessment" (i.e.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fine</ENAMEX>) out of his own money. The catch: He will borrow that money from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. The terms: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> annual interest, no payments required until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> figured that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> had paid the fine out of his campaign kitty or
a legal defense fund, he would have been forced from office. Instead, the loan
allows him to serve out the maximum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, at which point he
can repay the loan out of his campaign kitty or a legal defense fund. The
short-term betting says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> has quelled the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> mutiny against him
and bought himself time to regain his stature as a policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. Liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and editorialists, having warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> that he would be evading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> and creating a conflict of interest if he failed to pay the fine with
his own money, accused him of evading justice and creating a conflict of
interest when he agreed to pay the fine with his own money. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/18</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> recommended
indictments against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> , his justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>. The charges concern an alleged deal to
appoint an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> who would go soft on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>
subsequently quit). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> quickly concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> was in grave
trouble, then backed off after learning that the proposed indictment against
him rested largely on the testimony of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>. The growing scandal is
expected to hinder the peace process by preoccupying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, weakening his
hold over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s extreme right, and discouraging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> from forming
a coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with him. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/18</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indicted CompuServe</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> on charges of distributing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pornography</ENAMEX> . This is regarded as an ominous precedent: the first
prosecution of an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> in the West for providing access to material
it did not produce. (The porn is produced by independent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and distributed
through Internet newsgroups.) Under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> could get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>, though this is considered unlikely. He has previously threatened
to circumvent prosecution by playing the Internet's trump card: moving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CompuServe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/18</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabisco</ENAMEX> are discussing a possible <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> settlement of all cigarette
liability suits against them. They would accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> supervision and
advertising restrictions in exchange for an act of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that would require
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> to seek compensation from a general tobacco-industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> rather
than from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> initially gloated over the news, on the
grounds that the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were offering unprecedented concessions. But
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> turned skeptical, complaining that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
even <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> wouldn't hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> enough; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) they would simply pass
the cost along to their addicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) awarding them immunity from
liability would be immoral, unconstitutional, and profitable, as evidenced by a
rise in tobacco<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-company</ENAMEX> stock on news of the talks. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/18</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> struck
down a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> law requiring drug tests for political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> . The
court ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8-to-1</ENAMEX> that the urine tests were an unreasonable search under the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX> Amendment because: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) there's no evidence of a drug problem among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the law was designed to be symbolic rather than
effective (e.g., it allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to pick <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> they will be tested). The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX> Amendment spin is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, having upheld a series of drug-testing
laws (for railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX>, customs-service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student athletes</ENAMEX>),
finally encountered one too preposterous to tolerate. The ideological spin is
that the principled left and principled right (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>) defeated the unprincipled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>).
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are turning up
the heat on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> for failing to appoint an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund-raising scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">henchman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mitchell</ENAMEX>, and
threatened to summon her before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and investigate whether she was
involved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D.</ENAMEX>, replied that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> of ethics," had neither the right nor the credibility to intimidate
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>. The press contrasted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s invective with the more
careful and substantive criticisms leveled at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> joined in
the criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> came to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16</NUMEX>)
            

            The Dow Jones
industrial average bounced back strongly after falling <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 10 percent</NUMEX>
below its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> peak <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. The drop had wiped out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s gains and
persuaded some market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> to declare the slide a correction. Healthy
corporate earnings reports and near-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> inflation in the consumer sector
turned stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> exuberant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irrationally</ENAMEX> so? asked the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . Probably not, said most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, while agreeing that the market
was likely to keep lurching in response to changes in economic indicators.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16</NUMEX>)
            

            Major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League Baseball</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retired Jackie Robinson</ENAMEX> 's number. To commemorate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>'s shattering
of the color barrier in sports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> will ever again be
assigned the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Selig</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joined Robinson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> at a ceremony honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> during a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets-Dodgers</ENAMEX>
game at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shea Stadium</ENAMEX>. Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> boasted that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> was once again
crystallizing the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> progress. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Killjoys</ENAMEX> pointed out that blacks
own none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> failed to sell out, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> was overwhelmingly white (as is usual at baseball games), and that nearly
everyone left the game after the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 th</NUMEX> inning ceremony. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Vecsey</ENAMEX> suggested that latter-day black sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> have insulted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>'s legacy of
sacrifice by devoting themselves to self-promotion and corporate marketing.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> defeated a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> criticizing its human-rights abuses. Under threats from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>,
several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> abstained. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> refused to co-sponsor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> (human-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s eagerness to conclude an
airplane deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>). Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> said she would attend the ceremonies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
colony reverts to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> control--to show her support for continued democracy
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16</NUMEX>)
            

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is selling life insurance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> . This is the first
such insurance offer since the onset of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, and is viewed as tentative
commercial confirmation that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is now, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s words, "a treatable
chronic illness rather than a terminal disease" for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> hailed it as proof of the success of new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> makes money on the policy, other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> are expected to follow.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> is being
fingered in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases of terrorism. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported
that a top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> has been linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> suspected in last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> said that
if the evidence holds up, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should consider a military strike
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> implicated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> recent
assassinations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> marched on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX> to protest the ruling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> trying to storm the embassy
were thwarted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The betting is that neither side will let the
crisis escalate, because their trade relationship is too cozy.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/14</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX> 
               won
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Masters golf</ENAMEX> tournament and was anointed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transcendent Sports</ENAMEX>
Phenomenon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> to win a major golf
tournament, and broke the course records for best score (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18</NUMEX> under par), biggest
margin of victory (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> strokes), and youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victor</ENAMEX> (he is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
declared it a triumph of youth and racial progress, comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> (whose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary of breaking the color barrier is
being celebrated simultaneously), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Ashe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Elder</ENAMEX> (who became the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black golfer to play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woods</ENAMEX> was
born). The game's current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the world and
possibly in history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimists</ENAMEX> predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> will make golf hip and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX>, especially among nonwhite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pessimists</ENAMEX> grumbled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> is so
superior he'll make tournaments boring, and that his corporate marketing
machine (whose hour-long biography of him was aired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> during the
tournament) is tarnishing his divinity. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/14</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
