



In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> experience with evil, we choose repeatedly to put our faith in law and the legal culture to redeem ourselves from sin. Over and over again, we find states indulging in total war, terror, genocide, and the mass killing of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and then turning to the legal culture in the hope that they can atone for the iniquity and live once again as a civilized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. This view‚Äîthat the law shall make us clean‚Äîshould give us pause. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> in the law has not been an unqualified virtue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian West</ENAMEX>. One might expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> influenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚Äôs Sermon</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX> to turn <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to love and charity as the means of atonement. But nations‚Äîorganized, organic societies‚Äîmust take a different path. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> must proceed collectively to find redemption.
I write in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of religious ideas and their value in understanding our legal experience. This, admittedly, is an unusual take in our rigorously secular academic world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> world has distanced itself from the sensibilities of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who take the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> seriously as a source of wisdom and who live their lives with devotion to values of faith and redemption. In this interpretation of law as the path to national redemption, I seek to find a middle way between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> thinking. There is no doubt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> whose struggles I describe‚ÄîFrance, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States‚</ENAMEX>Äîthink of themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. Yet, the very idea of redemption of the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> through law resonates more with the older tradition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> national mission under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> revealed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Sinai</ENAMEX>. My account seeks to unite the divergent strains of all religions that trace their roots to the original idea in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> living under God and under law.
To understand the phenomenon of communal redemption, we must turn to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. The model of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hebrews‚</ENAMEX>Äô deliverance from servitude and their ensuing acceptance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs law at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Sinai</ENAMEX> have repeatedly appealed to dominant powers of the West and often to opposite sides of the same conflict. In the rhetoric of the abolitionists, slavery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> made the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into ‚Äúa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Bondage</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> identified with the same story of liberation from this domain of oppression. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Turner</ENAMEX> thought he was recreating the biblical story when he led a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> revolt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1831</TIMEX>. The slaves whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriet Tubman</ENAMEX> led to freedom in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> called her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> readily saw himself in the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> leading his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of bondage into the realm of freedom.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrews</ENAMEX> fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> in order, eventually, to accept the law revealed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Sinai</ENAMEX>: delivery from servitude requires more than violent revolt. The message of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX> is not simply liberation from slavery but the domesticating of violent sensibilities under the rule of law. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> celebrate this submission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs law in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shevuot</ENAMEX>, which commemorates the revelation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Sinai</ENAMEX> and is celebrated fifty days after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> have reinterpreted this event as the descent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spirit</ENAMEX>, celebrated in the analogous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring holiday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentecost</ENAMEX>.
The idea that freedom exists only under law is often understood as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central European</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> approach to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> in society. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> tend to subscribe rather to the myth of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lockian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of nature, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> exist prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of society under a social contract. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> relies heavily on the principle that the ‚Äúconsent of the governed‚Äù is indispensable to the legitimacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Yet, in actual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> practice, the law‚Äîparticularly constitutional law‚Äîserves the same function of sanctifying the social order as it does in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> experience. Before turning to the details of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> appeal to law after the surrender at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Appomattox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Courthouse</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1865</TIMEX>, let us examine <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> significant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> efforts to domesticate tendencies toward violence under the rule of law.


Redemption by Law in 
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>

Think first about the way in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> sought repose from post-revolutionary terror in their <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> civil. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> passed through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> of regicide, terror, and mass executions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amidst</ENAMEX> voices clamoring for stability and security, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Napoleon</ENAMEX> staged his coup <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">d‚Äô√©tat</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1799</TIMEX>. High on his agenda was revamping the legal system. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1804</TIMEX>, he charged a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> with the task of drafting a new civil code in language accessible to ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> produced the elegant <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> civil, now a mainstay of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> culture and a model for civil codification all over the world. The language is so refined that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Stendhal</ENAMEX> reportedly reviewed the style of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> code provisions <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> before retiring. Today, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francophones</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> preach the distinctiveness of their culture, they never fail to mention their <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> civil, modeled after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon‚</ENAMEX>Äôs effort to use the law as the means of restoring civilized order to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> civil has proved to be remarkably durable in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> culture. Constitutions have come and gone and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have endured recurrent changes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">communes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorships</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX>. Yet, through all this, the civil code has survived. It is the cultural monument that unites the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> across history.
In its substantive content, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> civil is strongly identified with the achievements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1789 Revolution</ENAMEX> against the ancien <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. The code sweeps away the vestiges of feudal influence in the law of property and in the law of evidence and proclaims a liberal legal order. The end of feudalism in the law of property meant that a single concept of ownership would replace the ancient system of embedded estates. The implication was that all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> would be freely alienable, without being burdened by the residual control of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX> higher in the feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. The code thus provides the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> for a market economy. The end of feudalism in the field of evidence means that the testimony of a nobleman is no longer worth more than the oath of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX>. Thus the code institutionalizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">√©galit√©</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, as promised in the slogan of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX>.
Standing for these liberal values, incorporating the messages of revolution, and surviving all changes of political regimes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> civil functions like a constitution for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> of the legal culture. In their code, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have found an enduring symbol of the rule of law, a conviction that the language, concepts, and rules of the legal order can hold back the impulses toward violence, terror, and reciprocal vengeance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> in the code has redeemed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from the nightmare of the guillotine.
The metaphor of redemption should not pass our lips lightly. In its original meaning, it has legal connotations; something on loan gets returned to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. The older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> law of homicide relied on the metaphor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goel</ENAMEX> haDam, ‚Äúthe redeemer of blood‚Äù to refer to the victim‚Äôs next-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kin</ENAMEX> who, under certain circumstances, could pursue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> and kill him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Daube</ENAMEX> has interpreted this practice against the background assumption that at the time of a natural death, the life force‚Äîsymbolized by blood‚Äîalways returns to God<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> If the death occurs at the hand of another, the manslayer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unnaturally</ENAMEX> acquires control over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">victim‚Äôs ‚Äúblood</ENAMEX>.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goel</ENAMEX> haDam, the redeemer-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, executes the manslayer in order to release the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">victim‚Äôs blood</ENAMEX>, thus enabling it to return to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divine source</ENAMEX>. The notion that our life force belongs to God accounts for the views of virtually all secular liberal systems that no one can validly consent to his or her own killing at the hand of another.
It is tempting to extend this idea and to think of all humanity as enjoying a temporary privilege of life on earth. God somehow will redeem all of us at the end of history. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> view, as it has evolved and matured, seems to have avoided this universalization of the idea that individual life stems from God. As the idea developed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> of redemption would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah</ENAMEX>, who would bring a reign of peace and harmony to life on earth. The redemption occurs in life as we know it. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jewish</ENAMEX> culture takes the observance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs commandments, living under the rule of revealed law as interpreted by the rabbis, as the way to hasten the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Messiah‚Äôs</ENAMEX> reign of harmony and order. The law, then, becomes the path toward redemption. Until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> comes to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúfulfill the law,‚Äù or until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apocalypse</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of days</TIMEX>, the secular law of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is the only means we have to work toward the perfection of life on earth.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúblood‚Äù</ENAMEX> in the religious tradition of redemption proves to be subtle and problematic. There are some strains in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition that link the letting of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> with returning the soul to God. The ‚Äúredeemer of blood‚Äù reminds us of that connection, as does the popular view that the founding of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> stood in some kind of organic relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. The connection between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and salvation becomes much stronger, however, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX> interpretation of its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> legacy. The theme of blood spilling from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> becomes powerful in the crucifixion and reaches its apotheosis in the faith that a great battle, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apocalypse</ENAMEX>, must precede the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Second Coming of the Messiah</ENAMEX>. The spilling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in a great battle is understood instinctively as the suffering that must precede redemption. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Brown</ENAMEX> was led to the gallows on the eve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, having unsuccessfully sought to stimulate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> revolt, he handed one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> a note, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúI John Brown</ENAMEX> am now quite certain that the crimes of this guilty land will never be purged away but with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù2</ENAMEX>
But blood alone does not save a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from its sins. The argument here is that indulgence in evil‚Äîslavery, mass killing, persecution‚Äîmust <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue in the suffering of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. To overcome their sense of self-inflicted brutality, they turn to the law as the path of secular redemption. They search for stability after having succumbed to their baser instincts. The law provides a source of hope that the civil order can resist the recurrent slippage into violence and brutality. The important point is that the rule of law‚Äînot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>, not prayer, not animal sacrifice‚Äîshould provide the means of secular redemption.
For <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> as a whole to seek redemption, they must find a discipline that operates on them as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. Individual acts of devotion will not suffice. Needed is the discipline represented by the law‚Äîthe expression of communal cooperation, par excellence. The compromises and obligations of life under the law hardly makes sense to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> standing alone, preoccupied by their own values and their own needs. The law redeems not the individual but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as a whole<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>
This view of the relationship between law and redemption finds expression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hebrew Bible, the Old Testament</ENAMEX>. It continues to inspire the law-based thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX>. The law given at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX>, the law embedded in the covenant, is not the expression of individual aspiration but only of collective obligation. Seeking redemption or salvation through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> or through faith provides a way of cleansing ourselves of sin and, as it were, perfecting our individual creation.
Legal cultures, too, must seek to perfect themselves. They cannot exist simply as the product of will. When legal cultures lose sight of their natural end of bringing a reign of justice and harmony to human affairs, they decline into corruption and the arbitrariness of power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> philosopher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gustav Radbruch</ENAMEX> defined the ideal of Law as the practice of establishing rules in the pursuit of justice<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communal</ENAMEX> life seeks, through law, to perfect itself. This secular idea parallels the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">eschatological</ENAMEX> aim of perfecting the creation of the world under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs reign.
Seeking redemption under the law cannot simply be a desire for one‚Äôs parochial values to triumph in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. It matters which values are in play. And it matters how these values are debated in the legal culture. Debate about legal issues must be open and robust, and the very process of legal argument must communicate respect for the opposition. At the end of a legal argument, both sides must have the sense that they have been listened to, and that the dignity of the losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is affirmed in the process of decision. Here, as well, we have much to learn from the model provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmudic</ENAMEX> debate. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> questioned how <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sages</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabbis Hillel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shammai</ENAMEX>, could persistently disagree, the response was: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThese and these are the words of the living God.‚Äù Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Hillel‚Äôs</ENAMEX> views are generally followed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Shammai</ENAMEX> is treated, in defeat, with the greatest respect.
It is not surprising that when the established authority‚Äôs respect for the political opposition is debased, the legal culture invariably suffers. This is most noticeably clear in dictatorial societies where legal debate is reduced to little more than efforts to placate the powers that be. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Socialists</ENAMEX> purported to rely on legal forms and administrative regularity, their contempt for free and mutually respectful discourse led to a corruption of the legal culture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis‚</ENAMEX>Äô conception of law fluctuated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between two</NUMEX> unpalatable extremes. Sometimes the slogan was that law was what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> wanted and commanded (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recht</ENAMEX> is das, was der <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F√ºhrer</ENAMEX> will). At other times, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> was the ultimate source of legitimacy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recht</ENAMEX> is das, was dem <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volke</ENAMEX> nutzt)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The National Socialist Party‚</ENAMEX>Äôs manipulation of these slogans and their observance of legal forms served only to bring the culture to a deeper level of corruption.
It is an extraordinary feature of postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> culture that a new generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurists</ENAMEX> managed to save, to redeem, their concept of law from its racist and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. In the wake of their unforgettable crimes against humanity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Germans</ENAMEX>, too, sought redemption in the rule of law, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rechtsstaat</ENAMEX> that they have cultivated along with economic prosperity. Living by the law, and seeking justice within the law, redeems the humanistic side of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> culture. It has suppressed the romantic will to break all restraints for the sake of glory in power.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, too, have a civil code that has united them, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, through the transitions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bismarck</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weimar</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Reich</ENAMEX>, to the present. Yet, under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Socialists</ENAMEX>, the code, which contains the provisions on family law, became tainted with notions of racial purity. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aryans</ENAMEX> could not marry. Of course, this stain disappeared in the postwar reform, but the memory remains of a corrupted civil code. Not surprisingly, then, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> have sought redemption by promoting both a new constitution, enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, and the rule of law in a united <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. More than any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> seeking redemption under law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> identified their new constitution, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grundgesetz</ENAMEX>, as the focal point of state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. The sanctity of the constitution‚Äîand not the personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of state‚Äîbecame the interest protected under the reformed law of treason. When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Germans</ENAMEX> felt their infant postwar republic endangered by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subversion</ENAMEX>, they appointed an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to protect the integrity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The announced aim of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> was to protect the constitution (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verfassungsschutz</ENAMEX>).
The preamble of this charter, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Law</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grundgesetz</ENAMEX>), repeatedly reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> of the imperative to atone for the sins of the past:

Conscious of its responsibility before God and humanity, possessed of the will to serve the peace of the world as an equal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Europe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volk</ENAMEX>] commits itself, by virtue of its inherent constitution-making authority, to the following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Law</ENAMEX>.6

No other constitution, so far as I know, stresses its sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúresponsibility‚Äù</ENAMEX> and declares as one of its primary purposes ‚Äúto serve the peace of the world.‚Äù These gestures recall the descent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> into the evils of aggressive war and crimes against humanity.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> article of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Law</ENAMEX> invokes the humanistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kantian</ENAMEX> underpinnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> culture: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúHuman dignity is inviolable. All <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state power</ENAMEX> is obligated to protect it and respect it.‚Äù This provision provides the backdrop for interpreting all the basic rights guaranteed under the constitution. The protection of human dignity is the fundamental value suffusing the entire legal order. The highest virtue of the postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> constitutional order, then, was precisely the greatest casualty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. The path to redemption lay in reclaiming the liberal and humanistic values most systematically violated in their darkest <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX>. The point is carried forward in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> article: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúEveryone has the right to flourishing of his or her personality. . . . Everyone has the right to life.‚Äù
These are provisions that enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> to redefine their identities. They would no longer be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> devoted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volk</ENAMEX> above all. They would become the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of human dignity that served the cause of human flourishing and the sanctity of human life. For the postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, then, the law, and particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Law</ENAMEX> became the means for suppressing evil impulses and returning to the promises of an earlier national self. This is what redemption means in a secular legal world.
The redemptive impulse leads national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to place an emphasis on values that resonate against past sins. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional Court</ENAMEX> has made a number of controversial decisions that make sense primarily as efforts to resolve the burden of memory. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decided to uphold a law abolishing the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-year</TIMEX> statute of limitations for concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> murders<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> It invoked the constitutional ‚Äúright to life‚Äù to strike down a liberal abortion law that permitted abortion on demand in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trimester<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> And, more recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> rejected an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX> statutory justification for border <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> who shot at their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> trying to flee the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for the West<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX> All of these decisions brought to the fore fundamental values of protecting life and punishing those with contempt for life. Yet, the particular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> emphasis on these values would probably not appeal in the same measure to other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> themselves have coined a unique, hard-to-translate phrase to describe the controversies that have driven their system of justice for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX>. They call it <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Bew√§ltigung der Vergangenheit‚Äî‚Äúovercoming‚</ENAMEX>Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúcoming to grips with‚Äù the past. Settling accounts with the past provides a critical perspective on the process of redemption from evil. We cannot avoid the past, for we are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> of it. In real life, we cannot reenact the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of wandering in the desert that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hebrews</ENAMEX> had to endure before they could shake off their ingrained ways and a new generation could seek redemption under the law. In the world of practical politics, we must act now, and criminal punishment often provides the mechanism for distancing ourselves from the past so that we can start anew.


Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Path</ENAMEX> 
to Redemption

As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> had their experiences of seeking redemption after reigns of terror, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, too, indulged in the mammoth bloodletting on the killing fields of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> sought to resupply <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Sumter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beauregard</ENAMEX> chose in response to fire on the federal fort, the long-simmering feud between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North and South</ENAMEX> bled into brothers‚Äô killing each other at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close</NUMEX> range. They fired their canons on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Sumter</ENAMEX>, they fixed their bayonets at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Round Top</ENAMEX>, they lobbed shells onto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vicksburg</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> could seize the forts reigning over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, they burned down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, and under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Tecumseh Sherman</ENAMEX> they scorched the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> on their march to the sea. The blue and the gray fell everywhere. And they were not sure why. They only had abstract ideas in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">heads‚Äîsome</ENAMEX> died for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, others for their separate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred thousand</NUMEX> lives stained the ground, more than all the former and subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> wars put together.
Having barely won reelection midway in this slaughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> could only say of the reign of terror, ‚ÄúWoe unto the world because of offences!‚Äù We had descended into the bloodiest war of our history without clear purposes or any understanding of how it might end. ‚ÄúFor it must needs be that offences come; but woe to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> by whom the offence cometh!‚Äù The self-inflicted pogrom is seen as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúwoe‚Äù</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúscourge‚Äù inflicted</ENAMEX> for the terrible ‚Äúoffence‚Äù of slavery. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> second inaugural address prayed for redemption. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> had bled its sins onto its own soil and craved a rebirth of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> civilization.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> turned to law. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year</TIMEX> into the war, after a string of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> defeats, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> learned that the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> could not possibly survive. ‚ÄúA new one had to be embraced.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù10</ENAMEX> And the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> would have to be based on a new constitutional order. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of free <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, including emancipated slaves, would bear responsibility for rebuilding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on the basis of a constitution acceptable to all. Formally speaking, the original charter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> would remain in place, but it would be so radically transformed that it would stand to the ancien <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> civil related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> feudal order or, as any redeemed legal culture compares to the brutality and chaos that precedes it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> hope for a new beginning lay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments‚Äîthe Thirteenth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth, and Fifteenth‚</ENAMEX>Äîall enacted in quest of a new definition of freedom and equality under the law. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> clause of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> specified who would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the new polity: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúAll persons</ENAMEX> born or naturalized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. . . .‚Äù With a single stroke the new constitution erased the effects of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the worst blemishes in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> constitutional history‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> decision of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX>, which held that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> descent could never become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, there would be no discrimination based on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. The only question that mattered was whether you were born within the polity and whether you were therefore likely to come to maturity with the language and consciousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture.
With just boundaries of the new nation-state properly defined, the highest order of business was to define the basic rights of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of these rights follows the pattern established in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence: life</ENAMEX>, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness. Yet, there was a new recognition that the inalienable rights of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were now to be realized not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of nature but under the rule of law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">naturalistic ‚Äúpursuit of happiness,‚Äù celebrated in the Declaration</ENAMEX>, gives way to the quintessential creature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">law‚Äôs definition‚Äîproperty</ENAMEX>. Yet, the basic rights of life, liberty, and property are inalienable without being absolute. The ideal must be adapted to the practical demands of competing claims. The legal system would have to decide when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> could fairly be deprived of liberty or property or even of life; thus, the coining of the famous and influential clause of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, namely that no ‚ÄúState [shall] deprive any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of life, liberty, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX>, without due Process of law.‚Äù The law would define the content and the limits of the inalienable rights celebrated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>.
Also, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, the law would define duties incumbent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The individual state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> must not only guarantee due process for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> within their jurisdiction, they must also secure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">‚Äúthe</ENAMEX> equal protection of the laws‚Äù for all to whom their power extends. True, the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> places some limits on the legislative competence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. They must defer to the supremacy of federal law and recognize the privileges and immunities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of all other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.11 And there were specific restrictions: They could not enact bills of attainder, ex-post facto laws, or any ‚Äúlaw impairing the obligation of contracts.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù12 In the postbellum constitutional order, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> acquired a pervasive duty to treat their residents‚Äîthose subject to their jurisdiction‚Äîdecently.
This was a revolutionary change. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were no longer the autonomous sovereigns that they thought they were when they claimed the right of secession. They were now, in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Governments</ENAMEX> existed to guarantee due process and equal justice for all. The local law was no longer simply a creature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> themselves were enmeshed in the law and subordinate to it.
In addition to embedding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the rule of law, the new constitutional order embarked on an affirmative program to ensure equality among those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> subject to the jurisdiction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The heart of the new consensus is that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, victorious in warfare, must continue its aggressive intervention in the lives of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. It must protect the weak against the risk that they would slip into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of subordination resembling the past from which they sought to escape. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, there could never again be relationships of slavery or involuntary servitude in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would have to be ever watchful to insure that this kind of slippage would never occur in the private relationships among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúequal</ENAMEX> protection clause,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> must recognize and promote the equality of those subject to their jurisdiction. To round out the commitment to equality, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> ratified in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> could no longer deny voting rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> on the grounds of their race, color, or previous condition of servitude.
These objectives and guarantees are insufficient in themselves to create a constitution, a framework of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> needs, in addition, a definition of legislative empowerment that would enable the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to realize its commitments. This definition is laid down in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of the postbellum amendments. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> grant the power to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to enforce the basic framework ‚Äúwith appropriate legislation.‚Äù True, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> takes as a given many of the provisions of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. The new order inherits an operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>. They would be recast in new functions, but the forms remained the same.
The argument, then, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">three Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> enacted a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> constitution. The terms of this constitution, as culled from the amendments‚Äîwith some rearrangement and leaving out historically specific clauses‚Äîcan be stated in a few words:

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second American Constitution</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">¬ß1</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> born or naturalized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> wherein they reside.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">¬ß2</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">¬ß4</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> shall deny to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">¬ß6</ENAMEX>. The right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to vote shall not be denied or abridged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or by any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> on account of race, color, or previous condition of servitude.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">¬ß7</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> shall have power to enforce the foregoing provisions by appropriate legislation.

These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> propositions summarize the enduring content of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX>.13 The key provisions of these amendments define political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX>, articulate basic rights, and provide an ambit of legislative competence. So reformed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would be able to protect individual rights as well as promote the equality of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who survived the war. Of course, we must assume a set of institutions‚Äîa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary‚Äîthat</ENAMEX> will continue to function according to the terms of their initial creation.
Still, there is something missing in this filtering off of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">three Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> and calling them a separate constitution. The missing factor is the consciousness of setting forth a new framework of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, a structure based on values fundamentally different from those that went before. To find that consciousness, we need to turn, I wish to argue, to the critical message of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, the address that would generate a new normative world in which to make sense of the epic war that consumed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> from the firing on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Sumter</ENAMEX> to the surrender at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appomattox</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nomos</ENAMEX>, the new framework of values that necessitated a new constitution, comes forth in one of the great prayers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> civil religion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>. It is worth recalling some of the enduring phrases of this civil prayer, the incantations that reverberated in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consciousness:

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> score and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> brought forth on this continent a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. . . .
From these honored dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of devotion.
We resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain, that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom. . . .
Government of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shall not perish from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>.
In the ensuing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, we will look at these words and the entire address in greater detail. For now, I wish to make the unusual claim that these revered words serve as the preamble for the constitutional order that emerged from the unification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. They are a preamble in much the same sense that the language beginning ‚ÄúConscious of our responsibility before God and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">humanity‚Äù</ENAMEX> provides the organizing principle of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> constitution or the following words echo in memory as the convening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Constitution</ENAMEX>:

We the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, in order to form a more perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, establish justice, insure domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tranquility</ENAMEX>, provide for the common defense, promote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general Welfare</ENAMEX>, and secure the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Blessings of Liberty</ENAMEX> to ourselves and our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Posterity</ENAMEX>, do ordain and establish this <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States of America</ENAMEX>.

Constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preambles</ENAMEX> speak in prophecy. They set forth a vision of the future‚Äîfor the broad purposes of the national charter that they introduce. And, most important, they define who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are who share in the constitutional vision. The original preamble in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> version stressed the position of ‚ÄúWe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚</ENAMEX>Äù as the enactors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, the body politic expressing itself in the new constitution included the prior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> who ‚Äúfour score and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> ago‚Äù adopted, with great courage, that proposition of equality that gave birth to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Those represented in the new order included the dead at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> and at all the battlefields of the war who, if the new order is realized, ‚Äúshall not have died in vain.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù And</ENAMEX>, furthermore, because he avoided all partisan references in his address, he clearly meant to articulate a conception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that included the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>, black as well as white. Ultimately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of the new order would be the future generations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, those who would flourish under ‚Äúa new birth of freedom.‚Äù
To say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX> provides the preamble to a new constitutional order is, to say the least, a bold claim. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> took the train up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1863</TIMEX>, he had in mind only to comfort the mourners of those who died in the fierce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX> battle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early July</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> were being pulled together from the battlefield and spared further decay. The soil was turned and the dead laid to rest. The battle had turned the tide of the war‚Äîjust barely, mind you‚Äîand it was time that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> began to articulate the meaning of the long suffering that culminated in the gruesome hand-to-hand fighting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> fields.
At the ceremony dedicating the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> was designated the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. The renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Everett</ENAMEX> spoke for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> mounted the podium. He had a written text with him that amounted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 268</NUMEX> words<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perhaps Everett</ENAMEX> prepared the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> to absorb the poignancy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs message. Perhaps the very brevity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs words lent them additional power. The impact of the address was felt not only by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mourners</ENAMEX> gathered at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> but by an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> yearning for a sense of meaning in the bloodshed.
True, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> Address was not legally binding, but preambles are never meant to have the status of positive law. They are designed to explain why it is necessary for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to bind itself to certain objectives. Lincoln‚Äôs preamble, accepted in the hearts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, explains the meaning of the war and provides a guide to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of a constitutional order based on nationhood, equality, and democracy. The setting of clear goals in inspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">language‚</ENAMEX>Äîthis is all one can expect of a constitutional preamble.
This constitutional order <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> in radical contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> drafted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> and amended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1791</TIMEX>. It defines membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, it brings the principle of equality to the fore, and it initiates the process of extending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> to virtually all adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> did none of these things. It slighted the problems of nationality and citizenship, it sidestepped the problem of equality, and it minimized the significance of popular democracy.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irrelevance of</ENAMEX> 
Original Intent

At the outset, I should be clear about the claims I am not making and the methods I am not using. Above all, I am not making an argument about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúoriginal intent‚Äù</ENAMEX> that lay behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX>. Nothing strikes me as intellectually and morally more impoverished than the current trend in constitutional scholarship to believe that the wishes, desires, and intentions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> should determine the content of our <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major hurdles that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of this method have never negotiated. First, we need an argument about whose wishes, desires, and intentions really matter. If we think we are bound by a certain take on the world that prevailed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787, 1791</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>, then we should decide whose sentiments matter. Should we look to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wrote the document, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> who voted for it, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> who ratified it, or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúpeople‚Äù</ENAMEX> as a whole for whom these various democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> acted? Among all these possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of ‚Äúoriginal intent,‚Äù there was intense conflict. I would imagine that even those who actually voted for and against various drafts suffered from doubt and changing sentiments. But even if each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> voting had a concrete intention to support every sentence he or she endorsed, there is no coherent way of finding a common denominator among their divergent positions. A single intent cannot unify the inevitable cacophony of desires that stand behind every piece of legislation. But let us suppose there was a single intent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. We then encounter a more basic question: Why should we care what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> actually thought?
The best political theory to support the relevance of original intent would be to think of the lawgiver as something like a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>.15 The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> wants us to do something, and has used the language of the law to move us toward action. We should try to figure out what these purposes are and execute them. And if we don‚Äôt? Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> cannot really punish us, but somehow we would be breaking faith with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> if we don‚Äôt act with the appropriate subservience or at least act as though we were submissive to the original intent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX>. This, I regret to say, is the best reconstruction I can offer for a view that never seems to get articulated; namely, why we should pay so much attention to the wishes and desires of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who bequeathed to us the words we live by.
In great historical moments of law making as well as literature, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> choose words that resonate far beyond their original context. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> ‚Äúpledged their sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">honor‚Äù</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1776</TIMEX> to a document that included the words ‚ÄúAll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal,‚Äù they may merely have intended to stress the equality of all ‚Äúcollective‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>: the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had as much right to choose their form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. They also could have had the limited purpose of arguing that they were of the same moral status as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX>. If all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal, then no one of them can claim to be anointed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> by divine right. The only source of legitimacy, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Declaration</ENAMEX> argues, is the ‚Äúconsent of the governed.‚Äù Whatever their intentions as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> or as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> may have been, their words had lasting significance. They bequeathed a great maxim to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people‚Äîa maxim that would in due course serve as the battle cry of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">emancipation</ENAMEX>.
When the drafters and ratifiers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> adopted a commitment to equality under the law, they did not think particularly about whether they wanted to bring about integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Yet, a vast literature has grown up around the question of whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúoriginal intent‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> was to integrate the schools‚Äîan event that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> did not mandate until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown v Board of Education</ENAMEX>.16 The dispute seems to be entirely irrelevant<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> The complex body of national and state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> who drafted, passed, and ratified <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> did not think about a single system of education for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. There were too many other issues on their minds. We cannot attribute to them an intention to have all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> study together in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>, nor can we burden their memory with a commitment to keep black and white forever apart.
Those who frame constitutions and constitutional amendments obviously have some purpose in mind, but the purposes are typically abstract. If they want to bring about equality among all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, they do not want to be bothered with working out precisely what equality means at each stage of historical evolution. If you had asked them whether, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> should be desegregated, they would have been nonplussed by the question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúWell</ENAMEX>, that is the reason we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>,‚Äù would have been the typical reply. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> established an ideal, it affirmed an idea that has roots in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>. The drafters implicitly endorsed the principle that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal and because they are created equal, they are entitled to equal treatment before the law. What this language should mean in practice was not their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. Together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> who reflect on the ideas behind the law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> assume responsibility for the proper interpretation of the language that constitutes a shared heritage of government principles.
I never cease to be amazed that legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, particularly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, continue to be confused about the relevance of the framers‚Äô original intent. Secular legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> could not possibly be more demanding, more deferential to authority, than religious cultures that believe that their binding legal principles were declared by God. Yet, a story from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX> beautifully illustrates the folly of invoking original intent in a dispute about the meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs commandments. A group of rabbis were engaged in a debate about whether a particular earthenware oven was kosher or not. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Eliezer</ENAMEX>, said no; the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbis</ENAMEX> said yes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Eliezer</ENAMEX> proceeded to invoke a variety of fantastic signs to support his view: at his command, a carob <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> was uprooted and flew across the field, a stream flowed upstream, and the walls started to collapse before they were halted. The rabbis were not impressed by these signs. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Eliezer</ENAMEX>, desperate and alone, invoked the argument of original intent: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúIf I am right, let heaven be the proof.‚Äù A heavenly voice then proclaimed: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúHow</ENAMEX> dare you oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Eliezer</ENAMEX>, whose views are everywhere the law.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Rabbi Joshua</ENAMEX> arose and quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deuteronomy</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúIt is not in Heaven.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Rabbi Jeremiah</ENAMEX> explained the reference: Ever since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> was given at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Sinai</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúwe pay no attention to heavenly voices, for God already wrote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Sinai</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù18 The point is that once the language is released and given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurists</ENAMEX> to fashion to the needs of their time, the task of lawgivers is finished. Their intentions and desires cannot rule‚Äîeither from the grave or from heaven.
The intention of those who framed the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> should, therefore, not control their interpretation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But what about the intention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>, when he mounted the podium on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 19, 1863</TIMEX>? There are some who will say that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> did not intend specifically to articulate the preamble to a new constitution, then the words spoken at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> could not possibly be, as I claim, the preamble to the postbellum constitution. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> did not intend to amend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> with his court-packing plan, then the resulting changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> could not constitute a de facto amendment, a radical transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law.
Here we take a page from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> constitutional history to understand how a practice can be become part of the accumulated historical constitution without this being the purpose of those who initiated the practice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> remains, as is well known, famously unwritten. Customary rules determine the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX> in a system that has evolved as a constitutional monarchy. Only the accepted practice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> prescribes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> must sign legislation for it to be binding as law or that the queen may intervene, under certain circumstances, to break a party deadlock and select a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>.19 In all systems of customary law, the relevant perspective is not that of those who first engage in the practice but rather of those who witness the pattern of the past and adopt it as binding on themselves. So it is with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>. The right question is not what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> intended, but rather what the words meant to those who looked to them as the explanation of the war and as a charter for freedom and equality for all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. If the address had been ignored, it would not have mattered what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> intended. But because these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">268</NUMEX> words20 were adopted into the civil religion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe secular meditation on who we were and what we were about‚Äîtheir life after formal recitation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> determines their constitutional status. They are the preamble to the constitutional order because we came to understand them as nearly sacred. And although we did not until now think of this secular prayer as the preamble to a new order of nationhood, equality, and democracy, that is what they became.
These words are, in fact, better known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> than the preamble to the first <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Schoolchildren</ENAMEX> routinely recite them and thereby imbibe the intuition that these words defined <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>. Yet, because we know these resonant phrases, we rarely stop to listen and ponder the meaning of each well-crafted line. Let us now put ourselves among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of mourners at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>. Let us transport ourselves back into the frame of mind of those suffering losses, those looking for the meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> slaughtering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> score and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> brought forth on this continent a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, conceived in liberty and dedicated to the proposition that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal. Now we are engaged in a great <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, testing whether that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> or any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> so conceived and so dedicated can long endure. We are met on a great battlefield of that war. We have come to dedicate a portion of that field as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> might live. It is altogether fitting and proper that we should do this. But in a larger sense, we cannot dedicate‚Äîwe cannot consecrate‚Äîwe cannot hallow this ground. The brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, living and dead, who struggled here have consecrated it far above our poor power to add or detract. The world will little note nor long remember what we say here, but it can never forget what they did here. It is for us the living, rather, to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they who fought here have thus far so nobly advanced. It is rather for us to be here dedicated to the great task remaining before us‚Äîthat from these honored dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of devotion‚Äîthat we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain, that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shall not perish from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>.



