



A specter is haunting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Karl Marx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Engels</ENAMEX> wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848</TIMEX>, as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Communist Manifesto</ENAMEX>. The specter they had in mind eventually became a political movement that came to dominate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> the world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twentieth century</TIMEX>. Behind this movement, however, lay an even more powerful idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> had inspired‚Äîa <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> conception of reality. The marketplace of economic relationships is not what it seems to be. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> enter into seemingly voluntary contracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, but underlying this system of apparent cooperation is a vast system of exploitation. Those who hold capital reap profits off the backs of those whom they hire as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>. This generates a dynamic of history that should, according to the theory, eventually produce a revolution by the exploited class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>. This theory failed to recognize the just contribution of capital in generating the opportunity to work, and the political incarnation of Marxism turned out to be historically more transient than expected. Nonetheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> remains with us that relationships of employment‚Äîindeed all forms of relationship‚Äîrequire more than nominal consent to be legitimate. Behind the appearance of voluntary interaction there lurks the ever-present possibility of unjust exploitation.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> challenge was but the beginning of a continuing critique of the idea of freedom, so revered at the close of the eighteenth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>. Behind the nominal appearance of freedom lies a structure of influence, a set of conditions that influences <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to make the choices they do. Sometimes these influences are morally desirable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and family pressure can lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to finish their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> degree or to stay in difficult marriages or to remain loyal when tempted to act in self-interest. Looking back, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who make these choices under social influence are often grateful for the external inducement to do the right thing. Yet, economic and social conditions can also lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to enter into socially and economically oppressive relationships, abusive marriages, and postures of dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. They can be induced to undress and prostrate themselves on stages in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booths</ENAMEX> with one-way windows. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are influenced by others or their economic and emotional needs is, in itself, morally neutral, but the results can vary widely.


The Paradox of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX>

This is the paradox of freedom in modern times. We still believe that freedom is the great contribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy to the culture of the West. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúFreedom‚Äù</ENAMEX> was our rallying cry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX>-long battle against the political enemy that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> labeled the ‚Äúevil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King, Jr.</ENAMEX> dreamed of a society committed to the proposition that would realize the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> vision of equality under law, the word that would sound from the mountaintops would not be ‚Äúequality‚Äù but ‚Äúfreedom.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù ‚ÄúLet</ENAMEX> freedom ring,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù King</ENAMEX> reminds us in the memorable refrain of his dream. In his choice of words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> harks back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, who recognized our commitment to the proposition that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal but hoped that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">emancipation</ENAMEX> would generate ‚Äúa new birth of freedom.‚Äù
We may be willing to die in the name of freedom, but we can no longer pretend that we live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the uncomplicated</TIMEX> moral world of the eighteenth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>. In a post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> world, we know that freedom requires more than the experience of choosing. We cannot escape our recognition that nominal freedom leads, sometimes, to exploitation and oppression.
The late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteenth century</TIMEX> was indeed a marvelously simplistic time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX> could write, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>, of the wonders of a free market, based on the voluntary cooperation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, and its invisible hand that would produce the maximum possible welfare for humankind<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immanuel Kant</ENAMEX> could glorify freedom in his theory of law, published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1795</TIMEX>, a theory based on the absolute right to enter into any contract that one chooses to make<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> And, of course, the great monuments to the eighteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> understanding of freedom are the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>. These documents are revered because they are designed to protect the individual sphere of freedom from a presumptively aggressive and overreaching central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The basic freedoms protected in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Amendments</ENAMEX>, ratified in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1791</TIMEX>, include freedom of speech and the press, freedom of religion, the right to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, the right to privacy against state intrusion in one‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and papers, and a plethora of rights designed to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> of crime against the federal government‚Äôs power to investigate and prosecute. All of these freedoms or rights are understood to be a matter of opposition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. They imagine a dyadic conception of government‚Äîthe individual pitted against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
The significant feature of our basic freedoms‚Äîapart from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> and those that arise in the criminal process‚Äîis that we can imagine enjoying all of them in a state of nature. We do not need government in order to exercise our freedom of speech or religion, to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> or to be free of state intrusion in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. As these rights are formulated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> acquires the image of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interloper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, the potential violator of our freedom to do as we please.
And who do we fear will invade and intrude upon our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> of freedom? At the time of the revolution, the fear was directed toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX> and his colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>. In the newly established <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX>, the fear was redirected toward the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. This dyadic opposition between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and state underlies most constitutional thinking to this day. The fear of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has grown into distrust toward all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. According to the official doctrine, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> only applies to limit ‚Äústate action‚Äù encroaching upon individual liberty. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akhil Amar</ENAMEX> recently formulated the idea, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are likely to act for their own benefit rather than the benefit of its citizens<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therefore</ENAMEX>, we must be eternally watchful against overreaching by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is to arm us with the legal means to check the tendency of the state‚Äîfederal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and indeed all forms of government‚Äîto limit our natural freedom.
But there is another model of thinking that recognizes the paradox of freedom. If freedom can generate exploitation, then the task of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> should be to intervene to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> against the exploitation by other private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. The paradigm of the exploitative, oppressive relationship in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> experience is, of course, slavery, and therefore in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX>, as the first task of the new constitutional order, we banned the very possibility of private relationships of slavery, established either by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> or by consensual agreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> charges the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with the responsibility to make sure that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúslavery‚Äù nor ‚Äúinvoluntary servitude‚</ENAMEX>Äù shall come to exist in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The amendment does not say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> may not create relationships of subordination or slavery. It says simply that these private relationships, however they might come about, ‚Äúshall not exist.‚Äù The important point about this formulation is not merely that it dispenses with the requirement of ‚Äústate action.‚Äù It does that and more.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> betokens an entirely new way of thinking about government‚Äînot as an ever-threatening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, but as a necessary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of a society free of interpersonal exploitation. The focus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> is not on the potential evils of government but on the wrongs committed by private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Unjust private relationships do not cease existing just because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> declares them not to exist. They can arise spontaneously, and in a state of nature some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would inevitably come to dominate others. The passive voice of ‚ÄúNeither slavery nor involuntary servitude shall exist‚Äù means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must be ever watchful, lest relationships of exploitation come into being.
The new function of government departs radically from the dyadic structure‚Äîthe individual pitted against the state‚Äîunderlying the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>. The relationship of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> becomes triadic or three-cornered. The relationship arises between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave owner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>, dominator and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate</ENAMEX>, aggressor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> pole is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which must intervene to insure that the incipient relationship of ‚Äúinvoluntary servitude‚Äù shall not exist.
A triadic relationship between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> represents an entirely new kind of constitutional order. A dyadic focus takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. The triadic orientation accepts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in conquering evil. The dyadic picture assumes that the desired form of liberty exists in a state of nature and it treats the transition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as a threat to liberty. The triadic conception recognizes the evil of domination inherent in a state of nature and treats <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> not only as necessary to rid us of that evil but as a welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the effort to build a civilized society.
This difference in the attitude toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> parallels a different understanding of freedom and how it comes into being. The freedom celebrated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> resembles an island of solitude, a retreat from society. Its ideal is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of nature, intimated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry David Thoreau‚</ENAMEX>Äôs retreat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walden Pond</ENAMEX>.4 The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> stands alone, fearful that a far-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will aggress against him and limit his freedom. But the liberty that comes to the fore in the intended postbellum constitutional order and under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Secret Constitution</ENAMEX> requires the intervention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty</ENAMEX> is born in the state‚Äôs assertion of responsibility to oversee and prevent relationships of oppression. The relationship between rights and freedom is thus turned on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Those who identify with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> and the mentality of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1791</TIMEX> think of both rights and freedom as islands of autonomy protected by the walls of the law against the threat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The view that comes to the fore in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Constitution</ENAMEX> recognizes that freedom as well as rights depend on the proper interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Government is not the enemy of freedom but rather the mechanism by which freedom is secured in a society that tends toward domination and oppression.
The assertion of a triadic conception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> brought us into line with the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> conception of freedom as the privilege that arises from living in a matrix of protective state regulations. It is not nature but the law that makes us free. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX> is realized not by the state‚Äôs absence but from the construction of a network of laws that liberate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> from the oppression that would otherwise occur. Compulsory temperance and drug laws generate freedom for those who are able to stay clean. Prohibitions against sexual self-degradation and peep shows strengthen the inner freedom of our human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">selves</ENAMEX>.
This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> conception of constitutional freedom. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Law</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> declares human dignity to be the foundational value of the constitution, the implications run through all relationships that may come into being. This ‚Äúthird-party effect‚Äù means that private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are bound to respect the human dignity in each other, precisely as they are bound not to subject each other to relationships of involuntary servitude or, during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX>, not to sell each other alcoholic beverages. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must avoid sexual harassment on the job, even though in this case the ‚Äúthird-party‚Äù effect arises not directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> but from federal legislation.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> tripartite conception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> requires funding. Fighting a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> campaign to suppress the Southern insurrection required a stronger financial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">base</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had needed up to that time. The war drove up spending from the customary <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of the gross national product to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>. (By comparison, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, government spending represented <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the GNP.)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> With no place left to turn, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> approved the first income tax in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1862</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX>, the income tax generated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 20 percent</NUMEX> of federal revenue, the balance coming from tariffs and reintroduced excise taxes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> income tax lapsed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX>, and when the direct tax against income returned to the national agenda in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>, the times were different. The disputes took on the tones of class struggle. This time, it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who favored the tax as a measure of social justice. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy</ENAMEX> who were affected by the modest <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> tax denounced the measure as socialist. Almost immediately after the tax‚Äôs introduction, a challenge under the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> made its way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> were convinced that any form of income tax violated the prohibition against direct taxes not in proportion to the census<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> Progressive politics as well as the government‚Äôs demand for revenue generated a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> that supported a constitutional amendment to reverse the decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sixteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> found the necessary <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-fourths</NUMEX> vote for ratification, and the income tax became a basic tool of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> finance.
The origin of the income tax in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> has largely symbolic meaning. It testifies to the government‚Äôs beginning to conceive of itself as an aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> charged not only with winning a total war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in insurrection but also with taking charge of the postbellum constitutional order that would be based on different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> from the social order of freedom and fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> founding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> constituted themselves as a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> ‚Äúconceived in liberty and dedicated to the proposition that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would assume the task of supervising relationships in the commercial and private spheres to assay whether they were impermissible relationships of domination‚Äîrelationships morally equivalent to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúinvoluntary servitude.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was newly envisioned as a triadic structure powered by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, well-financed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> did not clearly get the message.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conceptions</ENAMEX> 
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>

The tension between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> conceptions of government‚Äîbipartite and tripartite‚Äîcame to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in a classic decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of New York</ENAMEX> had enacted legislation designed to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> trade. Among other provisions, the legislation limited the permissible <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of work to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> per day and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> per week. The legislation was based rather clearly on the assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are at a serious bargaining disadvantage and cannot protect their interests adequately simply by negotiating the number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> they want to work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was reaching out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, motivated by compassion for those who lacked the bargaining leverage to limit their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of employment.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lochner</ENAMEX>, was prosecuted under a provision of the statute that made it a misdemeanor to employ someone in excess of the limit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> concluded by a large majority that the statute violated the liberty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> and presumably of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> as well‚Äîalthough the latter were not complaining about being prohibited from working too many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours.7</TIMEX> A majority of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Court</ENAMEX> read the notion of liberty in the due process clause (‚Äúno <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> shall be deprived of life, liberty, or property without due process of law‚Äù) as including freedom of contract. The dyadic structure prevailed. A similar analysis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Peep Show</ENAMEX> case would have led to the conclusion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> had the right to contract any form of self-exhibition they thought desirable. Any other result supposedly implies paternalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autonomy</ENAMEX> (if not dignity) requires freedom of contract as a basic right.
The alternative view of the case, winning support from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Marshall Harlan</ENAMEX>, was that limiting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of employment was a legitimate way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to exercise its responsibility to protect the health of those who chose to work as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bakers</ENAMEX>. The dissent, written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Harlan</ENAMEX>, explicitly addressed the problem of unequal bargaining power between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bakers</ENAMEX>:

It may be that the statute had its origin, in part, in the belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> were not upon an equal footing, and that the necessities of the latter often compelled them to submit to such exactions as unduly taxed their strength<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> had the same point in mind when he wrote, apodictically, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúThe Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> does not enact Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Spencer‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Statics</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù9 In other words, the principles of the free market economy need not be entrenched as a dimension of constitutionally protected liberty.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lochner</ENAMEX> ranks among the more widely scorned decisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. The general complaint is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> ignored the interest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in furthering the health and welfare of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. To put this objection in other terms, the opinion ignored the ascendancy of the tripartite conception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The issue remains with us‚Äîif only in a slightly different guise. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1930s</TIMEX>, the principle of freedom of contract has given way to the propriety of the state and federal measures to protect working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the job. Yet, the question of liberty and its potential abuse in an oppressive relationship remains a flash point of debate. Although the concept is not mentioned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, the freedom to say ‚Äúyes‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúno‚Äù to particular commercial relationships has become an essential dimension of personhood. It is as much a part of the basic liberty protected under the due process clause as the right to be free from unjustified physical restraint.
Freedom of contract enables <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to express their personhood, but it also facilitates relationships of oppression, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúslavery</ENAMEX> and involuntary servitude.‚Äù After all, it is possible to choose to enter into a contract of slavery. The book of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Exodus</ENAMEX> permits the purchase of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>, but after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of service ‚Äúhe shall go out free, for nothing.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù10 Yet, there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> recognizes, who prefer the condition of servitude:

And if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> shall plainly say, I love my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> . . . I will not go out free, then his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> shall bring him . . . to the door or to the door post, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> shall bore his ear through with an awl and he shall serve him Forever<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX>

In this example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> chooses the condition of servitude. We know from the fate of many long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> that after a certain period they choose a life of dependence, free of the responsibility of caring for themselves. It is not impossible that someone might actually prefer the secure life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> to the anxious life of the free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who must care for himself.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct grounds on which the law might sensibly prohibit the possibility recognized in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX>. First, the claim might be that freedom and its blessings represent a great gift that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> ‚Äúmade in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs image‚Äù should be able to forfeit as though it were a disposable piece of property. Alternatively, the argument might be that in principle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have the right to choose to forego their freedom, but that in reality these choices are always influenced by personal necessities that becloud the choice actually made. This is especially true under market conditions, where the need for sustenance can drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into relationships that they would not choose in and of themselves. It is clear that even the choice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX> can never be shown to be completely free. The legal arrangements also stipulate in the same passage that if during his period of servitude the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> acquired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, then he must leave them behind when he leaves his master‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. Some purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> might decide to opt for permanent servitude simply because they cannot bear to live without their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The full text in the quoted passage reads: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúI love my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, I will not go out free.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù12 The cruelty of subjecting him to the choice between freedom and leaving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> obviously means that his choice is not free in any meaningful sense.
Under modern capitalism there are many conditions that render choices less than fully free. Material necessity is the most obvious. But, as we have learned from the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and cigarette consumption, advertising and peer group influence can lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to develop habits that they later regret. The same is true of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> consumption, which may readily develop into a condition of dependency in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> may enjoy the illusion of freely choosing not a hole bored in his ear but rather numerous telltale holes bored in his veins.
The question of exploitation and manipulation of consent has shifted from the economic to the sexual arena. That is why the peep show case so beautifully captures our concerns about equality and human dignity. The right to enter the romantic and sexual relationship of one‚Äôs choosing is surely an important dimension of freedom. It includes the right to marry the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of one‚Äôs choice, to choose and act upon a sexual orientation, gay or straight, to enjoy (within appropriate limits) reproductive freedom, and to say ‚Äúno‚Äù to sex if one is so inclined.
The law of rape has become a major battleground of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law. The central question has become whether nominal consent to sexual relations constitutes actual consent, deep agreement in the heart. As in the economic context, power tends toward exploitation. The problem is particularly acute when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> seeking sexual favors‚Äîusually a man‚Äîis in a position of authority over his desired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. The most hotly debated cases are spun from skepticism about whether nominal consent actually generates the kind of voluntary relationship that should be regarded as an expression of freedom rather than of exploitation. The same is true of regulation of sexual harassment on the job. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> promises advancement or threatens disadvantaged treatment on the job, the appearance of complete and voluntary participation is readily undermined. So far, in the name of equality, we are willing to tolerate rather intrusive regulation of dating practices in corporate or university settings, but one can sense a coming backlash favoring the principle that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> old enough to vote should be old enough to make a responsible decision about their sexual lives<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX> Making it a crime or private action for damages for coworkers or costudents to have sexual relations would surely violate the right to sexual autonomy now recognized as an aspect of liberty protected by the due process clause<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX>
The problem of exploitation in apparently voluntary sexual relations has long been with us. In the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteenth century</TIMEX>, the problem was whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mormon</ENAMEX> practice of polygamy should be regarded as protected as liberty and the free expression of religious conviction. Those who defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, as provided in the accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormon</ENAMEX> religious doctrines of the time, cited its social benefit of caring for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in a society in which the available <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had fallen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> to the hardships of settlement and warfare. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, by contrast, claimed that the choice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in these cases is not really free and voluntary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stuart Mill</ENAMEX>, a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of liberty, sided with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of polygamy<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX> Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have had no qualms about prohibiting the practice, sometimes for parochial religious reasons, sometimes out of solicitude for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are subjected to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> that arguably diminishes their status. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormons</ENAMEX> sued, thinking they had the kind of argument that eventually prevailed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lochner</ENAMEX> case. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1878</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> upheld the conventional view that the prohibition represents permissible intervention by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to protect the weak against entering into exploitative relationships<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX> Many voices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> argue that this decision was wrong. The freedom to choose any form of domestic arrangement one wants should prevail against the state‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> against their own potentially bad choices.
The same problem recurs in the current debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>-assisted suicide. The argument for freedom and autonomy holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> should be able to choose when and how to end their lives. If they need the assistance of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> to be able to die with dignity, they should have that right. The contrary view stresses the dangers of manipulated consent. Once the possibility of voluntary euthanasia is recognized, the danger presents itself that terminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> will encounter social and economic pressure to consent to an early and painless death. Again, the problem is whether choices are as free as they seem on the surface, or whether they represent the subtle pressures that lead us to think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should intervene to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from manipulation and exploitation.
The anchor for this new conception of government‚Äîa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that intervenes in private choices in order to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> from exploitation‚Äîlies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>. Yet, it seems very ambitious to derive all of this from a black-letter prohibition against private arrangements of ‚Äúslavery and involuntary servitude.‚Äù The fact is that we are not entirely sure how far we should extend the prohibition against unjust relationships of domination. At the time the amendment was enacted, it was fairly clear that the drafters and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> had a broad construction in mind, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> became the constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights Act‚Äîindeed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> that is still used <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to prosecute those who, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> who beat up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX>, engage in racially motivated deprivations of civil rights<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> Because the deprivations of civil rights were understood to be an instantiation of relationships of unjust domination, it is clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> envisioned a new constitutional order much broader than merely business as usual, just without slavery.
Academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have found the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for constitutional speculation. Some have claimed that the amendment goes so far as to require the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to be watchful and intervene against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Others</ENAMEX> have argued that the amendment offers convincing grounds for recognizing abortion rights. Requiring a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to carry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to term arguably amounts to an oppressive form of involuntary servitude<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX> A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> voice holds, much in line with the argument of this book, that the potential ambit of ‚Äúinvoluntary servitude‚Äù includes all forms of employment and labor that are unjust and oppressive<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX> These are imaginative readings, and others are possible<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.21</NUMEX>
Some restraint is necessary. We have to be mindful of the prospect that the values of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Constitution</ENAMEX> might play themselves out more effectively as the informal restraints of civil society rather than as binding rules of law. As we have seen, our impulse to promote religion, love for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúpolitically correct‚Äù speech</ENAMEX> seems to yield greater results when the state holds back and limits itself to a gentle nudge in the right direction. But, more significantly, we have to recognize that we are locked in ongoing contradiction between the values of our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> constitutions.
The first <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> commits itself to freedom and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> builds both on a preference for equality and the recognition that freedom is often an illusion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> of freedom want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to keep its hands off, lest Big Brother‚Äôs intermeddling do more harm than good. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Constitution</ENAMEX> place their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> not in the natural mechanisms of social interaction but in the judgment of a vigilant hierarchy.
The first <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> plays on the theme of distrust in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. We must secure our freedoms against potentially abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> seeking ‚Äúrents‚Äù by pursuing their own bureaucratic interests.22 The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> constitution presupposes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in an aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX> of transactions that might slide into the forbidden <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúinvoluntary servitude</ENAMEX>.‚Äù In this regard, public opinion seems to be at odds with the de facto tolerance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for governmental action that is becoming ever more intrusive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> supposedly suffers from declining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in government<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.23</NUMEX> Yet, in fact, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> tolerates actions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that can make sense only on the assumption that those potentially affected by governmental abuse see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in a common struggle. A good example is the census and the popular reaction. The census form for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>, like several before it, poses probing questions about racial and ethnic identity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wants to know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> live in particular sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The questionnaire imposes a detailed grid of racial variations on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might otherwise simply have thought of themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> or perhaps as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúminorities</ENAMEX>.‚Äù This information becomes relevant, it is said, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> monitoring the distribution of voting power in congressional districts<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.24</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would not cooperate in answering these questions if they did not trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> not to misuse the collected information. There was a time when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sought indirectly to find out how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> still spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> at home. One can be sure that the purposes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early twentieth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, ever concerned about swelling immigration patterns, were not benign. And yet, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the common assumption is that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> may be trusted with a precise racial and ethnic map of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Popular attitudes even go beyond tolerance for the intrusion into our personal identities. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of multiracial backgrounds prefer to identify themselves as ‚Äúblack,‚Äù on the theory that it enhances the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to appear as numerous as possible<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.25</NUMEX> For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to serve as the vanguard of a new constitutional order, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> must trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> with additional powers and run the risk of governmental abuse.
This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> makes sense‚Äîdespite the surveys in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> report distrust‚Äîon the assumption that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> chooses to cooperate in the ascendancy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX> of equality and popular democracy. The breach of equal treatment need not be feared, and information on the distribution of potential voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> serves the cause of securing fair representation of all major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society.
Yet, the very effort to secure this fair representation of all voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> threatens both the sense of common nationhood in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and calls into question the integrity of individual decision making in democratic elections. Encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to identify themselves as hyphenated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> encourages multicultural consciousness and generates a growing sense of puzzlement about what it means to say that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Also, the assumption that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> can be elected only by black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> places us on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> that we cannot pursue to a logical conclusion. It would hardly be consistent with the premises of popular democracy to consider‚Äîeven as a thought-experiment‚Äîvoting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> that consisted primarily of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. The notion that particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are entitled to congressional representation merely as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> eventually runs squarely into the principle that in a democratic system <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> vote not as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> but solely as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. They have no duty to a hyphenated consciousness.
Yet, a trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can do much to remedy past discrimination and eliminate the badges of slavery. A new conception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might yet emerge to realize the ambitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>, to ensure equality of all those ‚Äúcreated equal‚Äù as it simultaneously promotes a ‚Äúnew birth of freedom.‚Äù It is as though nothing has been resolved. When the pursuit of equality begins to encroach upon our basic freedoms we are unsure where to turn.



