



With his carefully crafted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-minute</TIMEX> speech at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>, the best political address in the nation‚Äôs history, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> created a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nomos</ENAMEX>, a world of norms and meaning, for comprehending the mass slaughter on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> soil. The new understanding of why we were in mourning pointed to a resolution of the conflict and the beginnings of a new constitutional order. Rereading the speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> as the preamble to that new order, we can begin to understand the significance of the phrases so carefully chosen. The words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> Address are too powerful, they represent too much concentrated energy and wisdom, to be absorbed in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> that it takes to read them slowly. I suggest that we proceed and listen, sentence by sentence, phrase by phrase, to these words heard so often.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence states the heart of the matter and sums up the past, present, and future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> commitment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> score and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> brought forth on this continent a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, conceived in liberty and dedicated to the proposition that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal. This sentence alone was enough to formulate the preamble to the new constitution. It harbingers the themes that follow in the address and that will come to dominate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the 1860s</TIMEX>. Let us read each of these phrases as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in the preamble to the postbellum constitutional order.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> score and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX>. . . By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>, a historical consciousness had taken hold in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> thinking. Rooting ourselves in the past stands in sharp contrast to the preamble of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1787 Constitution</ENAMEX>, which begins simply, without setting the context: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, in order to form a more perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. . . .‚Äù There is no reference in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> document to the first settlement dating back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 160 years</TIMEX>, no sense that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was the outgrowth of an English-speaking culture across the seas. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> still desired to create ‚Äúa more perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>,‚Äù but it had in addition a past that both inspired and troubled the newly indigenous psyche.
The particular past that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> cultivates retains its ability to surprise and to make us take notice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to root his address in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> that created his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, but the great address is defiantly silent about the initial <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. As the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> document was silent about its great embarrassment, slavery, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> passes over a national charter that carried within it the seeds of war. In this preamble for a new order, the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is nowhere mentioned. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> locates the birth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> four score and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>. Until you do the arithmetic, you do not realize that, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs mind, the critical moment of the founding was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>, the signing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>. For those who knew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> well, this might not have been a surprise, for he had said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years before</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúI never had a feeling politically that did not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> from the sentiments embodied in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù1</ENAMEX>
The historical retreat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> with a major paradox. He claims to be speaking as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> owed its existence to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article II of the Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>. Yet, he thought himself back prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> convention and the creation of the presidency. He pulled the rug of legitimacy out from under his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. To be able to advocate the principle that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was born committed to this principle, he had to speak from a time prior to the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> died.
The precursor to this unusual mode of dating comes in an unexpected place‚Äîin the final paragraph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emancipation Proclamation</ENAMEX>, which went into effect on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1863</TIMEX>:
Done at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Washington</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this first day</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hundred</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty three</TIMEX>, and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States of America</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>.
By the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABRAHAM LINCOLN</ENAMEX>

It did not occur to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> that there might be some dissonance between his relying on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> as the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and his acting in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">office</ENAMEX> constituted by a document drafted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>. When he returned to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November of the same year</TIMEX>, he meant to stress the continuity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs vision, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who died at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> gave their lives not for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, not for a constitution, but to realize the peculiarly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> blend of nationhood and a set of ideas, particularly the idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was ‚Äúconceived in freedom.‚Äù There might be some disagreement about the moment of national coalescing, but to be sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was at war by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1775</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriots</ENAMEX> exposed themselves to great risk by appearing to have committed treason. It is with some appropriate fear of reprisal that they conclude the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence: ‚ÄúWe</ENAMEX> mutually pledge to each other our lives, our fortunes and our sacred honor.‚Äù
Lincoln‚Äôs posture toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1787 Constitution</ENAMEX> was less than reverent. He treated the founding charter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> more as a guideline to action than as a set of absolute restrictions on his actions. His decisions, particularly in the early stages of the war, suggest a willingness to assert extraconstitutional executive power and, thus, to permit the exigencies of war to restructure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1861</TIMEX>, in the immediate shadow of the shelling of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Sumter</ENAMEX>, he declared a blockade on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX>. Whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> could properly seize <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> without congressional approval became one of the early legal controversies of the war<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> And then came the dispute about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs authorizing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> in the field to suspend the writ of habeas corpus‚Äîthe great writ by which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> retain the power to supervise the arrest and detention of criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> permits suspension of this protection in times of civil unrest‚Äîbut fails to specify whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> may act unilaterally in ordering suspension. Sitting alone as a circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taney</ENAMEX> interpreted the constitutional provision to require congressional authorization for suspending the writ<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> In light of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taney‚</ENAMEX>Äôs notorious opinion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> case<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX> his views hardly carried much weight in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. In a move widely regarded as authoritarian, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> simply disregarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taney‚Äôs</ENAMEX> opinion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> justified his unilateral action with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> claim of necessity, articulated in a message to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4, 1861</TIMEX>:

The whole of the laws which were required to be faithfully executed were being resisted . . . in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly one third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Must they be allowed to finally fail of execution, even had it been perfectly clear that by the use of the means necessary to their execution some single law, made in such extreme tenderness of the citizen‚Äôs liberty that, practically, it relieves more of the guilty than of the innocent, should to a very limited extent be violated? . . . Are all the laws but one to go unexecuted, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> itself go to pieces lest that one be violated?<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>

Read with our current sensitivity to civil liberties, these are embarrassing words. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> argues, in effect, that he can justify violating a constitutional prescription by appealing to the necessity of the moment. Of course, if the stark option were posed‚Äîviolating this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúone law‚Äù</ENAMEX> or letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> ‚Äúgo to pieces‚Äù‚Äîmost of us would agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should survive the emergency, even by transgressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. Yet, there is no evidence that the country‚Äôs circumstances were anywhere near this flashpoint of imminent destruction. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs casual disdain for the writ of habeas <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corpus (‚Äúit relieves</ENAMEX> more of the guilty than of the innocent‚Äù) reveals a lack of appreciation for the point of constitutional protections in criminal procedure. My own reading is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs suspending the writ on his own initiative and disregarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taney‚</ENAMEX>Äôs supposed invalidation of the decision testifies to an altered state of constitutional thinking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> lay suspended in the fires of battle. A new constitutional order would arise from the war, but no one quite knew what shape it would take.
Of course, during the war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1787 Constitution</ENAMEX> remained nominally in force. There was little suggestion of a ‚Äúmilitary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>,‚Äù though some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> invoked the phrase. Lincoln‚Äôs elected term came to an end in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1865</TIMEX>. In the midst of the war, therefore, he was constitutionally required to stand for reelection. This event in itself warranted the stability of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, but still ambiguity reigned on the shape of the postbellum constitutional order. The confusion came to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>, for arguably asserting excessive executive power in firing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">War Edwin Stanton</ENAMEX>. The outcome of that impeachment trial is well known: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> avoided conviction by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote. Less well known is the outcome of the struggle to develop a new constitutional order, the struggle that is signaled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs address commemorating the dead at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>.
. . . our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> brought forth on this continent. . . The biblical cadence of these words resonates in memory. We know that we have encountered it someplace before. They remind us of the way God introduces himself to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moses in the Book of Exodus: ‚ÄúI am the God</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> . . . So I have come down to rescue [my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>] from the hand of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, to bring it up from that land to a land, goodly and spacious, to a land flowing with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>. . . .‚Äù It is not surprising that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> would evoke the style of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX>. Even the introductory phrase ‚Äúfour score and seven‚Äù has a prophetic ring. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, after all, was one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs favorite books‚Äîalong with the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aesop‚Äôs Fables</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX> makes much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> influence in shaping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> style at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>.6 But of the biblical influence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wills</ENAMEX> has almost nothing to say. This is a rather curious twist in seeking to understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> whose thinking and rhetoric were probably more influenced by the biblical idiom than the writings of any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> second inaugural address is replete with references to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, including, notably, the latter part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Psalm 19</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10: ‚</TIMEX>ÄúThe fear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> is clean, enduring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX>; the judgments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> are true and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">righteous</ENAMEX> altogether.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Lincoln</ENAMEX> saw the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> as a righteous judgment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divine</ENAMEX>. It is almost inconceivable that he would seek to formulate a framework for understanding the war‚Äôs place in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history without relying on biblical imagery.
Of all the biblical themes that shaped <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lincoln‚Äôs thinking, the Hebrews‚Äô Exodus</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> was the most compelling. In a speech he gave in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trenton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX>, he referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as ‚ÄúHis almost chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù The ‚ÄúHis‚Äù</ENAMEX> refers, of course, to God. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> stand, one almost dares to say, in the place of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in a covenantal relationship with God. The idea that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> or some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> replaced the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in their covenantal relationship was a familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> theme. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilgrims</ENAMEX> brought the idea with them as they founded their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> settlements. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> comes close to repeating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> idea. This accounts, I believe, for the apparent redundancy in ‚Äúbrought forth on this continent.‚Äù His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> would surely have understood that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> was talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> ‚Äúfour score and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> ago‚Äù without locating the events ‚Äúon this continent.‚Äù But this continent was the locus of the new covenant. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilgrims</ENAMEX> had made a journey to a new land, and the new land promised a partnership with God that was not possible without an exodus from the old world. The single word ‚Äúcontinent,‚Äù reminding us of the journey, invokes an entire theology.
We should remember that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> overflows with references to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creator</ENAMEX> and the imprint of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> destiny, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> is a totally secular document. In style as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> returns to the religiosity of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration</ENAMEX>.
. . . brought forth on this continent a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. . . The use of the word ‚Äúnation‚Äù signals a major theme of the address. In the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">252</NUMEX> words, it will appear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more times<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> By accentuating the term ‚Äúnation,‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> sets himself at odds with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> preamble‚Äôs invocation of ‚ÄúWe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚</ENAMEX>Äù as the source of all legitimacy. Now, in place of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> appears the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, a term that with its connection to birth (nasci, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> for ‚Äúto be born‚Äù) suggests a conception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that extends over generations‚Äîreaching back to the founding eighty-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> before and encompassing those who will survive the war and flourish in its aftermath.
‚ÄúWe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚</ENAMEX>Äù are sovereign in every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. A single cohort can found a constitution and another can presumably decide to withdraw from the commitment. Thus some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> have argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> retain the authority both to transform the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> or, if they so choose, to repeal it entirely<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.8</NUMEX> I disagree. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are understood as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> including the dead and the unborn, then no single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> can undo the work of the past or renege on its implicit promise to the future. There is no way that those who happened to be alive in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1860s</TIMEX> could overrule the confirmation by preceding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. Thus, by extending themselves out over history, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> sense, in the same sense as had already been realized in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and was then making itself felt in the unification movements in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-nineteenth century</TIMEX> was a time in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of the West, tracing their lineage to common linguistic and historical roots, built political movements grounded in a shared national identity. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> broke out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy‚Äôs Risorgimento</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist awakening</ENAMEX>, entered its critical phase. Thanks to the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camillo Benso di Cavour</ENAMEX> in the north and the military prowess of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giuseppe Garibaldi</ENAMEX> in the south, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> achieved a unification of diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont, Sicily</ENAMEX>, the papal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sardinia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Emmanuel II</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sardinia</ENAMEX> became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the united <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX>, by a combination of military annexation, diplomacy and bribery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto von Bismarck</ENAMEX> was able to unify the northern and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Reich</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prussia</ENAMEX> as its central power. There followed, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX>, the enactment of the first pan-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> criminal code.
This process of unifying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and, at the same time, establishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to govern the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> had given us the idea of the nation-state. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as a prepolitical reality finds its embodiment in the apparatus of state power. The traditional view is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was different, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> sense. I beg to differ.
My claim is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> address expresses the same idea that was then current in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of common history and language constitutes a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, and the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">form</ENAMEX> for the nation‚Äôs survival was in a state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>. The idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> constituted an organic national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> explained, implicitly, why the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> could not go their own way. As he assumed the presidency, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> still spoke of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>; but in the course of the debates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> immediately preceding, the notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> had acquired the metaphysical qualities of nationhood. In his first inaugural address, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> invoked the ‚Äúbonds of affection,‚Äù and even before <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX> were fired on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort Sumter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston Harbor</ENAMEX>, he stressed the unbreakable ties of historical struggle:

The mystical chords of memory, stretching from every battlefield, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot grate</ENAMEX>, to every living heart and hearth-stone, all over this broad land, will yet swell the chorus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. . . .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was bound together by historical experience and by its destiny, its ‚Äúmanifest destiny,‚Äù in the phrase used to explain the push westward that occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> leading up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>.
Lincoln‚Äôs purpose on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 19, 1863</TIMEX>, was not to intensify but to transcend the war effort. Significantly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnation‚Äù</ENAMEX> of which he speaks includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>. He was speaking at the dedication of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX>, but there is hardly a partisan word to be heard in the entire address<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>
My sense of the literature of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history is that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> not only ignore the biblical influences on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs thinking at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> but also fail to understand the significance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnation‚Äù</ENAMEX> that ‚Äúour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> brought forth on this continent.‚Äù The common mistake, particularly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, is to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnation‚Äù</ENAMEX> in this context as equivalent to the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, or to the national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> as opposed to local geographical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. In this limited sense, the ‚Äúnation‚Äù is constituted by a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or by a physical space staked out on maps and recognized by other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is then equivalent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> or the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. But the issue is not the authority of the ‚Äúnational‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in contrast to states‚Äô rights. The derivative sense of nationhood as denoting ‚Äúunified at a federal level‚Äù is surely present as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> meaning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs invocation of the term, but this could not possibly be all that he meant to say.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, as it existed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> sense. The assumption that drove the movements of national unification on the continent was that each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> should be able to govern itself. And self-government requires that each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> should be able to constitute itself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. If this was the thrust of mid-century <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> history, the same was to be expected of the immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
. . . a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, conceived in liberty and dedicated to the proposition that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal. Thus ends the remarkable first sentence of the address. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of which we speak is immediately qualified. This is not simply a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of common lineage‚Äîan extension of tribal identity. We are indeed different from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is born of an idea. It is conceived in liberty and dedicated to an aspiration of equality.
What exactly does it mean to be ‚Äúconceived in liberty?‚Äù This phrase is so redolent with meaning that we simply savor it without reflection. Does it mean that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is conceived free, as if it were in a state of nature? Is it only after its conception that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> binds itself by the strictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>? It could mean these things. Or it could simply mean that our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> constitutional commitment was to freedom, which, as we shall see, was certainly true. Yet, somehow the glorification of freedom of speech, freedom of religion, the right to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arms‚</ENAMEX>Äîamong the freedoms sanctified in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights‚</ENAMEX>Äîfails to capture the measure of being ‚Äúconceived in liberty.‚Äù Our liberty persists as our birthright, even as we search for the proper way to build a democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of equal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
A stylistic point should intrigue us. It is hardly an accident that in this phrase ‚Äúconceived in liberty,‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> chose the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>-based ‚Äúliberty‚Äù rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanic ‚Äúfreedom.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù ‚ÄúConceived</ENAMEX> in freedom‚Äù might have had roughly the same meaning, but it would have lacked the lyrical ring. The reason, I believe, is that both <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúconceived‚Äù</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúliberty‚Äù derive</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. We return to this point later in the address, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">links ‚Äúfreedom‚Äù</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúliberty‚Äù</ENAMEX> with the image of a new birth.
What, then, is the relationship between liberty and equality in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs vision of a new order? We are conceived in liberty and dedicated to the proposition of human equality. That was the way it was then, and it is the way it is now. The realization of equality in practical affairs will always elude us. Even after this aspiration was incorporated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, the ideal of equality remained a distant point on the spectrum of political possibilities. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would be rendered politically equal and receive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>; eventually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> would be integrated and the laws against mixed marriages would, with a sense of shame that they ever existed, be struck down. None of this was obvious in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863 or 1868</TIMEX> or even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>. Yet, the commitment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> made at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gettysburg‚</ENAMEX>Äîall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, are created equal‚Äîbecame a moral lodestar testifying to the equal dignity of all human beings, whether the legal culture had validated that equality or not.
Implicit in this structure‚Äîconceived in one value, dedicated to another‚Äîlies a conception of an ordered legal culture. Some values are stated in rules that are capable of immediate realization; others are stated as principles of aspiration. The latter are ideals to be pursued, opportunities for self-improvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty</ENAMEX> is a given. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equality</ENAMEX> remains the promise.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylists</ENAMEX> have objected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs labeling the great maxim of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúproposition</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Encountering</ENAMEX> this word in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence, the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Arnold</ENAMEX> reportedly stopped reading in literary disgust<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">.10 ‚ÄúProposition‚</NUMEX>Äù was too legalistic for his taste. But it was critical for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> to restate his understanding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Declaration‚</ENAMEX>Äôs vision of equality. As he said in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX> speech in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1857</TIMEX>:

They [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration</ENAMEX>] meant simply to declare the right, so that the enforcement of it might follow as fast as circumstances should permit. They meant to set up a standard maxim for a free society, which should be familiar to all, and revered by all, constantly looked to, constantly labored for, and even though never perfectly attained, constantly approximated, and thereby constantly spreading and deepening its influence. . . .


Immediately following the victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>, in an informal talk at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4, 1863</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> began the process of looking to and reiterating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äústandard maxim‚Äù</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>. Thinking of equality as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúproposition‚Äù</ENAMEX> gives it a reality, an ontological presence in our lives, not quite captured by alternative terms like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúideal‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúvision.‚Äù We are conceived in one value and live anchored to another proposition, not yet instantiated in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> practices.
In structural terms, this means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> and, notably, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> represent the baseline. They enshrine the liberty in which we are conceived. But the ideals toward which we yearn are incorporated in a charter morally superior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, namely the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of 1776</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Declaration</ENAMEX> served both as a legal brief for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX> and as the standard for criticizing the compromise represented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>. The freedom achieved in the war against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> necessitated another war in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX> to redeem us from tolerating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">South‚Äôs ‚</ENAMEX>Äúpeculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù11</ENAMEX>
In this magisterial first sentence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>, there lurks <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX> for both sides in the great conflict that surrounded the calm of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 19, 1863</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> could draw sustenance, as I have suggested, from the reconceptualization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as an organic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. But so far as the address also validates the case for separation from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, it also provides an argument for secession from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. What, after all, was the difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America‚</ENAMEX>Äôs seceding from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South‚</ENAMEX>Äôs leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> loyalists could well argue that as their grandfathers had consented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, they were entitled to withdraw their consent. They as a group were equal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>, and, therefore, they could choose which form of the social contract would work for them.
We sometimes forget the context in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> in which we find the phrase: All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal. The claim of equality prepares the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> for the more important thesis that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, as equals, possess certain inalienable rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúthat</ENAMEX> among these are life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.‚Äù The purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is to secure these rights. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> to realize these ends. But if ‚Äúany form of government‚Äù should be perceived as ‚Äúdestructive‚Äù toward these ends, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that originally gave their consent are entitled to withdraw it. They are entitled to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúalter or abolish‚Äù a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that departs radically from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to which had given their consent. It follows, supposedly, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> were entitled to withdraw their consent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX>.
When fully stated in this fashion, the argument of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> invites several observations. First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> never officially gave their consent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX>. They grew up under the tutelage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> monarchy and their adhering to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX> was something like a child‚Äôs joining its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The most that one could say is that they never consented and that therefore when they matured and reached the age of consent they were entitled to say no. By contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> did join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> by signing the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and ratifying the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. If they gave their consent to a form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, they‚Äîby the logic of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1776‚</NUMEX>Äîshould be able to withdraw from the pact. Paradoxically, it seems, the logic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> applies more cogently to the claim of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> than to the arguments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>.
Note further that in the structure of the argument, the premise of equality plays a curious role. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal. So what? How does that strengthen the case against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX>? The cornerstone of that case is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> derive their legitimacy from the consent of their governed. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> has not consented to their form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is not legitimate. This would be true even if within the society, human beings were not all of equal dignity and status. Whether some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were intrinsically superior to others or not, they could all enjoy a collective right to withhold consent from a repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>.
What, then, is the point of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Declaration‚</ENAMEX>Äôs claim that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal? The answer is twofold. First, there is an implicit claim that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are equal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and to all other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>. If any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be able to consent to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, too, enjoyed that fundamental right. That they were a colony‚Äînurtured as the metaphoric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown‚</ENAMEX>Äîdid not mean that they could not assume the posture of an equal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. If this is the meaning of equality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration</ENAMEX>, then it provides little support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was dedicated to a proposition that implicitly required the abolition of slavery.
A more compelling reading of ‚ÄúAll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal‚Äù would be that all human beings are equal among themselves as well as being equal as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">collective entities</ENAMEX>. They are equal among themselves precisely in that they possess inalienable rights‚Äîthe same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inalienable rights to ‚Äúlife</ENAMEX>, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness‚Äù possessed by everyone else. Reading the document in this way enables us better to understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs posture toward abolition. There is ample evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> regarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> as morally and socially inferior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. He said so in numerous speeches in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1850s</TIMEX>. But despite these ‚Äúracist‚Äù assumptions that were common to his time, he fervently regarded slavery as an evil. It was an evil precisely because it deprived <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> of their inalienable rights to life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness. They could not enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> of their own labor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX> was a system under which slaveholders were ‚Äúwringing their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> from the sweat of other men‚Äôs faces.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù12</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is born dedicated to this proposition that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are equal with regard to their basic human rights. This idea is extracted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>, but the rest of its argument is discarded as outdated. There is no mention at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> of the requirement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consent to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and that they should have the right to withdraw consent when unsatisfied. Nor, in light of the argument‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX>, would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> have acceded to the language of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>. He would have little reason to argue that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> had the right to consent or withhold consent to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was in place, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> made claims across time. No particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> could undo the work laid so carefully in the past.
The address continues with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> sentence that locates us in the present. Now we are engaged in a great <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, testing whether that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> or any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> so conceived and so dedicated can long endure. Thus begins the internal portion of the address, which is devoted to the war and its dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> repeats the conventional label for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> indulgence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bloodletting‚Äîthe ‚Äúcivil‚Äù</ENAMEX> war. The word has the connotation of the private or domestic (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> civil) or of a phenomenon arising spontaneously up from the citizenry (civil society). The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> preferred the expression the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">‚ÄúWar</ENAMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>,‚Äù by which they hoped for recognition that the war was more than a rebellion and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX> had full legal status as a belligerent under international law. Lincoln‚Äôs choice of the favored Northern expression is his only partisan word in the address.
I prefer the unconventional label: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">‚ÄúThe War</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers‚</ENAMEX>Äù or the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">‚ÄúBrothers‚Äô War</ENAMEX>.‚Äù That is indeed what it was. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX> met and fought each other in the field. But even more significant, the slaying of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">620,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> should be understood as an offering on the altar of fraternity. For every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> who were liberated, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had to die. They gave their lives so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> ‚Äúmight endure.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Significantly</ENAMEX>, in this sentence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> repeats the claim of nationhood and stresses that the great evil of the war is not that it threatens the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. The great danger is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> threatens the survival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, of course, includes both sides in the conflict.
This conception of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> accounts for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs religious language in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugural address delivered, as victory seemed near, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4, 1865</TIMEX>. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> thinks of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North and South</ENAMEX> as bound together in their religious devotion: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúBoth read the same <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, and pray to the same God; and each invokes His aid against the other. . . . The prayers of both could not be answered.‚Äù The massive bloodletting of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> war is seen as a divine response to evil in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> founding.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almighty</ENAMEX> has his own purposes. ‚ÄúWoe unto the world because of offences! For it must needs be that offences come; but woe to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> by whom the offence cometh!‚Äù The terrible war is seen as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúwoe‚Äù</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúscourge‚Äù inflicted</ENAMEX> for the terrible ‚Äúoffence‚Äù of slavery. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> was committed by all‚Äîthose who were active and those who were passive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> suffered punishment for its collective sin. But it could return to normalcy with the same sense of collective compassion, and thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> extends his hand: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWith malice toward none, with charity for all; with firmness in the right, as God gives us to see the right.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ends his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugural address in the expectation of peaceful reconstruction and with a gesture of solidarity toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the killing fields.
The policy of ‚Äúmalice toward none, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> toward all‚Äù is anticipated in the affirmation at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> enduring, as it were, a calamity imposed for its sins. Yet, there was a deep contradiction between this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> expressed toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> and the military objectives that were becoming obvious in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1863</TIMEX>. In order to achieve the newly set goal of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emancipation</ENAMEX>, to achieve the end that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX> he calls the ‚Äúright, as God gives us to see the right,‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> would send his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> to wage total war against the civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Sheridan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Shenandoah crops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Tecumseh Sherman‚</ENAMEX>Äôs conquest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, and then his march to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> all anticipate the terror that became commonplace some eighty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> in the bombings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dresden</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appomattox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> will maintain a political policy of charity and reconciliation, coupled with a military posture that would leave no doubts about the right in the minds of the defeated.
The choice of the words ‚ÄúCivil War‚Äù to describe the conflict also expresses charity toward the rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX>. They are not treated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> attacking federal installations and killing federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. Rather they are in a joint effort with their fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> to determine the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
There follow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> sentences in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> ties together the mourning of the moment with our commitment to higher ideals:

We are met on a great battle-field of that war.
We have come to dedicate a portion of that field as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> might live.
It is altogether fitting and proper that we should do this.
But in a larger sense, we cannot dedicate‚Äîwe cannot consecrate‚Äîwe cannot hallow this ground.
The brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, living and dead, who struggled here have consecrated it far above our poor power to add or detract.
The world will little note nor long remember what we say here, but it can never forget what they did here.
It is for us the living, rather, to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they who fought here have thus far so nobly advanced.
It is rather for us to be here dedicated to the great task remaining before us‚Äîthat from these honored dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of devotion‚Äîthat we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain. . . .

Let us leave this sentence in the middle and reserve the final peroration for a closer look. Here, in the heart of the address, it becomes clear that the key themes of the preamble for the postbellum legal order are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, death, and dedication. And the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ideas conveyed by these words are intimately connected. The notion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and the fact of death root us in the past. These are irreversible facts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is born of history; the dead link us to time past. The fantasies of power, the aspirations of ‚ÄúWe the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People‚Äù</ENAMEX> cannot undo the defining power of history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is implanted in time, and the dead are interred in the plots that lie before the speaker‚Äôs dais. Yet, the dead can live, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> can live, if these shadows of the past are transformed into memory, and memory is nourished by dedication to the values that define the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> remains ambiguous about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúgreat task‚Äù</ENAMEX> to which we should be dedicated so that ‚Äúthese dead shall not have died in vain.‚Äù The long-range objective is the redemption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúoffences‚Äù‚</ENAMEX>Äîfrom its original sin of having tolerated entrenched inequality in the very framework of its original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. The immediate task is finishing the war and reuniting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. We are not informed of the task that matters until the concluding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> clauses of the address: that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shall not perish from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. Along with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence, these words have taken on a nearly sacred quality in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America‚</ENAMEX>Äôs conception of itself and its mission in the world. They retrace the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> themes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, death, and dedication. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúnation‚Äù</ENAMEX> is present, now in conjunction with God. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> shall defeat ‚Äúdeath:‚Äù it shall have ‚Äúa new birth‚Äù and it ‚Äúshall not perish.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> will surmount death with its new dedication‚Äîto freedom for all.
These words have entered into the civil religion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. They are better known than the preamble to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>. Let us pause and take a closer look.

. . . that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, under God, . . .

The invocation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divine</ENAMEX> signals a major departure from the resolutely secular nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Constitution</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> itself repeatedly refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creator</ENAMEX>. Yet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> studiously avoids any word suggestive of a power higher than the will of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The purpose of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> national charter is to serve the goals enumerated in its preamble (justice, domestic tranquility, the common defense, the general welfare, and securing liberty), and its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">legitimation</ENAMEX> lies exclusively in the possibility that a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will advance these worldly goals. This was fitting for a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> that sought to distance itself from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that had established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> at the national level and that relied on religious tests for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. There would be none of that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX>
Significantly, the abolitionist movement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1830s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1840s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1850s</ENAMEX> brought a passion for religious truth in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics that had not previously existed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Parker</ENAMEX>, among other devout <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the movement, preached against <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúthe Slave Power‚</ENAMEX>Äù in tones that made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> think that the devil was marching into the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territories</ENAMEX>. The recognition that slaves, too, were ‚Äúmade in the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God‚Äù</ENAMEX> provided a powerful rallying point for a crusade to correct the original mistake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>. Of course, various biblical passages served the other side as well, but the ardor for abolition drew heavily and indispensably on the sense of a higher law.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>, as written, apparently did not contain the reference to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthis <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, under God.‚Äù As he spoke, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> spontaneously broke with his prepared text. The reference to God appears in neither of the drafts that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Hay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Nicolay</ENAMEX>, said were the prepared texts. Yet, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who were present reported hearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">divine invocation</ENAMEX>, though some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> saying ‚Äúthis <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> shall under God have a new birth‚Äù rather than the word order that has come to be accepted ‚Äúthis <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, under God, shall have a new birth.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù14</ENAMEX>
The reference to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthis <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">God‚</ENAMEX>Äù reinforces the conception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as an organic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, a single subject that could, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, enter into a covenant with a God. The substitution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for the covenanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jews‚</ENAMEX>Äîhowever sacrilegious the idea may sound‚Äîlanded in the New World with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritans</ENAMEX> and became a standard item of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> theology. Thus, we can understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> referring at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trenton</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúHis</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">God‚Äôs</ENAMEX>] almost chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù15</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> was not only a war to establish the unbreakable bond that unites all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. It was also a war understood by many, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> included, to have theological significance. It drew its power from religious claims about the humanity of all human beings, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> found their solace in psalms and prayers. To close his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugural address, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> expressed the faith: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúThe judgments of the Law</ENAMEX> are true and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">righteous</ENAMEX> altogether.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù16</ENAMEX>
We can date the advent of civil religion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to this period of theological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ferment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. It was at this time, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1864</TIMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> initiated the practice of printing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúIN GOD WE TRUST‚Äù</ENAMEX> on our coins and currency. It is hard to imagine that any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western world</ENAMEX> would permit their money‚Äîthe currency of secular commerce‚Äîto advertise a religious message. Yet, nondenominational expressions of faith have become normal in the rituals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Opening sessions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with a prayer, using the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> in swearing-in ceremonies, recognizing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> as national holidays‚Äîall of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rituals</ENAMEX> testify to an abiding nondenominational religiosity. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are virtually united in their willingness to advertise a widespread faith in God. For some reason, this is not generally understood as contradicting the principle of separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> laid down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">phrase ‚Äúnation</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">God‚</ENAMEX>Äù has acquired an almost casual banality. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> after the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1892</TIMEX>, the practice of reciting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pledge of Allegiance</ENAMEX> spontaneously swept the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In the original version of the pledge, we swore allegiance to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúone <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> indivisible. . . .‚Äù In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>, the sense that something was missing persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Eisenhower</ENAMEX> to return to the formulation that crossed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs lips at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúOne <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all.‚Äù
As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnation</ENAMEX> under God,<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">‚Äù Americans</ENAMEX> have been both blessed and cursed by a sense of mission in the world. Covenanted with higher powers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">destiny‚Äîa ‚Äúmanifest destiny‚</ENAMEX>Äù as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John L. O‚</ENAMEX>ÄôSullivan dubbed our policy of westward expansion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1840s</TIMEX>. The phrase took hold and gave <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> a sense of national purpose as they annexed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1845</TIMEX>, negotiated a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, and led the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>.17 This was territorial aggrandizement in the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnation</ENAMEX> under God.‚Äù These were the aggressive moves that established most of the boundaries of the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as they are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> belief in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmanifest destiny‚Äù</ENAMEX> and territorial expansion led ineluctably to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>. As long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> was fixed at a certain number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> states and a certain number of free, both sides could calculate the future. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> could count on the continuation of its ‚Äúpeculiar institution‚Äù despite fierce opposition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>. But the westward expansion and the absorption of new territories led to intrigue and suspicion about whether slavery would be permissible in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that would eventually develop out of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territories</ENAMEX>. The acceptance of slavery in the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> might have been an unholy compromise. With manifest destiny and the occupation of new territories, the compromise became not only unholy but unstable.
. . . shall have a new birth of freedom, . . . Here, near his peroration, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> reaffirms the foundational value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>. Freedom of speech, of the press, of the right to bear arms in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfree‚Äù state‚Äîthese</ENAMEX> were the motivating values of the original constitutional order. They would be cherished in the new order as well, but for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time freedom would be available to all. There would be no scar in its connotations, as there was in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-fifths compromise, which for purposes of representation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> counted ‚Äúthe whole number of free persons‚Äù and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-fifths ‚Äúof all other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù18 That distinction between the free and the unfree would disappear in the birth of a new constitutional order.
Our stylistic question recurs. Why did it seem more natural for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> to use the word freedom in this context than liberty? Somehow it would not do to speak of ‚Äúa new birth of liberty.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> of ‚Äúconceived in liberty‚Äù and ‚Äúnew birth of freedom‚Äù convinces me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> origins of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> (con√ßue en libert√© in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germanic</ENAMEX> roots of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> (eine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neue Geburt der Freiheit</ENAMEX> in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>) lends internal harmony to these phrases. It is almost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> can expect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX>, that in forging a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of black and white he should recall for us the melding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
. . . and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shall not perish from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. In this final phrase that, along with the opening ‚Äúfour score and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> ago‚Äù has become the most familiar cadence of the address, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> formulates an additional commitment of the postbellum era. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should be elected ‚Äúby the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,‚Äù it should be ‚Äúof the people‚Äù and exist ‚Äúfor the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.‚Äù The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> would vote at the polls. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would serve the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. At least, this was the aspiration. It would take several more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to absorb not only black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of all races.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hypnotic cadence ‚Äúof</ENAMEX>, by, for the people‚Äù did not originate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>. In an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1850</TIMEX> speech to an antislavery convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Parker</ENAMEX> had used similar language in explaining the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> conception of democracy:

That is, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, by all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; of course, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the principles of eternal justice, the unchanging law of God<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX>

There might be a strong link between thinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as a single organic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and bringing God into politics, but it is much harder to make out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker‚</ENAMEX>Äôs view that a democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would function ‚Äúunder the unchanging law of God.‚Äù The democratic idea is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> remain free to change the law by majority vote. A more generous interpretation of this phrase is suggested, however, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker‚</ENAMEX>Äôs linking the law of God to the ‚Äúprinciples of eternal justice.‚Äù As the law of judicial review would eventually develop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, these ‚Äúprinciples of eternal justice‚Äù provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> for testing the constitutionality of state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúdue process‚Äù clause of the Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>. One could well accept, then, the idea of a universal popular franchise exercising its authority to make and change the law under the check provided by ‚Äúeternal principles of justice.‚Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker‚Äôs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> commitment to popular democracy represents a clean break with the limited forms of indirect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> recognized under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> document drafted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>. According to the √©litist republican scheme envisioned at the founding, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> that would be popularly elected would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>, and that body would be chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that was qualified to elect ‚Äúthe most numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Legislature</ENAMEX>.‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù20 Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would be elected by each state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>.21 The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was, and still is, to be elected by an electoral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.22</NUMEX> The original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> was silent not only about who was entitled to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> but also on the questions of whether only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> should be entitled to vote. All this was left to state law and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> generally limited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> to white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male adult citizens</ENAMEX> who owned the requisite amount of property. The word ‚Äúdemocracy‚Äù is not even mentioned in either the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>.
War has a democratizing influence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> fight side by side and when they lay down their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> they expect to be able to rule side by side. It is not surprising, then, that in the aftermath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> we find a new commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> by all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The postbellum constitutional order takes the expansion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> as one of its first priorities. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> secured the right to vote regardless of ‚Äúrace, color, or previous condition of servitude.‚Äù Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> succeeding amendments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixteenth</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twenty-Seventh</ENAMEX> (leaving aside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eighteenth</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twenty-First</ENAMEX> repealing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eighteenth</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> have addressed the extension of the power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to choose their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.23</NUMEX> In short, the securing of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> promise of universal popular suffrage became the primary focus of the new constitutional order.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>, understood as the preamble to a new constitutional order, underscores <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> values that stand in radical relief to the motivating concerns of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> as it stood, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1791</TIMEX>. In outline form these are the constitutional structures:

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary ConstitutionCivil War Constitution</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dates: Dates:</ENAMEX> 
Proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>, ratifiedPreamble in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>, went into force <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1789</TIMEX>, amendedReconstruction amendments
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> 1791in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865, 1868</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX>

Source of authority:<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Source</ENAMEX> of authority: 
We the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">PeopleThe Nation</ENAMEX> as Defined 
by History

Primary value: Primary value: 
FreedomEquality

Mode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mode</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: 
RepublicDemocracy

Highest power: Highest powers: 
Will of the livingCommand of history, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">divine</ENAMEX> mission

The contrast could not be stronger. And, most significantly, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> new points of reference were all articulated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>.
Each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groupings</ENAMEX> hangs together with internal coherence. It makes sense for a constitution that glorifies the will of the living also to take freedom as its highest value. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> charter was very much a document of eighteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> reason: it placed faith in the capacity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to order their affairs as they saw fit. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> score years of history proved that their self-ordering led them, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> put it in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugural, into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">committing ‚Äúoffences‚Äù</ENAMEX> for which they would pay with a ‚Äúterrible war.‚Äù
The new constitutional order begins more humbly with obeisance to both God and the finer strains in our own historical tradition. It partakes of the historicist thinking that dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> Romantic thought at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúspirit of the times‚Äù‚Äîthe Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Savigny‚Äôs</ENAMEX> classic phrase‚Äîwas speaking in the triumph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and its commitment to the equality of all.
The new constitutional order cohered as a compelling ideological whole. The values of nationhood, equality, and democracy were interrelated and mutually supportive, precisely as was the original trilogy of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1787‚Äîpeoplehood</NUMEX>, freedom, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">republican √©litism</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> vision of a new constitutional order may have been too radical for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurists</ENAMEX> of the time. There emerged reactionary forces that sought to mystify and entrench the values of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>. Before turning to the counter thrust of postbellum history, we need to understand more fully the internal coherence of the constitutional order signaled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>.



