



The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX> is that it took the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> and found in them a crystallization of a meaning suitable for the refounding of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>, the idea that ‚Äúall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal‚Äîfor all purposes‚Äù had no precedent in the declarations of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Even the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of the Rights of Man</ENAMEX>, issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Revolution</ENAMEX>, preached a more limited version of equality‚Äî‚ÄúAll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are born and remain equal under the law.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù1 In its original context, the famous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> words ‚Äúall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal‚Äù had a limited function. They undermined the pretension of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX> to rule under the divine right of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>. If all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were of equal stature under God, then no one could claim to have been anointed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> by supernatural authority. At the same time, however, the famous maxim could also be understood as referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúmen‚Äù</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">collective entities</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> have equal status.‚Äù It was not particularly novel to argue that all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, had an equal claim to govern themselves. The principle of national self-determination, urged so adamantly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twentieth century</TIMEX>, derives from the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>: every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is entitled to preserve its own culture, cultivate its language, and express itself as a subject of the international community. International law is based on the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, anchored in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, enter into legal relationships. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> are embodied enjoy legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>. They incur debts and, significantly, these debts are not extinguished by revolutionary changes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The forms of the state come and go, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> endures through it all. It is no wonder, therefore, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> would assert that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were equally entitled, with all other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, to determine their form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> senses of the famous ‚Äúall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal‚Äù capture the ambiguous quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> revolt against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. It was both a revolutionary and an anticolonial war of independence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary spirit</ENAMEX> was captured in the categorical rejection of monarchy. The anticolonial thrust appears in the assertion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans‚</ENAMEX>Äô equal claim to rule by ‚Äúconsent of the governed.‚Äù
More far-reaching than both of these original meanings, however, is the individualist interpretation: All human beings are of equal dignity. They are created equal and remain equal in the eyes of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creator</ENAMEX>. There can be no foundation, therefore, for the claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> are superior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> should count more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Of course, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave owners</ENAMEX> and most, if not all of them, were patriarchal heads of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. Yet, they bequeathed to the world a rhetorical phrase that was pregnant with meaning deeper than many of them may have intended. This deeper meaning lay, embedded in the text, ready to come alive for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time as their Declaration became the sacred text of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> abolitionist movement.
Legal texts often bear one meaning on their surface and a higher meaning that requires faith and personal investment beyond the surface meaning. A good example is the commandment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decalogue</ENAMEX> prohibiting homicide. Allow me a short digression on the commandment against killing to illustrate the phenomenon of a text that carries one meaning on its surface and a more radical meaning beneath.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> expression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixth Commandment</ENAMEX>, lo tirtsach, is generally read: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thou</ENAMEX> shall not commit murder. The term ‚Äúmurder‚Äù implies a prohibition only against unjustified killing, implying the permissibility of killing in self-defense. Yet, a survey of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> law reveal that the term also bears the interpretation found in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> translations: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thou</ENAMEX> shall not kill. ‚ÄúThou shalt not murder‚Äù is a rule that we can expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to follow, but ‚ÄúThou shalt not kill‚Äù hardly lends itself to the same strict enforcement. The morality of not killing becomes an aspiration, a challenge for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to realize in their struggle with imperfection. Whether they can renounce self-defense, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mennonites</ENAMEX> appear to have done, is a matter of personal moral realization. Whether they can extend the prohibition against killing to all living <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>, as some exemplary spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have done, depends on their moral evolution. Those who eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> are not wrongdoers or sinners. They simply have not yet reached the highest point of aspiration. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> should respect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>, for respecting all forms of life by not killing, but those who fall short of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> are not subject to blame.
The same contrast can be drawn between the equality of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and the equality of all human beings. The equality of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> has become a postulate of the international legal order. There may be debate about which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> constitute <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> entitled to self-determination and representation in the international community, but the principle seems to be accepted by all. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, so recognized, equality‚Äîlet us, say, with regard to voting rights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations‚</ENAMEX>Äîbecomes a norm readily enforced.
Not so for the equality of all human beings. First, it is not at all clear what we mean by equality, why we should recognize it in all human beings, and what we should do to realize equality in practice. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> did not favor the equality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> for all purposes, including social and marital relationships. And even if we think that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are equal in the sight of God, we might understandably bequeath our property to our own kin. How much equality and the form that it should take remain a matter of constant debate.
As in the case of ‚Äúnot killing,‚Äù in the field of granting equality, there is always more that one can do. The minimum is recognizing an equal ‚Äúright to life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.‚Äù This requires, to be sure, the abolition of slavery. But there arises then the question of equality in the exercise of basic legal rights, like owning property, serving on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>, and testifying as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Some of these basic legal rights of equality did not accrue to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> until well into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. At a further frontier is political equality, namely the right to express opinions, to vote, and to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Further up the scale of equality, we encounter equality of opportunity in economic competition: Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> should have the right to compete on an equal footing, with equal education and the basic resources required for the market.
At this point in the spectrum, we begin to make the transition from equality of opportunity to equality of outcomes. Everyone should arguably have an equal claim to the world‚Äôs resources. The manna of life, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Ackerman‚</ENAMEX>Äôs apt metaphor, should be distributed equally<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> The accidents of birth prevent us all from having equal talents, but perhaps those born with lesser talents should receive some form of compensation for their deprivation. All other outcomes, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rawls</ENAMEX> argues, would be ‚Äúarbitrary from a moral point of view.‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù3</NUMEX> A similar form of compensation might be urged for those who fall short in the unfolding of their lives. Some have bad luck in romance, fail at their creative efforts, suffer the accidental loss of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. An extreme egalitarian might see an injustice, requiring compensation, in these differential life paths.
We might refer to this layered set of possibilities as the spectrum of equality. As in abstaining from killing, one can cross the initial stage of this spectrum and remain unsure about how far to ascend on the scale. To whatever height <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ascends on the spectrum of equality, there should be a strong connection between that perch and the reason for recognizing human equality in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Once again, the analogy with the commandment against killing (or murder) proves instructive. However much one becomes convinced that killing is wrong, one needs a reason for that degree of conviction. In order to renounce self-defense you need a reason, something to the effect that violence only breeds more violence. Or, if you wish to emulate the model of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Schweitzer</ENAMEX>, you must say something like: All living things are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> of God, they all deserve to live. This is not to say that your reason must be demonstrably correct, but you need a reason for your commitment for it to make any sense at all.
The abolitionists, too, must have had reasons for believing in equality in a way that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern and Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow citizens</ENAMEX> rejected. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>, too, followed an inner logic in cultivating the deeper meaning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we must also have grounds for taking human equality seriously as a basic ideal of social and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>.
Providing these reasons turns out not to be so easy. As a descriptive claim, the thesis ‚Äúall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal‚Äù is obviously false. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> differ in every conceivable respect‚Äîsize, strength, intelligence, musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, beauty. But being equal is not equivalent to being the same, identical, or similar. Equality is a curious relationship, and its model is arithmetic relations. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of an equation are stipulated as equal, but this may not be apparent to the untrained eye. For example: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 x</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">289</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the equation are not identical in notational form but equivalent in numeric value. The suggestion is that all our differences are like notational form. My <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, my biography, my talents, are certainly not the same as yours, but these differences become superficial in light of the deeper equivalence of moral value. What gives us this deep equality of value?
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> have tried to analyze human equality by searching for some single factor by virtue of which we are equal. We might all be equal because we can use language and say things like, ‚ÄúI am as good as you are.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù4 Utilitarians</ENAMEX> claim that we are equal because we feel pleasure and pain<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Locke</ENAMEX> argued that we are all equal because we are all the property of God<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> Or as contemporary secular thinkers claim, we are all equal because, in principle, we can act both rationally and reasonably<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> All these arguments suffer from the same objection. Suppose someone could not speak, would he not be equal to other human beings? Suppose she could not feel pleasure or pain, would that put her outside the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>? If he were not rational, would he not be one of us? None of these criteria alone could be an adequate test of equality unless it was accompanied by a theory that explained why that factor, and that factor alone, was sufficient to generate the strong sense of human equality. Of little value, as well, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Locke‚</ENAMEX>Äôs influential argument that we are the property of God. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> also belong to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creator</ENAMEX> but that does make them equal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.
Modern philosophical approaches toward equality all suffer from the same flaw. They are strongly committed, vaguely, to some position on the spectrum, but they offer no reason why they are so intensely committed to this value that has become so powerful in the English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West</ENAMEX>. Human equality seems to be an unquestioned postulate‚Äîone of those truths that we hold to be ‚Äúself-evident.‚Äù And those things that are obvious apparently require no grounding in reasons. In the contemporary liberal culture, equality is one of those values that has become so deeply held that it is neither questioned nor justified.
Given the long history of popular belief in the intrinsic superiority of certain classes of people‚Äîmen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe philosophical belief in equality stands as a critique of commonly held beliefs. It is clear that the popular culture still harbors many biases about some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being intrinsically better, entitled to greater privileges, than others. Yet, the long-range popular trend favors overcoming our biases in favor of a belief in the equality of all humanity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolution</ENAMEX> took the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step by abolishing the privileges of the nobly born. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1787 Constitution</ENAMEX> prohibits both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from granting ‚Äútitles of nobility.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù8 There was this much equality in the founding, but anchoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúpeculiar institution‚Äù</ENAMEX> of slavery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> was the great ‚Äúoffence‚Äù against equality that could be expiated only on the killing fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antietam</ENAMEX>.
The postbellum history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has carried the egalitarian message of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> into the liberation of ever more marginal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">emancipation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, the movement for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">women‚Äôs suffrage</ENAMEX> gained strength and finally triumphed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>, and then in unclear succession came the contemporary efforts toward the equal treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúillegitimate‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX>, and even undocumented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>.9 The thrust toward inclusion of more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> within the inner circle of the equally privileged has been one of the central themes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. Yet, even the victory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> is not yet complete. The badges and vestiges of slavery still haunt the land. The quest for redemption from the original sin of slavery continues in our own time.
Our sensibilities are conditioned by our history. But, however difficult the struggle, we have a history of which we can be proud. We <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to conceptualize the great maxim of equality and to label it a self-evident truth. No other legal system, so far as I can tell, relies explicitly on the principle that all human beings are created in the image of God. Yet, all modern legal systems and international documents of human rights <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> subscribe to the principle of equality before the law. Typical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> influence is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1789 French Declaration of the Rights of Man</ENAMEX>, which provides in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 6</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThe law must be the same for everyone, regardless whether it serves to protect or to punish.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù10</ENAMEX>
Equality before the law is the most limited claim of human equality. This form of equality applies only to fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> subject to the same legal order. More ambitious are the arguments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ackerman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> who claim that equality is the first principle of social justice. At the outer reaches of principle, we find the great maxim invoked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> Address: All human beings are equal in the sight of God.
Let us limit our thinking, for the time being, to the most modest claim‚Äîthat all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, black and white, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, gay and straight, born in wedlock and out of wedlock, should be treated equally under the law. We did not recognize this principle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1787 Constitution</ENAMEX>. It came into our positive law‚Äîthe law actually applied by the courts‚Äîin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>. But what is the grounding for this transformation in our attitudes toward equality under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">law</ENAMEX>? Did we need the more radical faith in equality in the sight of God to discover the imperative of treating everyone equally under the law? Is equality under law limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>? If so, why does the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> literally protect all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúpersons‚Äù</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that deprive them of equal protection of the laws? These are the difficult issues to which we now turn.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crucible</ENAMEX> 
of Equality

Gettysburg forged a link between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and egalitarian thinking that we sometimes forget. The connection between the limited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and unbounded equality has paradoxical overtones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is dedicated to the proposition that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal. The thrust toward equality has universalist implications. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> argued that only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúAmericans‚Äù</ENAMEX> were created equal. The claim was that all people‚Äîin principle, all human beings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">planet‚Äîare</ENAMEX> born with equal dignity. Yet, this universalistic thinking thins our commitment to equality to a point of fragility.
Equality flourishes in an environment of mutual sympathy and reciprocal identification. The love for each and the needs of each come to the fore in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the affective</TIMEX> bonds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, friendship, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>, and, by extension, in the reciprocal attachments of nationhood. The limited political sphere of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> facilitates the recognition of others as human beings sharing a common history. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northerners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX>, eventually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, could respect each other as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> participating in the same national drama, they would lay a foundation for affirming their mutual equality. They need not be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and not exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, but they could at last recognize each other as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compatriots</ENAMEX> with a common language, a single history, and a shared future.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for this association between bonds of affection and equality lies outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Judeo-Christian</ENAMEX> tradition, notably in the philosophy of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>. The fullest development comes in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aristotle‚Äôs Politics and in the Nicomachean Ethics</ENAMEX>. The idea of universal human equality was foreign to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aristotle</ENAMEX>, but he did believe in the mutual recognition of equality within the bonds of friendship and other close <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. Indeed, wishing well for the other as an end in himself is an essential component of philia or friendship understood broadly, and this sentiment, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aristotle</ENAMEX> believed, provides the necessary foundation for all virtuous behavior<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX>
Equality appears as a central theme in the virtue of justice as well as friendship. The just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is one who pays due regard to his own interests as well as to those of others. He is able to maintain the proper balance between his own interests and those of others. This is an aspect of distributive justice that generally requires each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to receive a due or proportionate share of the good to be distributed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aristotle</ENAMEX> describes this proportion as an expression of geometric equality. Similarly, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> wrongs another, some correction is necessary. This species of justice is also based on equality, understood arithmetically. The wrongdoer and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> should both be restored to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> they were in prior to the wrong. This might be done by compelling the wrongdoer to pay compensation from the gains that he has received in order to make up the loss to the victim.
These virtues of friendship and justice require cultivation, for they contribute to the flourishing of the virtuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. Adapted to the nationalist argument for equality among all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle‚</ENAMEX>Äôs argument about friendship would go something like this: we should treat all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> polity as equal, with equal concern for their lives, precisely as we would treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. By so doing, we as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> will flourish and we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> will flourish from our taking the ends of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compatriots</ENAMEX> as seriously as we would those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> must seek equality for the sake of its own flourishing. The sense of common destiny is nowhere better expressed than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> expression: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kol Jehudim</ENAMEX> eruvim ze bze [All <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are responsible for each other]. In the rhetoric of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nationalism, the metaphor of the chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, of the substitution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, recurs as a familiar trope. The sense of organic closeness is implied. The responsibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> should run to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> as all those naturalized or born on the soil of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and subject to its legal jurisdiction.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nationalism</ENAMEX> becomes a virtue if it avoids hatred of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> as it encourages mutual respect among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>. This, indeed, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ambition in seeking reconciliation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX> and in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugural address. Accepting his idea of a ‚Äúnew <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> dedicated to the proposition that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal‚Äù would have enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to negotiate the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">postbellum period</TIMEX> without self-seeking and rancor. But this was not, as we saw, the way it happened, particularly after the tragic turn at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ford‚Äôs Theatre</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson‚Äôs</ENAMEX> plan for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> was plagued by controversies about whether the previously disloyal were still full <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, once emancipated, should ascend a step higher and receive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> on equal terms with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> imagined grounding the equality between black and white, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern and Southern</ENAMEX>, in a shared sense of nationhood. With the rancorous infighting that dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865 to 1870</TIMEX>, the relevance of nationhood began to recede. More important were the ideological issues of loyalty, personal desert, and political self-interest. The question of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> became associated with the fears of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of freedmen and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would dominate the postbellum <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
But this should not surprise us. Politics merely occupies the surface of our lives. The give-and-take of daily conflict can lead us easily to forget both our shared purposes and our enduring principles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> had ushered in a commitment to the equality of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Whatever the struggle for adoption may have been, the language of egalitarian principle came into force. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>, we had in place a clause in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> that was unique in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> constitutional history: no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> could ‚Äúdeprive any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of the equal protection of the laws.‚Äù What this clause would imply in practice, no one quite knew. We did know, however, that the legal idea of equality carried no historical gloss. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> had already spoken of ‚Äúprivileges and immunities‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù12</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>, of securing ‚Äúlife, liberty, and property‚Äù against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">deprivation ‚Äúwithout</ENAMEX> due process of law.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù13 But the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> had never before contained the notion of equality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> before the law.
The remarkable feature of this ideal-bearing language is that it protects all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> within the power of the state‚Äîall those whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> can touch with its legal power. This was hardly a self-evident way for the provision to be drafted. Given the nationalist background of our sentiments of equality, one could readily have formulated the clause: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúNo state shall deny to any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.‚Äù That is, because we were bound together foremost as fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, one would expect a commitment <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to the equal treatment of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Weimar Constitution</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> found this to be a perfectly natural way of formulating the commitment to equality: All <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> are equal before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law</ENAMEX>.14 It was not until the postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Law</ENAMEX> came to be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany</ENAMEX> recognized that a commitment to equality had to be universal. The provision now reads: All human beings are equal before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law</ENAMEX>.15 The striking fact is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> came to this principle of universalization <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 1868</TIMEX>.
As the distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> constitutional law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> and philosopher of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Weimar</ENAMEX> period <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Leibholz</ENAMEX> pointed out, the Western theory of equality has united <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct strains of thought<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX> The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotelian</ENAMEX> principle, which grounds the virtue of equal treatment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the affective</TIMEX> bonds of friendship or, by extrapolation, in the ties of nationhood. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of different cultural strains, some with power, others without, to see themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compatriots</ENAMEX> of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Their mutual recognition as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in a common struggle generated a sense that at least they‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans‚Äîwere</ENAMEX> created equal.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> great principle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leibholz‚</ENAMEX>Äôs egalitarian synthesis stressed the universality of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> in the love of God. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">universalization</ENAMEX> derives from the biblical faith that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> are created in the image of God<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is limited and circumscribed by the bonds of affective identification. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> breaks the bonds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and extends to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> unknown and unimagined. We will allow ourselves a slight detour to explore these religious ideas and to understand their impact on the theory of equality as it developed under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religious Basis</ENAMEX> 
of Equality

The abolitionist movement began on the heels of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Great Awakening</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three decades of the century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> overflowed with the religious pursuit of self-perfection, talk of the millennium‚Äîthe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand years</TIMEX> of peace before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Coming of the Lord‚</ENAMEX>Äîand of the hand of God in human affairs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> revivalists adopted the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> idea that our purpose on earth is to complete and perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs creation. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William G. McLoughlin</ENAMEX> sums up the fervor of the times: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThe new consensus also included the belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are a peculiar race, chosen by God to perfect the world.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù18</ENAMEX>
Many of the preachers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Awakening</ENAMEX> supported the abolitionist cause but many others did not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> in God and the higher law of revelation enables some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to confront the injustice they see around them; it enables others to retreat and to find solace in their personal quest for salvation. Religious beliefs also supported the cause of those who believed in slavery. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> summed up the ambivalent role of religious faith in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Brothers‚Äô War</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúBoth [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>] read the same <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, and pray to the same God; and each invokes His aid against the other.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù19</ENAMEX>
Religious faith hardly lays out a straight path leading to the affirmation of human equality. Yet, it is hardly an accident that many of the great abolitionists such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Lloyd Garrison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Parker</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> whose faith fired their dedicated opposition to the great sin of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man‚Äôs</ENAMEX> owning another. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> carried with them an intimate knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, yet they did not require a consensus of biblical interpretation to support their political commitments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Douglass</ENAMEX> argued that slavery was a sin because by ‚Äúsubjecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to the arbitrary control of another, it contravenes the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> command of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decalogue</ENAMEX>. . . .<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù20</ENAMEX> He was appealing to the basic principles of monotheism. But sophisticated biblical exegesis was unnecessary for those who shared the root intuition that slavery was an abomination. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> thought it obviously wrong for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> ‚Äúto ask a just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God‚Äôs</ENAMEX> assistance in wringing their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> from the sweat of other men‚Äôs faces.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù21</ENAMEX> These were strong intuitions of evil, tutored by religious faith but obviously not determined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.
The religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abolitionists</ENAMEX> had every reason to be drawn to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>; there they found the religious inspiration for which they could search in vain in the secular monument called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúWe hold these truths to be self-evident, that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal.‚Äù Behind those created equal stands a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creator‚Äîthe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> as well of our basic human rights, for the text continues by listing the truths we hold to be self-evident: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthat they are endowed by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creator</ENAMEX> with certain inalienable rights, that among these are life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.‚Äù This noncommittal Deist theme runs through the rhetoric of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>. God is mentioned only as ‚Äúnature‚Äôs God,‚Äù by virtue of which every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is entitled to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúa separate and equal station‚Äù in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. This is the basis for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">people‚Äôs</ENAMEX> claiming that no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> may rule them without their consent. The end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> Declaration resonates with another invocation of a higher power: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúwith a firm reliance on the protection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Divine Providence</ENAMEX>, we mutually pledge to each other our lives, our fortunes and our sacred honor.‚Äù
The religious refrain in the charter of our independence differs radically from the flat, secular tone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1787 Constitution</ENAMEX>, which makes no reference to any of the words, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúGod,‚Äù ‚ÄúCreator,‚Äù ‚ÄúProvidence,‚Äù ‚Äúdivine,‚Äù</ENAMEX> or any of their synonyms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> recognizes no power higher than the will of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúWe the People</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Yet, the close bond of religious zeal and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics returns in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Awakening</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early decades of the nineteenth century</TIMEX>, a period leading not only to the abolitionist movement but also to the expression of religious passion in foreign policy, particularly in westward expansion under the ideology of manifest destiny.
The invocation of God in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX> is both accidental and entirely predictable. It is accidental in the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> spontaneously added the divine invocation as he neared the end of the address<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">.22</TIMEX> The innovation was predictable. Lincoln‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and God derived from his deepest convictions. He thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">God‚Äôs ‚Äúalmost</ENAMEX> chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,‚Äù successors to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in a relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divine</ENAMEX> that could be described as ‚Äúalmost a covenant.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù23 In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-nineteenth century</TIMEX>, it was relatively easy to believe that we were in the grip of a great historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, possibly emanating from a higher power. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIN GOD WE TRUST‚Äù</ENAMEX> became a popular motto, appearing for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time on the nation‚Äôs coinage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1864</TIMEX>. Trust in God can generate diverse conclusions, but this does not subtract from the obvious way in which, at the time, faith in God and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> nourished the radical claims of human equality.
For modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, those who do not think instinctively in the idiom of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Genesis and the Psalms</ENAMEX>, it is worth reviewing the kind of argument for equality found in biblical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. The central idea that generates the concept of universal humanity or universal brotherhood is that we are made in the image of God. As the story has come down to us from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Genesis 1, 26</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>:

And God said, Let us make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>] in our own image after our likeness, and let them have dominion over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> of the sea, over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> of the air, over all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>, and over every creeping thing that creeps on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. So God created <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in his own image, in his own image He created him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and female He created them<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.24</NUMEX>

There is much to be said about the proper reading of this passage, particularly in relation to the contrary story of creation in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Genesis 2</ENAMEX>, a story that supposedly justifies the subordination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The proper reading of the text, as I have argued elsewhere<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,25</NUMEX> has God creating a single being, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and female. God gives this being, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adam</ENAMEX>, dominion over all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> but not over the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, yet to be created. Only in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Garden of Eden</ENAMEX> do we encounter the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> and subordination of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX>. For those who look to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> for guidance, therefore, it makes a tremendous difference whether one relies primarily on the egalitarian message in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 1,</ENAMEX> of ultimate human dignity for all, or on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 2</ENAMEX>, with its story leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that they be ‚Äúruled by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
That creation in the image of God resonated in the culture of the abolitionists is undeniable; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of emancipation readily read into the line ‚Äúall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal‚Äù the vision of creation set forth in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Genesis 1</ENAMEX>. If you believe that an individual is created in the image of God, it is difficult to deny his or her ultimate worth. There is no higher value than God, and therefore partaking of that value confers upon all human beings ultimate human dignity. This point is brought <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the grounding of the prohibition against homicide in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Genesis 9</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6:</ENAMEX>

Whoever sheds <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">man‚Äôs blood</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> shall his blood be shed;
for in the image of God he made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>. . . .

The infinite dignity of the potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> generates an absolute ban on killing. The dignity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> is as great as any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who might wish to kill him and, therefore, the homicide of an innocent is never justified. This is a remarkable passage for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> in which the killing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúother,‚Äù</ENAMEX> was a routine occurrence.
The basic ideas of Genesis receive their best secular rendition in the moral philosophy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immanuel Kant</ENAMEX>, who takes the idea of creation in the image of God and bequeaths to us the idea of universal humanity. We are all essentially alike as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. We all partake of infinite human dignity:

In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of ends everything has either value or dignity. Whatever has a value can be replaced by something else which is equivalent; whatever, on the other hand, is above all value, and therefore admits of no equivalent, has a dignity<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.26</NUMEX>

The idea of human dignity, which we now take to be a shared premise of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> civilization, became the backdrop for our current faith in human rights and crimes against humanity.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> is our placeholder in the evolution of egalitarian thinking. We know very little about how much equality the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> of the amendment intended to secure, and frankly it does not matter. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> must struggle to assay how far they are willing to go in the name of egalitarian justice or, by contrast, how far they wish to surrender to the surviving counter-values of hierarchy. In the aftermath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> it was clear, ironically, that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were far ahead of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in ascending the scale of egalitarian possibilities. Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> acquired, at least nominally, both the right to vote and the right to serve on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>. White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> alike would acquire neither until well into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX>.
Some might argue that because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> lagged in recognizing equal legal rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the mood of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX> would have been hostile to recognizing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were equal in the sight of God<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.27</NUMEX> When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> said, ‚ÄúAll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal,‚Äù therefore, he meant men‚Äîonly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> were equal in the sight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creator</ENAMEX>. This objection is easily countered. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> explicitly invoked the figures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in his discourse on human dignity. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX>, in his speech attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> decision, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> explicitly refers to the dignity and inherent equality of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>:

In some respects she certainly is not my equal; but in her natural right to eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> she earns with her own hands without asking leave of any one else, she is my equal, and the equal of others.28

Even if the textual evidence were silent, however, we would have to interpret ‚Äúall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal‚Äù as inclusive of all human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beings‚</ENAMEX>Äîall variations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. This inclusiveness follows from anchoring the great maxim in the idea that human beings were created in the image of God: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúSo God created <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs own image, in the image of God created God it, the first being, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> God created them.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù29 (I recognize that one reading of the biblical text, widely accepted in various religious traditions, holds that God did create a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX> in his own image and later removed a rib to create <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX>.)
Recognizing the inherent moral equality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX> did not mean, however, that they would receive full legal and political equality as did black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The notion of ‚Äúappropriate roles in life‚Äù still governed relations among equals and it would take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to grasp that the politics of equality can not brook the coercion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into domestic, apolitical roles, nor could some misguided theory of social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> tolerate the relegation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to a limited number of lower-status professions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Dignity</ENAMEX> as a 
Placeholder for Equality

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> basic value remains curiously absent from those enthroned in the postbellum legal order. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> to redeem ourselves from the evil of slavery should have prompted a commitment to a value even more basic than equality: the infinite human value of all human beings. In the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> recognized that this was the proper way to initiate the catalogue of basic rights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1949 Basic Law</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúHuman dignity is inviolable. All <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state power</ENAMEX> is obligated both to protect this value and to respect it.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù30 This provision clearly bears the imprint of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kantian</ENAMEX> moral philosophy, which treats respect for human dignity as an absolute duty of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> of the state<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.31</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article I</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Law</ENAMEX> bears a striking resemblance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, which in its core provides: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúNeither slavery nor involuntary servitude shall exist within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.‚Äù If we think of the prohibition against slavery and involuntary servitude as an affirmation of autonomy, then the passive sentence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> could be rewritten, without change of content, in the form of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Law</ENAMEX>:

Human dignity and autonomy are inviolable. All <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state power</ENAMEX> is obligated both to protect and respect autonomy, by eliminating slavery and involuntary servitude.

This would, admittedly, be an unconventional way of formulating the demands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>. The usual commentary on the amendment stresses simply that it omits the requirement of action by state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that we find in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth and Fifteenth Amendments</ENAMEX>. Yet, it is clear that the postbellum order sought to declare a fundamental value as the symbol of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The motive was similar to the impulse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drafters</ENAMEX> seeking to ground their postwar constitution in the humanistic values of human dignity. There may be intriguing and important differences between human dignity and autonomy, and we shall return to these later. For now, it is important to note merely that the postbellum legal order begins with a commitment of all state power to eliminate the evil that had cursed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> since its founding.
Significantly, both human dignity and autonomy, both due process and equality, transcend the limits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. It is not only our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> who are entitled to these basic human rights. All human beings, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, should enjoy the same rights‚Äîat least so far as they are within the jurisdiction of the state securing those rights. Our commitment to nationhood generates the reciprocal sympathy that enables us to make the move from particular to universal. We may come to understand the meaning of basic rights in the context of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> but then we are driven to see that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> or not, are entitled to the same treatment.


Alternative Readings

Not everyone agrees that the equality of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> represents the moral breakthrough of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>. In an alternative version of the postbellum legal order, also based on the value of nationhood, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Black</ENAMEX> stresses the reliance on national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúAll persons</ENAMEX> born or naturalized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> wherein they reside.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Membership</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is now defined by birth on the land, and the fact of nationality, legally recognized as citizenship, generates the most basic right of the new legal order. Black reasons that the amendment places <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> at the center of the new constitutional order. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúNo State</ENAMEX> shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.‚Äù The centerpiece of the new order, therefore, should have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> and the elaboration of the ‚Äúprivileges and immunities‚Äù of citizenship.
The appeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black‚</ENAMEX>Äôs reading of the postbellum legal order is that it, too, draws on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence and the Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>. The key phrase in his reading of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration</ENAMEX> is not the commitment to equality but the clause immediately following: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthat they are endowed by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creator</ENAMEX> with certain inalienable rights, that among these are life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Black</ENAMEX> imagines these words coupled with the language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Ninth Amendment</ENAMEX>, which implies an unspecified catalogue of rights ‚Äúretained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.‚Äù These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúinalienable rights‚</ENAMEX>Äù should express themselves in a catalogue of human rights, including the right to sexual privacy, to reproductive freedom, and to governmental services necessary for the ‚Äúpursuit of happiness.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù32 The latter might plausibly encompass education, medical care, a minimal standard of welfare, and perhaps even guaranteed employment.
There is much to be said for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black‚Äôs</ENAMEX> interpretation of the constitutional text. He brings together strands of our legal culture that until his writing seemed to lack internal coherence. He grounds his argument in the familiar rhetoric of rights. He builds his interpretation on critical planks of the postbellum legal order, namely the ideas of nationhood and national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. Yet, the content of his argument reverts back to the language of rights, inalienable rights, rights retained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. He invokes the rhetoric we associate with our eighteenth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> enthroning freedom over equality. True, as the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black‚</ENAMEX>Äôs book reminds us, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> address does rely on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> phrase to establish a link with the old legal order: A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Birth of Freedom</ENAMEX>. Yet, Black ignores the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> values of equality and democracy, which, along with nationhood, represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cornerstones</ENAMEX> of the postbellum legal order.
Taking the ‚Äúprivileges and immunities‚Äù of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> as the pivotal value of the new order, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> does, creates its own problems of equality under law. Why should only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident aliens</ENAMEX> enjoy the inalienable rights of ‚Äúlife, liberty and the pursuit of happiness?‚Äù Do not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and even undocumented illegals have rights as human beings? The universalist language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> hardly dovetails with the parochial category of citizenship in a particular governmental polity. If all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal, if we are endowed by our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creator</ENAMEX> with certain inalienable rights, it cannot be the case that these rights are limited to those who are classified as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of a particular sovereign.
To be sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> had to define <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, at least to heal the divisive scars left by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> decision. That infamous act of judicial will, which served only to fuel the passions for war, held that a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> could never become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. That is why the amendment adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> also ‚Äúof the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> wherein they reside.‚Äù They could avail themselves, therefore, of a body of law already developed to secure the mutual recognition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúall Privileges and Immunities‚</ENAMEX>Äù of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in sister <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.33 As history would have it, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúprivileges and immunities‚Äù clause of the Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> has not had‚Äîat least until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recently‚</TIMEX>Äîany impact on constitutional debates<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.34</NUMEX> The language has lain latent in the text of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>. Whether it will find a suitable purpose in a constitutional scheme built on equality and due process remains to be seen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> pursues the theme of freedom and ignores the phrase that in fact requires emphasis in reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>: a new birth of freedom. The redemption and renaissance of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would become possible only by confronting our ‚Äúoffences,‚Äù and that meant recognizing and compensating for the evil of slavery. The issue that could stimulate a new birth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, therefore, was not freedom itself but freedom tempered by equality before the law.
Yet, there is reason to applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black‚</ENAMEX>Äôs reading of our history, as there is to honor the divergent views found in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Ackerman‚</ENAMEX>Äôs and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akhil Amar‚</ENAMEX>Äôs writings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ackerman</ENAMEX> focuses on the de facto transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wrought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, enacted by a rump <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in violation of the express language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>.35 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amar</ENAMEX>, too, reads the history in his own way. The postbellum legal order, in his view, shifts our focus from rights that enable us to participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to rights that celebrate individual freedom<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.36</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> all these readings flourish. They testify to the innate multiplicity of meanings inherent in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> founding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in the postbellum legal order. Our only problem, then as now, is that we are not sure which way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary refounding</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> should go.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cusp of Revolution</ENAMEX>

By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX> and the enactment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, we were perched on the threshold of a constitutional revolution. An entirely new legal order was yearning to work its way clear from the turmoil of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1860s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of this new order was painted bold in the phrases that resounded at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>: nationhood, equality, and democracy. The mechanism for implementing these exhortations would be the new grant of congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> in the final clause of the new amendments: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> shall have power to enforce, by appropriate legislation, the provisions of [these articles].‚Äù A more powerful central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was a critical part of the new constitutional order. This would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that would raise income taxes, as it started to do during the war. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would enact welfare legislation to care for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orphans</ENAMEX> of the war. And, most important, it would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that would have the capacity to supervise private relationships. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> was no longer focused just on the individual struggling to secure his freedom against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would have an active role in protecting and securing the autonomy of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. As my rewriting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> would have it: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Securing</ENAMEX> and protecting the autonomy of labor would become the duty of all state power. Government would have to keep a vigilant watch on all labor transactions to insure that there never again would arise relationships bordering on slavery or involuntary servitude.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> began to act on its responsibility to guard against the aftershocks of slavery by prohibiting discrimination in all <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> open to the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX> were part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, and they should be entitled, as a matter of equality with others, to have access to public transport, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, and hotel accommodations. The first Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights Act</ENAMEX>, therefore, would seek, in the later words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Harlan</ENAMEX>, to eliminate ‚Äúthe badges of slavery.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù37</ENAMEX>
The commitment, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost, of the new constitutional order was to the equality of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> affected by the laws of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. No one knew how far our collective promise to realize equality in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life would take us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> could conceivably have been sufficient to insure equal voting rights for all, doing away with the need for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifteenth</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nineteenth</ENAMEX>, and later amendments to secure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>.
With these ideals in place, we have to recognize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> of war had stilled very few of our fundamental social conflicts. The rough and tumble of postbellum politics pitted one segment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> against the other. The freedmen could aspire to power in the region where they previously had been slaves. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX> could join forces with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scalawags</ENAMEX> to remake the agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> in the image of the industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>. At stake was the class structure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> with its landed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentry</ENAMEX> commanding a servile class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>. Behind the political conflicts, however, was a remaking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> conception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would fight by any legal means necessary to realize the position they could not secure with their sacrifices on the battlefields of recent memory.
If war, in the famous saying of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clausewitz</ENAMEX>, represents a continuation of politics by other means<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,38</NUMEX> then postbellum legal disputes stood for a continuation of war by other means. All the disputes that eventually led to armed conflict between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would begin, in the period after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX>, to plague the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and throw into question the values that the war should have secured. States‚Äô rights, the holding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in a form of servitude called segregation, withholding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> from women‚Äîall of these would remain central issues for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least another hundred years</TIMEX>.



