



Revolutions are never easy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who inhabit the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> are the same as those who dominated the old detested order. They cannot be expected to change quickly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who interpret the new law are basically the same as those who interpreted the old law. Even if the law changes, even if there is a nominally new constitution, the process of reading the new document will gravitate toward the old. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> changes, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are, after all, the same.
The ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelites</ENAMEX> would spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> wandering in the desert before the passing of time would generate a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, unaffected by the mentality of the ‚Äúfleshpots of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Modern</ENAMEX> political conditions rarely offer this luxury. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> dreamed of creating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnew man‚Äù</ENAMEX> who would regard the communist system as the natural backdrop for cooperation. History never gave them the chance. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> could engineer a radical transformation after the fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX> and the unification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Germans</ENAMEX> absorbed the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">German Democratic Republic</ENAMEX> and then restaffed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and the law faculties with new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, drawn overwhelmingly from Western ranks.
For <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postbellum period</TIMEX>, the obstacles to revolutionary change were daunting. Emancipating the slaves was one thing, changing attitudes toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> was quite another. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1860s</TIMEX> were essentially the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had tolerated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of slavery; their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> were of the same background and schooling as those who had declared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> decision that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> descent, whether born free or born in bondage, could never become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
As part of its reconstructing the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX>, the victorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> tried to cleanse the formerly rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of their ‚Äútreasonous‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, which the rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were expected to ratify as the price for reinstating their right to representation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, included a clause disqualifying from public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, in either the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> or the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, anyone who had taken an oath to uphold the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and thereafter ‚Äúengaged in insurrection or rebellion against the same.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù2 This provision could conceivably have rid the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> of those who supported the war for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> independence, but it could not liberate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who were ambivalent about the equality of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> changed entirely between the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> decision in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX> and the first major constitutional decision of the postbellum period in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX>. Yet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who came onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> still carried with them the values and confusions of their antebellum youth. They could not easily imbibe an entirely new spirit of nationhood and a strong commitment to equality. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> did not express the vision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX> but rather the reluctant judgment from within that the vanquished, too, had arguments on their side.
Securing a nominal legal change in the form of the black-letter rules of constitutional revisions was not so difficult. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> was ratified as soon as the war was over, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth and Fifteenth</ENAMEX> followed within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX>, the language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> change was in place. The only question was whether the words on paper would bring about a fundamental change in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> self-government.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> promises of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gettysburg‚Äînationhood</ENAMEX>, equality, and democracy‚Äîshould have become the guiding values for interpreting the amendments that would govern postbellum <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. These amendments had the form of a new constitution. They set forth the basic principles of government and each of them granted authority to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to realize the amendment with appropriate legislation. The amendments needed only the backdrop of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> then in operation. It would not have overtaxed the legal imagination simply to incorporate the existing structure of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> into the new constitutional order.
Had the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> been able to begin anew, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> educated in the values and vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>, with a new generation unaffected by old habits of thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs prophecy at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> might have prevailed. The commitment to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">‚Äúa single nation‚Äù</NUMEX> of black and white would have provided the foundation for a jurisprudence of equality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would have become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX> of private relationships that approached too close to the forbidden line, defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúslavery‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúprevious condition of servitude.‚Äù The ‚Äúself-evident truths‚Äù of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe inalienable rights to life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness‚Äîcould have generated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of a new constitutional order. Yet, this was not to be the fate of postbellum <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
Part of the problem is the way we came to think of the great sacrifice that occurred on the battlefields of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antietam, Vicksburg‚</ENAMEX>Äîall the places where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> rushed to give their lives for the sake of vague principles. If we did not have the great articulation of the war‚Äôs aim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> gave us at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>, the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> would have reeked of the absurd. ‚ÄúI am fighting for my rights,‚Äù a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> might have said‚Äînot too sure what those ‚Äúrights‚Äù were. On the other side, in blue rather than gray, he might have said, ‚ÄúI am fighting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union‚</ENAMEX>Äù with the nagging sense that dying for a governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> was slightly ridiculous.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> Address was pregnant with the sentiment that the war expressed the fraternity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The bond was expressed not only toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> who were liberated but also toward the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred thousand</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who fought side by side, though in separate battalions, with white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to liberate those still under domination<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> The national <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tie‚Äîthe ‚Äúbonds</ENAMEX> of affection‚<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Äù4 ‚Äîis</NUMEX> expressed as well toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in arms who, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs view, never ceased to be part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. This was a war between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>. It was necessary to settle the inevitable family quarrel about the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would become.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history took its course in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> that followed the ‚Äúwar for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>,‚Äù we managed to betray the inner meaning of the great sacrifice that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> sought to consecrate at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>. We absorbed the war into the preexisting political and legal vocabulary. We could have celebrated a new vocabulary of politics‚Äîa vocabulary we shared with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> who were then moving toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of internal solidarity. And, yet, we ignored the appeal of the new for the sake of the old. We drove the solidarity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> underground. We converted the ideas that should have become our new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> national charter into our passive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Constitution</ENAMEX>.
The issues that concerned postbellum <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> were not the ideas of solidarity and reconciliation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> managed to articulate both at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> and in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugural address. With the assassination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1865</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had preached a new order of ideas, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> obsessed with power. The great issues of the postbellum period breathed the tensions of institutional conflict.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>, himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> with roots in the yeomanry of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX>, was less eager than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to effectuate a cleansing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> that had supported the rebellion. He was opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, which would have subjected the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to continuing federal scrutiny, and he was at odds with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Stanton</ENAMEX>, who concurred in the effort to seek radical reconstruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. Fearing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> would fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed a statute requiring congressional approval to remove a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> resisted; he fired his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of war. In retaliation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> began impeachment proceedings. After a fierce trial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> himself did not attend, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> survived, by one senatorial vote short of the required <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> was humbled and offered less resistance thereafter to congressional policies, including the enactment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>.
Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sturm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">und</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drang</ENAMEX> of the nation‚Äôs first impeachment trial was a struggle for power between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the presidency. Would the constitutional structure that emerged from the war more closely resemble the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> style of parliamentary democracy, with the executive cabined by congressional directives? Or would the presidency remain an independent <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>? Wars have a way of throwing open basic questions of this sort, and by unleashing aggression within a society, a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> inevitably invites a redefinition of governmental power. Thus, a whole new set of issues came onto the agenda of constitutional discussion.
Among the most important of these was the proper relationship between the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. This is the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfederalism‚Äù</ENAMEX> that still preoccupies <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. There is no doubt that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> came out of the war more powerful than ever. It had experimented with an income tax and, therefore, could look forward to more effective funding. It had coordinated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and now it would undertake to guide the redevelopment and integration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> in a society governed by a new set of values. The question now was whether under a new governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> could nourish the principle that they were the residual source of governmental power as set forth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tenth Amendment, ‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> powers not delegated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, nor prohibited by it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>, are reserved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> respectively, or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1791</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> was ratified, it made sense for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tenth Amendment</ENAMEX> to affirm that all federal power derived from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> represented a pact among preexisting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> between the founding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them, could hardly be thought of as enjoying the same history of a prior state of independence as the original thirteen.5 The new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, with the exception perhaps of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, came into being by federal fiat. They were born, in almost all cases, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territories</ENAMEX> already possessed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. They were created as administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and then recognized as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. To think of them as being the residual source of powers delegated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> that created them is the kind of self-deception that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> can devise.
The new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> admitted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX> should have enjoyed only the autonomy that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> allowed them to have. Yet, the great myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> constitutional theory‚Äîthat the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were just like the original thirteen‚Äîprevailed. Perhaps this sleight-of-hand was necessary to maintain equality among the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. It would not do to regard the original thirteen as constituting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> country superior to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country</ENAMEX> constituted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> thereafter recognized. Yet, it would have made sense, after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, to recognize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tenth Amendment</ENAMEX> had lost its relevance to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that embodied a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of equal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.
This is not to say that for the purpose of administrative efficiency, it would not make sense to divide functions between the federal and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. This kind of efficient allocation of functions would make sense against a conception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of governmental power. Perhaps this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> for efficiency is all that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> mean when they talk about the problems of states‚Äô rights and a limited federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Yet, the discussion remains haunted by the myth that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> admitted after the founding retroactively granted authority to the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that created them.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> emerged to articulate and preserve this myth of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> enjoying residual powers under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> had assumed the power to declare federal and state laws unconstitutional ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Marshall</ENAMEX> so interpreted our basic charter in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1803.6</NUMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifty-five years</TIMEX> leading up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> used this power sparingly<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> In the postbellum institutional shakeup, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> would become more aggressive in exercising its power to overrule decisions by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It would articulate the ideas‚Äîit would, as we now say, give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúspin‚Äù</ENAMEX> to our basic concepts‚Äîthat would define the fate of nationhood, equality, and democracy in postslavery <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
How the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> accomplished these acts of reinterpretation constitutes a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> in the intellectual history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It is the history of the way in which we took the words of the postbellum legal order, betrayed their inner sense, and assimilated the new legal order into the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>. Blending the new language into our old habits nullified the vision of a new legal order. The principles that should have inspired postbellum <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> became our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Constitution</ENAMEX>, remaining latent for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> before they would reappear to shape the contours of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law. The story may be disheartening but it must be told. To explore the process of reinterpretation, I will focus on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions of the time, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> decision, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights Cases</ENAMEX>.


The Plight of the 
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> Butchers

In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1869</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> after the war was over, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> passed a statute that brought home the persistence of a dispute about economic freedom that reached back to the earliest stages of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> legal history. The great virtue of the case was to remind the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that many issues of freedom had nothing at all to do with the war of solidarity to preserve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and emancipate the slaves.
At the time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> were engaged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of receiving shipments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> coming down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, slaughtering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and packing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> for distribution. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1869 Act</ENAMEX> claimed to concentrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX> and meat packing trade into selected areas. It provided that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> could be unloaded and slaughtered exclusively on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX> owned by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> engaged in the trade. All the butchers in the area had the right to use these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, but they had to pay a prescribed fee to the patented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>. The ostensible reason for consolidating these activities was ‚Äúto protect the health of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äù8 The Act</ENAMEX> was entitled: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúAn act to protect the health of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>, to locate the stock-landings and slaughter-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, and to incorporate the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crescent City Live-Stock Landing and Slaughter-House Company</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äù The Act</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seventeen people</ENAMEX> who were entitled to exercise the privileges of the incorporated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and, further, it imposed fines for every violation of the patent. The excluded local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butchers</ENAMEX> were enraged. They thought as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landowners</ENAMEX> they were entitled to use their land to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">slaughter animals</ENAMEX> as the market required. They wanted nothing more complicated than to pursue their trade as they saw fit on their own land.
On the assumption that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> had acted in good faith, that there was no graft involved in vesting this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crescent City Slaughter-House Company</ENAMEX>, the controversy seemed to be an easy one‚Äîat least by contemporary standards of public regulation. This was a reasonable exercise of the state‚Äôs ‚Äúpolice power,‚Äù its general authority to promote the common good. The single slaughterhouse was in the nature of a public utility‚Äîmuch like a telephone or electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that has received a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to provide service to a particular area. In describing the case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Black</ENAMEX> dismissed the controversy as trivial<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX> The complaint by the butchers should not even have generated a serious constitutional question.
At the time, however, the dispute claimed attention as posing fundamental issues. The dispute reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appomattox</ENAMEX>. The passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> was still fresh in the minds of everyone. The age overflowed with vision‚Äîbut not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.
The argument was close, but in the end the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of state power won in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> the battle they could not win on the killing fields. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> voted to uphold the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1869 Act</ENAMEX> granting a monopoly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crescent City Company</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> of the articulated dissents empathized with the independent butchers‚Äô economic freedom to carry on their trade without paying tolls to those favored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Field</ENAMEX> honestly expressed the intuition that motivated the search for legal arguments for the dissent: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúNo one will deny the abstract justice which lies in the position of the [independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">butchers</ENAMEX>].‚Äù
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> will forgive me, I hope, for dwelling on these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1872</NUMEX> opinions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> whose names we barely remember. The confrontation was so deep and so wrenching for the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> that these conflicts have taken on epic proportions. Speaking for the majority favoring the autonomy of state power there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Miller</ENAMEX>, appointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1862</TIMEX>, and on the other side, we encounter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> passionate opinions expressing sympathy for the plight of the independent butchers. I shall focus here on the conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Field</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúabstract justice‚Äù</ENAMEX> mentioned by the dissenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX> derives from the weight of history. In the early stages of capitalism, independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> found themselves embedded in a feudal system of overlords and toll collectors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for the butchers eloquently expressed the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> in prerevolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX> could not cross a river without paying to some nobleman a toll, nor take the produce which he raised to market until he had bought leave to do so; nor consume what remained of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grain</ENAMEX> till he had sent it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lord‚Äôs mill</ENAMEX> to be ground, nor full his cloths on his own works, nor sharpen his tools at his own grindstone, nor make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, or cider at his own press<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> 

The plight of the craftsman is expressed equally poignantly: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthe prying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> followed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butcher</ENAMEX> to the shambles and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> to the oven.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù11</ENAMEX> 
Reading this passionate language <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, we can grasp the way so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> felt about the principles of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúabstract justice‚Äù</ENAMEX> favoring the butchers. The struggle for the right to work and to retain the fruits of one‚Äôs labor was one of the passions of the nineteenth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>. The same sense of justice that inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> worked its way, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same middle decades of the century</TIMEX>, into the disputes of the butchers against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New Orleans</ENAMEX>.
The problem was to capture in concrete legal terms the abstract wrong committed against the butchers. The lexicon of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American jurisprudence</ENAMEX> was freshly stocked with high-sounding language in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth and Fourteenth Amendments</ENAMEX>. Were these restrictions on the butchering trade an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúinvoluntary servitude‚Äù</ENAMEX> as prohibited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, or were they a violation of the ‚Äúprivileges and immunities‚Äù of citizenship, either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> or federal, or an infringement against the state‚Äôs duty to accord all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> subject to its power both due process of law and the equal protection of the laws?
Before they reached this rich stock of possible constitutional arguments, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for the butchers tried a simple tack: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> statute infringed the common law of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, the basic principles of which had become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of these principles was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> were per se invalid. The leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurist</ENAMEX> of the seventeenth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Coke</ENAMEX>, articulated this principle in a case in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX> had granted an exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> merchant to buy and sell playing cards of a certain type. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> was sued, he claimed that he was free to engage in his chosen trade; celebrating the principles of free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> declared the monopoly invalid<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> 
This case would have been persuasive precedent for the butchers but for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hurdles that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> had to negotiate. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was to brand the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> slaughtering franchise a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmonopoly</ENAMEX>.‚Äù That proved to be problematic. The dissenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> had no trouble concluding that requiring the butchers to use, for a fee, a single slaughterhouse was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as ‚Äúmuch</NUMEX> a monopoly as though the act had granted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> the exclusive privilege of buying and selling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> themselves.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù13 But the majority, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, balked. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> was willing to accept the label of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúmonopoly‚Äù</ENAMEX> but denied ‚Äúthe assertion that the butchers are [thereby] deprived of the right to labor in their occupation.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù14</ENAMEX> 
If the analogy with common law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> had held, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> problem would then have consisted of transplanting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> practice of invalidating statutes simply because they violated, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward Coke</ENAMEX> said in another leading case, ‚Äúcommon right or reason.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù15 There was no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would or could invalidate statutes simply because they violated the ‚Äúcommon law.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> never took this attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> statute seriously. It interpreted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke‚Äôs</ENAMEX> decision in the Case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monopolies</ENAMEX> to be about whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> could grant a monopoly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> supposedly took the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commons</ENAMEX> against the king, but left open the question whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> could grant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX>. The impermissibility of the statute is dismissed with the rhetorical question: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWhoever doubted the authority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> to change or modify the common law?‚Äù16 The notion of legislative power to regulate the economy prevailed. The elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> enjoyed wide-ranging discretion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> to enact measures that had at least the nominal purpose of promoting the public good.
To find a way of striking down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> statute, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> butchers would have to invoke a constitutional prohibition that would override the presumed competence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>. The specific clause would have to capture the sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúabstract justice‚Äù</ENAMEX> favoring the butchers, the sentiment of right and wrong that, in the opinion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX>, no one could deny.
In exploring the lawyers‚Äô and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court‚</ENAMEX>Äôs arguments, our primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> should be the fate of the ideas proposed at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of the postbellum legal order. Our task is to ponder the fate of the ideals of nationhood, equality, and democracy, to understand how the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> founding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> imploded and merged, at least nominally, with the first <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationhood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizenship</ENAMEX>

As much as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> sought to evoke a consciousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationhood</ENAMEX>, this idea did not readily resonate in the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The word ‚Äúnation‚Äù was not used in the postbellum amendments. I doubt if it even occurred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> for the butchers to come into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and argue that independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tradesmen</ENAMEX> had a right, granted to them by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, to practice their trade without the duty to pay tolls and use specific <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Their rights derived, if from anyplace, from universal principles governing the free market and dignity of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Yet, this very argument‚Äîthat the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was the source of rights acquired under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth and Fourteenth Amendments‚</ENAMEX>Äîwould show itself, remarkably, in a majestic dissenting opinion in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1883.17</NUMEX> 
The idea of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> may have been in the air in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s</TIMEX>, but it was not part of the stock of concepts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> would draw on directly to domesticate its abstract sense of justice. The concept of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> creed, but it had yet to become a fixed feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law. It enjoyed a fate comparable to the inalienable right to the ‚Äúpursuit of happiness‚Äù as articulated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>. The latter is sometimes mentioned in legal opinions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,18</NUMEX> but it never became the rationale for decision making in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. It remains an article of faith, as does the commitment to think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
The faith in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, along with the inalienable right to happiness, constitute affirmations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> civic religion. They belong side by side with the frequent invocations, on the currency of the affirmation of faith: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIN GOD WE TRUST</ENAMEX>.‚Äù These are the background assumptions by which we live. The same is true of the sense of nationhood. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1892</TIMEX>, the secular prayer to the flag and the nation‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pledge of Allegiance‚Äîwould</ENAMEX> spontaneously sweep the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.19 It stood for the idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was ‚Äúone <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> indivisible‚Äù‚Äîa residue of ‚Äúthe war between brothers‚Äù that occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years before</TIMEX>. However important these ideas may be in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> civic religion, however much they dominate the thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in the civil society that exists side by side with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, they might not be suitable as legal doctrines for deciding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Nationhood</ENAMEX> rings of romance. It appeals not to the analytic mind but to the sentimental heart. As between thought and emotion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have a bias for the linear creations of mind. The appeals of nationhood are left to poets. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> opt for its analytic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. As used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> is a purely formal idea, dependent solely on one‚Äôs place of birth. In the debates about the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> butchers before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, the notion of citizenship and its privileges became the stakeholder for any residual yearnings to express the rights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
Perhaps, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Black</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> have argued, the privileges and immunities of national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> capture whatever relevance the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has to constitutional law. The position is defensible, though in my view, there remain important differences between the romantic extralegal idea of nationhood and the formal legal concept of citizenship. But let us leave these differences aside and imagine that if nationhood is to play a role in constitutional law, it must become domesticated under the rubric of citizenship.
The original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> recognized both state and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. Only citizens‚Äînot merely residents‚Äîof different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> could bring their cases to the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>.20 More important, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> pact sought to equalize the legal status of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by guaranteeing that ‚Äúthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens</ENAMEX> of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> shall be entitled to all Privileges and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immunities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens</ENAMEX> in the several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">National</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>, either for a specified period of time or by birth, was necessary to run for national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.22 Yet, the charter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> said nothing about how one becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> either of a state or of the national polity. The matter was left entirely to state law, as it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. In antebellum <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> in the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> requires that you first pass the local hurdles set for local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. Leaving the matter of citizenship to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> meant that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">slave states</ENAMEX> could deny citizenship to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or to anyone they chose. This proved to be disastrous in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> decision, where first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> held that the bloodline of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> forever excluded them from citizenship<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.23</NUMEX> 
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> item of business in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> was to establish who, as a formal matter, belonged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> polity. To find a simple definition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> adapted the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> rule that it is not blood but place of birth that matters: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúAll persons</ENAMEX> born or naturalized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> wherein they reside.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Applying</ENAMEX> the traditional rule of jus soli to everyone born on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> soil‚Äîexcept for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ‚Äúnot subject to the jurisdiction‚Äù of the country‚Äîhad the radical effect of eliminating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and racial history from the definition of the bond between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
This part is simple and direct. Complications begin to arise as soon as we note the difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. It would have been much simpler to have a single conception of national citizenship, the same idea that one finds in virtually every other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> had really been an entirely new constitution, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> could have ignored the concept of state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> altogether. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> itself mentions it: Every national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in which he resides. And to make things more complicated, each form of citizenship carries its own privileges and immunities. The original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> prescribes that every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> must respect the privileges and immunities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> extends the same duty of recognition to the privileges and immunities of national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>.
The problem that confronted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> case, therefore, was twofold: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, how to interpret the relationship between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of citizenship and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, how to fit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúabstract justice‚Äù</ENAMEX> favoring the butchers‚Äô claim into the confines of the privileges and immunities of either form of citizenship.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dissenting Justice Field</ENAMEX> constructed an ingenious interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> that had the effect of promoting the butchers‚Äô cause. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in the argument was to find a principle of equality embedded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1787</ENAMEX> clause prohibiting discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of sister <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Although the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> does not mention the word ‚Äúequality,<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äù the ‚Äúprivileges</ENAMEX> and immunities‚Äù clause can be read as a mandate of equal treatment regardless of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of origin‚Äîat least as to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Now, let us suppose that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> enacted a statute prohibiting out-of-state butchers from using the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crescent City Slaughter-House Company</ENAMEX>. This kind of preference for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of butchers over another would have been clearly unconstitutional, as the case law in this area readily reveals<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.25</NUMEX> It follows that if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> cannot arbitrarily disfavor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, it would seem odd that they could do the same thing to a group of their own butchers. Prior to the postbellum constitutional amendments, there were a limited number of clauses that made the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> accountable for wrongs committed against their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The most notable were the prohibitions against ex post facto laws, bills of attainder, and laws impairing the obligation of contracts.26 But these provisions hardly provided a foothold for attacking the special privileges accorded to the butchers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crescent City Company</ENAMEX>.
At this point in the reasoning process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX> made his striking claim: the very purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> was to fill this gap left by the other clauses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. It made no sense for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to guarantee better protection for butchers out of state than for those within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. To bring about parity between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these two classes‚</TIMEX>Äîthe protected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the unprotected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of one‚Äôs own state‚Äîthe concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> should protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> against the actions of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
The intellectual problem was similar to the situation that occurred in international law after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The legal order among the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> protected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> against atrocities committed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, but it did not protect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> against their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. This was a remarkable omission in the structure of international law. To correct it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> generated the idea of crimes against humanity. Today, in disputes from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, we take it for granted that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have duties, under international law, toward their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaughterhouse Cases</ENAMEX> struggled to achieve the same breakthrough in the relationship between individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
The conceptual hurdle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX> was the same as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. In order for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to have duties toward its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> must be considered as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> higher than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to be held accountable. In other words, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> must both be considered as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of a higher legal order. Nuremberg located <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> within the higher legal order called humanity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> terror were to be protected simply because they were human beings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX> thought, correctly in my view, that the notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> was akin to being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a legal order higher than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, a legal order to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> themselves owed a duty to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> no worse than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
There is little doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field‚</ENAMEX>Äôs analysis, though rejected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> decision, eventually became the guiding principle for interpreting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>. The proper home for this analysis turned out not to be the dual concepts of the citizenship clauses but rather the due process and equal protection provisions in the neighboring clauses of the same amendment. Both of these latter provisions, it will be remembered, are directed to the protection of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúany persons‚Äù</ENAMEX> (due process) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúany <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> within the jurisdiction‚Äù (equal protection). The drafting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> thus anticipated the theory underlying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> principle of a crime against humanity. Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> standard, the international order imposed a duty on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to treat their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> decently. In the postbellum legal order, the same result derived from federal constitutional principles.
But this gets us slightly ahead of the story. The question remains why and how the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ingenious construction of harmony between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> levels of citizenship. Keep in mind what the stakes were. There was no question that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were subject to a higher legal order. The only question was whether that higher order would be the order established by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or the order implicit in the idea of humanity. Would the controlling feature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butchers</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> be their membership in the polity called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or their status as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúpersons‚Äù</ENAMEX> entitled to due process and the equal protection of the laws?
Field‚Äôs argument carried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> votes. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> recoiled at the thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> owed duties to a higher legal order called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> did not have the effect of leveling the distinction between local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> and being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. To read the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> in this way would ‚Äúfetter and degrade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> by subjecting them to the control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù27 The primary issue, as understood by the majority, was whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would retain their own special authority over their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> that was expressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúpolice power‚Äù</ENAMEX> to legislate for the common good. The implication was that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> could readjust private rights and obligations among their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> if doing so served the overall advantage of the state‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. Granting a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crescent City Slaughter-House Company</ENAMEX> was simply an illustration of a general authority to help some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and hurt others‚Äîall within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. What no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> could do, however, was to seek to promote the interests of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
This, we should note, carried forth the struggle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> by other means. The special solicitude shown to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthe relations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to each other and of both these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to the people‚Äù harks back to the rhetoric of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1830s</TIMEX> about the asserted autonomy of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to decide whether they would go one way or the other on the issue of slavery. It is almost as though the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> had accomplished <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> objective, namely settling the issue of secession, while doing nothing to define the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or to establish a principle of equality among all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
Nonetheless, writing for the majority, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> constructed a plausible theory of what it should mean to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The picture presented is something like the posture of a supplicant toward a distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> should be able to address <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in person, make claims against the higher power, and receive its protection as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> abroad or on the high seas. None of this is particularly radical, and it fails, to be sure, to incorporate the commitments to nationhood and equality bequeathed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>.
On these larger issues, the opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Court</ENAMEX> proves to be a great historical disappointment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">opinion‚</ENAMEX>Äôs perception of our unity as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> comes across in this remarkable sentence:

And quoting from the language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taney</ENAMEX> in another case, it is said ‚Äúthat for all the great purposes for which the Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was established, we are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> common <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, we are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. . . .<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù28</ENAMEX> 
The date of this other opinion is not mentioned, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taney</ENAMEX>, it will be recalled, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> opinion, which did indeed affirm that we were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> [white] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> descended from slaves could never become a part of it. To cite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taney</ENAMEX> on the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nationhood is a bit like invoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Capone</ENAMEX> on the rule of law.


Equality

And equality‚Äîthat glaring omission from our original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>? How did the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment‚</ENAMEX>Äôs attempt to rectify the sins of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> fare in the grip of the antebellum intuitions that drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>? The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> could have applied the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúequal protection‚Äù</ENAMEX> clause and achieved the same result that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX> had engineered under his construction of the dual tracks of citizenship: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butchers</ENAMEX> rendered dependent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crescent City Company</ENAMEX> were subject, they could easily have concluded, to impermissible discrimination. That would not have been a particularly radical result, and it would have established an enduring commitment to equality under the postbellum constitution. But no, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> turned away from the larger issue of principle for the sake of overcoming a narrow historical injustice. The ‚Äúevil to be remedied by this [equal protection] clause,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> writes, was ‚Äúthe existence of laws in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> where the newly emancipated Negroes resided, which discriminated with gross injustice and hardship against them as a class.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù29 In other words, the only point of the new commitment to equality should be simply to eliminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of slavery and its concomitant legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. But if that was the only purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirteenth</ENAMEX> had already done the job. There was no need for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> and its commitment to the larger principle of equality among all ‚Äúpersons in the jurisdiction.‚Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan B. Anthony</ENAMEX> had already begun her campaign for women‚Äôs suffrage, but as of the date of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> opinion there was little sympathy for moving the spectrum of equality up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> notch to include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as a class worthy of protection. Immediately after resolving the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> dispute, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> turned to the petition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myra Bradwell</ENAMEX> to be admitted to practice law in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>.30 There was no dispute about whether she was qualified. She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, and she had the training and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> to make a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, but there was one problem: She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. This was sufficient for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to bar her admission, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> dissenting, thought this was an acceptable exercise of state power. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> decision, it was a minor stretch for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> to conclude that practicing law did not fall within the ambit of ‚Äúprivileges and immunities‚Äù of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The amazing feature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court‚Äôs</ENAMEX> decision in this case is that it did not even occur to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to justify the discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as compatible with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúequal</ENAMEX> protection of the laws.‚Äù The opinion is totally silent on the issue of equality. This was the temper of the times. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Minor</ENAMEX>, argued to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missouri‚</ENAMEX>Äôs denying her the right to vote violated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> resolved the matter by unanimous vote<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.31</NUMEX> It did not even mention the possibility that the discrimination violated equal protection of the laws.
Apparently, it lay beyond the imagination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s</TIMEX> that someday equal protection would be extended to protect all those created in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">God‚Äôs</ENAMEX> image. It would protect not only racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> born out of wedlock, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, and all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that suffered the stigma of arbitrary social and legal exclusion. They ignored the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúabstract justice‚Äù</ENAMEX> that screamed at them from the bold language of the new constitutional structure. Rather, they read the language to narrow it, to confine it to historical circumstances, in effect, to defeat the vision of a new, more just society. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> are an inherently conservative lot, but they are rarely as reactionary as these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> of the postbellum era. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconstruction Court</ENAMEX> did as much as possible to convert the vision of a new order into our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Constitution</ENAMEX>.
Yet, the values of nationhood and equality would not remain forever hidden, camouflaged in the deep structure of constitutional thought. They would begin to reassert themselves both in the political arena and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. The debate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> case had failed to take seriously the issues either of nationhood or of equality. The dissent never got to the question of equality because they were satisfied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> statute violated the ‚Äúprivileges and immunities‚Äù of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. The majority never reached that point because, as far as they were concerned, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> had the limited function of eliminating statutory discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court‚</ENAMEX>Äôs view that the purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúequal</ENAMEX> protection of the laws‚Äù was solely to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> from apartheid-like legislation was so clearly narrow-minded that it could not hold for long. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> would extend the principle of equal protection to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">launderers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> subject to discriminatory enforcement of zoning regulations<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.32</NUMEX> This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step toward a sensible jurisprudence of equality.
The historical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> dispute lend themselves to multiple perspectives. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of the butchers‚Äô economic rights, the critical perspective was the long history of emancipating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> from the feudal bondage that subjected them to a network of service and financial obligations. For the dissenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, the challenge posed by the case was the creation of a single national polity in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were obligated to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> as well as they treated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>. And for the majority, the issue was the one that should have been resolved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>: the struggle for power between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, that struggle would continue to haunt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of contentious litigation.


Apartheid in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>

It is tempting to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> case as a decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> to turn its back on the struggle for racial equality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In fact, as we should keep in mind, the case had nothing to do directly with discrimination against former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>. The decision does, however, signal a great concern for the autonomy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, for the revival of states‚Äô rights against the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. This could have generated a jurisprudence of deference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in their exercise of police power, even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and legislative decisions had the effect of discriminating against former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>. In subsequent decisions, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> established the basic principle that in the field of criminal justice at least, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> could not treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> as an inferior class. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one 1880</TIMEX> decision, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> upheld a federal penalty against a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who disqualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> service<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.33</NUMEX> And another decision in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> reversed a state court conviction of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African American</ENAMEX> tried by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> were not permitted to serve<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.34</NUMEX> With respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> Americans‚Äô exercising the basic rights of citizenship, particularly in the field of criminal justice, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> would be vigilant.
The more contentious issues arose in defining the way the emancipated slaves could move and function as supposedly free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society. The most fundamental rights of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> could not be taken for granted. The first Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights Act</ENAMEX>, enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX> on the basis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirteenth Amendment‚Äôs</ENAMEX> commitment to suppress slavery and involuntary servitude, established elementary civil rights for former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>: the right to sue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, to have the same legal remedies, and to be subject to the same penal and tax obligations as other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The act provided criminal penalties against any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who subjected any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to one of these basic legal inequalities on grounds of race, color, or status as an alien<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.35</NUMEX> 
The difficult question was whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could properly legislate under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> to protect former slaves against informal but rigid forms of customary discrimination, for example, the denial of service in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, the refusal to rent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and the segregation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act of 1875, Section 1</ENAMEX>, provided that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> should enjoy equal access to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúinns, public conveyances on land or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, and other places of public amusement‚Äù regardless of race, color, or previous condition of servitude<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.36</NUMEX> Section 2 attached a fine and a prison term of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to thirty days</TIMEX> for committing the misdemeanor of denying someone access to these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for the prohibited reasons. On the basis of these provisions, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> indicted various suspected violators around the country‚<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ÄîNew York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee‚</ENAMEX>Äîfor having denied access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> and other public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Significantly, all of these prosecutions were brought in areas that had been loyal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> in the war. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> appealed their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> convictions on the ground that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX> exceeded the authority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Their appeals were consolidated on appeal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.37 
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> decided that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress‚</ENAMEX>Äôs effort to prevent segregation and apartheid in public life overstepped their authority under both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth and Fourteenth Amendments</ENAMEX>. Accordingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> reversed the convictions and set free the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> who enforced the color line in public accommodations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> reasoned about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> in the same sterile and truncated way we have already witnessed in the Slaughterhouse Case. This discrimination in access to public transportation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inns</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> did not constitute an ‚Äúinvoluntary servitude,‚Äù for, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> had the temerity to suggest, these interactions in public were in the realm of ‚Äúsocial rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and races in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù38 The purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> was merely ‚Äúto declare and vindicate those fundamental rights which appertain to the essence of citizenship.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù39</ENAMEX> Of course, this was obvious discrimination on the basis of race. Why should it not qualify as the denial of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúequal</ENAMEX> protection of the laws‚Äù under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> focused on the wording of the amendment: No state shall deny to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> could violate the amendment. And the particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who enforced the color <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inns</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> were not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Their actions did not constitute legislation by any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or executive action by any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> wearing a badge of state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. And, therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was not responsible for these private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> denying ‚Äúsocial rights‚Äù to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The conclusion: If the wrongdoing was purely social or private, then the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could not punish it under legislation designed to enforce the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>.
This cramped and faithless reading of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> has become obvious to us over time, but it was apparent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883</TIMEX> as well. The lone dissent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Marshall Harlan</ENAMEX> records, with allusion and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>, the betrayal of what should have been the postbellum constitutional order. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan</ENAMEX> pinpoints the intellectual moves that led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> astray. On the issue of state action, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan</ENAMEX> recognizes the spectrum of possible positions ranging from purely private actions to the actions taken as the policy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. To grasp the subtleties of the problem, think of the following points on a spectrum of actions ranging from purely private action at home to the purely public functions of state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Actions taken at home, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Actions taken in public by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, for example, a store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> refuses to sell goods to a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Actions taken in public by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> entrusted with a public function, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ushers</ENAMEX> at the opera or conductors in railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> refuse to seat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Actions by a privately owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> that has a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> to provide service in a particular area, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Telephone</ENAMEX> refuses to sell service to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Actions taken by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> on their own, in defiance of governmental policy, for example, a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> refuses to include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> on the jury list.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Official policies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, discriminatory legislation, executive decisions not to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.

Except for purely private actions at home and official policies at the other extreme, the other points on this spectrum represent a mix of private decision making and government policies. In fitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> to the reality of these diverse combinations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> could have insisted on stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> as the threshold of behavior included within the scope of the amendment, thus limiting the supervisory power of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to the official action of state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. But it was clear from the outset that this would make little sense. Discriminatory application of sound laws could not escape federal scrutiny simply because state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> acted beyond the scope of their authority. Limiting ‚Äústate action‚Äù and official policies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to act beyond their legal competence. Thus, stage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> came to be included within the ambit of state responsibility.
The fatal mistake in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883</TIMEX> was concluding that everything below stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five</TIMEX> could properly be classified as private or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúsocial.‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs dissent stresses that stages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> are also actions in the public domain that implicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in various ways‚Äîas enforcer, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of the surrogate private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, or by direct or indirect funding (e.g., tax incentives). Reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> with a view to what it was intended to accomplish would have yielded a more generous understanding of ‚Äústate action.‚Äù The range of constitutionally relevant action would have included at least actions fulfilling the public functions of providing transportation, accommodations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>, education, and culture. And if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> had so interpreted the notion of state action, it would have had no difficulty sustaining both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act of 1875</ENAMEX> and the convictions brought against the violators of the provision requiring equal access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> open to the public.
Furthermore, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlan</ENAMEX> pointed out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> had read the new rights established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> as though they were just like other restrictions imposed on state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, for example, the prohibitions against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> enacting bills of attainder, impairing the obligations of contract, or granting titles of nobility<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therefore</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> could engage in close analysis of the specific prohibition against state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> and assess whether it was really the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äústate‚Äù</ENAMEX> that was responsible for the wrong committed against those who were shut out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> supposedly open to the public.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> ignored, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harlan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs clearheaded view of the case, the critical feature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX>, namely that each of them grants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> authority to effectuate the amendment with ‚Äúappropriate legislation.‚Äù This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in our history that constitutional amendments carried with them an expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> authority<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accordingly</ENAMEX>, it was up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to decide how best to implement the general commitments explicit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Thirteenth and Fourteenth Amendments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had acquired a general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> power in this area comparable to the state legislative power upheld in the Slaughterhouse Case.
Harlan‚Äôs most devastating argument was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> had long assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enjoyed a general legislative power to regulate the conditions of slavery. The constitutional text of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> had stipulated a right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave owners</ENAMEX> to recover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> who had escaped into free territory<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.42</NUMEX> On that basis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fugitive Slave Law</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1793</TIMEX>, which in a manner similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX> under attack had imposed a federal penalty on those who refused to cooperate in the return of runaway slaves<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.43</NUMEX> If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could elaborate on a constitutional clause securing slavery, surely they enjoyed an analogous power, reasoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Harlan</ENAMEX>, under an express grant of legislative authority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction Amendments</ENAMEX> to eliminate slavery and secure equal protection of the laws.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs position eventually triumphed‚Äîbut not until our own time. After a long process of litigation, addressed primarily to the constitutionality of New Deal welfare legislation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> expanded the authority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to legislate on all matters affecting ‚Äúinterstate commerce.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù44 This became the basis for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act of 1964</ENAMEX>, which finally enacted the broad-gauged protection against discrimination that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> had declared beyond the competence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883</TIMEX>. Grounding congressional competence to counteract discrimination in its power to regulate interstate commerce smacked of legal convolution. The better ground would have been precisely the original claim of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> asserted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Harlan‚Äôs fidelity</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln‚Äôs</ENAMEX> vision of the postbellum constitutional order becomes clear in his appeal to the concept of nationhood. Of all the opinions surveyed in leading cases decided in the aftermath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs is the only one that comes close to conceptualizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as a nation acting as a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>. When the term appears in the other opinions, it is always as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">adjective ‚Äúnational</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> opinion is studded with references that replicate the usage that we heard in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX> and then found in selected poetry and philosophy written at the time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It is an organic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, a source of authority. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan</ENAMEX> repeats nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> times in the course of his opinion, the ‚Äúnation has liberated‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù45</NUMEX> the slaves, ‚Äúthe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has established universal freedom in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äù46</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, denied citizenship in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> decision, acquired their equal citizenship ‚Äúin virtue of an affirmative grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù47</ENAMEX> 
Reasoning like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orestes Brownson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Lieber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlan</ENAMEX> distinguished clearly between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and the federal or national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is not a constituted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It is rather the source of authority that legitimates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. This conception of nationhood, synonymous with the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>, is evident in expressions stressing the logical priority of the nation‚Äôs will. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harland</ENAMEX> writes that to insure that ‚Äúthe purposes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> might not be doubted or defeated . . . the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX> was proposed for adoption.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù48 Equally</ENAMEX> poignant are passages that treat the rights and privileges of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> as ‚Äúderived from the nation‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù49</NUMEX> or that stress ‚Äúwhat the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has sought to accomplish.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù50</ENAMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Marshall Harlan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs entire philosophy, expressing the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Constitution</ENAMEX> in dissent, is summed up in this sentence:
Exemption from race discrimination in respect of the civil rights which are fundamental in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, is, as we have seen, a new right, created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, with express power in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, by legislation, to enforce the constitutional provision from which it is derived<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.51</NUMEX> 
