
   
      
         
            Red Pants



            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> whose business it is to be witty
often fail to produce, grave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> occasionally
are mirthful when laughter is farthest from their
minds.  From a lifetime of undisciplined reading with
innocent pencil in hand and malice prepense in mind,
I have gleaned a harvest of what I am pleased to denominate
Red Pants items, a sampling of which follows.
My designation derives from a splash of vivid
writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Thompson</ENAMEX>'s  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Corymbus for Autumn</ENAMEX>
in which he proclaims how ‚Äúday's dying dragon‚Äù
was


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panting</ENAMEX> red pants into the West.
            

            In this trousers category, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> must share the
limelight with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coleridge</ENAMEX> by virtue of the line in Kubla
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khan</ENAMEX> :


As if this earth in fast thick pants were breathing.
            

            Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelley</ENAMEX> may stake a claim, if only in the pajama
division of this sector, thanks to his description in
Epipsychidion of how


... the slow, silent night
Is measured by the pants of their calm sleep.
            

            Since everthing is to be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, it is not
surprising that on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> occasions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> has
contributed his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Pants nuggets</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Act IV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scene VIII</ENAMEX>, lines <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14 et seq</TIMEX> .)  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Antony</ENAMEX>
commands the wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Scarus</ENAMEX> to


... leap thou, attire and all,
Through proof of harness to my heart, and there
Ride on the pants triumphing.
            

            And in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Othello</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act II, Scene I, line 80</ENAMEX>) Cassio utters
the fervent prayer that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Othello</ENAMEX> might

            Make love's quick pants in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Desdemona</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>.

            A variation on this theme occurs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alba de C√</ENAMEX>©spedes'
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX> (translated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel</ENAMEX>
Quigly: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schuster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, page
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>) where she confides that ‚ÄúI still had a whole afternoon
before me to spend, and I used it to tidy up my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drawers</ENAMEX>....<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  One</ENAMEX> may well wonder what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Stowe</ENAMEX>
had in mind when, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Tom's Cabin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 5</ENAMEX>),
she narrates how <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúMrs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelby</ENAMEX> stood like one stricken.
Finally, turning to her toilet, she rested her face in her
hands, and gave a sort of groan.‚Äù  In this same vein, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mirthless Milton</ENAMEX> adds his bit to the general hilarity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> when, in describing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Etna</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book I of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paradise Lost</ENAMEX> (lines <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">236-7</ENAMEX>) he penned


And leave a singed bottom all involved
With stench and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX>: ...
            

            And in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter VI</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blenkinsop</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX>, sought to console <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amelia</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedley</ENAMEX>'s jilting of her dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thackeray</ENAMEX> confides
(indelicately?)  that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amelia</ENAMEX> wept confidentially on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX>'s shoulder ‚Äúand relieved herself a good
deal.‚Äù

            Chuckles often emanate from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> employment
of a term in a sense at variance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
usage.  There is that oft-quoted example, near the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">opening of Trial by Jury</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defendant</ENAMEX> asks, ‚ÄúIs
this the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of the Exchequer?‚Äù</ENAMEX> and having been
assured that it was, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defendant</ENAMEX> (aside) commands himself
to ‚ÄúBe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, be firm, my pecker.‚Äù  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, of
course, do not giggle at this bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilbertian</ENAMEX> dialogue,
since to them pecker means `courage,' as in the phrase
‚Äúto keep your pecker up.‚Äù  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the more common
examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British-American</ENAMEX> divergence of usage are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">screw</ENAMEX> and knock up .  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 39</ENAMEX>), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">niggardly</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pitt</ENAMEX> was not nearly the aerial acrobat
your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sophomore might fancy him to be
when he ‚Äúscrewed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> by letter.‚Äù  He was simply
making extortionate exactions upon his wretched lessees.
Similarly, when in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter XXXIV</ENAMEX> of the same
novel, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bute</ENAMEX> reminds her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that ‚ÄúYou'd have
been screwed in goal, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bute</ENAMEX>, if I had not kept your
money,‚Äù she was not speaking of pleasures deferred.  In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bleak House</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter XXVII</ENAMEX>) Grandfather
Smallweed, referring to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, warns Mr.
Tulkinghorn that ‚ÄúI have him periodically in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>.  I'll
twist him, sir.  I'll screw him, sir.<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù  In Kipling's The</ENAMEX>
Light That Failed (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter XIII</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torpenhow</ENAMEX> urges
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> to attend a party <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>, ‚ÄúWe shall be half
screwed before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>,‚Äù is his dismal sales pitch
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter VI</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thackeray</ENAMEX> reports
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Sedley</ENAMEX>'s drunken avowal to wed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX> Sharp the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, even if he had to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúknock up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canterbury</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambeth,‚Äù</ENAMEX> in order to have
him in readiness to perform the ceremony.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great</ENAMEX>
Expectations (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chapter VI</ENAMEX>), we learn how ‚Äú... Mr.
Whopsle, being knocked up, was in such a very bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temper</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  And</ENAMEX> who could blame him?

            Many a raucous snigger has been sniggered from
the pure-minded use of a word that suggests unmentionable
parts of the human body.  It does not take a
too-wicked mind to read into such terms meanings of a
lewd nature.  Who can, for instance, blame a youth
with but a mildly evil disposition from guffawing
when he reads in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pater</ENAMEX>'s Marius The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epicurean</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX>) a reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apuleius</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Golden Ass</ENAMEX> noting
that ‚Äúall through the book, there is an unmistakably
real feeling for asses ...‚Äù?  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scott</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bride of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lammermoor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chapter VII</ENAMEX>), one reads about a boy
‚Äúcudgelling an ass,‚Äù and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> goes back over the passage
to reassure himself that it does not contain a typographical
error for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúcuddling</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> may be indulged a giggle even though he is
sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isak Dinesen</ENAMEX> did not intend an impropriety
when she recorded in Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Part V</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) how ‚ÄúFathima's big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">white cock</ENAMEX> came strutting up
before me.‚Äù  And one is certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Rexroth</ENAMEX>,
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Poetry</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twentieth Century</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>) did not intend to hint
at closet biographical matter when, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter I</ENAMEX>, he
wrote that ‚ÄúWhitman's poems are full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> doing
things together,‚Äù or, later in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, when he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">referred to ‚ÄúWhitman</ENAMEX>'s joyous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workmen</ENAMEX> swinging their
tools in the open air.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  College</ENAMEX> freshman still read with
flendish glee the first line in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Canto I</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spenser</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faerie Queene</ENAMEX> (and never mind the title!) that tells
how

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentle Knight</ENAMEX> was pricking on the plaine.

            In his poem Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> (from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Selwyn Mauberley</ENAMEX> ),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezra Pound</ENAMEX>'s Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> advises kindly

            Don't kick against the pricks,

            although the identities of the latter are not divulged.

            One is entitled to speculate on what outrageous
proposal the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> had made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Proust</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Remembrance</TIMEX>
of Things Past, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vol. 2‚ÄîCities of the Plain</ENAMEX>
(translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. K. Scott Moncrieff‚</ENAMEX>ÄîModern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>) to cause the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchess</ENAMEX> to say,
‚ÄúApart from your balls, can't I be of any use to you?‚Äù
There is a famous letter penned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Brooke</ENAMEX> to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward Marsh</ENAMEX>, from somewhere near Fiji
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 463</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Treasury of the World's Great Letters</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon and Schuster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>) in which he relates
how he sends his native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> up a palm <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, where he
‚Äúcuts off a couple of vast nuts ...‚Äù (macho <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> not
disclosed).  In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Tom's Cabin</ENAMEX> ,
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Stowe</ENAMEX> offers a dialogue between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haley</ENAMEX> and Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelby</ENAMEX>, part of which goes, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äú `Well</ENAMEX>,' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley</ENAMEX>, after
they had both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">silently</ENAMEX> picked their nuts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX>,
`what do you say?' ‚Äù  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bleak House</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter XXIV</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> may cause some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to blush when he
wrote of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>'s blush that ‚ÄúHe reddened a little
through his brown.‚Äù

            We must move ineluctably to a consideration of
perfectly reputable words which, having acquired sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">connotations</ENAMEX>, cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">adolescent‚Äîand</ENAMEX> often adult‚Äî
hilarity, even when read by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of only mildly
prurient mind.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forster</ENAMEX>'s A Passage to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXXI</ENAMEX>) a vivid picture is created by the sentence
‚ÄúTangles like this still interrupted their intercourse.‚Äù
Pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter XXXVII</ENAMEX>), it is acknowledged that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúHe</ENAMEX>, too, felt that this was their last free intercourse.‚Äù
Apparently from then on, it was going to have to be
cash or credit card only.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bride of Lammermoor</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter V</ENAMEX>), we are informed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine ‚</ENAMEX>Äúplaced
certain restrictions on their intercourse,‚Äù a limitation
that might have been more usefully set in that same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Roy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chapter VII</ENAMEX>) where we are told of
the chance that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Vernon</ENAMEX> might be
‚Äúthrown into very close and frequent intercourse.‚Äù

            A variation of this theme is found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Flight of the Duchess</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Section</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX>):


‚ÄîNot he!  For in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> they told the elf
Our rough North land was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of Lays</ENAMEX>,
            

            even though it is generally acknowledged that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">n√∫mero uno</ENAMEX> in this area of human activity.

            More picturesque are the references to erections.
An arresting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> occurs in A Passage to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXI</ENAMEX>) in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forster</ENAMEX> describes a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> as ‚Äúa
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flimsy</ENAMEX> and frivolous erection,‚Äù while in The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casterbridge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter XVI</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> himself ‚Äúbeheld
the unattractive exterior of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farfrae</ENAMEX>'s erection.‚Äù  A
phrase can paint an astonishing picture for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>.

            Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' sharp image in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bleak House</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIV</ENAMEX>) when he describes how ‚ÄúSir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leicester</ENAMEX> leans
Or, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Nickleby</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter XLVII</ENAMEX>), where that
admirable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> graphically portrays how old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gride ‚Äúagain</ENAMEX> raised his hands, again chuckled,
and again ejaculated.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  And</ENAMEX> in his short tale, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lionizing</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Allan Poe</ENAMEX> is quite candid in describing the reaction
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äú ` Admirable</ENAMEX>! ' he ejaculated,
thrown quite off his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> by the beauty of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manoeuvre</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            Alas for perfectly lovely words that acquire pejorative
meanings over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>!  Earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>,
pansy became a derogatory epithet to describe an effete
male, thereby cheapening forever lines like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelley</ENAMEX>'s
noble image in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Adonais</ENAMEX> (verse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXXIII</ENAMEX>):


His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> was bound with pansies over-blown,
            

            not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poe</ENAMEX>'s odd allusion in For Annie :


With rue and the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pansies</ENAMEX>.
            

            Or, more slap-stickish, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.F. Benson</ENAMEX>'s action picture in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucia</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 8</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúGeorgie</ENAMEX> stepped on a
beautiful pansy.‚Äù

            Of more recent vintage is gay .  Nobody used to
snicker at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaucer</ENAMEX>'s line (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5818</NUMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Prologe of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyf of Bathe</ENAMEX> , in which that harried dame asks:


Why is my neghebores wif so gay?
            

            In his poem The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menagerie</ENAMEX> , one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vaughan Moody's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> advises:


If nature made you so graceful, don't get gay,
            

            while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Othello</ENAMEX> (ah, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX> again!)  in his dialogue
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desdemona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilia</ENAMEX> on the praise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Iago</ENAMEX> refers to the kind that


Never lack'd <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and yet went never gay.

(<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act II, Scene I, line 150</ENAMEX>)
            

            And what in the world is one to make of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler Yeats</ENAMEX>'s startling revelation in his poem Lapis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lazuli</ENAMEX> (from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poems</ENAMEX> ) that


They know that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lear</ENAMEX> are gay.?
            

            Indeed it is an amusing, albeit utterly wasteful
pastime to pursue the quest for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Pants</ENAMEX> examples.
May good cess befall all such quixotically misguided
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>!  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> caveat: never assume blithely that an odd
word or suspicious phrase is as lubricious as it sounds.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bride of Lammermoor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chapter VI</ENAMEX>) Bucklaw
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vows, ‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> will chop them off with my whinger,‚Äù and one
feels quite let down when he learns that a whinger is
but a whinyard, which is merely a short sword.
         
         
            
‚ÄúTurning a corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazza Gallerie</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tennis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, I was startled to see ... hordes of giggling high
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> ... ‚Äù [From an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Gilliam</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , .  Submitted by .]
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIGHT REFRACTIONS</ENAMEX>




            If you are a fan of old-fashioned jazz‚Äîwhat is now
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äútraditional‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äútrad‚Äù jazz‚Äîyou</ENAMEX> are familiar
with one of the standard ‚Äújump tunes‚Äù of the
genre‚Äîa tune most commonly called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Muskrat Ramble</ENAMEX> .
Even if you are not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, you must have heard it
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as least a dozen</NUMEX> times.  It is the one that goes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚ÄúDah</ENAMEX>!
Dah!  Dah!  Dah!  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">da-dat-dat-</ENAMEX>dah!  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Da-de-da-de-da-de</ENAMEX>-dat-dat-dah
!  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da-de-da-de-da-de</ENAMEX>-dat-dat-dah!‚Äù


That's it; sure; you've heard it.
            

            I think I first bought a recording of Muskrat Ramble
back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 1940</TIMEX>, when I was in my early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>.
My memory is rickety, but I am sure my first recording
was labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MUSKRAT RAMBLE</ENAMEX>, and I think, though I
am less sure, that it was played by the late ‚ÄúMuggsy‚Äù
Spanier, who was, to my mind, one of the greatest of
jazz trumpeters.  Later, I got another recording of the
same tune, this one by, I think, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mezz Mezzrow</ENAMEX>.  The
label said, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MUSKAT RAMBLE</ENAMEX>.  I thought that was surely
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I had ever seen such an obvious typographical
error in, of all things, a simple title on a
simple <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>-rpm record.  (This, remember, was in my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, and it was a time when typographical errors
were called typographical errors, not typos‚Äîat least
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in junior high.)  Some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> later, I got still
another version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MUSKRAT RAMBLE</ENAMEX>, with still another
version of the title.  This time, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MUSCAT RAMBLE</ENAMEX>.
That, I thought, was really absurd.  Not only had they
left out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúR‚Äù</ENAMEX>; they'd changed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúK‚Äù to ‚ÄúC‚Äù</ENAMEX>.  Now, it
made no sense at all.  On the other hand, I reasoned, if
there were, in fact, some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> called a muscat,
perhaps it wasn't so outrageous.  I looked up muscat in
my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster's</ENAMEX> and found that it is a `variety of grape.'
To name a ramble after a variety of grape seemed to
me preposterous.  I was young and, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s standards,
at least, pathetically innocent.

            During my time in senior high, and, after that, in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Army Air Force</ENAMEX>, I had other things on my mind
(there was a war on, after all), and I didn't give
the MUSKRAT-MUSKAT-MUSCAT RAMBLE problem any
thought.

            Speaking of my time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAF</ENAMEX>, which was utterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undistinguished</ENAMEX>, I think I must make a confession.
Now might be as good a time as any to reveal a
theft I committed at an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Air Force Base</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.  It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> and bitterly cold.  The wind
used to sweep across that damned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airfield</ENAMEX> with what
seemed an absolute determination to crystallize our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> when the wind chill factor was nearing
absolute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, I took <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> in the service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>.
There was the omnipresent phonograph, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vic</ENAMEX> , short
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victrola</ENAMEX>, and the stack of records next to it.  In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a rule did not take much care of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phonograph</ENAMEX> records.  Usually the records were taken
from their jackets and loaded naked in stacks, where
they picked up dust, scratched one another, and
traded static electricity.  I was shuffling through a stack
of about fifty records, and I came across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> Bessie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiths</ENAMEX>.  I played <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>, and the few other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX>s in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, which was quite large‚Äîbig enough for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fair-sized</ENAMEX> dance with a small orchestra‚Äîeither paid
no attention or asked me to put on something by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jimmy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Dorsey</ENAMEX> instead.  Among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bessie</ENAMEX>'s numbers were <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dying Gambler's Blues, Sing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sing Prison Blues</ENAMEX> , and one I had never heard called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Mountain Blues</ENAMEX> , which has the imcomparable
lines,


<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Mountain</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chile</ENAMEX>' will smack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yo</ENAMEX>'
face;

<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Mountain</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chile</ENAMEX>' will smack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yo</ENAMEX>'
face;

Babies cry for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> an' all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> sing bass.
            

            and


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goin</ENAMEX>' back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Mountain</ENAMEX>, me an' my razor
an' my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>;

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goin</ENAMEX>' back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Mountain</ENAMEX>, me an' my razor
an my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>;

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goin</ENAMEX>' cut him if he stan' still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goin</ENAMEX>' shoot him if he
run.
            

            I was, and still am, captivated by ‚ÄúBabies cry for
liquor an' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> sing bass,‚Äù and in the arrogance of
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, I was certain that nobody else on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airfield</ENAMEX>
either knew or cared who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bessie Smith</ENAMEX> was, nor
would any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX> be enchanted by basso <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, so I
turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>.  I can't remember how I did it, but somehow
I smuggled those records back to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> and
got them home intact on my next furlough.  I kept
them in good shape until my last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>-rpm turntable
died.

            End of digression and back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MUSKRAT-KAT-CAT</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muskrat Ramble</ENAMEX> is credited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward ‚ÄúKid‚Äù Ory</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Gilbert</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúKid‚Äù Ory</ENAMEX> played great jazz trombone.
The only thing I know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> is that I find him
listed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muskrat Ramble</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About thirty years ago</TIMEX>, when I was concocting an
epicurean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> and saw that I had no sherry on hand, I
went to the liquor store and bought a bottle of muscatel
that was being sold for an absurdly low price and
that I thought might be exactly right for my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>.  It
wasn't bad, The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> jogged my thoughts back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muscat Ramble</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muscatel</ENAMEX> is made from muscat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grapes</ENAMEX>, is sometimes called muscat , and, being relatively
cheap and sweet and high in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> content, is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> of choice for a great many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>.  An old
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who celebrated his twentieth
birthday‚Äîmeaning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> of AA sobriety‚Äîa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years ago</TIMEX>, tells me that when he was on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skids</ENAMEX> and riding the rails from drunk tank to drunk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tank</ENAMEX>, the favorite terms for muscat were muscadoodle
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Napa Valley</ENAMEX> smoke .

            I made up my mind that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muscat Ramble</ENAMEX> was
almost certainly the original name of the tune.  My
reasoning is that it is not likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúKid‚Äù Ory</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> had ever seen a muskrat, and it's even less
likely that they or anyone else has ever seen a muskrat
doing anything that we would be likely to think of as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rambling</ENAMEX>.  Muskrats, according to my encyclopedia,
look like giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, are found in and around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mudbanks</ENAMEX> bordering marshes and quiet ponds, have
partially webbed feet, and do a good deal of swimming.
They do not appear to do much rambling.  Muscat,
or muscatel, on the other hand, is found on skid
rows all over the land.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with a bottle-shaped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brown</ENAMEX> paper bag, damp and wrinkled at its upper
end, has almost certainly been slugging down a sweet
wine of high proof, and the odds are pretty good you
would find it is a muscadoodle .  After the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> finishes
his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Napa Valley</ENAMEX> smoke and has slept it off, he is looking
for the means to get another muscat fix.  Now he is on a
ramble with his hand out and a pleading look in his
roadmapped eyes.  I suspect that that is precisely the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX>'s origin.

            My theory is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúr‚Äù</ENAMEX> got put in there simply
because muskrat is a more common word than muscat .
It is the same reason most of us, I assume, have heard,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúHe</ENAMEX>'s in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> with prostrate trouble.‚Äù  Prostrate
is a more common word that prostate , so prostrate is
what we get.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúr‚Äù</ENAMEX> fits in naturally.  I got a strange
sort of corroboration from my good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosy</ENAMEX>
McHargue, who is now pushing eighty-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and
has spent most of his life playing clarinet and sax with
some of the best jazzbands‚ÄîBenny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Weems</ENAMEX>, and a slew of others.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosy</ENAMEX>, too,
had seen the tune as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muskrat, Muskat</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muscat</ENAMEX> .  I
asked him what he thought the original title was.  He
had known <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúKid‚Äù Ory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX>, and he said, ‚ÄúYou know,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>, I'm not exactly sure.  I once asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ory</ENAMEX> about it
and he said, `It's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">m-u-s-c-a-t</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muskrat</ENAMEX> .'  So I think that's
just the way everyone said muscat .‚Äù

            There you are.  I find a muskrat ramble difficult to
imagine visually.  I picture muskrats wallowing about
in the mire and paddling sluggishly through the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
but I wouldn't call that rambling.  On the other hand,
a wino with an empty paper bag on a ramble to maintain
his muscat level‚Äînow that has a touch of poetry.
Maybe not in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúall the birds</ENAMEX> sing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bass</ENAMEX>,‚Äù but poetry, nevertheless.
         
         

            As a nonexpert, although interested, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>, it is ‚Äúa bit mysterious‚Äù to me that the singular
noun absence takes the plural verb are .  I refer to
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence of your article about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longman</ENAMEX>
Dictionary [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XV,1</NUMEX>].



         
         

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen W. Power, in ‚ÄúWomen</ENAMEX> on Language;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language</ENAMEX>,‚Äù [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XV,2</NUMEX>] may bewail the insensitivity
of the male.  But she betrays her own elitist insensitivity
when she describes a flight attendant as ‚Äúthe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who passes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> on an airplane.‚Äù  I hope
Ms./<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss</ENAMEX>/Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Power</ENAMEX> never needs to draw on the considerable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first-aid</ENAMEX> and emergency training that every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> must master.



         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antipodean Newsletter</ENAMEX>



            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Bloomfield</ENAMEX>, having begun with a theory
of meaning which emphasized the environment in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> were present and named, had to add the
obvious proviso that we sometimes mention what is
not present.  I have lately been reading accounts of the
exploration of the western and northwestern deserts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s</TIMEX> and I have become very aware of
the effect absent necessities might have on the frequency
of particular items in discourse.  In the desert
the missing necessity is water.  As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">explorer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giles</ENAMEX> put it, the explorer's experience is a ‚Äúbaptism
worse than that of fire‚Äîthe baptism of no water.‚Äù

            My impression was that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> of desert
explorers the word <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> , alone or in compounds, and
words relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, were unusually frequent.  It is,
I suppose, likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with little money must
think of money more than the well-off do and that the
hungry will dwell on thoughts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and the thirsty
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>.  Here was a chance to quantify such things.  I
decided to make a count of words relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in
reports of desert exploration.

            Taking quite at random a single page (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> recording an early
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX>) exploration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> east and north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perth</ENAMEX>, I
find the word <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> times.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> pages on
(page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>), water occurs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> times but there are also
the related words stream (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>), well (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>), pool,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> , and the circumlocution ‚Äúessential element.‚Äù
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> words, dew and shower , refer in the context to the
presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>; the rest are in contexts indicating its
absence.

            I tried another explorer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Giles</ENAMEX>.  Taking
page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> again, I was reminded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giles</ENAMEX> is rather
given to semi-serious poetic diction at times, and we
find him referring to the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the Finke
River as ‚Äúthe stream purling over its stony floor‚Äù or,
quoting some bygone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúbrightly the brook through
the green leaflets, giddy with joyousness, dances
along.‚Äù  Perhaps present <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> called for some stylistic
celebration.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two hundred</NUMEX> pages further on there is less
exuberance in the circumlocution ‚Äúthat fluid so terribly
scarce in the region,‚Äù and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other references
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is simply water .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giles</ENAMEX> is not always waxing poetic
and may, like other explorers, be useful as a source
for the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> and general <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  His
use of the word tank to refer to a hollowed-out reservoir
(‚ÄúGibson dug a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> and the water soon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cleared‚Äù</ENAMEX>) antedates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> , for instance.

            Since this linguistic-statistical study of an obsession
might well prove to be an important contribution
to psycholinguistics, I decided to make a larger sample
of watery words, choosing the straightforward journals
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Egerton Warburton</ENAMEX>, who led an expedition
across the western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1873-4</ENAMEX>.  In a randomly chosen sequence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> pages
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151-60</NUMEX> of the published <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>) there were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-eight</TIMEX>
occurrences of the word <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of them in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">compounds</ENAMEX>), no page being without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> example.
In addition, there was a rich collection of words
relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, not necessarily indicating its presence.
‚ÄúHoping to find a lake‚Äù is included, though of
course it doesn't indicate the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.  Even
words which are usually of more general reference are
brought into relation with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in a text like this.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gum-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> or rocks (in areas of sand) appear as signs of
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.  Apart from these words and lake ,
words and phrases directly associated with thoughts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and reinforcing the sense of obsession include
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">springs</TIMEX>, drainage hole, clay hole, flood, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, water-hole, rock-hole, drink, drinkable,
running <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, stream , and native well .

            The last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> items merit comment.  Stream is often
said not to be used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> except in metaphorical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>, normally being replaced by creek .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warburton</ENAMEX>'s use: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúsandbanks intercept the stream,
which finally splits into narow water-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and
spreads itself over the plains, and so it ends as a creek‚Äù
suggests a somewhat more complex relation between
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words.  British-born explorers did not set out to
write <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian English</ENAMEX>, of course.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory</ENAMEX> uses
stream in the way normal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giles</ENAMEX> consistently
refers to gens in the hills of central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>,
though glen is not current (outside place-names) in
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.

            The other name, native well is, as a later explorer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Carnegie</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spinifex</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sand</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>),
points out, a misnomer.  He believes native <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> are
essentially rock-holes (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depressions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>) buried in
fairly shallow sand, which, when hollowed out by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">natives</ENAMEX>, appear to be <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>.  This sort of misnomer
leads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX> to suppose that ‚Äúto the uninitiated no
map is so misleading as that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Australia</ENAMEX> where
lakes are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>-bogs without surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, springs seldom
run, and native `<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>' are merely tiny holes in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX>, yielding from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0 to 200 gallons</NUMEX>.‚Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX> also describes namma-holes and soaks as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.  Soaks are shallow wells sunk near the
base of an outcrop to tap an underground reservoir.
Namma-holes have been variously described; to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>
they are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depressions</ENAMEX> on the surface of rocks, often
with a rounded bottom, where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> are often found,
suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> have something to do with
the formation of the holes.

            Some nostalgic early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> deplored the loss
in our speech of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> country words, the glens and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">streams</ENAMEX> (alive, anyway, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> of explorers),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coppices</ENAMEX> and brooks, woods, becks , and rivulets .  Perhaps
these words did not really fit.  We might have
done better with <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>.  Wadi , for
instance, would describe an inland creek rather well.
Be that as it may, a later <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drizzle</ENAMEX> might feel nostalgic when thinking of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parched</ENAMEX> and thirsty but water-obsessed vocabulary developed
in the drier areas of our sunburnt land.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Favorite Grammatical Game: Puzzling</ENAMEX> Pronouns




            Here is a game just made to while away the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
on a commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> with your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>,
a perfect place to hunt for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puzzling Pronouns</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fowler</ENAMEX> lists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> instances where a careless writer
can go wrong.  There is really no excuse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fowler</ENAMEX> says
(not he says!), but here we give examples of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
case only, where ‚Äúthere should not be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> justifying
even a momentary doubt about which the pronoun
represents.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  And</ENAMEX> here the deluge of printed matter
abounds with such specimens that one would
suppose them to be the rule rather than the exceptions.
It is a game that is like fishing in a barrel, but more
stimulating mentally.  I am not picking on the following
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>; it is just a random catch.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thomas Hardy's The Hand of Ethelberta</ENAMEX> , it is
suggested by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethelberta</ENAMEX> that she and some others go to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cripplegate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.  Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitor</ENAMEX>,
Neigh, who had proposed marriage in a previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX>, appears somewhat apprehensive at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethelberta</ENAMEX>'s
suggestion.  This apprehension is observed by a
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belmaine</ENAMEX> and mistaken by him for an indication
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neigh</ENAMEX> has been dragged into going to the church
against his will ‚Äúby his over-hasty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  One wonders
whether the marriage had secretly taken place between
the consecutive chapters!  You see, it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belmaine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who was doing the dragging.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Somerset Maugham</ENAMEX> was a good and careful grammarian
but now and then he slipped.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Letter</ENAMEX> , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>, is approached by a Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosbie</ENAMEX>:


He spoke beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, accenting each word
with precision, and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> had often wondered
at the extent of his vocabulary....
            

            Sometimes I wonder about the extent of my own vocabulary,
too, but really, not when I'm interviewing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>.

            From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Once and Future King</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T. H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>:


Naturally it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lancelot</ENAMEX> who rescued her.  Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>
had managed to find him at the abbey, during his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>' absence, and now he came back in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nick</ENAMEX> of time to fight Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mador</ENAMEX> for the queen.  Nobody
who knew him would have expected him to
do anything else, whether he had been sent away in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgrace or not‚Äîbut</ENAMEX>, as it was thought he had left
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, his return did have a dramatic quality.
            

            Not to say a quality of confusion‚Äîpronoun-cedly so.

            From Oh What a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> it Seems , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Cheever:


The size of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chisholm</ENAMEX>'s teeth, the thickness of his
glasses, his stoop and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> with which he
walked all marked him, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> thought, as a single-minded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>.  His marriage, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> guessed,
would have been unsuccessful and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
would have difficulty finding themselves.
            

            No wonder ‚Äî we've lost them already.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Twain</ENAMEX> poses us a little mystery in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pudd</ENAMEX>'nhead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>: which <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> does the killing?  Quiet now.
Lights, action:


I was asleep, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luigi</ENAMEX> was awake, and he thought
he detected a vague form nearing the bed.  He
slipped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> out of the sheath and was ready,
and unembarrassed by hampering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bedclothes</ENAMEX>, for
the weather was hot and we hadn't any.  Suddenly
that native rose at the bedside, and bent over me
with his right hand lifted and a dirk in it aimed at
my throat; but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Luigi</ENAMEX> grabbed his wrist, pulled him
downward, and drove his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
neck.  That is the whole story.
            

            Well, was it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luigi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX>'s?  If we had only
that scene to go by we would never really know, and
all because of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Puzzling Pronoun ‚Äîor two</ENAMEX>!


Oh, it can lead <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to a rhymed couplet:

He loves his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
Does he live a double life?
            

            Give me my grammatical games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> to a crossword
puzzle.
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Joys and Oys</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>



            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Robert Schenkerman</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Beth Jacob</ENAMEX>
            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX> was awarded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize for Literature</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, he remarked
in his acceptance speech:


The high honor bestowed upon me is also a recognition
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish language‚Äîa language</ENAMEX> of exile,
without a land, without frontiers, not supported
by any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, a language which
possesses no words for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX>, military
exercises, war tactics.

There is a quiet humor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> and a gratitude
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> of life, every crumb of success,
each encounter of love.  In a figurative way, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
is the wise and humble language of us all, the idiom
of a frightened and hopeful humanity.
            

            The word <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> derives from the German
judisch `<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>.'  The principal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> is
High <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> encountered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> from northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in the eleventh
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yiddish</ENAMEX> is written in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> of the
Hebrew alphabet and from right to left and enjoys
borrowing words from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and
all the other languages and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> along the routes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> have traveled during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past thousand years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rappaport</ENAMEX> once quipped, ‚ÄúI speak
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> languages‚Äîall of them <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> has been in danger of dying out
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the language is spoken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> throughout the world‚ÄîRussia, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>,
Rumania, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, where, like the bagel, it was leavened
on both coasts, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>.  It is
spoken even in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transylvania</ENAMEX>: A beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> awakens
in bed to find a vampire at her side.  Quickly she holds
up a cross. ‚ÄúZie gernisht helfen,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> smiles the vampire.
Translation: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúIt won't do you any good.‚Äù

            Most of us already speak a fair amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yinglish</ENAMEX>) without fully realizing it.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s Third
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New International Dictionary</ENAMEX> lists about <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">500 Yiddish</ENAMEX>
words that have become part of our everyday conversations,
including:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cockamamy</ENAMEX> (or cockamamie) `mixed-up, ridiculous.'

fin slang for `<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five-dollar</NUMEX> bill,' from finf, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
word for `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>.'

gun moll a double clipping of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonif</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
for `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.'

kibitzer `one who comments, often in the form of
unwanted advice, during a game, often cards.'

mavin `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>.'

mazuma `money.'

mish-mosh `mess.'

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">schlep</ENAMEX> to `drag or haul.'

schlock `shoddy, cheaply produced merchandise.'

schmeer the `entire deal,' the `whole package.'

schnoz slang for `nose.'

yenta `blabbermouth, gossip; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of low
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX>.'
            

            ... and so on through the whole megillah : `<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long,</TIMEX>
involved story.'

            A number of poignant <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> words defy genuine
translation into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>:


chutzpa `nerve; unmitigated gall;' a quality we
admire within ourselves, but never in others.  In
his delightful study, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Joys of Yiddish</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGraw-Hill</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Rosten</ENAMEX> offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> classic
definitions.  ‚ÄúChutzpa is that quality enshrined in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who, having killed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throws</ENAMEX> himself on the mercy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> because
he is an orphan.  A chutzpanik may be defined as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who shouts `Help!  Help!'  while beating
you up.‚Äù

mensch a `real authentic human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">being‚</ENAMEX>Äîa <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.'
naches the `glow of pleasure<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">-plus</NUMEX>-pride that only
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> can give to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>': <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThis is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctor!‚</ENAMEX>Äù

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oy</ENAMEX> not so much a word as an entire vocabulary, as
Rosten observes: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúcan express any emotion, from
trivial delight to the blackest woe.‚Äù

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oy</ENAMEX> vay; oy vay in mir literally, ‚ÄúOh, pain,‚Äù but, in
its long or short form, can be used for anything
from condolence to lament:

On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6, 1945</TIMEX>, the world's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> nuclear
weapon was dropped on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.  Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hundred</ENAMEX> and eighty-two <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> human beings
died and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> more were left
burned, maimed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX>.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>,
whose letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> had initiated the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> effort that resulted in the atom bomb
and whose special theory of relativity formed its
theoretical basis, heard the news on the radio.
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> he could only find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
words traditionally used by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in such circumstances:
‚ÄúOi vey.‚Äù

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄîThe Little, Brown Book of Anecdotes</ENAMEX>

tsuris the gamut of painful emotions‚Äîsome real,
some imagined, some self-inflicted.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yiddish</ENAMEX> is especially versatile in describing those
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who inhabit the world of the ineffectual,
and each is assigned a distinct place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> of
pathetic types: schmo, schmendrik, schnook, schmegegge,
schlep, schlub, schmuck, putz, klutz, kvetch ,
and nudnik .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yiddish</ENAMEX> easily coins new names for new
personalities: a nudnik is a `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pest</ENAMEX>'; a phudnik is a `nudnik
with a Ph.D.'  The rich nuances that suffuse this
roll call are seen in the timeless distinction between a
schlemiel `clumsy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jerk</ENAMEX>' and a schlimazel `habitual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>': the schlemiel inevitably trips and spills his hot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soup‚Äîall</ENAMEX> over the schlimazel.  (And the nebbish is the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who has to clean it up.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish language</ENAMEX>, through its color, its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>-accurate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expressions</ENAMEX>, its raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">idioms</ENAMEX>, and its sayings
exudes a refreshing magic and laughter, mixed with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sober</ENAMEX> thought, that has been handed down from generation
to generation and from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
never apologizes for what it is‚Äîthe earthy, wise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> of an expressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> learning that life is but a
mingled yarn, good and ill together.

            Which reminds us of the zaftig `buxom, well-rounded'
blonde who wore an enormous diamond to a
charity ball.  ‚ÄúIt happens to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> most famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diamond</ENAMEX> in the whole world,‚Äù she boasted.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> first is
the Hope diamond, then comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kohinoor</ENAMEX>, and then
comes this one, which is called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipschitz</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            ‚ÄúWhat a stone!  How lucky you are!‚Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúWait</ENAMEX>, wait,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>.  ‚ÄúNothing in life is all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mazel</ENAMEX> [`good luck'].  Unfortunately, with this famous
Lipschitz <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamond</ENAMEX> comes also the famous Lipschitz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curse</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> gasped and asked, ‚ÄúAnd what is
the famous Lipschitz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse?‚</ENAMEX>Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúLipschitz</ENAMEX>,‚Äù sighed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Women's History of the Word</ENAMEX>
            Those who are not familiar with feminist writings
may find it useful and interesting to consider a book,
recently published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, that is typical of the
harsher brand of such works.  The work in question
offers nothing regarding language, so its review here is
ancillary to the main function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>.  The feminist
movement is very much alive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúGreenham Common Women‚</ENAMEX>Äù are probably largely
responsible for much of the national sentiment against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cruise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> installed at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> near
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, as elsewhere, most books by
feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> are seldom assigned to review them, possibly
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> fears that they will be either
ignorant of or unsympathetic to the issues raised, if not
biased against them, or because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
Because writing an unfavorable review of a (bad) feminist
book would be tantamount to treachery, such
books are often unjustifiably praised, as was the case
with this work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalind Miles</ENAMEX>, which was well received
on its publication in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.

            According to the blurb on the dust jacket of this
distinctly unpleasant book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalind Miles</ENAMEX> is head of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre for Women's Studies</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coventry Polytechnic</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcaster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of
several other books, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhighly acclaimed‚</ENAMEX>Äù
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Jonson</ENAMEX>.  One might like to believe
that this gives her the cachet of authoritative scholarship,
but the text does not bear out the promise.

            For the most part, the book consists of a rewriting
of history, from the dawn of time, with the purpose of
demonstrating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main themes: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfact‚Äù</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were responsible for all the important contributions
to the advancement of civilization (as the development
of agriculture, for instance), often despite
the arrogance and stupidity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>; and the ‚Äúfact‚Äù
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have long been subjected to domination
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> suggests that such domination is a recent
phenomenon‚Äîonly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of thousand years</TIMEX>
old‚Äîfor she points to the clear superiority of women
in (primitive) religions and matriarchies, right on
through to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dynastic rulers</ENAMEX>.  At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point,
she gets so carried away with her thesis that she suggests
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> were responsible not only for all of
human evolutionary biology but for the very notion of
counting (in order to keep track of menstruation) and,
probably by the same token, astronomy.  She quotes
(and, presumably, accepts) another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> which holds
that ‚Äúwoman first awakened in humankind the capacity
to recognize abstracts.‚Äù  If you believe that balderdash,
you'll believe anything.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the good old days</TIMEX>, we were taught that the
pyramids were built by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of slaves.
Recent speculation has it that they were not slaves
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">but‚Äîwhat</ENAMEX> would one call them? ‚Äî ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>.
Here comes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>, authoritatively quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diodorus</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, who recorded (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-30BC</TIMEX>) that ‚Äúinnocent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> even swelled the ranks of pitiful slaves
whose forced labour built the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>:


... bound in fetters, they work continually
without being allowed any rest by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> or day.
They have not a rag to cover their nakedness, and
neither the weakness of age nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s infirmities
are any plea to excuse them, but they are driven by
blows until they drop dead.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p.49</ENAMEX>]
            

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> were already about 2500 years old
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diodorus</ENAMEX> wrote his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World History</ENAMEX> , one is given
to wonder what his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> might have been for such
a vivid description.  It is even less comprehensible how
a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> could accept it and have the effrontery
to promulgate it.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>'s book is riddled with
many similar distortions, convenient omissions, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">generalizations:</ENAMEX>


... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> have always commanded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX>
the sum total of human intelligence and creativity.
From the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sappho</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixth century</TIMEX> BC
was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to use the lyric to write subjectively
and explore the range of female experience, to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">polymath</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pan Chao</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ban Zhao</ENAMEX>), who
flourished around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AD 100</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronomer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> and educationalist, the range
is startling.  In every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> too numerous to
list were involved in developing knowledge and
contributing to the welfare of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> as they
did so: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Fabiola</ENAMEX> established a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
where she worked both as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, becoming
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> known woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> before she
died in AD 399.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p.52</ENAMEX>]
            

            Earlier, on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>, we learnt about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agnodice</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúwho
lived to become the world's first known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> gynaecologist,‚Äù
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> BC.  Clearly, this rosily
checkered past was soon to be replaced, chiefly, it
seems, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Judeo-Christian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX>-Confucian-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>
cultures flourished.  It was not too bad early on,
when, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maccabean</ENAMEX> martyrs
who ‚Äúsaved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism‚Äù</ENAMEX> did so only at the instigation
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> continues:


In early Christianity likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> found not
merely a role, but an instrument of resistance to
male domination; in choosing to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> of
Christ they inevitably cocked a snook at lesser male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fry</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> helped to build
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of God with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and
bones when frenzied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> or fianc√©s
preferred to see them die by fire, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> or the
fangs of wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> rather than live to flout [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX>]
the duty and destiny of womanhood.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p.63</ENAMEX>]
            

            But the situation soon deteriorated:


Even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Paul</ENAMEX>, later the unregenerate prophet of
female inferiority, was forced to acknowledge the
help he received from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lydia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> of purple
dyes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippi</ENAMEX>.  [ibid.]
            

            This rewriting of history is punctuated by an array
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-letter invectives applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adjectives</ENAMEX> like brilliant, unusual, inspiring , and so
forth to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.  Citing a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Judaic</ENAMEX> law-book of the 16th
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> which identified a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> preceding,
during, and following her period as niddah
`impure,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> has the lack of taste to write the following:.


As a final stroke, in a grim foreshadowing of
what the future held in store for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, the niddah
had to wear special clothing as a badge of her
separate and despised status.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p.83</ENAMEX>]
            

            Here and there in this morass of misunderstanding,
Miles treads on solid ground if one can agree with
the eminent anthropologist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Campbell</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>,
known for his extensive analyses of the world's
mythologies, religions, and cultures, noted the marked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> emerging from Judaic concepts,
later reinforced by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> doctrine.
Most of the religions of the world connected woman
with mother <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, fertility, and all the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progenetic</ENAMEX> and nurturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, and this was
borne out in the cultures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.  According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>, the only godlike female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
is the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, and she appears, identified as virgin,
only in the Gospel according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luke</ENAMEX>.  As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke</ENAMEX> was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was a carryover
from the paganism of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pantheon</ENAMEX>.
Although this might help explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Judeo-Christian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
tendencies to subjugate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
treating them essentially as chattel, it does not account
for a similar treatment accorded them in other cultures,
notably that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.  It is not entirely clear
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> was commenting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX>,
Buddhism, etc. as they once existed, conceptually, for
it is unlikely that he could have ignored the treatment
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the modern reflexes of the cultures adhering
to those religous precepts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> held that the ancient mythologies and
religions are allegorical and that there was no real
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">distinction</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between gods</TIMEX> and goddesses, who were
given sexual identity when in human form only to
make them more meaningful.  With all respect, that
seems a highly debatable issue and one far too complex
for this discussion, though we can certainly trace a
diminution in the role of female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divinities</ENAMEX> (or divinity)
when we come to examine Judaism and its congeners
and progeny.  Other debatable aspects are the questions
of whether the debasement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is a reflection of
the theology or the ritual, whether the scripture of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX> should be understood allegorically or literally,
and so forth.  If there is something wrong, it behooves
us to get at the roots of the problem, not to flail about
wildly, for only after the source of a disease has been
identified can one properly investigate its cure.

            ‚ÄúHistory according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosalind Miles‚</ENAMEX>Äù blasts away
at the symptoms in a misconceived notion that alleviating
them will effect a cure of the disease.  In this
jeremiad, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> are viewed as the ‚Äúenemy,‚Äù and are so
characterized throughout the book, which concludes
with exhortations to engage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> and a strident call
to arms (though not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Urdang</ENAMEX>
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Archaeology & Language</ENAMEX>

            [A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">VERBATIM Book Club Selection</ENAMEX>.]

            Just when you thought it was safe to assume that
we now know all we are ever likely to know about the
past, someone digs another hole and unearths (literally
or figuratively) some ancient artifact: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> it is a
fragile scroll, found in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cave</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dead Sea</ENAMEX>, that
turns out to be pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biblical</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> it is an entire
terracotta <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>: the next it is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skull</ENAMEX>, excavated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olduvai Gorge</ENAMEX>, that compels
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anthropologists</ENAMEX> (once again) to revise their guesses
about the earliest stages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homo sapiens sapiens</ENAMEX> vs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hominids</ENAMEX>.  Most of the relies from the past are gone
forever, destroyed by the plows of countless generations
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, reduced to rubble by erosion, by conquerors,
by prehistoric (and modern) urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>, by
fire and flood, and just by time.  Many, we may hope,
have not yet been found.  The interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s forebears
did not become fashionable upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roots</ENAMEX> : on a far larger scale,
we have been trying to discover all we can about the
origins not of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.  Strange to say, however,
that interest does not seem to be more than a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years old</TIMEX>: if the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romans</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> were curious
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about their own prehistory</TIMEX>, I have not heard of it.
Perhaps the fascination with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s past grew out of
the obsession with ruins evinced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romanticism</ENAMEX>; certainly,
modern archaeology seems to have followed
close behind, for the excavation of the supposed site of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy</ENAMEX> took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about 100 years ago</TIMEX>.  Perhaps it is
just as well, for only by the means available to modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> are we now able to preserve some of the artifacts
that we find and, through radiocarbon dating,
determine their approximate age.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archaeology</ENAMEX> is a popular pursuit, and its manifest
results not only receive considerable publicity but can
be seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>.  Not so paleolinguistics, or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstruction</ENAMEX> of ancient languages.  Even the remnants
we have from early languages that had a writing
system are relatively sparse: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Classical Latin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>, and a few other languages are better
documented than others; but for most all we have to go
on are a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tablets</ENAMEX> here, a few inscriptions
there, barely enough in many cases to allow us to
identify the language, let alone draw any conclusions
regarding its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> or meaning.  Perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
we shall find an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etruscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, buried deep in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> countryside; but for the present, we have to
make do with what we have, which is precious little.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> languages that had no writing system, we know
nothing at all.  But some very clever comparative linguists,
beginning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, theorized
about how the nature of the ancestors of the
more modern tongues.  In some instances, ancient languages
have been decoded, some from multilingual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inscriptions</ENAMEX>.  The work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Francois Champollion</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1790-1832</TIMEX>) in deciphering hieroglyphics from the Rosetta
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> was an astonishing accomplishment, for it
enabled us to read the myriad writings of the ancient
Egyptians on papyrus and in wall inscriptions and
revealed an enormous amount of the knowledge we
have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about their civilization, which lasted for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 2600 years</TIMEX>.  Another significant break-through
was that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ventris</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922-1956</TIMEX>), who deciphered
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linear</ENAMEX> B script found on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crete</ENAMEX> and identified
it as an early form of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>.  From the standpoint
of language, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ventris</ENAMEX>'s work was more important, particularly
because it filled in a gap in our knowledge of
the early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> languages.

            Many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linguistic scholar</ENAMEX> counted all of
the languages then spoken of which he had evidence.
The total was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 2800</TIMEX>, but that is probably
only a vague estimate: he undoubtedly missed
some; some have sprung up since his time (modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>, for instance); and some have vanished.  The
exact count is unimportant and, at best, spurious, for
it is extremely difficult to establish uniform criteria for
what distinguishes dialect from language.  Then, too,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> must examine the techniques used to group the
many languages of the world.

            Linguists examining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Classical Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slavic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch, Lithuanian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX>, and the other languages
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> found that there were
correspondences among many of the common words.
Some, like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX>,
had more in common with one another than they did
with, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>, which, in turn, bore only a remote resemblance
to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>, on the one hand, and the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extant</ENAMEX> varieties of, say, Gaelic, on the other.  One
rapidly runs out of hands and must resort to fingers
and toes, for after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of laboriously categorizing
these languages, the number of different main
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branches</ENAMEX> (called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and subfamilies) came to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ingeniously</ENAMEX>, certain differences between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were explained by various phonetic shifts that
(inexplicably) took place in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> but
not in another.  Although certain other languages were
geographically nearby, it was impossible to establish
any resemblances between them, hence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basque</ENAMEX>, for
example, is not classified as being in the same family
with other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> languages, nor are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungarian</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX>, both of which belong to their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
At the conclusion of this vast exercise, done without
the aid of computers, there emerged a pattern of familial
relationships that linked together languages spoken,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> times, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> as far east as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turkestan</ENAMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> as far north as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lappland</ENAMEX>.  Charts showing the chief languages and
their derivations can be found in many dictionaries‚Äîinside
the front cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Random House Unabridged</ENAMEX> ,
for example.  Because linguists are constantly
learning more and more about the relationships
among languages, it is best to avoid using an older
chart; for the same reason, it would be wise not to
stake too much on the accuracy of even a current
chart.

            The languages discussed here are what are usually
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>; similar family trees
could be drawn for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Semitic</ENAMEX> languages, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bantu, Malayo-Polynesian</ENAMEX>, and so on.
Each is a distinct phylum; although there may be
word-borrowing among them, lexicon is considered
less important in the classification of languages than
structure and grammar.  It is important, too, to note
that writing systems are irrelevant: for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polish</ENAMEX>
is written (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>) using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> alphabet, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>,
a related <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Slavic</ENAMEX> language, uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrillic</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Germanic</ENAMEX> language, is written in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> characters;
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanskrit</ENAMEX>, which resemble
one another rather closely in some respects, all use
different alphabets; and early examples, utterly unrecognizable
to untrained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of modern languages,
were written in cuneiform, quite suitable for writing
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soft clay tablets</ENAMEX> with a pointed stylus, and hieroglyphics.

            
It would be nice to think that while linguists were
working so hard to organize languages, they were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">working</ENAMEX> alongside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archaeologists</ENAMEX> who were providing
the raw materials.  But only rarely did they collaborate
and, with few exceptions, their work was not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correlated</ENAMEX> in a systematic way.  Schliemann, who discovered
the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Troy</ENAMEX>, used the evidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Homer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iliad</ENAMEX> to determine his digging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, where any ruins
had long since disappeared from view.  In many other
places, the ancient sites lay buried‚Äîand still
do‚Äîbeneath modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>: modern property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>
quite understandably take a dim view of tearing down
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> on the off chance that the remnants of
an ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> will be found <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several yards</NUMEX> below.
today, before a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is erected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archaeological</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> examines the cleared site for its
archaeological significance.  But there, as everywhere
else, nothing can interfere with progress and, regardless
of the finds and their importance, the archaeologist
must eventually yield to the bulldozer.  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Notwithstanding,</ENAMEX>
even the brief glimpses afforded by such
investigations can provide some insight into civilizations
that existed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> or, in some cases, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands</NUMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years earlier</TIMEX>.

            Based on the sparse evidence available, linguists
theorized about the earlier languages that had given
rise to those attested.  In other words, based on what
they knew about a group of languages which were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documented</ENAMEX>, they tried to imagine the language that
they sprang from.  In most cases, they dealt with words
and functional elements, creating what are called reconstructions
in hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> prototypes called,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variously</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Proto</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Proto</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proto-Germanic</ENAMEX>,
Proto-Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>, and so forth, the ultimate goal
being to posit a single language called Proto-Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>.
That is not entirely true, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linguists</ENAMEX> know
too much about language to suggest that there ever
was, literally, a single language from which all Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>
languages descended.  Nonetheless, it is convenient
to think about the existence of a group of
proto-dialects which can be referred to as Proto-Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>.

            
It seems only natural that once an original language,
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ursprache</ENAMEX> , was posited, the next step was to
speculate on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urheimat</ENAMEX> .  That is what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renfrew</ENAMEX> has tried to do.  Essentially, he proposes that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> of all Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> languages was itself
born in central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anatolia</ENAMEX>, whence it spread eastward,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">westward</ENAMEX>, and northward, being modified by the influences
of the languages with which it came into contact,
till it ultimately emerged in its recognizable,
modern manifestations which we categorize into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanic</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellenic, Italic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anatolian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX>,
Celtic, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tocharian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaltoSlavic</ENAMEX>.

            I have no quarrel with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renfrew</ENAMEX>'s theory‚Äînotwithstanding
the generally received wisdom that has
placed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Sea</ENAMEX> region
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volga</ENAMEX> steppes.  It is difficult for the nonspecialist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> (like me) to assess the validity of his arguments,
which are based on his contention that the
language (and its congeners) were carried along by the
spread of nomad pastoralism.  Using the evidence available,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renfrew</ENAMEX> contends that the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indo-European</ENAMEX>
language, closely related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hittite</ENAMEX>, separated
after 6500 BC, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> languages of western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
developing from western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anatolia</ENAMEX> and those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> from the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>.
The choice between the prevailing theory and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renfrew</ENAMEX>'s
depends on whether one accepts a ‚Äúwave‚Äù theory,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> promulgated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a hundred years ago</TIMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnanes Schmidt</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> linguist, or one of
indigenous development.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pottery</ENAMEX> finds can be interpreted
to support either the imposition of an elite culture
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkmenia</ENAMEX> or a late development of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indus</ENAMEX> civilization.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renfrew</ENAMEX> accepts the wave theory,
and in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Archaeology & Language</ENAMEX>
he sets forth his arguments in its favor.  Unfortunately,
the presentation of his linguistic argument, where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is clearly treading on more speculative ground
than in those parts dealing with outright archaeology,
where he is on more familiar territory, is disorganized
and repetitious.  It is difficult to place all the blame on
Renfrew, for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> should have noticed the lack of
coherence.  The result is an argument that is persuasive
but scarely convincing.

            Nevertheless, good books on archaeology assimilable
by laymen are not easy to find, and if the reader
can tolerate its shortcomings and is not overly concerned
about the precise <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Archaelogy & Language</ENAMEX> provides an interesting march
through the millennia of prehistory in seven-league
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boots</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Urdang</ENAMEX>
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Thesaurus</ENAMEX>
            This software consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> disks, one labeled
Installation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program</ENAMEX>, the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synonym Linguibase</ENAMEX>,
and a manual.  The manual sets forth everything
with clarity, and the program is simple to install, requiring
only <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> thing made me a
little suspicious when cranking up the system: in the
descriptive text that appears on the screen, the word
labeled is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">spelt ‚Äúlabelled‚Äù‚Äîdecidedly un</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.
However, I went ahead, and, since I was typing the
text you are reading, returned to the beginning of the
paragraph to see how some of these words would fare.
I looked up the word preceding and was, after a brief
moment, asked to type in the word, which I did.  The
screen bloomed forth with the following:

            Query: preceding

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)  adj being before especially in time or arrangement

            There were also some other parts of speech: one
definition for the preposition and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> for the verb
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">participial</NUMEX>) senses.  I called up the synonyms for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adj</ENAMEX> and the following appeared:

            Synonyms:


antecedent, anterior, foregoing, former, past, precedent,
previous, prior
            

            The way the program works is this: one uses the cursor
to highlight a particular word for which synonyms are
desired.  It is similar, in principle, to finding a synonym
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">synonym dictionary</ENAMEX> and then looking up its synonyms
to find them.  I am not sure why, but I expected
the program to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúnetwork‚Äù in the same way.  However,
when I highlighted antecedent , what appeared on the
screen was the same list of synonyms but with antecedent
missing, and preceding had reappeared.  If all this
is too complicated to follow, let me summarize: you
look up word <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> and get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">synonyms A</ENAMEX>, B, C, D, E, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.</ENAMEX>  You look up the synonyms for word A, and you
get synonyms <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>, B, C, D, E, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.</ENAMEX>  Even the
definition provided for the sub-listings is identical in
wording to that of the word originally sought.
