
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niceness Principle</ENAMEX>



            This is an essay about language and false recall.
I am interested particularly in how recall distorts
to smooth things out, to alter the old, harsh
meanings into new, pleasant forms reminiscent of
Hallmark greeting cards.  I call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Niceness Principle</ENAMEX>.
Let me illustrate.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, I taught an introductory literature
course in which I assigned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.E. Cummings</ENAMEX>'s poem
‚Äúnext to of course <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">god america i.‚Äù  It</ENAMEX> is a short pastiche
and parody of jingoist sentiment, swatches
from a patriotic after-dinner speech at the local Elks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>, perhaps.  I pointed out how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cummings</ENAMEX> was
making fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-patriotism</ENAMEX> and saber-rattling,
and we discussed the split between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cummings's</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s point of view.  I got some intelligent
responses, as well as some incredulity.  Some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> could not accept that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cummings</ENAMEX> was impugning
the flag.  When it came time for the midterm,
several identified the poem as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúGod Bless</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            This is a good case in point, I think, because it
exposes how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niceness Principle</ENAMEX> works: people
find a particular meaning unpleasant, so they unconsciously
change it to something more comfortable.
They make it nice --just as nice itself has changed
from a word meaning `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">niggling</ENAMEX>' to a word meaning
`pleasant' and applied to everything from ice cream
to sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>.  Unfortunately, this is hardly just
a foible of youth; rather, it seems endemic to cultures
that have shied away from the abattoir and the
baseness of human behavior.  In certain cases, the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meanings</ENAMEX> have become so ingrained in the language
that the old ones have been totally effaced.
Here are some nasty examples:

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pandora</ENAMEX>'s box is one that
most of us recall vaguely: though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pandora</ENAMEX> was told
not to open that box, of course she did--at which
point all manner of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">evils</ENAMEX> flew out, making our world
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of pestilence, famine, death, and destruction.
The consolation for all this lay at the bottom of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">box:</ENAMEX> hope, the precious quality that would help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> through it all.  Or so I had been taught.  It
was not until I took a classics course in college that I
was told the original reading: the worst evil of all
was at the bottom--hope, which feeds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> illusions,
which renders them blind to reality, which thrives
on lies.  And, in fact, this reading is far more in keeping
with the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> temperament.  So much
for historical accuracy.

            Our culture seems to like taming the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>.
Rough edges are planed away; disturbing elements
are omitted.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato's Symposium</ENAMEX> , for example,
may recall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristophanes</ENAMEX>' absurd myth of creation:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were originally egglike creatures
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> limbs, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> faces.
They were quite powerful, and in order to nullify
any threat they might pose to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX> cut
them in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.  From then on, concludes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aristophanes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sadly roamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, looking for their lost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">halves</ENAMEX>.  When the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two halves</NUMEX> meet, they embrace,
and this is love.

            Ask any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonclassicist</ENAMEX> who has read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symposium</ENAMEX> ,
and you will get this basic recollection.  But in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristophanes</ENAMEX>' description, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> type was cloven
into male and female, the original hermaphrodites.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other types were male-male and female-female,
and they account for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> love.  This
is no coincidence, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symposium</ENAMEX> portrays homosexuality
as useful and ennobling.  How curious,
then, that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of this work happen
to forget this part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristophanes</ENAMEX>' myth.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romans</ENAMEX> provide more fodder for the Niceness
Principle through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vergil</ENAMEX>, who wrote in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eclogues</ENAMEX> ,
‚ÄúOmnia vincit amor‚Äù `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> conquers all.'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generations</ENAMEX> of romantics (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath</ENAMEX>) have interpreted this to mean that love will
triumph over war and poverty, even over strict parents
and curfews, but this is a fuzzy reading of the
military metaphor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vergil</ENAMEX> intended.  The image Vergil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pursues</ENAMEX> is that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> forced to surrender,
beaten by an all-powerful passion.  Take a normal,
clear-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vergil</ENAMEX> implies, subject
him to love, and it will transform him into a physical
wreck who cannot sleep and cannot eat because of
his obsession.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ancients</ENAMEX> had a point.

            There is an etiology behind all this.  In Freudian
terms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niceness Principle</ENAMEX> is often equivalent to
the defense mechanism of reversal, in which the individual
transforms the situation into its opposite,
usually as a retreat from unpleasant emotions.  Other
defense mechanisms, such as repression and selective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forgetting</ENAMEX>, may also take part.  The question remains:
is this simply a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foible</ENAMEX>, or have we as a
culture grown ever more fond of sanitizing and
sweeping under the carpet?  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX>'s Civilization and
Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discontents</ENAMEX> suggests an answer: as civilization
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúprogresses</ENAMEX>,‚Äù it removes itself further and further
from harshness and crude emotions.  The emotions
still exist, however, and the psychological price we
pay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repression</ENAMEX> is in neurosis and other civilized
ills.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> tradition is not the only
happy hunting ground for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Niceness Principle</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> provides a wealth of material for misinterpretation
and faulty recall, though it often requires
nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> for this to happen.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Genesis 19</ENAMEX>, for
instance, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> see Lot as a pious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> living
in the midst of the wicked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sodom</ENAMEX>.  When
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> angels come down to see him, he protects them
against the evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who wish to molest
them sexually.  Lot is thus the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, who will
allow no harm to come to anyone under his roof.
What many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> forget, or omit, or simply never
heard of, is that Lot offers a sop to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>: his
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virgin daughters</ENAMEX>.  Take them, he begs, instead of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>.  Whether this reflects the inviolable rule
of hospitality, the undeniable misogyny in the Old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Testament</ENAMEX>, or that angels have higher standing than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> is open to question.  But the question cannot
even be asked when the details are mislaid.

            This is not to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> tradition has
a monopoly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niceness</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> proverb
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúInu ga arukeba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bo ni ataru‚Äù `</ENAMEX>A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that walks
around will find a stick' illustrates this nicely.  Modern
sources translate the proverb as something like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúSeek</ENAMEX> and ye shall find,‚Äù with the stick as a bone or
reward.  The original meaning is harsher and more
in keeping with traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> culture: the
stick is used to beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, who should not have
poked around.  In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúCuriosity</ENAMEX> killed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            Fairy tales have also come in for their share of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niceness</ENAMEX>.  The folklore the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grimm Brothers</ENAMEX> unearthed
was full of beheadings and torture; the stories
were both amusements and cautionary tales.
They certainly did not all end happily ever after.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic ‚ÄúLittle Red Riding Hood</ENAMEX>,‚Äù for instance,
was told to me as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nice</ENAMEX> version: after
the wolf swallowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, he got into
bed and waited for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Red Riding Hood</ENAMEX> to come.
When he sprang out at her, she fled screaming.  A
nearby woodsman came and cut open the wolf with
a hatchet, freeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.  Not so in the
original: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWhat big teeth you have,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Red</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riding Hood</ENAMEX>.  ‚ÄúThe better to eat you with<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">,‚Äù</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX>, and gobbles her up.  End of tale.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, at a remove of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four centuries</TIMEX>, provides
a hapless hunting ground for nice misinterpretations,
either through misquotation or quoting out
of context.  A typical example is the often-repeated
‚ÄúOne touch of nature makes the whole world kin.‚Äù
The pleasant drift is nature reminding us that we are
all in this world together--but this was not what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> intended, especially in his most satirical
and pessimistic play, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troilus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cressida</ENAMEX>.  The
line itself is spoken by the wily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ulysses</ENAMEX> attempting to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuade Achilles</ENAMEX> to return to battle.  The argument
he uses is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to praise what is recent:
‚ÄúThat all with one consent praise new-born gauds‚Äù
is the line that follows, and the implication is clear--
that this is what links <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>, this tendency to focus
only on the new and conveniently forget the
past.  It may be merely a coincidence that this is
what quoters of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> are doing when they
use this line incorrectly.

            Other examples abound.  To choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from
the movies: in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Casablanca</ENAMEX>, there is the famous line,
‚ÄúPlay it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> tells the piano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to play
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ilsa</ENAMEX> remembers as their song.  Not only is the
line usually misquoted as ‚ÄúPlay it again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>,‚Äù but
the sentiment itself is misunderstood as a nostalgic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glow</ENAMEX>.  In fact, it is painful for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> to hear the music
now, and the only reason he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> to play it is for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ilsa</ENAMEX>'s sake.  An etymological analogy is useful here:
nostalgia really means the ache or pain of return, but
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of nostalgia as pleasurable recollection.

            Transmutation of tales, legends, and sayings are
not the only effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Niceness Principle</ENAMEX>.  It
sweeps words in its passage, as well.  Awesome once
meant `terrible'; now it means `great,' and terrible is
reserved to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> cuisine.  Whatever happened
to a terrible strength?  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> was also once a
frightening word.  Even bad means `good' nowadays.
It is worth noting that some good words over time
have acquired a bad reputation, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> (going
from `honest' to `dull') and criticism (moving
from `appraisal' to `denigration').  But in general we
seem to lighten up meanings rather than darken
them.

            I do not mean to sound like a hidebound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalist</ENAMEX>.
Language is a living, changing phenomenon,
and it is no use railing against shifts in meaning,
which are bound to occur.  And avoiding unpleasantness
is often a reasonable aim.  But as an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> professor
who tries to teach the spirit of literature, I
have a vested interest in accuracy.  I cannot help
lamenting what I see as distortion.  And memory is
important.  Fuzzy recall indicates a disregard for history.
Or, as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> once said, ‚ÄúThose who cannot
remember the past are condemned to misquote
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santayana</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
         
         
            
‚ÄúThat is a mute point now, of course, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holyfield</ENAMEX>'s
victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Review-Journal/Sun</ENAMEX>,
:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1C.</ENAMEX>  Submitted by ]
         
         
            
Coming in on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> and a prayer: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúOne <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> was quoted as saying the shape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was
`like a mantra ray.' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ,
.  Submitted by ]
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">English Know-how, No Problem</ENAMEX>



            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX> there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
where you can get, along with a fairly high
risk of heartburn, what must rank as the ultimate in
culinary oxymorons: a hamburger called a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mini Big</ENAMEX> .
If that sounds a trifle too indecisive, you may choose
from such offerings as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cheeseburgare</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baconburgare</ENAMEX> ,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Dream</ENAMEX> , or something called a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Clock</ENAMEX> .
All these names are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, more or less.  It appears
that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, as in the world generally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not only increasingly speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> but also
eat it.

            And they wear it.  Anyone who has traveled almost
anywhere in the world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> will have noticed that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> everywhere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sport</ENAMEX> T-shirts, sweatshirts, and warm-up jackets
bearing messages that are invariably (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) gloriously meaningless.  Recently in
Hamburg I saw a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> jacket that
stated on its back: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúFull-O-Pep Laying Mash</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  In
slightly smaller letters, it added: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúMade by Taverniti
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oats Company Chicago USA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1091DS</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Economist</ENAMEX> sighted a T-shirt
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">proclaiming: ‚</ENAMEX>ÄúO <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bourgeoisie Milk Boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Milk</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
The words, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> supposes, were chosen from an unabridged
dictionary by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX> with a stick in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beak</ENAMEX>.  What is even more alarming is that these bewilderingly
vague sentiments have begun appearing
in the English-speaking world.  In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> I saw a jacket, made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, that
announced in large letters: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúRodeo--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 per cent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Atomic Atlas</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            What do these strange messages mean?  In the
literal sense, nothing, of course.  But in a more metaphoric
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> they do rather underscore the huge, almost
compulsive appeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in the world.  It is
an odd fact that almost everywhere on the planet
products are deemed more appealing and sentiments
more powerful if they are expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>,
even if they make next to no sense.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words are everywhere.  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> speak
of die <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teenagers</ENAMEX> and das <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walkout</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
snarl ‚Äú No comment ‚Äù at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> coat their faces with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">col cream</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanians</ENAMEX> ride the trolleybus , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spaniards</ENAMEX>, when
they feel chilly, don a sueter .  Almost everyone in the
world speaks on the telephone or the telefoon or
even, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">te le fung</ENAMEX> .  And almost everywhere
you can find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> and television .

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Economist</ENAMEX> assembled a list of English
terms that had become more or less universal.
They were <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, passport, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, telephone, bar,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soda</ENAMEX>, cigarette, sport, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, tennis, stop, OK, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>,
jeans, know-how, sex appeal, and no problem .
As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Economist</ENAMEX> put it, ‚ÄúThe presence of so many
words to do with travel, consumables, and sport attests
to the real source of these exports--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            There is no denying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language,
quite apart from its utilitarian purposes, holds an
odd, almost quaint fascination for many foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>.  I have before me a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> eraser that
says, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúMr Friendly Quality Eraser</ENAMEX>.  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friendly Arrived</ENAMEX>
!!  He always stay near you, and steals in your
mind to lead you a good situation.‚Äù  It is a product
made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> solely for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, yet
there is not a word of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> on it.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> cans in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> come with the slogan, ‚ÄúI feel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> & Sound
Special,‚Äù while until recently a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> company
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cream Soda</ENAMEX> marketed a range of products
with the exquisitely inane slogan, ‚ÄúToo old to die,
too young to happy.‚Äù  Some of these products betray
a rather comforting lack of geographical precision.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> bag showing yachts on a blue sea
had the message, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúSwitzerland: Seaside City</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  Another
carried a picture of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dancing elephants</ENAMEX> above
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">legend, ‚ÄúElephant Family Are Happy With Us</ENAMEX>.
Their <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Humming Makes Us Feel Happy</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>,
there is a sporting goods <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snoopy's Dribbling</ENAMEX> ,
while just off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Place</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> you
can find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutique</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Nuts</ENAMEX> , where a sign in
the window intriguingly offers, ‚ÄúSweat, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">690 francs</NUMEX>.‚Äù
Closer inspection reveals this to be merely a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX>
truncation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> sweatshirt .

            Usually <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words are taken just as they are,
but sometimes they are adapted to local needs, often
in quite striking ways.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbo-Croatians</ENAMEX>, for instance,
picked up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word nylon , but took it
to mean a kind of shabby and disreputable variation,
so that a nylon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is a `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothel</ENAMEX>' while a nylon beach
is where nudists frolic.  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have left the
words largely intact but given the spelling a novel
twist.  Thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herkot</ENAMEX> might seem wholly
foreign to you until you realize that it is what a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> goes to his barber for.  Similarly, unless
you heard them spoken you might not recognize ajskrym,
erebeta , and kontaklinser as, respectively, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polish</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> for elevator , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish</ENAMEX>
for contact lenses .  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of this dissembling
process must surely be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sciacchenze</ENAMEX> , which
is simply a literal rendering of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> shake
hands , although the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Swahili</ENAMEX> word for a traffic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kiplefti</ENAMEX> ( keep left ) runs it a close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.

            This practice of taking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words and hacking
away at them until they emerge as something
more like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native products</ENAMEX> is particularly rampant
among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, who have borrowed no fewer
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> words--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least ten</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cent</NUMEX> of
all the words in common use there.  (It has been
said, not altogether jokingly, that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
were required to pay a license fee for every English
word they used, their trade surplus would vanish.)

            Occasionally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> stretch the borrowed
words to fit more comfortably to their pronunciation--as
with productivity , which became in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> purodakuchibichi --but for the most part
they use the same sort of ingenuity miniaturizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words as they do in miniaturizing tape recorders
and video cameras.  So word processor in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> become wa-pro, personal computer becomes
masu-komi , and commercial is unceremoniously
shorn of its troublesome consonant clusters and
shrunk to a terse monosyllable: cm.  No-pan , short
for no-panties , is a description for bottomless waitresses,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> words touch and game have
been fused to make tatchi geimu , a euphemism for
sexual petting.

            Sometimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words are given not only
new spellings but also entirely new meanings.  In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last century</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>, for reasons that no one
now seems quite sure of, took the name of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vauxhall</ENAMEX>, and made it their generic
word for all railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>: vagzal .  In much the
same way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Japanese</ENAMEX> word for a fashionable cut
suit, sebiro , is a corruption of Savile Row .  More recently,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> borrowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> slang
words jerk and egghead but gave them largely contrary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meanings</ENAMEX>--namely, an egghead in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brainy person</ENAMEX> but a dimwit, while jerk is a term
of praise for an accomplished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX>--though at
least they respect the spellings.

            Occasionally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> of English words use
them to create new words.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> have lately
appropriated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> , respelled it
manshon , and used it to signify not a large single
dwelling but a high-rise apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.  But because
the syllable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> also means `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten thousand</NUMEX>' in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, they have coined a further word, okushon ,
based on their word for `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred million</NUMEX>' oku ,
because that implies greater luxury still.

            This practice of adopting an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word and
then using it as the basis for forming other words
quite unknown in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is more common than you
might expect.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, in particular, are adept
at taking things a step further than ever occurred to
anyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> goes
from being in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> to being in his twens , a book
that doesn't quite become a bestseller is instead ein
steadyseller , and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who is more relaxed than
another is relaxter .

            A final curiosity of borrowing is that the words
sometimes lose their emotional charge when conveyed
overseas.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>, most notably, have
adopted an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> expletive too coarse to reproduce
here (though if I say, ‚Äúhits the fan‚Äù I expect
you'll be with me), but they use it as a mild and
largely meaningless epithet, roughly equivalent to
our gosh or golly or even just hmmmm --to such an
extent, I am told that they must now take special
care not to startle English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.  Oddly
enough, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX> we did much the same thing
with a rude <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> term, pappekak , which we anglicized
into the anodyne poppycock .

            Of course, not all these borrowings are free of
charge.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language has become a very big
business indeed.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Globally</ENAMEX>, the teaching of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is
worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬•6 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> alone it is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>
largest source of invisible earnings, worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬•500 million</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are naturally better at mastering
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> than others.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> were issued with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> phrase-book that included such
memorable phrases as this instruction to a waiter:
‚ÄúPlease give me curds, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sower cream</ENAMEX>, fried chicks,
pulled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> jellyfish.‚Äù  When shopping,
the well-versed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emissary</ENAMEX> was told to order ‚Äúa
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>' worsted-nylon swimming pants.‚Äù

            If there is one thing we should be worried about
in the English-speaking world it is not that we are
doing poorly at learning other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s languages--
though that is worrisome enough--but that we increasingly
pay so little attention to the competent
use of our own.  Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randolph Quirk</ENAMEX> put it succinctly
when he wrote, ‚ÄúIt would be ironic indeed if the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
who are diligently learning the language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX> took more care in their use of English
and showed more pride in their achievement
than those for whom it is the native tongue.‚Äù

            We might sometimes wonder if we are the most
responsible custodians of our own tongue, when we
reflect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University Press</ENAMEX> sells as many
copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> as it
does in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> more than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethnic Slurs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Avoidance Thereof</ENAMEX>



            Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cavett</ENAMEX> had his talk
show on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, I heard him interview <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alfred</ENAMEX>
Kazin on his program.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kazin</ENAMEX> had just had published
an autobiography titled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> , and was probably
on television to plug the book, apropos of
which he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavett</ENAMEX> had more or less this to say:


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Why did you call the book `<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>'?  I
mean, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might consider that title...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>, a little provocative.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.K.</ENAMEX>, smiling, amused: Well, the title pretty well
sums me up.  I happen to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> who has identified
himself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> intellectual environment.

            

            To my mind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cavett</ENAMEX>'s question remained
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intriguing</ENAMEX>, not so much because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kazin</ENAMEX> failed to answer
it fully as because I wondered why the question
had occurred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavett</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.  Indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> does somehow seem to have an
almost hostile overtone.  Why?  Are we so imbued
with anti-Semitism or hypersensitivity to it that any
direct reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, particularly culturally intensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, touches a raw nerve?  Some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after the interview I asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> emeritus of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> who was originally
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (albeit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>),
what he thought about the matter.  He replied something
like this: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúHmm</ENAMEX>, well, yes, but isn't it a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blunt</ENAMEX>, a little hostile to call anyone by a bare ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noun</ENAMEX>?  Suppose we saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> we knew walking
toward us.  And then what if one of us said to the
other, `Here comes that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>.'  There's a nuance
of put-down, almost hostility there.  If we liked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> and had nothing against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> generally,
we'd probably say something like `Say, here comes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>... that young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>...
that old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> gentleman.' ‚Äù

            I have tested my professorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s observation
in a number of real and imagined situations involving
several ethnic or national categories and
have found it to be correct.  The unmodified noun
for an ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or nationality does imply a certain
hostility or contempt or, especially on the lips of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, a nuance of defiance, as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kazin</ENAMEX>'s case.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prouder</ENAMEX> or more arrogant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
apt to fling the bare noun at you, almost as if to add,
‚ÄúAnd you'd better believe it!‚Äù  A snooty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit</ENAMEX> may
staunchly declare,  ‚ÄúI am an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>,‚Äù where a
more modest denizen of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> would be more
likely say, ‚ÄúI'm <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>,‚Äù employing the adjective
rather than the noun.  There seems to be a kind of
semantic quality that makes adjectives softer and
gentler than nouns and makes of them softening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.

            In some cases the adjectives and nouns for ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are formally identical, as for example
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> .  But to soften the ethnic
term in such cases it can still be used adjectivally, as
in the example already given or in: <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúA Russian</ENAMEX> guy
once told me...‚Äù  Perhaps particularly where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noun</ENAMEX> and adjective are identical in form, if not function,
colloquially a blunt noun is invented, such as
Dutchman for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n.</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russky for Russian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n.</ENAMEX>),
Jap for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinaman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n.</ENAMEX>).  Conversely,
plain nouns for ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or nationalities
are sometimes replaced with adjectivally softened
terms like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colored Folks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX> , or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> .

            If adjectives soften ethnic terms, nouns can
harden them.  This function can be demonstrated by
comparing the noun <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> with the adjective <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> in
context.  When someone says, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">‚ÄúThat Jew</ENAMEX> business is
new here,‚Äù he isn't saying quite the same thing as
‚ÄúThat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> business is new here.‚Äù  Because of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abomination</ENAMEX> and shame of anti-Semitism, you tend
to respond more sensitively to language reflecting
attitudes toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, which is why jew down is
both derogatory and offensive while gyp or welch on
are relatively innocuous.  But the hardening effect of
plain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nouns</ENAMEX> can be detected with regard to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peoples</ENAMEX>.  ‚ÄúThat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swede</ENAMEX> church‚Äù isn't quite the same
as ‚ÄúThat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            The ethnic terms that seem bluntest or most indelicate
are sometimes simply what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call
themselves.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinaman</ENAMEX> is nothing but a calque of
zhongguo ren , morpheme for morpheme <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chinaman</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polak</ENAMEX> is simply Pole in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>.  And sometimes
ironically or defiantly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will call themselves by
names intended to be pejorative or downright insulting,
as when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX> call each other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nigger</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Odessa</ENAMEX> call one of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk heroes</ENAMEX>
Poltorazhida `Yid-and-a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.'

            When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> has been dealt with shamefully,
there is reason to dissociate it from its former identity
by giving it a new name.  The niggers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">darkies</ENAMEX> (where again the primarily adjectival word is
the less offensive) of slavery became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX> and
Coloreds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crow</ENAMEX> and are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African Americans</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX>, of course, are usually no
more black than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> are white.  The misnomer
must be acceptable because the parallelism implies
equality between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> so designated by adjectives
of color.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Newcomers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">American Southwest</ENAMEX> where
there is a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin Americans</ENAMEX> often
ask, ‚ÄúWhat do you call these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?‚Äù  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> ,
though currently the best answer, isn't entirely satisfactory
because the term lumps together <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
are about as alike as, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tahitians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haitians</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, before a sizable emigration from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> the Spanish-speaking
element of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> carelessly called
itself mexicano , as some of the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hispanics</ENAMEX> still
do, though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> had not been part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a century</TIMEX> and then for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about a</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter of a century</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Spain</ENAMEX> became the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>.  Anglos usually referred to the
Spanish-speaking element as native or, again in a
kind of leveling parallelism, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> , never as
Spaniards , on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, probably unconscious, of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> , short for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> who
prefer to emphasize cultural ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">la Republica Azteca</ENAMEX>, as most in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
definitely do not, may prefer to go by the name of
Chicano , which implies political as much as national
or ethnic identity.

            There are nationalities and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> so
confident, so satisfied with themselves that ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epithets</ENAMEX> either bounce off them like pebbles off an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> or are adopted as amusing or even ornamental.
What do you call an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
to insult him?  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aussie</ENAMEX> have been tried but
to no avail.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP</ENAMEX> started off with a pejorative nuance,
it seems to me, but has been accepted so
smugly by white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> that the
term has been appropriated by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it
doesn't fit, for instance <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> descent who may be agnostics of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> background.
Where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gringo</ENAMEX> , they
tend to be more amused than offended by the epithet.

            Then there are peoples too alien or exotic to the
mainstream of the dominant culture to have
prompted an attitude expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> seem to fall into this category.  One
says indifferently, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúHe's Navaho,‚Äù or ‚ÄúHe</ENAMEX>'s a
Navaho‚Äù as most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not say indifferently,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúHe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>,‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúHe's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>,‚Äù though in the case
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> the noun seems somehow more natural
and no less friendly.  This indifference does not,
however, extend to particular kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>.
Squaw, papoose , and maybe even brave are no
longer used, except <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">humorously</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smile</ENAMEX> when you
say that!) or, again, defiantly.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' basketball
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team of the Indian School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> call themselves
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lady Braves</ENAMEX>.  There is likely a touch of humor here.
In my experience the most endearing characteristic
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indians</ENAMEX> generally is their keen sense of
humor.

            When it comes to sensitivity to ethnic or national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">designations</ENAMEX>, the bulk of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seem to
be indifferent to nuance.  We as soon say, ‚ÄúI'm an
American‚Äù as ‚ÄúI'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">American‚</ENAMEX>Äù or jauntily ‚ÄúI'm a
gringo‚Äù or proudly ‚ÄúI'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yank</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  Are we made impervious
by a shell of arrogance, numb by self-satisfaction,
or tolerant by the wild ethnic diversity in
which most of us live?
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> suit was filed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
said it was unfair and illegal to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in skirts into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florentine Gardens</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX> for free on certain
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> while forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> without skirts to pay
a cover charge.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , :B-2.  Submitted by 
and by several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.]
         
         
            You Say Tomato...



            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> rang to say that she had just
got back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Majorca</ENAMEX>, only she didn't say
Majorca, she said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúMEEYORCA</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  I asked her how
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MADGE-ORCA</ENAMEX> was, and she said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEEYORCA</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lovely</ENAMEX>, and so the conversation went on.  Neither of
us mentioned the discrepancy in pronunciation, but
equally neither of us would budge from what we
knew to be right.  In an open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, I would have
explained that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-aunt</ENAMEX> lived there for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and never stopped calling it MADGE-ORCA, and
even if I gave up calling it MADGE-ORCA I would instead
call it MALLYORCA, and not the odd in-betweeny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEEYORCA</ENAMEX>.  But our conversation never
reached the open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, so she must have replaced
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receiver</ENAMEX> thinking me hopelessly ignorant.

            Pronunciation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> makes fools of us all.  One
only has to listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPs</ENAMEX>, particularly on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">benches</ENAMEX>, to note what a squidgy state it is in.
Recently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Waddington</ENAMEX> pronounced a particularly
grim terrorist act ‚ÄúD'STAARDLY.‚Äù  I had imagined
the pronunciation of dastardly was restricted to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> choices: either a long or else a sharp first <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX> .  Yet
here was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> offering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>.

            Such oddities emanate largely from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tories</ENAMEX> who
are midway through performing their own plastic
surgery on their vowel sounds.  I always felt sorry for
Cecil <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson</ENAMEX> when he was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade and Industry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúinDUStry‚Äù</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúDUS‚Äù rhyming</ENAMEX> with
bus --was one of the few words that gave him away.
Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>, too, pronounces various words in an
idiosyncratic manner.  ‚ÄúM-gnificent‚Äù she says, perhaps
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-compensating for fears that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúa‚Äù</ENAMEX> will
be too northern by removing it entirely.

            Things were not always so.  A regional accent
has only recently come to be seen as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> to advancement
in politics.  Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX> in history
to whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> ascribe smart southern accents
were in fact proudly northern.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">memoirist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monckton Milnes</ENAMEX> recalled a dinner at which Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladstone</ENAMEX> sat in the place of honor.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gladstone</ENAMEX> liked
to chew everything thirty-two times, so he spent the
meal largely in silence.  At last, he seemed ready to
say something, and his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> leant forward in
anticipation.  Picking up a nut, he said, ‚ÄúIt is many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> since I ate a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> NOT or indeed a NOT of
any kind.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Similarly</ENAMEX>, the posh long ‚Äúa‚Äù in <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> (and
indeed class ) was originally an affectation by courtiers
in imitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George IV</ENAMEX>: until then everyone in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> had pronounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to rhyme with lass .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, the shifting sands of pronunciation
claim many a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>.  As a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, I was brought up
to say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> with a long ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Äúa‚Äù--‚ÄúMAARSS‚Äù</ENAMEX>--but I have
recently been finding myself in such a minority that
I am at present attempting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddingtonian</ENAMEX> transition
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">towards Mass</ENAMEX> with a short <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">‚Äúa</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  At the moment,
I am stranded awkwardly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, and I'm sorely
tempted to struggle back to my original point of embarkation.

            There is a successful pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ballad</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúLady</ENAMEX> in
Red‚Äù that worries me every time I hear it because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Burgh</ENAMEX>, has to struggle through
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> lines ending with the words chance, dance , and
romance .  As far as I can recall, he pronounces
chance with a sharp ‚Äúa,‚Äù and dance with a long ‚Äúa,‚Äù
and then he finds himself in the disastrous position
of having to pronounce romance with a long ‚Äúa,‚Äù too.
These are troubled times.

            Those at the top of society have not helped matters
by their tendency to inverted snobbery.  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúEETHER</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward VIII</ENAMEX> used to
irritate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George V</ENAMEX>, by pronouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúLIDY‚Äù</ENAMEX> (to rhyme with tidy ), and when he became
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windsor</ENAMEX> he further upset everyone by following
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s pronunciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúDOOK</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week or two ago</TIMEX>, I heard Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrington</ENAMEX>
pronounce graph as ‚ÄúGRAFF,‚Äù with a sharp ‚Äúa.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  Presumably</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Carrington</ENAMEX> knows what he's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to</NUMEX>, but
let us hope that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddington</ENAMEX> did not hear him.
Having spent most of his working life trying to graduate
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúGRAFF‚Äù to ‚ÄúGRAFF,‚</ENAMEX>Äù it would be awful if
he now had to make the arduous journey back to
square <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feminist Critique of Language</ENAMEX>
            This is the book that gives you chapter and
verse to refute all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linguistic reactionaries</ENAMEX> who
cannot see why there is all that fuss about using he
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to mean a `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of either sex.' The debates
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Cameron</ENAMEX> illustrates are fundamental
to everyone's use of language whether they
be female or male--how it is used, how it is perceived
and received by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexes</ENAMEX>, how it can on the one hand bolster and on the
other break down attitudes and prejudices, and how
it can create new awarenesses.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feminist Critique</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language</ENAMEX> brings together
a wide range of views and approaches to its
subject, ranging from the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linguist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jespersen</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Woolf</ENAMEX> writing in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1920s</NUMEX> to contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the main
strengths of the collection is that it does not just put
forward <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> view, it maps out the debate allowing
different views to be stated and then criticized or
revised.  The eighteen essays and extracts and the
perceptive introduction reveal the range and depth
of the debate about feminism and language.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> divides the book into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, ‚ÄúSpeech and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence,‚Äù</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolf</ENAMEX> as
its starting point and includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cora Kaplan</ENAMEX> on ‚ÄúLanguage
and gender‚Äù as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> extracts
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Annie Leclerc on ‚ÄúWoman</ENAMEX>'s word‚Äù and an interview
with the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> Luce
Irigary entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúWoman</ENAMEX>'s exile.‚Äù  These essays explore
the notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúsilence‚Äù</ENAMEX> and the utopian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quest</ENAMEX> for a specifically female voice in culture.
Much of the real meat of the book comes in Part
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äú `Naming' and Representation</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Dale</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spender</ENAMEX>'s quasi-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Worfian</ENAMEX> views on ‚Äúman made language,‚Äù
published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, are counterbalanced by
the perceptive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spender</ENAMEX>'s book by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalind Coward</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muriel R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> essay on the semantic derogation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> leads into a discussion of compiling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">a Feminist</ENAMEX>
Dictionary against the grain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' view
in predominantly male lexicography.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the main strengths of this collection is
that it makes available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of literature
for instance--material which would otherwise
have been extremely difficult to get hold of.
This applies in particular to essays such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Bodine</ENAMEX>'s
on ‚ÄúAndrocentrism in prescriptive grammar:
singular `they,' sex-indefinite `he,' and `he or she.' ‚Äù
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, this dryly written paper
provides much of the analytical information needed
to counter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stereotypical ‚Äúhysterical fuss‚</ENAMEX>Äù reaction.
Bodine analyzes the ways in which (male)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grammarians</ENAMEX> (both descriptive and prescriptive)
have since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventeenth century</TIMEX> sought to establish
he as the sex-indefinite pronoun despite evidence
that actual usage consistently contradicts that.
It is a pity that the most recent material in the collection
appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1980s</TIMEX>.  In answer to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Bodine</ENAMEX>'s point, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Longman Dictionary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins Cobuild</ENAMEX>
Dictionary use they and their as the non-gender-specific
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pronoun/adjective</ENAMEX> (which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> probably
noted also in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph of this review).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critique</ENAMEX> has an amusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">slant</ENAMEX>, too.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the most telling and effective expos√©s of the entrenched
nature of sexism in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hofstaedter</ENAMEX>'s pseudonymous parody ‚ÄúA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> paper
on purity in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>,‚Äù written as a supposed
debunking of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúsilly prattle‚Äù</ENAMEX> about racist language.
He uses white and black in the place of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in examples such as chairwhite, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frenchwhite</ENAMEX>,
whitepower, whitehandle, oneupwhiteship , and so on.
Through such strategies and telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adaptations</ENAMEX> of
quotations like ‚ÄúAll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> are created equal,<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù ‚ÄúOne</ENAMEX>
small step for a white, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> giant step for whitekind‚Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hofstaedter</ENAMEX>'s short piece becomes a cutting revelation
of just how deep-seated are not only sexist but
racial prejudices in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>.

            The final part of the book, ‚ÄúDominance and Difference
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Linguistic Behaviour,‚Äù</ENAMEX> examines
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> actually use language, tackling
such areas as gossip, ‚Äútag‚Äù questions, and conversational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gambits</ENAMEX>.  I found this the least satisfactory section
in that the necessarily short extracts could not
provide sufficient detail.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> deliberately excludes some of the
more familiar work which is available elsewhere.  So
this collection contains texts that are more marginal
than would he ideal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who may read nothing
else on the subject.  It also means that some important
names, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Kristeva</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toril Moi</ENAMEX>,
are omitted.  Her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thematic structure</ENAMEX> also slightly defuses
the impact of the debate.  By beginning with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Woolf</ENAMEX> instead of some of the more linguistically
oriented material (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodine, Lakoff</ENAMEX>, and so on),
she does not immediately establish the ground to be
broken.  A chronological structure would have directly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juxtaposed Jespersen</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX> and then enabled
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to find a way through the developments
in the debate, giving a more coherent picture
of the broadening issues.

            A stimulating and entertaining collection, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feminist Critique of Language</ENAMEX> acknowledges and reflects
the range of the debates about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and language,
not only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>.  It should
be included in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> reading lists, but it also deserves
to be prescribed reading for those who feel
themselves to be concerned with language--across
the spectrum from the (hopefully diminishing) ranks
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">‚Äúhysterical fuss‚Äù brigade</ENAMEX> to already committed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Rooney</ENAMEX>

         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bloomsbury Dictionary of Dedications</ENAMEX>
            There are those who collect all sorts of collectables,
including, apparently, dedications.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian</ENAMEX>
Room, a well-known and proficient lexicographer
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">compiler</ENAMEX> of all sorts of collectables has produced
a book that some might find enormously
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entertaining</ENAMEX>, or useful, or both, but which I find
somewhat tedious.  I find nothing interesting, entertaining,
or useful about any of the following, which
are fairly typical of the fare:


To <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love and Courage.--Margot Fonteyn, Autobiography</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>.

To the unsinkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolly</ENAMEX>, who has a big brain
under that big yellow wig, and a big heart under
that big chest, this book is respectfully dedicated.--Leonore
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleischer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dolly</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>.

I dedicate this book to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>
Storr, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Before I Go...</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>.

To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, without whose constant encouragement
and advice this book would have been finished
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the time.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Payton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payton</ENAMEX>'s
Proper Names, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>.

Dedicated to those who gaze out of windows
when they should be paying attention.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
McGough, In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classroom</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>.

            

            These seem to me neither funny nor clever, but
there are so many of the type that I get the feeling
that I may be the odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> out, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the
world who finds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hardy</ENAMEX> excruciatingly boring:
I have a sneaking suspicion that there are many
like me but they are too embarrassed to admit it.

            I have had a book dedicated to me by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.
I haven't looked, but I would guess that it just says
something like ‚ÄúFor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which seems just right.
There are some interesting older dedications, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavelli</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>-line toadying exordium to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Magnificent</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> .  (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Italian</TIMEX> it probably
ran longer.)  But not all of the oldies are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Spenser</ENAMEX>'s dedications of his (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>) books
vary from one-liners to some very sleepy sycophancies
many times that length.  It must be remembered
that many successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of yore were supported
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX>, and praising a wealthy and powerful individual
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> before democracy became popular
was simply a matter of expediency.  Besides,
only the worst ingrate would fail to acknowledge to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">largesse</ENAMEX> provided.  Today, when commercial considerations
put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> into the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX>--despite
the fact that advances are repayable,
risks are taken--acknowledgment of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s (artistic)
contribution may be relegated to the closing
lines of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s foreword, which often grudgingly
suggests that the work was produced in spite of
rather than because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> cited.  But such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acknowledgments</ENAMEX> do not qualify as dedications in
the sense generally understood and in the book at
hand in particular.

            Occasionally, the identity of a dedicatee has remained
a mystery for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, with speculation bandied
back and forth endlessly in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queries</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evidently</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bram Stoker's</ENAMEX> dedication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>) was such a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>:


To my dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hommy-Beg</ENAMEX>.

            

            Had I ever noticed that, I cannot say that it
would have kept me awake <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> wondering and
worrying who Hommy-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beg</ENAMEX> might be: I would assume
it was a nickname for someone close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stoker</ENAMEX>,
possibly a private nickname known only to the two
of them, and I would have continued to nod off.  It
turns out to have been Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Henry Hall</ENAMEX>
Caine, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>; although the significance of
that revelation eludes me completely, it might well
have won some bookworm a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>.

            Dedication-collecting may be like stamp-collecting
(which I never understood, either).  If one
likes this sort of thing, there is no keeping him
down, I suppose, and if one must have a collection of
dedications, I suppose it ought to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Room</ENAMEX>'s.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Urdang</ENAMEX>

         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bloomsbury Dictionary of First Names</ENAMEX>
            This is a well-written, though fairly standard alphabetically
arranged reference book on given, or
first, or, as they like to call them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, regardless
of the religion of their possessors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
names.  It seems to be the product of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s
decision that such a book should be on every well-rounded
reference list, but as a work viewed in the
larger context of onomasiology, it breaks no new
ground as far as I can tell and offers nothing not already
covered by the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie A.  Dunkling</ENAMEX>
(for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>).  Which is to say that if you already have a
fairly comprehensive dictionary of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names--this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> claims <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX> ‚Äúnames defined‚Äù--you do not need
this one; on the other hand, if you have none and
want a good one, this one is likely to be as good as
the best and better than most.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Urdang</ENAMEX>

         
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of SurnamesA Dictionary of First Names</ENAMEX>
            Both of these books will find a place on the
shelves of any good reference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>.  They contain
a great deal of information that has been intelligently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collated</ENAMEX>.  The surname dictionary, in particular,
becomes the best available work on the subject;
the chief value of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name dictionary, for me,
lies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplements</ENAMEX>, which deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>
names (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Baker</ENAMEX>) and with the given names of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Subcontinent</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramesh Krishnamurthy</ENAMEX>).

            The awkward fact about the surname dictionary
is that a great many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will consult it in vain for
information about their own names.  It contains entries,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Introduction</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúfor most major surnames
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> origin, as well as for many rarer
ones.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù  ‚ÄúMajor‚Äù</ENAMEX> in this context means names like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> , frequently found in any telephone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directory</ENAMEX>.  Such names must of course be included,
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most anxious to discover something
about the original meaning of their surnames
are invariably those who bear the rarer names.  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> say that if they came across reliable information
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> rarer names, they wrote entries.  In other
words, if someone else had done the research in
what appeared to be a scholarly way, they took advantage
of it.  That seems to me to be a sensible approach,
since the only way properly to investigate a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surname</ENAMEX> is to go back through the male line as far as
possible, noting the various spellings of the name,
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was living in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past centuries</TIMEX>, and so
on.  Being asked to make a judgment about a surname
merely on the basis of its modern spelling is
rather like being asked to give the meaning of a
word such as pain without being told whether the
word is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and without knowing
whether the word should really be spelled pane .

            I have been using the surname dictionary regularly
and usually feel satisfied with the information
presented; but there are criticisms to be made.  Recently,
for instance, I was wondering about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boffin</ENAMEX> , a
name that obviously appealed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Dickens</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodges</ENAMEX> say that it is an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> name of
unknown origin but hint that it may be an anglicization
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh Baughan</ENAMEX> (found also as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vaughan</ENAMEX> ), a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diminutive of Baugh</ENAMEX> , ultimately from bach `little.'  A
general comment on the treatment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> ch
sound in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> would have been useful, but I personally
accept that theory.  I wonder, though, why
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baughan</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vaughan</ENAMEX> ) entries do not mention
that bach was an epithet that distinguished a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Welsh</ENAMEX> equivalent of junior .  I also
have my doubts about how ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of this dictionary
will cope with its metalanguage.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linguistic</ENAMEX>
boffins have no problems with a statement like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúdim</ENAMEX>.
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAUGH</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX> bychan , hypocoristic form of bach
little.‚Äù  But try that on an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
public, the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who will presumably consult
this book in a library, and add in for good measure
the last line of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baughan</ENAMEX> entry which reads:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúCogn.</ENAMEX> (of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corn</ENAMEX>.: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BEAN</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Acting</ENAMEX> on that last
hint, I looked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bean</ENAMEX> entry.  I found suggestions
that it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmetonymic occupational</ENAMEX> name,‚Äù an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
nickname or an anglicized form of a Gaelic personal
name meaning `life.'  There was no cross reference
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baughan</ENAMEX> , however, nor a mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX>
byhan/vyhan `little.'

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genealogical</ENAMEX> information is occasionally added
to the surname entries, but only when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
concerned are ‚Äúimportant‚Äù according to a very traditional
definition of that word.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> well-known
in the entertainment world, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie</ENAMEX>
Vaughan, are definitely not mentioned.  Under the
entry for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> , therefore, we are given notes on
the noble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of that name, along with the possible
derivations of the surname.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúnoble‚Äù</ENAMEX> theme
is continued in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name dictionary.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX>
are there told that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> represents ‚Äútransferred
use of the surname of an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            Entries like that for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> Names hardly encourage me to take the main
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of the book seriously.  The absence of hard
statistical evidence about the use of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names in
the English-speaking world is also very worrying.
Such evidence is vital for many reasons.  It enables
sensible decisions to be made about which names
should be included in a work of this kind.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodges</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hrothgar</ENAMEX> , for instance, because it
occurs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beowulf</ENAMEX> and was borne by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-chancellor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>.  I
do not consider that a sensible inclusion, especially
when they choose to ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX> , which has been
regularly if infrequently used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1860s</TIMEX>.

            Statistical evidence also indicates the reason for
a name's use.  It is absurd to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> has
been used in modern times because it is the surname
of an aristocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.  The popular use of
the name in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s</TIMEX> must have been in
honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Otis Howard</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1830-1909</TIMEX>), since
the surnames of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> were often used in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">baptism</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bearers</ENAMEX> of the name, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Hughes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Keel</ENAMEX> , later made the
name well known to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> and
Hodges totally ignore such <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> influence,
though the evidence for it is overwhelming.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' respective treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> as
a surname and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name is perhaps
symbolic of the different qualities of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dictionaries.
Surname interpretation mainly requires
good philological skills, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodges</ENAMEX>
supply.  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> names call for a frequent delving into
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of nonacademic, popular culture and recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> history, as well as a certain amount of linguistic
judgment.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names needs an
enthusiastic and genuine interest in the behavior of
ordinary human beings.  Whatever else is in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of First Names</ENAMEX> , it lacks that basic
enthusiasm.  It is much the poorer for it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Dunkling</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames Ditton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Surrey</ENAMEX>
         
         



            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postscripts</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThe Scandalous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau‚</ENAMEX>Äù

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> published an entire column
under the title ‚ÄúCounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Mistakes‚</ENAMEX>Äù (‚ÄúOn
Language,‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 15</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>) in which he enumerated a number of errors in
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> instructional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> and in
the census form itself.  He found misplacement
problems, mistakes in parallel structures, improper
use of commas, wrong or missing prepositions, incorrect
use of reflexive verbs, etc.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThe Census Bureau</ENAMEX>,‚Äù
he wrote, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhas</ENAMEX> had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 long years</TIMEX> to get its
forms straight.‚Äù  And all this about its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> !

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoysef Mlotek</ENAMEX>, Cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the fraternal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workmen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>
(‚Äú der arbeter ring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚Äù</ENAMEX>), published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yiddish</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forverts</ENAMEX> a sharp attack on the outrageous
illiteracy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> translation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau Guide</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20, 1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 16</ENAMEX>).  In a letter
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> he asked ‚Äúwhether other foreign
language translations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> were similarly
entrusted in such incompetent hands.‚Äù

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.  I sent a copy of my article [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>] to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>.  After a delay of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> I received a reply from Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan A. Stephenson</ENAMEX>,
Assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outreach and Program</ENAMEX>
Information, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decennial Planning Division</ENAMEX>.  He
wrote:


... To find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> to translate Assistance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guides</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> languages, we required the foreign
language expertise to be at least at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 3/3</TIMEX> level
as rated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Service Institute</ENAMEX> or a recognized
equivalent.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communication Technical</ENAMEX>
Applications, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> [which no longer exists] provided
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX>... a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">native Yiddish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> with expertise rated at the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5/5</NUMEX> level.


            

            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephenson</ENAMEX> further apologized for any inadvertent
offense that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> translation may have
caused, assured me that ‚Äúin light of your comments‚Äù
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> will no longer be distributed--an empty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurance</ENAMEX> since the count is over--and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>
will be interested in my views about materials
prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> may seriously question his characterization
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> as a ‚Äúnative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yiddish speaker‚Äù</ENAMEX> (see below).  Besides, it is axiomatic
that there is a basic difference between spoken
language and written language, and it is highly fallacious
to assume that a native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, even with a
fluent command of his language, can ipso facto intelligently
write in it, let alone translate from or into it.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.  I spoke twice on the telephone with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">translator of the Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> .  He was born in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and received his education in public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.  In his childhood a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> would
come to his home for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> a week.  He
never went to a secular <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
was taught as a basic subject and where other
subjects as well were taught in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>.  I had
guessed correctly that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>,
and that that was the main source of his knowledge
of the language.  In the course of our lengthy telephone
conversations I could not detect a sense of
informed literacy about <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> as a language.  It
also became clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> was
not standard <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>.  He never wrote or published
anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>, and he seemed to have used as
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">aids</ENAMEX> in translating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide Alexander Harkavy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yiddish-English Dictionary and Uriel Weinreich</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Modern English-Yiddish Yiddish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">English Dictionary</ENAMEX> .
Needless to say, translation by dictionary is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crudest</ENAMEX> and, if one may say, the cruelest form of
translation.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Samuel</ENAMEX> introduced to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-reading
public, in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The World</ENAMEX> of Sholem
Aleichem , the quintessential <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>-speaking
Tevye, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dairyman</ENAMEX> who addresses himself even to
God in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>.  (He is the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical ‚ÄúFiddler</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>)  And in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX>
Praise of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. xiii</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX> wrote about the
presumed absence of any rules in the language:


It is gratuitously assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> ... can
dispense with strict forms and usages, that part of
its appeal is supposed to lie in a happy-go-lucky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grammatical</ENAMEX> and syntactical laxity which makes
error impossible and everyone knowledgeable.
Nothing could be further from the truth.  [italics
added]


            

         
         


            In connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zellig Bach</ENAMEX>'s article,
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúThe Scandalous Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau‚</ENAMEX>Äù
[XVII<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,2</NUMEX>], I thought your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> might like to
know that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid December of 1990</TIMEX> I received a call
from an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> asking me
whether I concurred with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>'s negative comments
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> .  Having seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> ,
I replied that I indeed agreed fully with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX>.  I explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> was riddled
with atrocious spelling, syntactic, and semantic errors.
Though printed in the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>/
Hebrew alphabet, most of the words were misspelled,
as though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> had never seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>; the syntax was garbled almost beyond
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX>; the lexical content made little
sense.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> informed me that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> had been approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>
Technical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applications, Inc.</ENAMEX>, a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>,
whose word on the expertise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> tacitly accepted.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> admitted
that at least in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> had erred in relying on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>.  He
added that in the light of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>'s and my comments
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúwe</ENAMEX> will no longer distribute this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> .‚Äù  In
a subsequent letter he added that ‚Äúwe will keep ...
your name on file for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> census.  If we
prepare materials in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish language</ENAMEX>, we would
be interested in your comments.‚Äù

            I hope to live to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> to help with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> .  I am sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> will still be
around, surviving its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>, as it has for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.





         
         


            I must take issue with both of the BIBIOGRAPHIA
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan S. Kaye</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>].  In his review of Words
That <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make a Difference</ENAMEX> , he praises a sentence from
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> describing the miscellaneous
junk in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúeclectic bounty</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  If these items
were in a collection that I put in my front yard, eclectic
might be the word; but what is missing from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX>'s variety is the element of choice: eclectic
come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> legein `to choose or pick.'

            In the same piece, he traces savvy to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX>,
which might be correct, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mencken</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Language derives it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sabe</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX>'s nuance word is, at a guess, a suggestion from a
word-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processor</ENAMEX>'s spelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">checker</ENAMEX> which was derailed
by nonce word .

            His review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reverse Dictionary</ENAMEX> indicates
that he (and whoever revised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s book)
are behind the times on <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> weight classes: featherweight
should precede lightweight , [and other principal
divisions have been ignored].





         
         


            Is monotheism an inadequate word to describe
basic beliefs set forth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX>?  Recently,
while browsing through the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>, I
came across the word henotheism , defined as ‚Äúthe
worship of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gods</ENAMEX>, in contrast with
monotheism, which teaches that only one god exists.‚Äù
If many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the covenant believed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jehovah</ENAMEX> was the supreme god among
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">lesser gods</ENAMEX>, were they henotheists, rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monotheists</ENAMEX>?  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible Dictionary</ENAMEX> suggests,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúEven Moses</ENAMEX>, whom we may regard as the founder
of the religion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, was more probably a henotheist
than a monotheist.‚Äù

            The distinction is a neat and illuminating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.  I
wonder why henotheism is not as common a philosophical
designation as monotheism.  It seems to be
a way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> between polytheism and monotheism,
a useful concept that provides a missing link in the
evolutionary process.

            The root hen `one' is found in hendiadys , a rhetorical
figure labeling expressions like nice and
warm , instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúnicely</ENAMEX> warm.‚Äù  It is also found in
hendecasyllable, hendecagon , and hendecahedron .





         
         


            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Horowitz</ENAMEX> wrote about a mistranslation of
a word in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> which was ostensibly responsible
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s putting horns on his sculpture of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XVI,2</NUMEX>].  Another mistranslation which has
probably had a much greater influence on the Western
world is that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX> word almah , which
means `young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>' but was translated as `virgin.'
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaiah</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:14</TIMEX> reads ‚ÄúTherefore
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> himself shall give you a sign; Behold a
virgin shall conceive, and bear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>....<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Matthew</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:22-23</TIMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Testament</ENAMEX>, describes the birth
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, referring it back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaish</ENAMEX>, saying, ‚ÄúNow all
spoken of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> by the prophet, saying, Behold
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>....‚Äù

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX> word for virgin is bethulah , which
would have been used in the original had the young
woman been a virgin.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New English Bible</ENAMEX>, which was the subject
of another article in the same issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>, the
passage from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaiah</ENAMEX> reads, ‚ÄúTherefore the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> himself
shall give you a sign.  A young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and she will bear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>....‚Äù  In the translation
of the Holy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> according to the traditional
Hebrew text, published by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Publication</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaiah</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:14</TIMEX> reads, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúAssuredly,</ENAMEX>
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> will give you a sign of His own accord!
Look, the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and about to
give birth to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>....‚Äù
