
   
      
         
            Punch on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bungalow</ENAMEX> Veranda



            
               
                  bandanna, bangle, banyan, bungalow, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cheetah</ENAMEX>,
chintz, chit, chop, chutney, coolie, copra, cot,
cowrie, cummerbund, cushy, deodar, dinghy,
dungaree, gong, gunny, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>, jungle, khaki, krait,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loot</ENAMEX>, pajamas, punch, pundit, puttee, seersucker,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shampoo</ENAMEX>, swami, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX>, toddy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tom-tom</ENAMEX>, topee,
veranda
               
            

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will probably regard the above as
a list of unrelated, more or less well-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words that have been selected at random,
but they will be wrong.  Appearances are often deceiving
and this is a case in point.  The words are not
unrelated and they have not been selected at random,
for they all have one thing very much in common,
namely, they are all Hindi loanwords.  To be
sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> is not the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> in all cases, but
it was at least the final stopping point in the journey
of the words into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> lexicon.  (In this article,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> is used to cover loanwords which etymologists
attribute to either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hindi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urdu</ENAMEX>.  The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are
basically the same language, except that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> is
written in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Devanagari</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urdu</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> script.)  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> has, in fact, been a
more fruitful source of new words for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
lexicon than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize, a not unnatural result
of the centuries of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.  All
Hindi loanwords in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, of course, are not as
well known or as frequently used as those listed
above; indeed, many are obscure in the extreme and
are probably never used in speech or encountered in
print by the overwhelming majority of English
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>.  Nonetheless, all are recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
lexicographers as being good English words.
Thus, all those cited in this article are to be found as
separate entries in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s Third New International
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dictionary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Language</ENAMEX> .

            Not all the words that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> has borrowed
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> are pure <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hindi</ENAMEX>; that is, some words
passed through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> en route to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> but their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> origins lie elsewhere.  For example, out of a
sampling of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">481 Hindi loanwords</NUMEX> (that is, I know, an
odd number for a sampling of any kind, but it happens
to be the number I had carded as of the moment
I began writing this article), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">167</NUMEX> were borrowed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanskrit</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another four</NUMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakrit</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Persian</ENAMEX> was the ultimate source of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">55</NUMEX> (the latter figure includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> words that
entered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX> and are combinations of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>).  Begum `high-ranking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Muslim lady</ENAMEX>' derives ultimately from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Turkic</ENAMEX>,
while cowrie `a type of sea shell' comes from Tamil
or Malayalam kavati via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> kauri or kaudi .  Two
Hindi loanwords have their origin in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>: ayah
`native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>,' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX>
aia , and pulton or pultun `infantry regiment,'
adapted from paltan , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> version of English
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battalion</ENAMEX> .

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loanwords</ENAMEX> entered <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> directly,
but a few first passed through the filter of another
language.  Baiza `small copper coin of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oman</ENAMEX>,' for
example, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> paisa .  Datura
`type of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>' and vanda `variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orchid</ENAMEX>'
reached English via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Latin</ENAMEX>; gavial `large crocodile,'
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Hindi ghariyal</NUMEX> ) via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>; and mohar
`silver coin of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>' via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepalese</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portuguese</ENAMEX> was
the immediate source of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> words (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>,
it will be recalled, were also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several centuries</TIMEX>,
losing their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goa</ENAMEX> only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>): copra , from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> khopra via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malayalam</ENAMEX> koppara;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">machila</ENAMEX> or machilla `hammock slung from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pole</ENAMEX>,' from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Hindi manzil</NUMEX> (borrowed unchanged from
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>) via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamil</ENAMEX> macil or mancil; tael `<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of
weight,' from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Hindi tola</NUMEX> (adapted from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sanskrit tula</NUMEX> )
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">via Malay</ENAMEX> tahil ; and jambolan `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Java plum,' the English</ENAMEX>
version of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> jambulao , from Hindi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jambul</ENAMEX> .

            Some of the words in my sampling may or may
not be Hindi loanwords; that is, etymologists are uncertain
whether they are properly attributable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> or some other language of the subcontinent.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dhoni</ENAMEX> or doni `fishing or coastal trading vessel,' for
example, may have entered <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi, Marathi</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanarese</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canarese</ENAMEX>), or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telugu</ENAMEX>; dinghy
`small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>' from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengali</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kathiawari `</ENAMEX>breed
of horses' from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gujurati</ENAMEX>; khuskhus `aromatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vetiver</ENAMEX>' from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>; kirpan
`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sikh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dagger</ENAMEX>' from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjabi</ENAMEX>; and nagkasser
or nagkesar `<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>'. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patel</ENAMEX> `village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headman</ENAMEX>' and
pindari `<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> mercenary,' from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marathi</ENAMEX>.

            Several of the loanwords in my sampling are actually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX>; that is, they include elements both
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> and from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or more</NUMEX> other languages.
Memsahib `term of respect for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>,' for
example, derives from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English ma'am</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> sahib
`sir, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>,' a word borrowed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>; boxwallah `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peddler</ENAMEX>' combines <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> box
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> wallah `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in charge of a particular
thing'; chotapeg `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-sized drink' unites <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> chota
`little, small' and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> peg (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> slang
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 1864</TIMEX> for a drink, especially of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brandy</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda water</ENAMEX>); and shroffage `<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> charged
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shroffing</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combines</ENAMEX> shroff (an adaptation of Hindi
saraf `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>, money-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lender</ENAMEX>,' a word borrowed from
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> suffix - age .  Combinations of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> include:


a) balaghat `tableland above a mountain pass,'
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> bala `above' and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> ghat `pass;
passage or stairway descending to a river';

b) bhumidar `<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX> having full title,' from
Hindi bhumi `<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, land' and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> dar
`<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>';

c) chokidar `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchman</ENAMEX>,' from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> cauki `police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian dar</ENAMEX>; and

d) kalaazar `disease also known as dumdum fever,'
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kala `black</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> azar
`disease.'

            

            
               Mussalchee `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">torchbearer</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combines</ENAMEX> mussal `torch,
usually of oilsoaked rags,' adapted from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> masal
or mashal , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> mash'al , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkic</ENAMEX> - ci (or chi, ji ), a suffix denoting an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loanwords</ENAMEX> are simply transliterations
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> originals.  But since different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
have different ideas about how the Devanagari
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> alphabets should be transliterated,
in many cases there is no single ‚Äúcorrect‚Äù way to
spell a specific word and, instead, dictionaries offer
several--sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as six</NUMEX>--acceptable variant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spellings</ENAMEX>.  Burka `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loose woman</ENAMEX>'s garment covering
entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>,' for example, can also be spelled
bourka, burkha, burga, burqa , or bourkha , while mahua
`type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>' can also be spelled mahwa ,
mohwa, mowha, mowra , or mowrah .  Loanwords
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> recognized spellings include: chador,
chadar, chuddar, chudder, chaddar `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s cloth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> covering'; mahseer, mahsir, mahsur, mahaseer,
mahasir `freshwater <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>'; mali, mallee, mallie, mally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molly</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a gardening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caste</ENAMEX>'; naik, naig,
naique, naigue, nayak `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corporal</ENAMEX>'; and tussah,
tusseh, tusser, tussor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tussur `tan silk</ENAMEX>; also the silkworm
producing it.' Chukker `period of polo play,'
dhoti `loincloth,' dinghy, ganja `cannabis used for
smoking,' khidmatgar `male waiter,' khuskhus,
kutcha `<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, imperfect,' <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">myna `species</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>,'
puggaree `blight turban, scarf,' raggee `finger millet,'
ryotwar `system of collecting land rents or taxes,'
sambar `type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>,' and zamindari `system of land
holding' each have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other acceptable spellings.
My sampling contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about fifty</NUMEX> other words that
have either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> variant spellings each.

            Although most loanwords differ in form somewhat
from their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindi</ENAMEX> antecedents, the changes are
largely minor orthographic ones, as the substitution
of ch, gh , and sh for an original c, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX> , or s , etc.  Thus,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> has champac `<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>' instead of campak, gharry
`horse-drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX>' instead of gari, darshan
`a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX>' instead of darsan .  A change
of vowels or a doubling of a consonant is also not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infrequent</ENAMEX>, thus giving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> kunkur `variety of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limestone'</ENAMEX> in lieu of kankar, mulmul `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">muslin</ENAMEX>' in lieu
of malmal, muggar `kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crocodile</ENAMEX>' in lieu of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magar</ENAMEX> .  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of similar examples could be cited.
On the other hand, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loanwords</ENAMEX> have undergone
radical changes.  Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, I hazard, would be
likely, upon seeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> terms bilayati, bajara,
bajra, kaawch, pani , and rasaut , to cite only a few, to
discern therein the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> blighty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Indian</ENAMEX>
slang for `<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>,' brinjarry `traveling
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>,' budgerow `large, keelless
barge,' cowage `tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX>,' pawnee `<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>' and
rusot `<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> extract.'  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other good examples are
Juggernaut `unstoppable destructive force: or object,'
which derives from jagannath , and kedgeree
`cooked dish of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>, lentils, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>,' which derives
from khicri or khicari .  The familiar cot and
dungaree are close to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hindi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pronunciation</ENAMEX>, though not in spelling; they derive,
respectively, from khat and dungri .

            In the case of some loanwords, there has been a
change in both form and meaning.  Bandanna , for
example, comes from bandhu , which denotes a way
of dyeing cloth, while bungalow comes from bangla ,
an adjective meaning `of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal</ENAMEX>.'  Other loanwords
which have acquired changed meanings include chitra
`<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">axis deer</ENAMEX>,' from citra `spotted'; hathi `gray,' from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hathi `elephant</ENAMEX>'; pukka `genuine, reliable, good,'
from pakka `cooked, ripe, mature'; puttee `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>'s
legging,' from patti `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bandage</ENAMEX>'; pyke `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> at
whose expense a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> is treated,' from payik `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX>';
and toddy `type of hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>,' from tari `palmyra
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">palm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX>.'  These are only a few of the many
examples available.

            Some single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> words have given rise to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
different loanwords.  Bandar `rhesus <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>' and
bondar `palm <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">civet</ENAMEX>,' for example, both derive from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bada</ENAMEX> or badar <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`monkey</ENAMEX>,' while baniya `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>' is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> antecedent of both banyan `<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>' and bunnia
`<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">caste</ENAMEX>.'  Other examples
of the same phenomenon include: chokey `customs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>' and chowk `marketplace,' from cauki `marketplace';
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mulmul</ENAMEX> (see above) and mull `soft thin
muslin,' from malmal (see above); pandit `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> held in high respect' and pundit `very learned;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authoritative commentator</ENAMEX>,' from pandit `wise,
learned'; and numdah `thick felt rug' and numnah
`felt or sheepskin saddle pad,' from namda `carpet,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rug</ENAMEX>.'  Again, numerous other examples could be
cited.

            As the examples cited above make clear, Hindi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loanwords</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> relate to a wide variety of subjects.
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX> also includes the following
words in the indicated subject categories (words already
cited are not repeated):


<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>: balisaur, barasingh, bhalu, bharal, chikara,
chital, gaur, hanuman, jumnapari, kakar,
kastura, langur, nilgai, rusa, tangun, tattoo

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Birds</ENAMEX>: baya, chukar, hurgila, jermonal, sarus, shama

<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX>: chawl, gola, gunge, mandir, tope

Caste/religious terms: balahi, bhagat, bhangi, bhat,
bhora, chamar, chhatri, chuhra, churel, gadaria,
goala, granthi, jajman, kahar, kalwar, khatri,
kumbh mala, kumhar, kumkum, kurmi, math,
mela, nai, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nanakpanthi</ENAMEX>, pardhan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rajput</ENAMEX>,
samadh, samaj, sangh

Clothing: bursati, kambal, sari, sherwani

Coins: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anna</ENAMEX>, pice, rupee

<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs/chemicals</ENAMEX>: bikh, chandu, charas, goracco,
karaya, khair, kutira <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>, lac, munjeet,
passewa, reh

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fabrics</ENAMEX>: jaconet, khaddar, nainsook, pattu, tat

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fish/</ENAMEX>marine life: ghol, goonch, hilsa, rohu

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foods/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverages</ENAMEX>: chapati, chotahazri, dahi, ghee,
jaggery, khoa, puri

Governmental/legal terms: batta, begar, chaprasi,
dakoit, dakoity, dhan, dharna, kotwal, kotwali,
panchayat, pottah, sabha

Household items: bidri, chagul, chatta, chowrie,
chulha, dhurrie, gaddi, kangri, lota, phulkari,
pitarah, punkah, teapoy

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Insects</ENAMEX>: khapra

Measures: bigha, crore, lac, maund, ruttee, ser,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tank</ENAMEX>, tola, yojan

Military/<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>: kukri, kuttar, sangar, thana

Musical instruments: bin, narsinga, pungi, sarinda,
sitar

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Occupations</ENAMEX>: bapu, chokra, dhai, dhobi,
gharrywallah, madrasi, mahajan, mahout,
puggy

<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Plants</ENAMEX>: ber, bhabar, bhang, chirata, dhal, gulancha,
hursinghar, jarool, jowar, kans, khesari, kusa,
maloo, mand, mesta, mudar, munj, pan, rosha,
sarson, til, urd

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Snakes</ENAMEX>: baboia

Titles: babu, bhai, burra, maharajah, maharani,
rajah, rajpramukh, rani

Transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>: dak, dandy, morpunky,
palkee, pulwar, putelee, tonga

<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Trees/shrubs</ENAMEX>: bahera, bel, bendy, caraunda, dhak,
dhaman, dhauri, dhawa, haldu, jaman, jambo,
jambos, jambool, kapur, karela, kathal, kikar,
kokan, neem, palas, pipal, sal, salai, sunn, susco,
toon

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miscellaneous</ENAMEX>: abir, amla, bandarlog, banghy, bat,
bhadan, bhoosa, bhut, bidi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bock</ENAMEX>, bukh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">chee-chee</ENAMEX>,
chopper, churrus, ghurry, goonda, hartal,
Holi, hundi, jheel, jungli, kaithi, kartik, keddah,
machan, nautch, nullah, pachisi, piuri, paig,
purree

            

            The above do not include those loanwords deriving
from words earlier borrowed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Persian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, which are (in addition to those
already cited):


From <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>:

Clothing: jama, rumal

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fabrics</ENAMEX>: kincob

Governmental terms: daroga, dewan, durbar,
parganna, peshwa, purwannah, russud,
sheristadar, zamindar

Household items: charpoy, chillumchee, rezai

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> terms: khaksar, khankah, pir, purdah

Legal terms: benami, dastur

Military: sepoy, subahdar

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Occupations</ENAMEX>: begari, bheesty, bildar, bobachee,
chakar, chobdar, darzi, khansamah, mazdoor,
phansigar, rahdar, shikari

Titles: akhundzada, bahadur, shahzada, sirdar

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miscellaneous</ENAMEX>: bas, bazigar, buckshee, bund,
charka, chawbuck, cillum, dasturi, gunge,
kajawah, koftgari, koomkie, sarod, shikar,
shikargah, shikra, tabasheer

From <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>:

Government terms: abwab, hookum, jumma, malik,
mofussil, munshi, munsif, musnud, nabob,
nawab, nizam, omrah, tahsil, taluk

Military: maidan, nazim

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Occupations</ENAMEX>: mutsuddy, syce, vakeel

<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Plants</ENAMEX>: gingelly

Religious terms: fatwa, khalsa, mazhabi, minah

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miscellaneous</ENAMEX>: baba, howdah, izzat, khalat, kharif,
majoon, nuzzer, rabi, shrab

From <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">combinations:</ENAMEX>

Government terms: burkundaz, daftardar, faujdar,
faujdary, malguzar, malikana, nazir, tahsildar

Military: dafadar, havildar, jemandar, risala,
risaldar

Religious terms: shahidi

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miscellaneous</ENAMEX>: halalior

            
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThe Baths</ENAMEX> is a dying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, we refunded
money to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">86</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who died.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Magazine , .</ENAMEX>  Submitted by ]

         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúBox 2101 Terminal Annex</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [The address of a life
insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.  Submitted by ]

         
         
            
               ETYMOLOGICA OBSCURA
            
         
         
            snake oil


            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was drilled
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1859</TIMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin L. Drake</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titusville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> named for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Titus</ENAMEX>, who settled
it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1796</TIMEX> (and wanted to call it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>).
Before oil was actively sought, it seeped out of the
ground in various parts of the world...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúHere</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oil Creek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> skimmed the
surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for domestic uses, and white
settlers bottled it for medicinal purposes and called
it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seneca Oil</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            Was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seneca Oil</ENAMEX> the origin of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snake oil</ENAMEX> ?

         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World of Abbreviations</ENAMEX> and Acronyms



            I have traveled throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, but nowhere have I found
more abbreviations and acronyms in use than in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, particularly in the medical field.  In the small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where I teach and practice hematology
and oncology, I frequently struggle to decode
the abbreviations and acronyms used by house
staff and medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.  While this process is
frustrating at times, certain abbreviations and acronyms
add humor to the atmosphere of busy and
stressful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> medical practice.  For example,
while we often say that a patient needs lots of TLC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúTender Loving Care</ENAMEX>,' at times we end up seeing the
result of another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX> --`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Total Lack of Concern</ENAMEX>.'
Many of us, including me, use WNL for `Within Normal
Limits' to describe the results of various x-ray
and laboratory tests; however, at times we find this
may well mean `We Never Looked.' When NMR
`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nuclear Magnetic Resonance</ENAMEX>,' which is now better
referred to as MRI `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</ENAMEX>,'
was first introduced to the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer advocates</ENAMEX> and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
fearing the escalating health-care costs associated
with this expensive diagnostic procedure, thought a
better translation would be `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No More Radiologists</ENAMEX>.'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRG `Diagnosis Related Group</ENAMEX>,' the term <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> uses to describe prospective payment to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>,
could mean `<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damned Regulatory Government</ENAMEX>'
to the medical profession or `<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">De</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The</ENAMEX>] Revenues
Gone' to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital administration</ENAMEX>.

            For those of us in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, we all carry a title
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.D</ENAMEX> .  `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doctor of Medicine</ENAMEX>.'  When I was drafted into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> as a Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX>, my title was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúDal Yoo, M.D., U.S.A.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Army)‚Äù</ENAMEX> and I
recall my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master Sergeant</ENAMEX>'s morbid joke that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.A.</ENAMEX> could stand for `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Many Die and U Shall Also</ENAMEX>.'
Speaking of various titles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.D.s</ENAMEX> are not the only
ones who get the bad names.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.S.</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bachelor of Science</ENAMEX>'
could well mean `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bullshit</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.S.</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More of the</ENAMEX>
Same,' and Ph.D. `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pile Higher and Deeper</ENAMEX>,' etc.

            In the field of medical laboratory testing, you
may remember a test called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIA</ENAMEX> for detecting
abnormal macroglobulin in the serum.  The test is
performed by putting a drop of serum into distilled
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, producing a grossly visible white precipitate
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldenstrom</ENAMEX>'s macroglobulinemia
and other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dysproteinemic disorders</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walden</ENAMEX>-strom
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years ago</TIMEX> told me that he had an opportunity
to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sia</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> who first
introduced this simple bedside technique to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>.
However, when I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany</ENAMEX>, this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIA</ENAMEX> test was labeled as `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Serum In Aqua</ENAMEX>.'  Another
example comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasoactive Intestinal Poly</ENAMEX>-peptide.'
This assay was quite variable from laboratory
to laboratory when first introduced; thus it
meant `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Very Inconsistent Polypeptide</ENAMEX>' to some of
the gastroenterologists and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeons</ENAMEX> who were pondering
the possibility of pancreatic surgery in patients
with high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX> .

            These abbreviations and acronyms are generating
laughter in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> life as well as in the medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>.  Some time ago, I heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s budget proposal was DOA `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead On Arrival</ENAMEX>'
on the congressional floor.  However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOA</ENAMEX> was `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Defining Opportunity</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.'  More recently, during the war
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> we saw both pro- and anti-war demonstrations,
thus generating <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SMASH `Students Mobilized</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>,' as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SCUD</ENAMEX>
`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sadly Confused Unpatriotic Demonstrators</ENAMEX>.'  At
times abbreviations or acronyms get upside-down as
well as backward meanings.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, when inflation was sky high, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> used
the slogan WIN `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whip Inflation Now</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
turned the WIN button upside down, making it NIM
`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Immediate Miracle</ENAMEX>.'  For the backward example,
I saw the sign for DAM which is supposed to
represent `<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mothers Against Dyslexia</ENAMEX>.'

            When I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> to plan my future
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postgraduate</ENAMEX> training, a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquaintance</ENAMEX> gave
me a quick <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> tour which included the worldfamous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Museum of Art</ENAMEX>.  The windows
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> gave some nice views of downtown
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>.  The visit was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early summer</TIMEX> when
ongoing road <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> work was generating strong
smells.  From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> window we could see a
neon sign with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSFS</ENAMEX> in bright letters on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
high-rise downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.  The letters stood for
`<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Savings Fund Society</ENAMEX>' but on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> I
told my local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> that they stood, more appropriately,
for `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Philadelphia Smells Funny Sometimes</ENAMEX>.'
However, I later fell in love with this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of brotherly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, not only for its excellent medical training
but also for its rich metropolitan atmosphere.

            Speaking of smells, we have the organization
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NOSE</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> suburban area
which, as you may have guessed, stands for `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Neighbors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stench Elimination</ENAMEX>.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOSE</ENAMEX> is
fighting for the beautification of residential housing
districts.  Like everything else, the meaning of certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abbreviations</ENAMEX> or acronyms could vary depending
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SABENA</ENAMEX> could stand for `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Such A Bad Experience</ENAMEX>--
Never Again' but also could mean `Such a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful</ENAMEX>
Experience--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Alone</ENAMEX>.'  Indeed we do not seem
to be able to get away from numerous abbreviations
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acronyms</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> of our lives because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>,
magazines, and TV newscasts love to come
up with new and innovative ones.  The latest scandal
of the television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> concerns the organization
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTL</ENAMEX> , which is supposed to stand for `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Praise</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>' or `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">People That Love'</ENAMEX>; others think it
means `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pass The Loot</ENAMEX>.'  In this era of the litigationprone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, including the high rate of malpractice
suits, I noted an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> called, HALT `Help
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abolish Legal Tyranny</ENAMEX>.' I welcome any means of
bringing laughter into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bedside medicine</ENAMEX>, which we
all think of as the last place where one could ever
find any decent humor.  When the medical practice
gets tough, particularly for those truly complicated
cases where I have no idea what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> has, I
apply my favorite of all the abbreviations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOK</ENAMEX> syndrome
`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God Only Knows</ENAMEX>.'
         
         
            [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoo</ENAMEX> would like to hear from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who have heard or seen
outrageous abbreviations or acronyms.  Address him at: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dal Yoo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.D.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACP/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education/Hematology/Oncology Section/Providence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital/Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20017-2180</TIMEX>.]
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúFree</ENAMEX> lays to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">!‚Äù</ENAMEX> [From an invitation
to a ‚ÄúBlue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii‚Äù Beach Party</ENAMEX> in Staff Bulletin No.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">31, p. 6</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Area</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech College</ENAMEX>.
Submitted by ]

         
         
            
‚ÄúNo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">detail</ENAMEX> is too small to overlook.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX> [From an advertisement
for a lawn product on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCMO-TV</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri,</ENAMEX> .  Submitted by 
]
         
         


            Once again the myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>-replacing-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-by-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-vote
has surfaced, this time in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pages of VERBATIM</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:21</TIMEX>].  The myth began its
life in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-19th century</TIMEX> histories attempting to document
the contributions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
culture and history.  But it is no more than a myth.

            There was a language-related vote that may be
the ultimate source of the myth, but that vote had
nothing to do with choosing an official language.  It
did not take place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>, as is often maintained,
but on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 13, 1795</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
debated a proposal, not to give German
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> status, but merely to print copies of the
federal laws in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  An ad hoc
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> reported favorably on the proposal, but
during the debate a motion to adjourn failed by one
vote.  The failure of the motion to adjourn probably
represents a vote of no confidence in the committee
report.  After some further debate, which focused
not so much on translation as on the means by which
copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> versions of the federal statutes
were to be furnished to the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> was appointed to study the matter and
report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>.  In the final vote, which took
place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month later</TIMEX>, the proposal for translation
was defeated.  The ayes and nays of the final vote are
not recorded.  It is from the close interim vote, not
on an actual bill but on adjournment, that the so-called
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúGerman vote‚Äù</ENAMEX> legend has been built.

            There is a further bit of embroidery to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">myth</ENAMEX>: it is often claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. A. Muhlenberg</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a prominent
assimilationist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, stepped down to cast
the deciding vote damning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> forever
to minority-language status (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muhlenberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>
go so far as to assert that his own German
was pretty incompetent).  But while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muhlenberg</ENAMEX>'s
voting record in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Congress</ENAMEX> did not seem to
annoy his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>, they did
react quite strongly when, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, he stepped down and cast the deciding
negative vote against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Jay Treaty</ENAMEX>.  This action
caused his brother-in-law to stab him, and it cost him
his congressional seat in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1796</TIMEX> election as well.
This significant tie-breaker soon became confused
with the earlier adjournment cliffhanger, conveniently
fleshing out the myth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> vote.





         
         
            [ A helpful letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colyn L. Phillips</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>, provides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> possibly useful references
for those who might wish to document this issue further :


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American State Papers</ENAMEX>, Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">037</NUMEX>, Class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>:

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Miscellaneous:</ENAMEX>


Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúLaws published in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> Language‚Äù
93rd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1st Session</ENAMEX>

Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúPromulgation of laws extended to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> language editions‚Äù

Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúPromulgation of laws‚Äù (latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
from 3rd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2nd</NUMEX> session).


            

            
               Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> adds :

            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this same</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> there were also proposals
to adopt the metric system of weights and
measures as the official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> standard.  These
proposals also failed, as I remember (from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long-ago</TIMEX>
reading), by a close margin.]
         
         


            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are frequently guilty of nonsense
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> language, but it is regrettable to
see it spilling over into your pages.  Thus, in ‚ÄúRedundancy
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Languages‚Äù</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XVII,3</NUMEX>], Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonner</ENAMEX> cites <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> nouns, Autoreparaturwerkstatt
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haupthandelsartikel</ENAMEX> , as being ‚Äúsimply
longer than they strictly need to be.‚Äù  These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are
alleged to mean `<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>' and `staple.'  But a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> is
not necessarily an auto repair workshop, and a principal
stock in trade is not necessarily a staple (except
in the loosest sense).  Actually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> noun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stapel</ENAMEX> is used much more precisely than its English
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, as in such terms as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabelstapler</ENAMEX> `forklift
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truck</ENAMEX>' and, more poetically, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hochstapler</ENAMEX> `swindler.'
The immense combinative resources of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> language may lead to the creation of ponderous
nouns, but seldom to redundancies.





         
         


            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William H. Dougherty</ENAMEX>'s article, ‚ÄúFrench
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leave‚Äù</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>], concerning the difficulty of translating
satisfactorily the title of the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Au Revoir</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">les Enfants</ENAMEX> , reminds me of a conversation that, as an
undergraduate at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, I had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice E. Coindreau</ENAMEX>, who was engaged
in translating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.  As an example
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind of difficulty that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translators</ENAMEX> face,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coindreau</ENAMEX> cited the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s The Unvanquished
and asked, ‚ÄúIs it plural or singular?  Masculine
or feminine?‚Äù  He said that the translators, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raimbault</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.P. Gorce</ENAMEX>, had put those questions
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>, who only laughed.  Knowing that any of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> possibilities would considerably narrow the
range of suggestion in the original, but helpless,
they settled for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'Invaincu .</ENAMEX>





         
         


            It is understandable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel Vercambre</ENAMEX>
would find it disconcerting to run into blue jaundice
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Welsh dictionary [‚ÄúInstant Welsh</ENAMEX>,‚Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>].  The term seems to contradict itself, but at
least it is to be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> and means `cyanosis.'
My own surprising encounter with color occurred
when, in a report on the restoration of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>--an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>,
speaking in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>--said that they had used a preparation
that contained whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúincluding the
red.‚Äù  I was, of course, appalled to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s
work was in the hands of someone who
sees yolks as red.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curiosity</ENAMEX> led me to consult an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictionary</ENAMEX>, where I found for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">yolk</ENAMEX> , `rosso
d'uovo.'  So as to leave no possible doubt, I checked
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rosso</ENAMEX> and got `red,' as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">il mar Rosso</ENAMEX> .  Can you
help explain that one, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vercambre</ENAMEX>?





         
         


            I recently asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>, an experienced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, to review some material I had written
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>.  When the review was completed,
our conversation led to the following addition to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English language</ENAMEX>, which we would be pleased to
share with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>'S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>:


lallaperuser `a world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>.'

            






         
         


            Upon reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Room</ENAMEX>'s ‚ÄúDon't Get Your
Titles in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Twist‚Äù</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>], I was happily surprised to
see reference made to the tiny, misspelled, but spellbinding
novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Ashford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Young Visiters</ENAMEX> .
I have been an ardent admirer of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúMiss Daisy‚</ENAMEX>Äù ever
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, when I had the good fortune to be cast
in a dramatization of her novel, presented at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strand Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of that year</TIMEX>.  It
was a special matinee, under the auspices of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stage Society</ENAMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> drawn exclusively from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of prominent theatrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.  We were
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all between the ages of seven</TIMEX> and fifteen, which was
entirely appropriate, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Ashford</ENAMEX> had written
her novel at the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Truex</ENAMEX>, had been appearing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West End</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> and was currently
starring in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>! , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.G.</ENAMEX>
Wodehouse, thereby assuring my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> and
me of an invitation to audition for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Whale</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whale</ENAMEX> was a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of the theater who wore
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> hats on this occasion, donating his services as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, and scenic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>.  After the
auditions it was announced that I had been cast as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX> (the future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
was to play an old crony of his, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clincham</ENAMEX>.
This was pretty exciting stuff!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> proclaimed that ‚ÄúMiss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Ashford</ENAMEX>'s
famous story, dramatized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mackenzie</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Norman</ENAMEX>, will be acted
by the following promising juveniles....‚Äù  There
followed a list of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than thirty</TIMEX> names.  The leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> were played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Casson</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sybil Thorndike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Casson</ENAMEX>) as Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salteena</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Hyson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Hyson</ENAMEX>) as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel ‚ÄúMonticue</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Christopher</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Casson</ENAMEX>, read the passages which
linked up the various scenes.

            I still remember the enthusiastic reception we
got from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>; but, better still, I can quote
from the glowing review we got from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John Irvine</ENAMEX>,
the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The London Observer</ENAMEX> ,
who observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher ‚Äúdisplayed</ENAMEX> all the
signs that denote an accomplished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  As
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irvine</ENAMEX> called her ‚Äúa very beautiful
little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and, at the risk of turning her head, she has
the makings of a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  And our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Casson</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúread the passages with a clearness
of utterance that was remarkable.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Towards</ENAMEX> the end
of the review Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irvine</ENAMEX> added, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúMr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Truex</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, were extremely diverting
in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parts</ENAMEX>; and I was greatly touched by the
spectacle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Truex</ENAMEX>, in the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, solemnly removing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX> during the
singing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Anthem</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  I decided then
and there to go on the stage.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Visiters</ENAMEX> lent itself readily to dramatization,
except that one loses the special sort of
charm inherent in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy</ENAMEX>'s quaint spelling.  But there
are other things to charm one in a stage version.  We
all had the pleasure of getting to know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy</ENAMEX> a little
bit at rehearsals and felt very much at home with
her, which wasn't surprising, since she was only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eighteen</NUMEX> herself.

            I was totally entranced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Hyson</ENAMEX> and,
before we had to return to school, I persuaded our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> to take us to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX>.  There I had the
thrill of winning a canary by rolling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX> down a
slide into a tiny bull's-eye.  With a flourish, I presented
it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>.  Soon after that, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> got a
good offer to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, and I didn't see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> again until a number, of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> when
she came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in a play titled Most of the
Game .  Well, sure enough, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irvine</ENAMEX> was right: she
was a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--and a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>!  But,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alas</ENAMEX>!, she was married.  She did, however, confide to
me that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúour‚Äù canary</ENAMEX> was still in good voice.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX> wisely reissued The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>
Visiters , and it got a rave review by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Friedman</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> .  He called it ‚Äúa tiny novel
that begs comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tolstoy's War</ENAMEX> and
Peace , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flaubert's Sentimental Education</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> in Love may be bigger, but The
Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visiters</ENAMEX> too manages to contain and display,
more gracefully than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>, an entire civilization.‚Äù
He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Ashford ‚Äúis</ENAMEX> as ambitious
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Eliot</ENAMEX> and as innovative as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Virginia Woolf</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  Well, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrice Lillie</ENAMEX> used to
say, ‚ÄúYou could have knocked me over with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fender!‚Äù</ENAMEX>  I really had not thought about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Young</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visiters</ENAMEX> in that context.  That is to say, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> we
budding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thespians</ENAMEX> looked on acting in the play as
simply a joyous lark.  We loved the story and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, but we had never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flaubert</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy</ENAMEX>.  At this stage in my life I could see that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> was on to something: I knew, for instance,
that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.M. Barrie</ENAMEX>, who
had written the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Introduction</ENAMEX>, had written the novel
himself, and I had sneered at that theory.  But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>
went further than that.  He insisted that ‚ÄúNothing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barrie</ENAMEX>'s fiction can match <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashford</ENAMEX>'s chefd'oeuvre....
But most of all, even though she
shows us a world of buffoons--for no one escapes--
she causes us to love them.‚Äù  And I say ‚ÄúAmen‚Äù to
that!




         
         


            Though my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX> is rudimentary, I cannot
help commenting, as my eyes fall on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM XVII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonner</ENAMEX>'s statement, ‚ÄúChinese
has no notion of tense,‚Äù is erroneous.  As in the
case of the future tense in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, tense in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX>
is indicated by an auxiliary <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">verb</ENAMEX> or a particle, not by
inflection of the verb.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would translate the Caesarean
Veni, video, vincam! into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> something
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`Wo laide</ENAMEX>, kan, yao desheng.'





         
         


            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bummel</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> river [‚ÄúDon't Get
Your Titles in a Twist!‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>]?  If so, neither the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rand McNally</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> atlas has noticed it.
Nor do the etymologies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langenscheidt</ENAMEX> .
If my memory is reliable, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX> was rhapsodizing
about the experiences of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on a footloose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bicycle</ENAMEX> tour.  Take away the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX>, and it is as
near to the meaning of ein <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bummel</ENAMEX> as one can get.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> usage is worth comparing with the obsolescent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bummer</ENAMEX> and with bummle in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> dialect.  Could your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>, notwithstanding
his correct identification of the background
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Men on the Bummel</ENAMEX> , be confusing it with
the better-known <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Men in a Boat</ENAMEX> , where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scenery</ENAMEX> is decidedly fluvial?

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> employ the definite
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> where the indefinite would be equally appropriate.
Might not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX>, who knew <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> well
and spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> fluently, have simply chosen the
slightly more forceful of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> alternative titles?





         
         
            [ In all fairness, it must be said that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Room</ENAMEX> wrote
as soon as he realized his slip in referring to the Bummel
as a river.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> .]
         
         


            We would really have to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schleppers</ENAMEX> (with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capital S</ENAMEX>: the learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will not the distinction)
to drag the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>, me among them, from saying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s me.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canutian</ENAMEX> position [EPISTOLAE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>] reminds me of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> cravenly caving in to some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
who lambasted him for having written, ‚ÄúWho are
you rooting for?‚Äù  When I wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> to ask
whether he could imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hara</ENAMEX> sitting in the grandstand at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yankee Stadium</ENAMEX>,
hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> (with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard</ENAMEX>) in hand, asking each
other, ‚ÄúWhom are you rooting for?‚Äù, he responded
with a form <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">postcard</ENAMEX> answering a question about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">locution God Bless</ENAMEX> , one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> and I could
certainly get along without.

            Context is important.  I can imagine myself answering,
‚ÄúIt is I, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>),‚Äù to a voice from a burning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bush</ENAMEX>, but not to the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of Chatauqua
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.





         
         


            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúThe Scandalous Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>,‚Äù by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zellig Bach</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>], I
must say that I wholeheartedly agree with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s
assessment of the awkward and often amusing
government translation.  The strange concoction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grammar</ENAMEX> and syntax served up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> no
doubt confused and discouraged many of the people
it was meant to benefit.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yiddish</ENAMEX> deserves better, and
based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>'s accurate analysis of this recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gelechter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yiddish</ENAMEX> `joke'), I propose that the government
hire him as its official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> of future <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>.




         
         


            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Mason</ENAMEX>, in his ‚ÄúLittle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waterloos</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language Frontiers‚</ENAMEX>Äù [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>], cites the case
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> mountain railway ticket which entitled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> to `<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Fahrt Fr.</ENAMEX> 9,50' as an indication of the
high cost of living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and I were
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>, we had occasion to use
an elevator in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Svendborg</ENAMEX>.  When
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> pressed the button it immediately lit up
with the words I FART `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">IN MOTION</ENAMEX>,' causing him to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remark</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄúI bet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> think
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> run awfully fast in this little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.‚Äù





         
         


            In the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lederer</ENAMEX>'s ‚ÄúWorld According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Bloopers‚Äù</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XIII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>], I enclose a
collection of fourth-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' replies to test
questions, given to me by a public-school teacher
when I taught at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>.

            
               A virgin forest is a forest in which the hand of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX> has never set foot .

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> purifies its water supply by filtering the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then forcing it through an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aviator</ENAMEX> .

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who followed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> were called
the twelve opossums .

            
               The spinal column is a long bunch of bones.  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> sits on top and you sit on the bottom .

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the main causes of dust is janitors .

            
               Animal husbandry is having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> .

            
               The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four seasons</TIMEX> are: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>, pepper, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vinegar</ENAMEX> .

            
               The climate is hottest next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creator</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syntax</ENAMEX> is all the money collected at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sinners</ENAMEX> .

            
               The difference between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and a king is
that a king has no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VIII</ENAMEX> by his own efforts increased the population
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> .

            
               The triangle which has an angle of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">135 degrees</NUMEX> is
called an obscene triangle .

            
               In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the 18th century</TIMEX>, all the morons
moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> .

            
               We do not raise silkworms in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
because we get our silk from rayon.  It is a larger
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> and gives more silk .

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout</ENAMEX> obeys all to whom obedience is due and
respects all duly constipated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> .

            
               Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> are made of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plaster</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> .

            
               To prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> colds, use an agonizer to spray
into your nose until it drops into your throat .

            
               Strategy is when you don't let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> know
that you are out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX>, but keep on firing .





         
         


            While no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> will be unhappy with a review
that begins, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äú The Surname Dictionary</ENAMEX> , in particular,
becomes the best available work on the subject,‚Äù
several points in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leslie Dunkling</ENAMEX>'s remarks on A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dictionary of Surnames</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:11</TIMEX>] require comment.

            He writes, ‚Äúthe awkward fact... is that a great
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will consult it in vain for information
about their own names.‚Äù  He is right that the dictionary
concentrates on the more frequent names
(though it is not limited to these), yet that is inevitable
in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> attempt at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">pan-European</ENAMEX> dictionary.
Even so, the book contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">almost seventy thousand</NUMEX>
family names, which is nothing to sneeze at in a pioneering
effort.  (Future editions will, of course,
contain more.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> say that if they came across reliable
information about rarer names, they wrote entries.
In other words, if someone else had done the
research in what appeared to be a scholarly way,
they took advantage of it.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  One</ENAMEX> should not think
that the book is a scissors-and-paste job.  The compilers
write, ‚Äú...the number of reliable reference
works [on family names] is remarkably small‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xlvii</ENAMEX>).  After mentioning these few, they conclude,
‚ÄúAt this point the list of honourable exceptions begins
to run out‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. xlviii</ENAMEX>).  Therefore, to compensate
for the scarcity of reliable secondary literature,
the compilers turned to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>.  From the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> pages of personal acknowledgments (as opposed
to a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pages of bibliography), it should be
clear that the dictionary rests largely on original research.
As ‚Äúspecial consultant‚Äù for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
names, I can say that all of my explanations are original
with me.  (How the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> names were treated is
described in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúThe Jewish Family Names</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of Surnames ,‚Äù Jewish Language Review</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 1987</TIMEX>, pp. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">139-46</TIMEX>.)

            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunkling</ENAMEX> has ‚Äúdoubts about how ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of this dictionary will cope with its metalanguage,‚Äù
citing lines which contain several abbreviations
and technical terms.  With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty-one</NUMEX> pages of
Introduction and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pages devoted to the resolution
of abbreviations, the task is not as hard as he
makes it out to be.

            He writes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúgenealogical</ENAMEX> information is occasionally
added..., but only when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> concerned
are `important' according to a very traditional
definition of that word.‚Äù  Yes, and that is
because genealogical information is most abundant
for such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: what, for instance, is known about
the ancestry of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie Vaughan</ENAMEX>?  Also, if anyone
infers from later remarks in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunkling</ENAMEX>'s review
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about ‚</NUMEX>Äúthe `noble' theme‚Äù) that only <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúnoble‚</ENAMEX>Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
are the subject of genealogical notes, that assumption
would be wrong: there are genealogical
vignettes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelts</ENAMEX>, and many other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúcommoners.</ENAMEX>‚Äù

            What I missed in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunkling</ENAMEX>'s remarks is
mention of a major innovation in this dictionary:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nesting</ENAMEX>.  The family names are not listed as in a telephone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directory</ENAMEX>, merely in alphabetical order, with
no articulation between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> entry and the next:
rather, if names are etymologically related to one
another, they are all listed under the same entry.
For example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 285</NUMEX> names appear under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> .
Moreover, within each entry the names are broken
down according to form and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>--for example,
variants, cognates, diminutives, augmentatives,
patronymics, and patronymics from diminutives--
with further classification (according to language)
and comment.  A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">230</NUMEX>-page alphabetical index guides
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to the location of the names.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surnames</ENAMEX> is thus more like a thesaurus than an
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">alphabetical dictionary</ENAMEX>.





         
         


            The anecdote of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who resented
the slur on her country [review of the Bloomsbury
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dictionary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Slang</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVII</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:17</TIMEX>] reminded
me of an incident related to me by a friend
who taught <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>-affiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
The story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nativity</ENAMEX> was under discussion, and
the least sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> raised
her hand to ask, ‚ÄúWhat is a virgin?‚Äù

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> explained, in terms that she hoped
were appropriate to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.  When she had
finished, the class Brain turned to the questioner and
smugly elucidated, ‚ÄúSo you see, you're a virgin.‚Äù

            ‚ÄúI am NOT! ‚Äù shrieked the outraged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-year-old</TIMEX>.





         
         



            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will recall with pleasure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Rosten</ENAMEX>'s
THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDUCATION OF H*Y</ENAMEX>*<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>*A*<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>*A*P*L*A*<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> , which appeared in the late 1930s
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 40s</TIMEX> and which dealt with the amusing difficulties
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Pale</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Settlement</ENAMEX> in coping with what we now call ‚ÄúEnglish
as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  Rosten</ENAMEX>'s articles were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">good-humored</ENAMEX>, and there was no intimation of negative
or hostile feeling toward an ethnic minority.  To
be sure, as it was fiction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosten</ENAMEX> exaggerated a bit,
but the real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> were then extant, and I can
vouch for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> from my own experience.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a certified public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, acquired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>, an affable, outgoing insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>
(pronounced SALE-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ess-mahn</ENAMEX>) whose accent reflected
his origins in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pale of Settlement</ENAMEX>, specifically in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minske Gebernyeh</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX> was an echt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Litvak</ENAMEX>.
Over and above the accent and intonation, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>
had a knack for transmogrifying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anguish</ENAMEX>
Languish into levels of meaning scarcely intended
by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>.  I can cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> examples:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> noontime Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> went
out to lunch from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on Devonshire
Street.  Within a few paces they encountered an acquaintance
of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>'s.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúMr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pincus,‚Äù</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>,
‚ÄúI want you should meet mine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Ober</ENAMEX>.  He's the finest figurehead in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
True enough, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a lightning calculator
and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> at solving arithmetical puzzles.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> incident occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years later</TIMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1960</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> to
have his aortic aneurysm repaired by the distinguished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael DeBakey</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> was a
great success, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> afterward my father
received a get-well card from Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>.  The
picture was suitable enough, but the handwritten
message read, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúDear Harry</ENAMEX> - Hoping this will be
your last <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>....‚Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, one rarely hears the echt Litvisch accent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> has largely died
off, and its progeny have become Americanized.  We
lose in color what we gain in homogeneity.

         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Webster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Dictionary</ENAMEX>
            This dictionary might be said to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Random House Dictionary of the English Language</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">- College Edition</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, of which I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> (with the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart B. Flexner</ENAMEX> as managing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College</ENAMEX>
Dictionary [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACD</ENAMEX> ], <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence L.</ENAMEX>
Barnhart was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief.  There are, naturally,
many resemblances among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>
Edition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revised Edition</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, reviewed in Volume
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> (pp. 172ff. in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">VERBATIM: Volumes</ENAMEX>
I & <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> ).  Before discussing the content, I may be allowed
a comment on the title.

            It is taken as given in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictionary business</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dictionary bears</ENAMEX> the name ‚ÄúWebster‚Äù
it magically attracts sales far beyond those of a
dictionary that tries to rely for its success on quality
alone.  Compared to the soft-drink <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, that is
like saying that all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola drinks</ENAMEX> ought to be called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>, though one would be legally enjoined
from doing so.  Not so with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> , for, owing to a
bit of folly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G. & C. Merriam Company</ENAMEX>,
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> to the line
of dictionaries originated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Webster</ENAMEX>, published
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">synonym dictionary</ENAMEX> and called it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Publishing Company</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, had the
wit to see that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam</ENAMEX> had, in effect, forsworn its
birthright, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah</ENAMEX> had never published a synonym
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>.  World called its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary Webster's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World ; Merriam</ENAMEX> sued and lost, confirming that
the appellation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> had fallen into the public
domain.  That is why virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dictionary
of any shape, size, provenance, comprehensiveness,
quality, and lexicographic persuasion is
likely to be called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.

            When I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the reference department
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, at meetings
held with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett Cerf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Klopfer</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lew Miller</ENAMEX>, sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, we often touched on the
matter of what the new dictionary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACD</ENAMEX> , was to be called.  It was pointed out then that
including the name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> in the title would be
likely to increase the sales by a measurable amount;
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>, staunchly independent and
proud of the successes gained in the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> , would not hear of it.  It was I who proposed
the original title for the series of dictionaries
published from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> onwards: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dictionary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Language</ENAMEX> - Unabridged
Edition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Edition, School Edition</ENAMEX> , and any
other subtitles that might come along.  From what I
know of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>, the decision to include
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> in the title of this book has probably set
them spinning in their graves.

            There is another aspect to this change: lamentably,
it emphasizes the abiding ignorance and gullibility
of the dictionary-buying public.  Anyone who
compares the multifarious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dictionaries</ENAMEX> bearing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> name cannot help observing the differences
in quality, quantity, and treatment offered: the name
has become meaningless, made inferior by its universal
application to virtually any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>.

            While I am making general observations, I
might add, for the record, that my review of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House College</ENAMEX> was not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">favourable</ENAMEX> because it was based on an examination of
the entries mentioned in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jess Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preface</ENAMEX>: I had,
out of a feeling of sympathetic and loyal association
with the book's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> edition, which still constituted
more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety per cent</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> edition, selected
for analysis the words mentioned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preface</ENAMEX>
on the premise that they were ‚Äúshowcase‚Äù entries
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> were especially proud of.  As
it turned out, I was compelled to point out several
glaring errors in most of those entries, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jess Stein</ENAMEX>
never spoke to me again.  I must confess to being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">displeased at Stein</ENAMEX>'s having removed my name from
the title page of a book only slightly changed from
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> edition so that he could insert his own as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief; but that was nothing new for him, as
he had deleted from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> editions of the ACD the
name of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence L. Barnhart</ENAMEX>, to
insert his own.  So much for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De</ENAMEX> mortuis ...

            The present work contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180,000</NUMEX> entries,
fully <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> more than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> edition and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>
more than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> edition.  It would be a waste of
time to go through the editions noting the differences:
in most cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> followed the wise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictum</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄúIf it ain't broke, don't fix it,‚Äù so little has
been done to the basic information in the original
edition.  The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collegiate</ENAMEX> introduced the practice of giving, in the
etymologies, ‚Äúdates of earliest occurrence,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù</ENAMEX> data
presumably derived from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX>
(for, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>
maintained a citation file for the tracking of new
words and senses, there was no point in duplicating
work done long ago by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>).  It is questionable
to what purpose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of dictionaries are to
put this information.  Naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>--by far the majority--are
bound to misinterpret the dates as meaning
‚Äúwhen the word <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared in the language‚Äù
rather than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as ‚</NUMEX>Äúthe date of the earliest recorded evidence
found (at press time).<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Moreover</ENAMEX>, the date
cannot be associated with any particular definition,
so it is a bit misleading, for an entry like log , which
has several definitions, to show it as having entered
the language ‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äú1350</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1400.‚</NUMEX>Äù In which sense?  And
what is to be made of the following?:


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.  All numbers, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> through twelve, are
listed as having entered <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English ‚Äúbefore 900‚</ENAMEX>Äù except
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, for which ‚Äúbef. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1000‚</NUMEX>Äù is given.  Are we
to conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got along without the
number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years</TIMEX> before someone,
perhaps feeling that ‚Äúsomething was missing,‚Äù
awoke <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> to invent it?

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.  If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> looks up the ordinals, the following
information is revealed:

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first     ‚Äúbef.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1000‚Äù   tenth</NUMEX>         ‚Äúbef. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1150‚</NUMEX>Äù
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>    ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Äú1250-1300‚Äù   eleventh      ‚Äúbef.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1000‚</NUMEX>Äù
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>     ‚Äúbef. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">900‚Äù</NUMEX>    <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">twelfth       ‚Äúbef</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1200‚</NUMEX>Äù
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>    ‚Äúbef. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">950‚Äù    seventeenth   ‚Äú1300-50‚</ENAMEX>Äù
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>     ‚Äúbef. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1000‚Äù</NUMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eighteenth    ‚Äúbef</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900‚</NUMEX>Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sixth     ‚Äú1520-30‚Äù     twentieth     ‚Äúbef.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900‚</NUMEX>Äù
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>   ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Äú1275-1325‚Äù   fortieth      ‚Äúbef.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1100‚</NUMEX>Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eighth    ‚Äúbef</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1000‚Äù</NUMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fiftieth      ‚Äúbef</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1000‚</NUMEX>Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ninth     ‚Äúbef.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">900‚Äù</NUMEX>    <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eightieth     ‚Äúbef</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">850‚</NUMEX>Äù

            

            To be sure, there is nothing to justify the assumption
that the names of the numbers emerged in numerical
order from the primeval ooze of language; but
one might mistakenly conclude that the very first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ordinal</ENAMEX> to be talked about in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> was eightieth ,
and this at a time when only a small percentage of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> had a life expectancy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> that.
And it might be imagined that in giving directions to
get to one's hovel, one would say, ‚ÄúGo to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
hovel, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> is the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,‚Äù for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> did not
come into being till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixteenth century</TIMEX>.  One
would expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to have signaled the truth
of the matter under <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Using This Dictionary</ENAMEX>, despite
the reluctance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to refer to such things.  But
no; here is the only comment:


when and how the word entered our language,
including the date that it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared and its
source or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in other languages

            

            The redundancy of when and the date that is confusing
enough; but to describe the date as when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">word ‚Äúfirst</ENAMEX> appeared‚Äù is grossly misleading and inaccurate:
it is the date for the earliest written evidence
of the form.  That might seem a niggling
point, but dictionaries dwell (and thrive) on niggling
points, and such misstatements are unforgivable.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> would have been on safer ground had
they simply followed the wording in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Unabridged</ENAMEX> , to wit:


Most dates are expressed as a spread of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>,
giving the time within which the earliest document
containing the main entry was written or
published....  In many cases a term may have
existed in the spoken language long before it first
appeared in texts and, in any event, earlier written
evidence may exist that has not yet been discovered
or reported.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p. xxxiv</ENAMEX>]

            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of college dictionaries in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> provides an outstanding textbook demonstration
of the principles of competitive free enterprise
at work and of what used to be called supply and
demand, but is now dubbed ‚Äúmarket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  There
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major dictionaries of approximately the
same size competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> in the market.  It is
impossible to get an accurate figure for the total
market, which has been estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX>
sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX> steadfastly refuse to reveal
their sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> because of the highly competitive
nature of the business, though it is generally acknowledged
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth New Collegiate</ENAMEX>
outsells its nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
That nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> is probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s New
World, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3rd Edition</ENAMEX> , with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House College</ENAMEX>
(occupying a niche to be filled by the book under
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heritage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2nd Edition</ENAMEX> neck
and neck for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> place, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webster's II New Riverside</ENAMEX>
bringing up the rear in this horserace.  These
are only guesses.
