
   
      
         
            The Past As Prologue



            The diary that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Pepys</ENAMEX> kept from the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day of 1660</TIMEX> till he thought he was losing his
eyesight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight and a half years later</TIMEX> can tell us a lot
about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language has changed or remained
more or less constant over the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and a
half <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>.  There may be other sources equally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> in examples for comparison, but there can hardly
be another that is at the same time so much fun to read
and accessible.  Moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration</ENAMEX> period
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pepys</ENAMEX> kept his diary is a good time to compare
with ours, because by then the basis of modern English
had been laid down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabethans</ENAMEX>.

            For a mechanical and therefore objective lexical
comparison I did a spelling check with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Q&A</ENAMEX> software
on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> paragraphs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 7</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, cover story on anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Sawyer</ENAMEX>
and on the slightly longer first entry in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary</ENAMEX> ,
dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1660</TIMEX>.  Except for proper
names, the spelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">checker</ENAMEX> stopped on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> paragraphs that were not in its lexicon:
show- biz and credentialed .  Likewise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s entry gave pause to the checker, though
they are not so much lost words as obsolete forms of
words: hath and doth .  I should add that where Pepys
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phonetically</ENAMEX> wrote then he meant than and that he
used the adjective handsome to describe his financial
condition, as we would rarely do today.  Nevertheless,
the spelling-check test provides some indication
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vocabulary</ENAMEX> has not discarded as
many words over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three centuries</TIMEX> as one
might expect.  Our vocabulary has rather been
swollen by these centuries of technological breakthroughs
and social and political revolutions.

            Though such words as betimes and whither and
such forms as doth and hath have dropped out of
ordinary usage, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of
average education can read most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Diary</ENAMEX> without
encountering any word that would send him to
his dictionary.  In fact, so rapidly does our vocabulary
continue to expand by the addition of such technical
neologisms as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> or star wars and such borrowings
as zaftig and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ayatollah</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX> could well be more taxed to know the meanings
of all the words in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> than to
understand all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary</ENAMEX> .

            Besides the lexicon, grammar--especially syntax--has
changed somewhat, too, though again not
so much as to be incomprehensible to the average
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>.  On the one hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s English
may seem slightly stilted or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical</ENAMEX> by modern standards,
with frequent absolute constructions and the
use of do as an auxiliary for affirmative verbs where
no emphasis is intended, as, for example, in his entry
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 31, 1662</TIMEX>, where he thanks ‚ÄúAlmighty
God, who doth most manifestly bless me in my endeavors
to do the duty of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--I now saving
money, and my expenses being very little.‚Äù  This casual
use of the auxiliary do seems to be creeping back
into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> usage, especially among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX> for
some reason, who are increasingly wont to announce,
‚ÄúAs the catch of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, we do have red
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snapper</ENAMEX>....<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Ordinarily</ENAMEX>, though, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
speech the auxiliary do is reserved for negative or
interrogative statements as in Don't do it or Do you
do it?  or for emphasis, particularly in rebuttal, as in
But I do do it !  We have gained a handy distinction
here.  On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, while familiar
enough to us, may sound slightly nonstandard,
as where past-tense forms and past participles are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalesced</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pepys</ENAMEX> writes, just as we might say but
ought not write, ‚Äú... running up and down...
with their arses bare... being beat by the watch.‚Äù
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 23, 1668</TIMEX>)

            The progressive tense occurs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary</ENAMEX> ,
as for example in his entry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 1665</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúShe</ENAMEX> was dressing herself by the fire...and there
took occasion to show me her leg‚Äù; but he uses it
much less than we do.  For us it has practically replaced
the future tense, as when we say, ‚ÄúI'm going
to town <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Contractions</ENAMEX> are even rarer in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Diary</ENAMEX> but do occur, for example in his entry for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 9, 1667</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúSays that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knepp</ENAMEX> won't take
pains enough...‚Äù

            More surprising than evident but relatively insignificant
differences between the language in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys's Diary</ENAMEX> and our everyday language are the
words and expressions that have persisted in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than three centuries</TIMEX> without having ever
gained full acceptance.  For instance, take I when
compounded with another pronoun or a noun in the
objective case, as in: Between you and I ....  Even
educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> nowadays often use I in combinations
where me is prescribed.  There is an academic
legend that this solecism is a hypercorrection forced
into our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American English</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of
schoolmarms pounded into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of generations
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> that they must not say me in such
combinations as me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> done it .  Not so.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX>
Pepys, never confused by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolmarm</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invariably</ENAMEX>, so far as I have found, used I instead
of me when the pronoun was combined with
another pronoun or noun as the object of a verb or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preposition</ENAMEX>.  To cite a few examples: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú... did take
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queenes</ENAMEX> presence-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>
...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 22, 1660</TIMEX>); ‚Äú... who pleased my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I ...‚Äù (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 27, 1660</TIMEX>); ‚Äú... Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> talking with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I...‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 20</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1663</TIMEX>); ‚Äú... if God send my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I to live ...‚Äù
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 8, 1667</TIMEX>); and ‚ÄúThis <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> up, with mighty
kind words between my poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1668</TIMEX>).  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys</ENAMEX> does not use they and its inflected
forms as an indefinite singular pronoun
nearly as commonly as we do in such constructions
as ‚ÄúEveryone on their feet!‚Äù, but in his entry for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20, 1668</TIMEX>, he writes ‚Äú... everybody endeavouring
to excuse themselfs.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  And</ENAMEX> in his entry
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 14, 1667</TIMEX>, we find ‚Äú... till they send
for me‚Äù where the subject is no one in particular.
Similarly, who in the objective case appears to have
been on the threshold of acceptance into standard
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than three hundred years</TIMEX>.  Pepys
repeatedly uses the pronoun so, for instance: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>, who I took in and drank with‚Äù (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1667</TIMEX>).  However, in his entry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 7, 1668</TIMEX>, we
find: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú... whom I was pleased with all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>....
‚ÄùAs for lay for lie , whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of usage has by now
almost won acceptance into the standard language,
we find in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s entry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22, 1667</TIMEX>:
‚Äú... found not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on board her [a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>] (and her
laying so near them was a main temptation to them
to come on).<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  (Compare this with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kipling</ENAMEX>'s ‚ÄúWhere
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Flotilla lay‚</ENAMEX>Äù where lay is the past tense of
lie .)

            There are also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s Diary words and
phrases that have been admitted to our standard language
but that still sound a bit colloquial.  This is me,
which we find in his entry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 31, 1667</TIMEX>, has
finally been accepted into standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, though
it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three centuries</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX>'s fiat
to do it.  When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pepys</ENAMEX> writes mad, usually he means
angry, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do today: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú... which
makes our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> mad‚Äù (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 9, 1664</TIMEX>).  Telling
of annoyances on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 10, 1667</TIMEX>, he twice
writes: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú... which did make me mad,‚Äù as well as:
‚ÄúI begun heartily to sweat and be angry <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">...‚Äù Today</ENAMEX>
this meaning of mad is more at home in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
than in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British English</ENAMEX>.  The same can be said of certain
other of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s locutions, for example the past
participle gotten instead of got: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú... who were by
this time gotten most of them drunk‚Äù (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1666</TIMEX>).

            In general, one tends to find confirmed in the
language of the Diary the relative conservatism of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> as contrasted with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>.
So far as dialects are concerned, I know British
dialects too little to say.  But there is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary a</ENAMEX>
locution that I have encountered only there, I believe
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, and commonly, though less
and less, in the speech of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>: like(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)
to ... as in ‚ÄúThat ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> like to of killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hisself‚</NUMEX>Äù or
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s entry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14, 1660</TIMEX>:‚Äú... the purser
... had like to have been drowned had it not been
for a rope.‚Äù

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three hundred years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys</ENAMEX> the general
drift of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> has been towards a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> kind
of grammer with loss and confusion of inflection and
with phrases used as words.  A carelessness about inflection
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> is shown above with the examples
of the objective I and who .  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rarer</ENAMEX> back then
was the use of whole phrases as single words as, for
instance: to quickly and efficiently do this job, where
the verb and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adverbs</ENAMEX> are treated together as a
so-called split infinitive marked by to, instead of the
prescribed to do this job quickly and efficiently,
where only do is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">infinitive</ENAMEX> marked as such by to
and modified by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> adverbs.  So it comes as something
of a surprise to find a clause in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1662 Diary</ENAMEX>
that sounds like wording in a television commercial:
‚ÄúI saw the so much by me desired picture of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Castlemayne</ENAMEX>....<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 20</TIMEX>).  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys</ENAMEX> also
has a tendency to omit subject pronouns, reminding
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of television commercials: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúHad a bowl of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whamo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>.  Feel great!‚Äù a trim, muscular
type in a TV commercial might exclaim, sounding
rather like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pepys</ENAMEX> when he wrote over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three centuries</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, ‚ÄúDined with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephens...‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1660</TIMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúLay long in bed...‚Äù (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 1660</TIMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys's Diary</ENAMEX> owes its eventual status as a classic
to its candor and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s privileged position
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration England</ENAMEX>.  But he did
have a style of his own that should be taken into
consideration in any evaluation of the language of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Diary</ENAMEX> .  His <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, as suits the dairy of so exuberant
and impatient a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a stenographer
among other things, strikes us as almost telegraphic
in its compression.  It is doubtful that in conversation
he would ever remark, ‚ÄúUp early ...‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúUp betimes...,‚Äù
the phrases with which he so often begins
his dairy entries.  But allowing that the language
is well adapted to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stenographer</ENAMEX>'s very private diary
and of its particular time and place, we find little
that is obscurely archaic in its style.  Despite such
interesting differences as are noted above, the language
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepys</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, however dated, is not generically
unlike what we might expect to find in a
secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> kept by a yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> of our
times.

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reference</ENAMEX> throughout this essay is to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Diary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Pepys</ENAMEX> , edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Latham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California Press</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>.]
         
         
            A Few Words (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">235 To Be Exact</ENAMEX>) About the 1980s



            Abortion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acquisition</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayatollah</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Acid rain</ENAMEX>.  Air
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordans</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Arbitragers</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ALF</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>.  Arms control.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>
Light.  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blush wine</ENAMEX>.  B1.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Ball</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bran</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bimbos</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> boomer.  Bailouts.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúBig.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Brat Pack</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernhard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goetz</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crocodile Dundee</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corazon</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúCats.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  Calvins</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camcorder</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classic Coke</ENAMEX>.  Crack.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CW</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX>.  Compact discs.  Car
phones.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colorization</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Couch potatoes</ENAMEX>.

            Deal.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>.  Deregulation.  Deficit
spending.  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett Koop</ENAMEX>.  ERA. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.T.  Ewoks</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falkland Islands</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferdinand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imelda</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fitness</ENAMEX>.
Fax.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fergie</ENAMEX>.  Gene mapping.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo</ENAMEX>.
Glasnost.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gretzky</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenpeace</ENAMEX>.  Greenmail.
Global warming.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ghostbusters</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handguns</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hacker</ENAMEX>.  Hostile takeovers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>
equity loans.  Homeless.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyundai</ENAMEX>.  IRA.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iacocca</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatible.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Boesky</ENAMEX>.  Junk
bonds.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tammy</ENAMEX>.  Jarvik heart.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Isuzu</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kitaro</ENAMEX>.  Laptops.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX>.  Leveraged buyout.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Skywalker</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lech Walesa</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúLes Mis√©rables.</ENAMEX>‚Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mujahedeen</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Milken</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muesli</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX>.  Merger.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Fox</ENAMEX>.  Magnetic resonance scanner.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey, Jr.</ENAMEX> New Age.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>.  National
debt.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ollie North</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ozone</ENAMEX> depletion.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX>.
PC.  Poison <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúPhantom of the Opera</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Poindexter</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTL Club</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qadhafi</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganomics</ENAMEX>.  Rust belt.  Range <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rover</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin & Mike</ENAMEX>.  ‚ÄúRead my lips.<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù  Roseanne</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Steroids</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stealth</ENAMEX>.  Short <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Round</ENAMEX>.  Sound bite.  Star
Wars.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>.  Significant
Other.  SDI.  Tax reform.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tofu</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taipan</ENAMEX>.  Terrorism.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage Mutant Ninja</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Turtles</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Umberto Eco</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanna</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horton</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Windham Hill</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúWhere</ENAMEX>'s the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef?‚Äù  Yugo</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeager</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            Lest We Forget



            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúAnd</ENAMEX> now,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> announced the quizmaster, ‚Äúfor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> prize, including wealth beyond description,
just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more questions.  Remember you must
answer promptly.  First, explain E=<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mc¬≤</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            --‚ÄúThis is the equivalence of mass and energy,
with c the speed of light.  Simple ....‚Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúCorrect.</ENAMEX>  Now, what is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hegelian</ENAMEX> absolute?‚Äù

            --‚ÄúThe all-inclusive totality of reality.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> must,
of course, mention the schema of immediacy--
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">negation</ENAMEX>--negation of negation....‚Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúQuite</ENAMEX> so.  Now, the final question.  How many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> are there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>?‚Äù ... [pause] ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BUZZ</ENAMEX>!]
‚Äú... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is up.  I'm sorry.  You lose.‚Äù

            What happended?  The unfortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX>
simply knew his physics and philosophy,
and recall was immediate.  Since there is no logic to
the lengths of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, he had facilitated memory of
them with a mnemonic device.  Before the answer
could be given, he had to summon up a variation on
the venerable theme--


<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty days</TIMEX> hath <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April, June</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>;
All the rest have thirty-one,
Excepting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> alone,
And that has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-eight days</TIMEX> clear
And <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> in each leap year.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevins MS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">c. 1555</ENAMEX>), quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Dictionary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quotations, 3rd, ed.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Univ</ENAMEX>. Press, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>.
            

            --and time expired while the verse was internally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recited</ENAMEX>.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, probably to be difficult, points out a
visual mnemonic for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> lengths--something involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">knuckles</ENAMEX>.  Indeed, visual mnemonics were
used by classical orators so they could speak without
notes.  Points to be made were assigned to various
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loci</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> then mentally toured
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> while delivering the speech.  Our use
of ‚Äúin the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, etc.) place‚Äù is an offshoot of
this method.  Because this is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúThe Language Quarterly</ENAMEX>,‚Äù
further discussion will be limited to mnemonics
using language.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mnemonics</ENAMEX> actually are codes for associated,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> facts.  Their techniques of encryption may
be divided into: reduction coding, which minimizes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> to be stored (e.g., acronyms: reducing words
to single letters); and elaboration coding, which
strengthens weakly linked memory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> by
adding material (e.g., rhymes, and epi-acronyms: in
which initial letters of words in phrases are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">code</ENAMEX>).  Having a mnemonic is no panacea.  For example,
to recover the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Lakes</ENAMEX> one must first remember
a mnemonic (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HOMES</ENAMEX>, or, going west to east,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúSergeant- M ajor H ates E ating O nions‚Äù</ENAMEX> ), and then
decrypt it.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Erie</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Superior</ENAMEX> are nowhere in the brain, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HOMES</ENAMEX> will
not put them there.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poetry</ENAMEX> is an ancient mnemonic device.  The Biblical
psalmist undoubtedly used the combination of
the verse form and an abecedarius to remember
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Psalm 119</ENAMEX>, each of whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> octaves begins
with a successive letter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> alphabet.
Though it is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iliad</ENAMEX> , all young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spellers</ENAMEX> know the
rhyme mnemonic


I before E
Except after C
Or when pronounced A
As in neighbour and weigh
            

            so well that they are destined chronically to misspell
seizure .  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ogden Nash</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orthographist</ENAMEX>'s mnemonic, of
more limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>, at least has no exceptions--


The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-l <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lama</ENAMEX>,
He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-l llama,
He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>.
And I will bet
A silk pajama
There isn't any
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>-l lllama.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThe Lama‚</ENAMEX>Äù in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ogden Nash</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Wheeling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schuster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>.
            

            Mnemonics were life-preservers in the stormtossed
educational seas of my youth.  They rescued
me in spelling (‚ÄúThe princi <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>), physics
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy G. Biv</ENAMEX> , or maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Of York Gains Battles</ENAMEX>
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vain</ENAMEX>
               , for the order of the spectrum's colors--
and mathematics.  (A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter century</TIMEX> after high
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trigonometry</ENAMEX>, about all I can remember of it
is the benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian ‚ÄúSoh-Cah-Toa‚Äù</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sine</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">o pposite</ENAMEX>/ hy potenuse,
C <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">osine</TIMEX> = a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">djacent/ hy potenuse,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">angent</ENAMEX>= <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">o pposite</ENAMEX>/ a djacent, relating the lengths of
the right triangle's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> to the functions of its angles).
In science class I learned the planets, by distance
from the sun <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">(‚Äú M ary V ery E arly M ade J</ENAMEX> ane
S ome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> nusually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N ice P</ENAMEX> ies‚Äù--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uranus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neptune</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pluto</ENAMEX> ), and the functions of living things (‚ÄúSensible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> otorists <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> efrain F rom <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> riving A utomobiles A t E xcessive
R ates‚Äù--sensation, movement, respiration,
food-taking, digestion, absorption, assimilation, excretion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reproduction</ENAMEX>).  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> I could recite
the hills of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> (and would have suffered less had I
known ‚Äú C an Q ueen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V ictoria E</ENAMEX> at C old A pple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P ie?‚Äù</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitoline, Quirinal, Viminal, Esquiline</ENAMEX>,
Caelian, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aventine, Palatine</ENAMEX>), and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> could deal with calends (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX>,
right?).  As for nones and ides , forget it.  Had I but
learned the rhyme--


In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March, July</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ides</ENAMEX> are on the fifteenth day,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nones</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>; all other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> besides
Have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> less for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nones and IdesJohn Barlett, Familiar Quotations, 13th ed.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>.
            

            --I might be a classicist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            Instead, I proceeded to that hotbed of mnemonics,
medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.  [I wish to assure non-physician
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> do not, as a rule, think of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' problems as word games.  When memory
fails, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> actually look things up.]  Suffice it to
say, after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> pages or so, the plot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anatomy</ENAMEX> wears thin, even for the most avid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thence</ENAMEX> emerges the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">insight--‚</ENAMEX>ÄúI can't remember
all this stuff.‚Äù  In desperation, I learned
such acrostics as novel (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nerve, Artery, Vein</ENAMEX>, Empty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">space, Lymphatic</ENAMEX>--inguinal structures, from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lateral</ENAMEX>
to medical) and bitem (appropriately, the muscles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mastication</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buccinator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal</ENAMEX> pterygoid,
Temporalis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">External</ENAMEX> pterygoid, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masseter</ENAMEX>); the
abecedarius of lead poisoning (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anemia</ENAMEX>, Basophilic
stippling, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colic, Dementia, Encephalopathy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foot</ENAMEX>
drop, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingival</ENAMEX> pigmentation ); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (What a
waste of precious brain space!)  epi-acronyms for the
cranial nerves--the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äú O n O ld O lympus</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T owering T op A F inn A</ENAMEX> nd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> erman <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX> iewed S ome
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> ops‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olfactory, Optic, Oculomotor, Trochlear</ENAMEX>,
Trigeminal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abducens, Facial, Glossopharyngeal, Vagus</ENAMEX>,
Spinal accessory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hypoglossal</ENAMEX>), and the more
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äú O h O h O h T o T ouch A nd F eel A</ENAMEX> 
               G <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">irl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX> agina-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AH</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">!‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [Having passed anatomy, practising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> usually refer to these nerves as I-XII.]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lively</ENAMEX>, preferably lewd, imagery was appreciated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who kept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with cadavers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>.
The bones of the wrist (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navicular, Lunate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trique-trum</ENAMEX>,
Pisiform, greater <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Multangular</ENAMEX>, lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Multangular</ENAMEX>,
Capitate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamate</ENAMEX>) were brought to mind by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äú N</ENAMEX> ever L ower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">illie</ENAMEX>'s P <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M amma M ight C</ENAMEX> ome
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> ome.‚Äù  For those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> with severe anatomy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">burnout (‚</ENAMEX>ÄúI can't remember anything !‚Äù)  we devised
the acronyms teon (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Eyes, One Nose</ENAMEX>), and, for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, sew (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shoulder-Elbow-Wrist</ENAMEX>).

            It is the consensus of mnemonists that the more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bizarre</ENAMEX>, sharp, or humorous the image, the more effective
the mnemonic.  How can one forget <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohm</ENAMEX>'s
Law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volts</ENAMEX>=<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amps √ó Resistance</ENAMEX>, given <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äú V</ENAMEX> irgins A re
R are.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> ?  Heteronyms, absent extraneous verbiage,
reinforce the standard-daylight time changer,
‚ÄúSpring ahead, fall back.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Conversely</ENAMEX>, who remembers
the bass clef lines and spaces (with, respectively,
the insipid ‚Äú <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> reat B ig D ogs F ight A nimals‚Äù
and ‚Äú A ll C ars E at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> as‚Äù )?  The treble clef lines
are only a bit more memorable (‚Äú E very <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> ood B oy
D oes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F ine‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú E very <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> rizzly B ear D igs <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F igs‚Äù</ENAMEX> ); its spaces' notes, at least, crisply spell face .  Who
knows how many musical aspirations have been
dashed against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass clef</ENAMEX>, for want of adequate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mnemonics</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coherent</ENAMEX>, grammatical sentences can make effective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mnemonics</ENAMEX> because language structure is already
in place in our minds.  Witness, for the taxonomic
division of living things, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">‚Äú</ENAMEX> King 
               Phi lip  C ame
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> ver <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ene</ENAMEX>'s Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety ‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>, phylum,
class, order, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, genus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, variety).  On the
other hand, I find this one for pi, coding digits by
word lengths,


Now I sing a silly roundelay
Of radial roots, and utter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚ÄúLackaday</ENAMEX>!
Euclidean results imperfect are, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>...
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mnemonic</ENAMEX> arts employ<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">!‚ÄùWillard Espy, An Almanac of Words at Play</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarkson N. Potter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>.
            

            more difficult to remember, with its tortured word
order, than the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> places of pi it yields.

            Even the best mnemonics are not free of drawbacks.
Rules or lists may change, thus rendering the
mnemonics obsolete.  A key religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
history-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">st. dapiacl</ENAMEX> --gave us the presidential
cabinet posts in order of their creation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Postmaster General</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>), critical
to answering ‚ÄúAccording to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Succession Act</ENAMEX>, who is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> in line to the presidency?‚Äù
Subsequent deletions and additions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmaster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX>,
Energy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>, in) would yield stdaiaclhhtee ,
not really the most pronounceable acronym, at least
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  Nevertheless, the good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. D.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retired</ENAMEX>, is still occupying a good number of my cerebral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurons</ENAMEX> and synapses.

            Worse is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-recalled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mnemonic</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> may
remember <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> is a mnemonic, but forget what it is
a mnemonic for.  My personal albatross is the couplet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúEight</ENAMEX> ever/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine</ENAMEX> never‚Äù which has to do with taking
a fitnesse in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>, and how many cards my side
has in the suit; to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>' distress, I forget the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finesse</ENAMEX>--against the king, or against the queen--to
which the rule applies.

            Can we ever discard a good, though unnecessary,
mnemonic, or are we forever doomed to have
delayed responses as these jingles, on cue, run
through our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>?  Does a sea <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> think ‚Äúport,‚Äù
or, rather, ‚Äú <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> letters--same as left ‚Äù?
When he enters a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX>, does he know the red nun
buoys mark the right side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, or must the
alliterative ‚ÄúRed right returning‚Äù come to mind
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>?  Can property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> forget on each ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> pen,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> otorious, E xclusive, A ctual, C ontinuous, H ostile)
when recalling the requisites for adverse possession
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squatter</ENAMEX>'s rights, to us not of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>)?  Do speleologists
remember which of those things in caves is
which, without having to hear that little internal
voice <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chant ‚Äústala c tite</ENAMEX>--c--ceiling; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stala g mite</ENAMEX>--
g--ground‚Äù?

            We collect and preserve mnemonics, however
redundant, as insurance against embarrassing lapsus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memoriae</ENAMEX> .  They are not foolproof.  According to Sir
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Coke</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄúIt is ... necessary that memorable
things should be committed to writing, (the witness
of times, the light and the life of truth) and not
wholly betaken to slippery memory which seldom
yields a certain reckoning.‚Äù  For those of us who
forget to take the shopping list to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>,
let alone calendars and rosters of planets and cabinet
posts, memory will have to do.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forsan et</ENAMEX> haec olim
meminisse iuvabit.
               
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevins MS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">c. 1555</ENAMEX>), quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Dictionary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quotations, 3rd, ed.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Univ</ENAMEX>. Press, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan D. Baddeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Psychology of Learning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic</ENAMEX>
Books, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willard Espy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another Almanac of Words at Play</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarkson N. Potter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThe Lama‚</ENAMEX>Äù in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ogden Nash</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Wheeling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schuster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan D. Baddeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Psychology of Learning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic</ENAMEX>
Books, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>.
            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> provides ‚Äú <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M y V ery E ducated M other J</ENAMEX> ust
Served <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U s N ine P</ENAMEX> ickles.‚Äù  From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979 to 1999</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pluto</ENAMEX> is closer to the sun than is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neptune</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willard Espy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another Almanac of Words at Play</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarkson N. Potter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Barlett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Familiar Quotations, 13th ed.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bloomfield and E. Ted Chandler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocket</ENAMEX>
Mnemonics for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Practitioners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbinger Medical</ENAMEX>
Press, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winston-Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gyles Brandreth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Joy of Lex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>.
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John W. Schaum</ENAMEX> Note <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Speller Book One, Belwyn</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Grambs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Words About Words</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGraw-Hill</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willard Espy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Almanac of Words at Play</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarkson N. Potter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>.
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Les Reports de Edward Coke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vol.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1,p</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1660</TIMEX>) as
quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Respectfully Quoted, Suzy, Platt, ed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>.
            Lacking a mnemonic for it, I had to look up this
quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aeneid</ENAMEX>, but perhaps some
day it will be pleasant to remember even these
things.
         
         
            Stuff and Nonsense



            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the wonders of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language is
that it contains so many words about words
themselves.  Among the most colorful and intriguing
are those that describe the piffle, prattle, twaddle,
and flapdoodle that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in all talks of life tend to
spew forth.  Here is a small start on a glossary of glossolalia,
a demidictionary of drivel that lists the varieties
of verbal obfuscation and explains the etymologies
of these often playful terms.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applesauce</ENAMEX> (an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> variant is apple <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">sass</ENAMEX> ),
which has come to designate a `camouflage of flattery,'
is excessively sweet, mushy, pulpy and insubstantial,
and thrifty boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> serve an abundance
of the stuff to divert awareness from the
scarcity of more nourishing fare.  A similar connection
is made between senseless banter and baloney,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eponymously</TIMEX> descended from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bologna</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> turned out a type of sausage
crammed with odds and ends from slaughter, including,
some say, assmeat.  It is but a short step from the
cheapest ground cold cuts to cheap talk, and the
same steps takes up from tripe, the walks of the first
and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stomachs of ruminants,' to `worthless,
foolish speech.'  Adding to the pile of verbal garbage
is balderdash, which reaches back to the late 16th
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> and originally meant a `hodgepodge of liquors,
such as wine mixed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>,' perfect for
washing down a mishmash of pretentious and frivolous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blather</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosh</ENAMEX> looks as typically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> as balderdash,
yet it actually descends from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
adjective bos `empty, useless.'  The word became
popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 19th century</TIMEX>
through the oriental romances and memories of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
Morier, who enhanced his exotic tales with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
terms.

            Spook etymology misinforms us that babble is a
Biblical reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Genesis 11.17</ENAMEX>, in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Babel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX>) built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> reaching to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heaven</ENAMEX> and incited God to confound their language.
The less romantic truth is that babble descends from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle English</ENAMEX> babelon and is probably of imitative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origin</ENAMEX>, echoing the ba ba sounds typically made
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> in their repetitive chatter.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blarney</ENAMEX> and
bunk, on the other hand, do hail from the names of
actual places.  Blarney refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blarney stone</ENAMEX>,
located in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blarney Castle</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cork</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>.  Those who kiss the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blarney stone</ENAMEX> are reputed
to be able to charm the pants off everyone
ever after.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bunk</ENAMEX> is a shortening of bunkum, itself a
respelling for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buncomber County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>,
whose congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> once remarked
that he was ‚Äúonly talking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buncombe</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            
               Claptrap turns out to be a show biz metaphor
for high-sounding but empty language.  The word
was originally a theatrical term for a showy trick or
patch of high-flown, grandiose language that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
would use to attract (`trap') applause (`<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claps</ENAMEX>') from
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>.  Another rhyming reduplication,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mumbo</ENAMEX> jumbo, is probably borrowed from a word in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> Mandingo: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama Dyumbo</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deity</ENAMEX> who
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> to bewilder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> whom they suspected
of talking too much.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cowper</ENAMEX> once wrote ‚Äúphilologists
who trace<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">panting</ENAMEX> syllable through time and
space,/Start it at home, and hunt it in the dark/To
Gaul, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, and into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ark.‚Äù  Almost</ENAMEX> always,
an etymological safari into any subject bags at
least a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.  A cock and bull story, for example,
derives from ancient fables and medieval bestiaries
in which cocks moralized, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bulls expostulated</ENAMEX>,
and a menagerie of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> discoursed in human
language.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockamamie</ENAMEX> has nothing whatever to
do with roosters, talking or otherwise.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> applied increasingly
elaborate beauty spots to their upper cheeks.  This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">craze</ENAMEX> became known as d√©calcomanie, from d√©calc-
(from d√©calquer `transfer a tracing' + - o - + manie
`mania,' whence we get decalcomania ( decal for
short for the transfers), and the adjective cockamamie
some say echoes the sense of florid but superficial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embellishment</ENAMEX>.  Hogwash, of course, is a designation
for language as `worthless, disgusting, and unfit
for human consumption, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig slops</ENAMEX>.'

            Puffy, bureaucratic verbiage if often called gobbledygook,
a word credited to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maury Maverick</ENAMEX>, who compared the tortuous (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">torturous</ENAMEX>) prose of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> to the
senseless gobbling of turkeys.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maverick</ENAMEX> made the
word famous with a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> memorandum denouncing
the bloated language found in government
reports: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúBe short and say what you're talking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>.  Stop `pointing up' programs.  No more `finalizing,'
`effectuating,' or `dynamics.'  Anyone caught
using the words `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX>' or `implementation' will
be shot.‚Äù  Closely related to gobbledygook, but more
Council of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teachers</ENAMEX> of English established a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Doublespeak</ENAMEX> to help identify and
stamp out evasive and obfuscating terminology slithering
out of public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, such as ‚Äúuncontrolled
contact with the ground‚Äù for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúairplane crash‚Äù</ENAMEX> and
‚Äúinoperative statement‚Äù for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúlie</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Doublespeak</ENAMEX> is a
blending of Double-talk and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Newspeak</ENAMEX>, the insidious
language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Orwell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nineteen Eighty-Four</ENAMEX> .

            A number of loopily echoic words resonate with
the nonsense of non-sense.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folderol</ENAMEX> (or falderal ) is
drawn from the meaningless syllables sung in the refrains
of many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">folksongs</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúfol-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de-rol-deray</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
Tommyrot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compounds tommy</ENAMEX>, `simpleton, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>'
(as in tomfoolery ) and rot, `worthless matter.'  In his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browser</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ciardi</ENAMEX> suggests
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">that ‚Äú tommy</ENAMEX> is a variant of tummy, the sense shift
having been from `stomach garbage' to `brain garbage.'
‚Äù  And poppycock comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pappekak</ENAMEX>,
literally `soft poop' or `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby poop</ENAMEX>,' an appropriately
scatological etymology for logorrhea.

            That we have been able to come up with so
many words to describe forked-tongued and muddle-headed
language indicates that we may one day
not just speak but communicate.  That we have been
so intelligent about identifying unintelligible persiflage
gives hope that we may learn not just to talk
but to say something.
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> sometime in the recent future, a city
beleaguered by the sleaziest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and defended by
a police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
[From a movie listing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robocop</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Washington State</ENAMEX> edition, .  Submitted
by ]
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communication Ravine</ENAMEX>



            For nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I worked
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in a church
school.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Call us ‚Äúmissionaries‚Äù</ENAMEX> to make it simple.)  Of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> different languages in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, we
learned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.  One was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanesian Pidgin</ENAMEX>, which, besides
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiri Motu</ENAMEX>, is one of the official
languages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> language we
learned was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K√¢te</ENAMEX> (pronounced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">kaw-tay</ENAMEX>), an area language
spoken by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only several thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.  Living
and working overseas with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of another
culture and language made us realize how complicated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> can be.

            Speech is the most obvious form of communication.
But using speech to communicate is more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> said,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù ‚Äúhe</ENAMEX> said,‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthey said.‚Äù  Sometimes the
words we use are the sounds of the communicating:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whispering</ENAMEX>, cackling, prattling, chuckling, chortling,
mumbling, grumbling.  Other words suggest motives
behind the speech: lying, gossiping, negotiating,
plotting.  Speech is certainly more than plugging in
vocabulary words to express a thought.  We had to
learn nuances of meaning which were not found in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dictionaries</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Pidgin</ENAMEX> word tok by itself means ‚Äútalk‚Äù and
its synonyms, in both verb and noun forms.  Whereas
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> there are totally different words to express
different aspects of speech, the word tok combines
with other words to define various kinds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>: tokaut `speak out,' tok baksait `gossip,'
toktok `converse,' tok mama `advise,' tok hait
`secret,' tok tru `truth,' tok nogut `foul language,' tok
giaman `lying,' tok pait `argue,' tok ples `local language,'
tok tasol `idea,' tok nating `nonsense,' tok isi
`comfort,' tok pani `joke,' tok strong `emphasize.'

            Voice intonation and body language complicate
the communication process further.  Using no words
at all, you can express joy, sorrow, anger, disgust,
skepticism, ridicule, criticism, fear, and many other
emotions.  Tone of voice, facial expressions, placement
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, and body stance all contribute to nonverbal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> of feelings.  In practical terms,
we had to learn not only to choose our words very
carefully, but to be aware of what we said in nonverbal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>.  We occasionally used in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a ‚Äúsafe‚Äù
language for discussion or making decisions when
there were no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> around.  We were
aware that they were reading the cues of intonation
and body language to get an idea about how the discussion
was going.  We only hoped they would not
misread the cues.  We, too, tried to read their nonverbal
cues when they spoke too quickly for us to
understand or when they used an uncommon language
with which they alone were familiar.

            There can be, however, a danger in relying on a
language for secrecy.  One missionary told of the
time his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> went home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> on furlough.
Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> did not realize others spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>,
but rather thought it was their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s personal, private
language.  So one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, standing in a
customs line in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX>, shouted, ‚ÄúLook, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, see
that great big FAT <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>!?‚Äù

            Even if you become skilled at controlling nonverbal
means of communication, there are still other
cultural assumptions and traditions you cannot know
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> without proper briefing.  We had heard from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ways
of doing things may be insulting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX>.  In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, for example, it is a great insult to offer your
left hand in any way, even handing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> your
money to pay for something.  The left hand is considered
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúdirty‚Äù hand</ENAMEX>, the right hand the ‚Äúclean‚Äù
hand.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, showing the bottom of your foot
is an insult.  This sounds easy enough to avoid until
you consider how many times you cross your legs
when sitting at meetings, on a bus, or in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">PNG</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> hiss and
boo at other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who step across rows of food
spread on the ground at the marketplace, for women
are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúunclean‚Äù</ENAMEX> and must take proper steps to insure
the purity of the food being handled.  Even symbolic
contamination is taken very seriously.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> refused to eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> prepared for
their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>: because one of them had seen some girls
sitting on the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bales</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> stacked in the school pantry,
they considered the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice unclean</ENAMEX> and therefore
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inedible</ENAMEX>.

            Much of what is appropriate in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
not in another, and vice versa.  In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> the first
questions we ask small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with whom we are
confronted are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúWhat</ENAMEX>'s your name<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">?‚Äù</ENAMEX>  and ‚ÄúHow old
are you?‚Äù  In PNG those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions are the wrong
questions to ask.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question is inappropriate
because names are private.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe that
evil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spirits</ENAMEX> can control you if they know your name.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guineans</ENAMEX>, therefore, have several
extra names, depending on who needs to know
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>).  But they have one
private, hidden name which remains a family secret.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question, ‚ÄúHow old are you?‚Äù  is one
which might get you a puzzled look or a blank stare.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, and nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, neither know
nor care when they were born.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> might be
able to tell you, ‚ÄúNow let's see...she was born the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> we had that big flood.‚Äù  But as a practical consideration,
age in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> has nothing to do with anything.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> go to school when the parents and
village <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> feel they are ready for it.  The passing
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> of one's life is celebrated generally for
everyone as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> finishes and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the New Year</TIMEX>
arrives.  The language even reflects this, for the Pidgin
word for `birthday' is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krismas</ENAMEX>.  Besides, their
concept of time is circular, not linear, so marking the
passage of time is not as important as celebrating the
return of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> events.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phrase ‚Äúcommunication gap‚Äù</ENAMEX> takes on new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meanings</ENAMEX> in another culture.  Our views about how
well we are communicating are often misleading; a
better phrase might be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúcommunication ravine</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
There is a classic case (and true, we are told) of a
misunderstanding between a missionary and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cook</ENAMEX>.  The missionary told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> what to prepare
for dinner: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúGo out and catch that old rooster, pluck
it, and put it in the refrigerator.  We'll cook it later.‚Äù
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several hours later</TIMEX> the missionary opened the refrigerator
door only to find one very angry, naked
rooster staring at him: he hadn't told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> to kill
it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.  Meanwhile, what do you suppose the cook
told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> when they asked why he
was so tattered and scratched: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúYou'll never guess
what that crazy missionary asked me to do today!‚Äù

            Symbols are still another form of communication.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Drivers</ENAMEX> use symbols all the time to know how
and where to drive.  <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic games</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
must identify symbols in order to find everything
from locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telex</ENAMEX> machines.  Despite the
growing use of internationally recognized symbols,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">symbols</ENAMEX>, which are baffling to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>.  Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guineans</ENAMEX> can look at the face of another
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinean</ENAMEX>--on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> or in a picture
book--and tell you which part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is from.  They know by style of face-painting
and headdress where a singsing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX> is from, and
they can look at designs on carvings or woven string
bags and say where the work originated.  Many of
these designs and symbols tell stories of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
and have meanings which are unknown to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX>.

            One missionary, who for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> had lived and
worked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north coast</ENAMEX>, told us of one
enormous mistake made for just that reason.  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of expatriate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> was called in to design
and build a high school.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> decided that
the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would like the school better if it had
designs with which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were familiar.  So
they chose from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äústory board‚Äù</ENAMEX> (an elaborate carving
showing the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that area) a
symbol which was--to them--abstract.  This symbol
became the logo for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and was used on
everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> letterhead to the sign in
front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.  When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> opened, none
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> came.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> were baffled
and asked for advice from this long-time missionary.
He took the problem back to the local village <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX>,
who explained why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was being boycotted:
the logo chosen was from that part of the village
history which described an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> arriving to rape
all the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>.  That symbol was
the most repugnant part of their whole history, and
it was an embarrassment to have it plastered on signs
and papers all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.  To Westerners, it was a
‚Äúneat‚Äù design; to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, it was a symbol of
great shame.

            Conversely, we saw T-shirts imported, bought,
and worn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had no idea what the symbols
or words meant.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> wore a shirt
with ‚ÄúMILK MILK‚Äù printed on it corresponding to
the appropriate part of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">anatomy</ENAMEX> beneath the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shirt</ENAMEX>.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> elder who stood up to read the lesson
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church service</ENAMEX> wore a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> that read ‚ÄúI do
it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>.‚Äù  Even had they known <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, milk
would seem a tame enough word; and it might likely
refer to something as innocent as brushing one's
teeth or going to sleep.

            Being a native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> is still not enough in the
game of communication.  Because of historical, political,
and economic ties between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Guinea</ENAMEX>, there are many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> living and
working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PNG</ENAMEX>, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guineans</ENAMEX>
who learn <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> speak it.  So in shops
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we encountered
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, but not as we were accustomed to hearing it
spoken.  What would you buy if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> gave
you a shopping list asking for ‚Äúcapsicum, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver beet</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mince</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jelly?‚Äù</ENAMEX>  (She would expect green peppers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> chard, hamburger, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jell-O</ENAMEX>.)  Or what
if she offered your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúcordial‚Äù</ENAMEX>?  (All she would
be giving him is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kool</ENAMEX>-Aid.)  Or what would you think
if the gentleman down the street said, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúWhat a</ENAMEX>
lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>!  May I nurse him?‚Äù  (He would only be
asking to hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>.)  If you were invited out for
‚Äúsupper‚Äù your hostess would serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>,
while an invitation to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äútea‚Äù would be for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
meal.

            Translating can be a treacherous means of communication,
too.  Although we did not translate more
than our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> notes or study materials for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, we could sympathize with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose
sole job was translation.  Literal translations have
been troublesome to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical</ENAMEX> phrase, ‚ÄúYour sins were as <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">scarlet</ENAMEX>;
they shall be white as snow‚Äù simply does not work.
Red is the color for weddings and celebrations;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX> is the color of death and mourning.  Interestingly,
the word for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúwhite‚Äù</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>] and ‚Äúcorpse‚Äù
are nearly identical in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">K√¢te language</ENAMEX>: qangqang
and \?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">\√¢ng</ENAMEX> \?<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">\√¢ng</ENAMEX>, respectively.

            

            Key words presented some of the worst
problems.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúGrace‚Äù</ENAMEX> is almost impossible to translate
because their cultural assumptions allow no possibility
for a truly free gift.  There is a basic suspicion that
no kind of gift, earthly or heavenly, can possibly
come without strings attached.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K√</ENAMEX>¢te words
mang jaung (literally `care from the heart/belly') are
not too bad a translation for `love.'  However, there
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> possibilities for translating `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">love' in Pidgin</ENAMEX>,
neither of which is satisfactory.  One is laikim, as
in ‚ÄúI love (i.e., `like') cucumbers.‚Äù  The other is
givim bel, which literally means `give the heart/
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">belly</ENAMEX>,' but which commonly means `to make pregnant.‚Äù
Believe it or not, it is the latter phrase which
has been chosen to translate the word `love' as found
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.  Those sorts of translation difficulties
leave room for a lot of explaining!

            While we worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX> the
chances for miscommunication were myriad.  Hard
work, combined with luck, eventually bridged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ravines</ENAMEX>.  We derived great pleasure from attempting
to unravel the languages and their cultures, and we
found that the desire to understand and to be understood
comes early in life, remains long, and seems to
be universal.
            The difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways of writing the ‚Äúq‚Äù
reflects a slight variation in pronunciation: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúq‚</ENAMEX>Äù being an explosive
kp sound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äú\</ENAMEX>?\‚Äù being a voiced gb sound.
         
         
            Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Get Your Titles In A Twist</ENAMEX>!



            I don't know about you, but I tend to get a touch
irritated by book titles, encountered in the media
and elsewhere, that seem slightly ‚Äúdeviant.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Deviant</ENAMEX>,
that is, from standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, or from what
one is expecting.  Some titles are catchy, and easy to
remember, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.G. Well</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kipps</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>), or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Patagonian Express</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>), and
some are less memorable, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Moor</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>'s
Tales of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mystery and Romance</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>), or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlyle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Heroes, Hero-Worship, and the Heroic</ENAMEX>
in History (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX>).  But at least they are reasonably
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">straightforward</ENAMEX> and comprehensible.

            What I am getting at are titles with skew spellings,
rogue punctuation, and ‚Äúweird and wonderful‚Äù
names and words that are difficult to relate to anything
meaningful.

            Why, for example, does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chatwin</ENAMEX>'s highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">readable</ENAMEX> collection of anecdotes and aper√ßus, What
Am I doing Here (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), have no question mark?  Or
come to that, why didn't he call it What I Am Doing
Here?  What is the significance, if any, of this small
deviation from the norm?  And what was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to</TIMEX>, calling his novel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pet Semetary</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>)?
Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrison Keillor</ENAMEX>'s lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lake Wobegon Days</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>) had me worried.  Why should I make an extra
effort to remember that the name of the ‚Äú1001st
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">lake</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as he describes it, is a twisted
version of woebegone?  The trouble with such ‚Äúoff‚Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spellings</ENAMEX> and punctuations is that you really need to
remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> extra things, on top of the little itself:
first, that the title is ‚Äúdeviant,‚Äù and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, how it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deviant</ENAMEX>.

            However, the fact remains that all through literrary
titles in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> there are such irritants, and I
thought I might as well tackle the issue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on and
see where the longstanding and popularly perpetrated
snags lay.  I offer my findings in the hopes that
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> will be able to
see some light in this particular thicket, as I think I
can myself discern now.

            Let us take the matter of name spellings <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>,
whether personal names or place names, real names
or fictitious ones.  Here are some classics: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smollett</ENAMEX>'s
novel is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humphry Clinker</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1771</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúHumphrey‚Äù;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson's</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarissa Harlowe</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1748</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúHarlow‚Äù;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defoe's</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson Crusoe</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1719</TIMEX>), not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúCruso‚Äù; Rider Haggard's</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Quatermain</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1887</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúQuartermain‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúQuatermaine.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  (A
slap on the wrist here to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rose Ben√©t</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encyclopedia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth McLeish</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bloomsbury Good Reading Guide</ENAMEX>, which respectively
give the latter misspellings.)  Also in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, I would say, are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Bront√</ENAMEX>´'s Wuthering
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heights</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúWeathering,<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù ‚ÄúWithering,‚Äù</ENAMEX> or
any similar fancy, and, admittedly more trickily, Aldous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huxley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crome Yellow</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>), not `<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chrome</ENAMEX>,‚Äù
although of course the pun on this word is intentional.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crome</ENAMEX> is the name of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, just as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wuthering Heights</ENAMEX> is.)  And we can conveniently
add a couple of pause-causing poetic titles here, too:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Moore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lalla Rookh</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1817</TIMEX>), and not a jot
otherwise, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennyson</ENAMEX>'s The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX> of Shalott
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1832</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúShallot,‚Äù which makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> smack
strongly of veganism.

            It is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> small step from such pitfalls to
those holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">punctuational</ENAMEX> and related snares, the
latter often involving the problem of whether a title
is one word or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">apostrophe</ENAMEX> has much to
answer for here, as it does in everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  So
let us note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX>'s novel is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finnegans Wake</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúFinnegan's,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù E. M. Forster</ENAMEX>'s is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howards End</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>) (another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> name, by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>), not ‚ÄúHoward's,‚Äù and, a potential double delusion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s famous play is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love's Labour</ENAMEX>'s
Lost (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1598</TIMEX>), with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> apostrophes.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of these
is the possessive, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> represents the vowel of
is .  (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> title is typical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s linguistically
inventive but allusive style, and is actually a
compound of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> proper names: that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX>
MaCool, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk-hero</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Finnegan</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of a music-hall ballad, who sprang to life in the
middle of his own wake.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyphens</ENAMEX> can cause difficulties, too.  So Melville
wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby-Dick</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1851</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Buchan</ENAMEX>'s autobiography
was called Memory Hold-the-Door (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>),
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson Davies</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tempest Tost</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>),
with no hyphen.  As for the ‚Äúone-or-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-word‚Äù
problem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Scott</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgauntlet</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Buchan</ENAMEX> (again) named his novel of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> adventure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntingtower</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>).

            While we're about it, we should not overlook
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coleridge</ENAMEX>'s poem, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rime</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Mariner</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1798</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúRhyme,‚Äù or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Childe Harold</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pilgrimage</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1811</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúChild,‚Äù or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrows</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chace</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX>), not ‚ÄúChase.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Both Byron</ENAMEX>'s and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX>'s wayward words are directly related to their
modern equivalents but have essentially historic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spellings</ENAMEX>.

            And there we have another whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river</ENAMEX> to cross,
since some of the best-known literary works have
retained their historic titles, complete with outmoded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spellings</ENAMEX> and punctuations.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spenser</ENAMEX> is notoriously
troublesome here, with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shepheardes</ENAMEX> Calender
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1579</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Faerie Queene</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1590</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hubberds Tale</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1591</TIMEX>) among the greatest hazards.
In a sense, it seems illogical that we have retained
the historic spellings for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spenser</ENAMEX>'s works yet use
modern spellings for the titles of plays by his contemporary,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX>.  But perhaps it is
just as well that we have <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Midsummer Night</ENAMEX>'s
Dream (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX>), not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Midsommer nights dream</ENAMEX> , as it
originally was when first published, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fifth</NUMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> ) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX>), not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> the fift .  A later
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX>, but still with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äúolde-worlde‚</NUMEX>Äù spelling, is Izaak
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compleat Angler</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1653</TIMEX>), which oddly
enough, seems to present little problem.

            What can cause a bout of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-scratching is deciding
whether the definite or indefinite article is
involved.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> play that quite often
goes wrong is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Winter's Tale</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1611</TIMEX>)--‚ÄúThe,‚Äù not
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúA,‚Äù</ENAMEX>--while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome K. Jerome</ENAMEX>, giving no trouble at
all with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Men in a Boat</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX>), followed it up
by taking the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on a tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Men on the Bummel</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>).  The last word
of this is the name of a river, so ‚ÄúA‚Äù is quite out of
order.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth McLeish</ENAMEX>, once again hold your
hand out!)

            A sort of juvenile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-off here, spellingwise, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Ashford</ENAMEX>'s charming novel, written when she
was only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Visiters</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>).  The authoress
may be excused her youthful slip, but once
she has made it, we are obliged to preserve it!
Among the true deviants, the titles that are neither
immediately nor even sometimes ever really meaningful
(although they may become so during the
reading of the book), are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-minefields</ENAMEX> of such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Alther</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinflicks</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mervyn Peake</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gormenghast</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carey</ENAMEX>'s Illywhacker
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>).

            Of course, similar titular problems occur in areas
outside literature, too.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughan Williams</ENAMEX>'s chilly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symphony</ENAMEX> that developed out of his music for the
‚ÄúBritish hero‚Äù movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antarctic</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>)
was actually entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinfonia Antartica</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>),
which seems rather perverse.  And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gay</ENAMEX>'s greatest
but much more light-hearted work was called
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beggar's Opera</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1728</TIMEX>), singular, not plural.
Even more obviously in the world of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical</ENAMEX> (and
visual) entertainment, it is worth noting that the Folies
Berg√® are spelled with the first word plural,
but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> singular.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everyman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encyclopxdia</ENAMEX> ,
write it out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times!).

            Well, I'm off to bed now, for good re-read of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Burgess</ENAMEX>'s A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clockwork Orange</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>).  At
least, I think it's ‚ÄúA‚Äù....
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> truck now has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 191,000 miles</NUMEX> on it and has never
had a major problem until recently.  The timing gear broke in the
front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> after coming home from the orthodontist.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From the
Letters column, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends , .</ENAMEX>  Submitted by ]
         
         
            
‚ÄúThat dive was right on the edge of new exploration and
new technology.  Taking new technology into unexplored realsm
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> is a once in a lifetime opportunity that I hope to
repeat many times.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underwater USA</ENAMEX> , .  Submitted
by ]
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writing Systems</ENAMEX> of the World
            [Note: This book may be ordered form any bookstore
that has the wit to look up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> in
Books in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Print</ENAMEX> .]

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Literacy</ENAMEX> and numeracy have come to the fore in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> as major issues, not only (or even so
much) in the Third World as in the industrialized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>.  Leaving numeracy aside for the moment,
those of us who have studied linguistics have usually
been told that as language is essentially spoken, its
written form is of lesser (or no) importance for the
analysis of language.  That is patent rubbish, of
course, for it can easily be demonstrated that written
language cannot be ignored for a variety of reasons:
the more formalized versions of language that are
reflected there, the relatively complex constructions
that are accepted as normal to writing but would be
difficult to construct viva voce and difficult to assimilate
unless read, the preservation of fossilized
forms--both words and grammar--made possible
by written records, and so on.  These and other features
of writing have an undeniable effect on language,
and it would be foolish to ignore them just
because language is, at bottom, an oral means of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>.  That is not to say that writing and
speech should be measured by the same yardsticks,
only that writing cannot be ignored in a proper
treatment of language.

            Writing has not been ignored entirely by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
on language, but its role has been consistently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underplayed</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coulmas</ENAMEX>'s clear exposition of the history
of writing systems traces the development of
various kinds of writing systems--ideographic, pictographic,
morphemic, syllabic, phonemic, and phonetic--through
history, discussing them individually,
describing how certain ancient scripts were
deciphered, and presenting his cogent arguments for
regarding at least some aspects of language through
the analysis of writing.  It is only through their written
forms that we know anything at all about certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languages</ENAMEX>, and the written forms of others serve to
confirm the findings of diachronic linguistics in positing
the pronunciation and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of long-dead
tongues.

            It is generally conceded that writing was invented
because of the need to keep records as civilizations
became more complex.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> generally
agree that the use of a numerical marking system
preceded attempts at developing methods for transcribing
language per se ; I find in accepting that fact
some interesting implications for theories about how
the mind works and, in particular, its capacity for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abstracting</ENAMEX>.  It must be emphasized, of course, that
language preceded numeracy, but it is interesting to
see how very early in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s acculturation the ability
to deal with the abstract notion of counting manifested
itself and was then transferred into an encodable
form.  In its most primitive form, a record might
consist of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of clay similar in shape to those of the
items being counted (for identification), the quantity
of bits being equal to the number of items counted.
Subsequently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay bits</ENAMEX> were replaced by marks
(even as we make them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\?\</ENAMEX>) with a picture of
what was being counted (pots or sheaves of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incised</ENAMEX> alongside the count.  Much later, to save
space, the `<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\?\</ENAMEX>' was to be replaced by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>,
say, `<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>.'  Meanwhile, the picture of the grain sheaf
was itself to be replaced by a shorthand version, and
that is where things begin to get complicated.  I have
already simplified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coulmas</ENAMEX>'s description out of all
sensible recognition for the sake of brevity, but,
while the time compression has been severe, I do
not think I have distorted the facts.
