
   
      
         
            What's in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> Name?



            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">toponymy of Rome</ENAMEX> offers an entertaining
supplement to the study of its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-seven</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years</TIMEX> of history.  The etymology of the
name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> itself remains a mystery.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legend</ENAMEX> attributes it to a more or less imaginary eponymous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romulus</ENAMEX> , or, in a less familiar version,
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhome</ENAMEX> (whose name is a
Greek word for `strength').  Modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> attempt
to explain the name more scientifically as being
based on a word meaning `river,' or on an Etruscan
name.  Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, noting evidence for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> word ruma meaning `breast,' have concluded
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> owes its name to the supposed shape of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palatine Hill</ENAMEX> as it appeared to the eye of an exceptionally
determined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Tetons</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American West</ENAMEX> illustrate this same phenomenon
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.

            Major natural features of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> whose ancient
names are still in use include the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tiber River</ENAMEX> and the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> hills.  The etymology of all these names remains
as elusive as that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">of Rome</ENAMEX> itself.  Various legends
were invented to account for them; for example,
the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitoline Hill</ENAMEX> (from which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capitol</ENAMEX> comes) was said to be derived from a human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> ( caput ) found on it when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>
Capitolinus was being built.  This was taken as a portent
of future glory.  The adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palatine Hill</ENAMEX>,
which was eventually reserved for imperial structures
(whence our words palace and palatial ), was
derived from the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pallas</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evander</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> who according to epic tradition settled on the
site of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> before its ‚Äúreal‚Äù founding.
The fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pallas</ENAMEX> constitutes a major motif in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vergil</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aeneid</ENAMEX> .

            One relatively unfamiliar hill in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monte</ENAMEX>
               Testaccio , is a sizable, artificial eminence near the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiber</ENAMEX> south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, rising <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hundred feet</NUMEX> above
the surrounding level.  This was the commercial
dock area in antiquity, and more recently the site of
the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s slaughterhouse, not much frequented
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, although it is near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX>
that contains the grave of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Keats</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte Testaccio</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testaceus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>) means `hill of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">potsherds</ENAMEX>'--an
exact description of its makeup.  For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> it was
formed by the dumping of debris from the dock
area, mostly pieces of broken amphoras, which then
became compacted.  Walking on its surface is an extraordinary
experience.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX> is the popular name for the most famous
surviving ancient building of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.  Its official
name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flavian Amphitheater</ENAMEX> , after the family
name of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vespasian</ENAMEX>.  The
name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colosseum</ENAMEX> , now usually taken to refer to its
size, originally referred to the fact that the amphitheater
was built adjacent to a huge statue (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colossus</ENAMEX> )
of the sun god that had been commissioned by
Nero, allegedly in his own likeness.

            The name of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most favored places of
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piazza Navona</ENAMEX> , is a disguised form of
a word for the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> whose site it occupies,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>) built by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domitian</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza Navona</ENAMEX> still preserves the exact
shape of that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>, of which practically nothing
else is left.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> itself, and the kind of activity
that took place there, were called agon , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
word which originally meant simply `competition,'
but which has given us our word `agony.' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX> Agnes
suffered martyrdom at this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> after her hair
grew with miraculous rapidity to cover the nakedness
by which her persecutors sought to humiliate
her.  Consequently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that was later built
there was called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúSt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agnes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Agone</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  The phrase
in agone came to be corrupted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navona</ENAMEX> , by way of
intermediate forms such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navone</ENAMEX> .  Until
well into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the present century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, if little
used, name of the piazza was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Circo Agonale</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piazza di Spagna</ENAMEX> , site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> Steps, is so
named because since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX> it has been
the location of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy See</ENAMEX>.
The main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that leads to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> Steps, despite
its present concentration of elegant and renowned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boutiques</ENAMEX>, has the most prosaic of names:
Via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condotti</ENAMEX> , after the aged conduits that serve the
nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trevi Fountain</ENAMEX>.

            Many ecclesiastical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> have
striking names.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Giovanni</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oleo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> near the
spot, just inside the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porta Latina</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John the Evangelist</ENAMEX> is said to have survived immersion
in boiling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>.  The name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria sopra Minerva</ENAMEX> recalls that it was built over a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> of the pagan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minerva</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Maria</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cosmedin</ENAMEX> remains an etymological puzzle.  This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> served <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 8th century</TIMEX>,
and the designation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cosmedin</ENAMEX> is usually assumed
to be connected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> word kosmidion , diminutive
of kosmos , meaning `embellishment.'

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> names of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> reflect both its long
history and the fanciful imagination of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via del Babuino</ENAMEX> , running north from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza di</ENAMEX>
Spagna, is named after an ancient fountain with a
statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silenus</ENAMEX>, the grotesque drunken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follower</ENAMEX> of
Bacchus, which seemed to resemble a baboon.  A
similar circumstance accounts for the strange name
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Santo Stefano del Cacco</ENAMEX> , which refers to a
statue of an animal-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deity</ENAMEX> discovered
in the remains of the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple of Isis</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> was identified as the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>
called in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> a macaque , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">macacco</ENAMEX> , here
colloquially truncated.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Via di Ripetta</ENAMEX> `Embankment
Street' skirts the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tiber River</ENAMEX> as it passes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacis and the Mausoleum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus</ENAMEX>.  Here until
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present century</TIMEX> there was a bustling landing
place for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> that plied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiber</ENAMEX>, a popular
subject in old photographs and prints.  Now a flood
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> has recessed the river below the level
of the adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and the ripetta has disappeared
except in name.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via di Ripetta</ENAMEX> imperceptibly
merges into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via della Scrofa</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Street of the Sow</ENAMEX>,'
named after another ancient sculpture that is still
preserved there.  Just off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via della Scrofa</ENAMEX> is an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tower</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torre della Scimmia</ENAMEX> .  A votive lamp
permanently lit on this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> commemorates the miraculous
rescue of a baby girl from a scimmia `pet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey'</ENAMEX> that had carried her off to its top.  Its principal
interest for many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, however, is that
this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tower</ENAMEX>, where the ethereal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> of
Nathaniel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawthorne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marble Faun</ENAMEX> lived while she
studied painting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> names in the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> recall how <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medieval artisans</ENAMEX> used to congregate
in specialized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarters</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via dei</ENAMEX> Giubbonari
`<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of coats,' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Calderari</ENAMEX> `tinkers,' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pettinari</ENAMEX> `makers
of combs,' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coronari</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rosary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>,' Balestrari
`<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crossbow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>,' and many others.  The words in
this list are obsolete in contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, but the
street names survive.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that retains a picturesque name
is Via delle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Botteghe Oscure</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Street of Dark Shops</ENAMEX>.'
The widening of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> resulted not
only in the brightening (or disappearance) of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, but also in the uncovering of important archaeological
remains, much to the inconvenience of
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>--an old story in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.  The
street gave its name to the influential literary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Botteghe Oscure</ENAMEX> , published there in the 1950s
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marguerite Caetani</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-born member
of the aristocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> whose ancestral palace
stands at the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.

            The single most prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> of street names
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risorgimento</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th-century</TIMEX> revolutionary
movement that unified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> grew
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenomenally</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risorgimento</ENAMEX>.
One result of this growth was an abundance
of new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> that needed names; the worthies of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Risorgimento</ENAMEX> largely filled the bill.  Its principal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Vittorio Emanuele II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garibaldi, Mazzini</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavour</ENAMEX> --are commemorated in the names of
the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and piazzas of virtually every city
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, not least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.  Via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venti</ENAMEX> Settembre
`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">20th of September Street</ENAMEX>' illustrates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> propensity for naming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> after historic
dates, in this case the date of the breach in the ancient
fortification wall of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, through which Italian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">troops</ENAMEX> stormed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to bring the Risorgimento
to an end.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via del Plebiscito</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">connects Piazza Venezia</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Largo Argentina</ENAMEX>, now
almost totally surrendered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxis</ENAMEX>, was
named for the `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plebiscite</ENAMEX>' held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX>, shortly after
the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th of September</TIMEX>, when the people
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> voted to join the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, ending
the temporal power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>.

            
               Via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veneto</ENAMEX> , site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> and of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">la</ENAMEX> dolce vita in general, was named for one of the
provinces of the newly unified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, as were other
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> nearby ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Toscana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Lombardia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via</ENAMEX>
Campania, etc .), when what had been the gardens of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa Ludovisi</ENAMEX> were urbanized almost exactly a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years ago</TIMEX>.  Following <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via</ENAMEX>
Veneto was renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Vittoria Veneto</ENAMEX> , after a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Veneto</ENAMEX> that had been the scene of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
battle of that war.  (This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> itself had been renamed
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX> in honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vittorio Emanuele</ENAMEX>
II.)  To this day, hardly anyone ever calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Vittorio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veneto</ENAMEX> anything but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Veneto</ENAMEX>.

            Few of the street names that originated in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fascist</ENAMEX> era have survived it.  The grandiose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dell'Impero</ENAMEX> that was rammed through the central archaeological
zone in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> was named after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">short-lived Fascist ‚ÄúEmpire‚Äù</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>.  It has been
renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via dei Fori Imperiali</ENAMEX> , some what ironically,
as the frenzied traffic on it is a serious blight to the
enjoyment of the remains of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fora</ENAMEX> themselves.  Proposals to demolish this street
and restore the unity of the whole archaeological
zone from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitoline Hill</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX> are
often in the news.

            Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via della Conciliazione</ENAMEX> , which
cleared the approach to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Basilica of St. Peter</ENAMEX> from
centuries-old congestion, commemorates the `Reconciliation'
effected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Lateran Treaty</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>.
This regularized the relationship between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, which had remained
unsettled during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risorgimento</ENAMEX>.

            Just inside the southern part of the ancient wall
there is another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that has escaped renaming,
although it commemorates a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fascist</ENAMEX> victory in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> war.  This is the exotic-sounding
Via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amba Aradam</ENAMEX> , named after a plateau in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX>,
a battlefield in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>.

            In the southern part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> stands the rather
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forlorn EUR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> of obsolescent modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
The initials, always pronounced as one Italian
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">word ‚Äúay-OOR‚Äù</ENAMEX>), stand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esposizione Universale di</ENAMEX>
Roma , a world's fair that was to have been held in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX> but yielded instead to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, visible from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> that serves
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, is a bizarre structure officially called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo della Civilt√° del Lavoro</ENAMEX>.  Its principal design
feature is the rounded openings that cover all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of
its exterior walls.  The major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> guidebook to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> soberly claims that this building has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nicknamed Il Colosseo Quadrato</ENAMEX> , `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Square Colosseum</ENAMEX>.'
In fact, what most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> really call it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Il</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palazzo di Groviera</ENAMEX> `The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss Cheese Palace</ENAMEX>.'

            A scattering of names referring to more recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> history can be found.  At the base of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aventine</ENAMEX>,
a postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> has been named the Parco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Resistenza dell'Otto Settembre</ENAMEX> , commemorating
the heroic action against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> there on that
date in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX>.  Nearby, just
outside the ancient wall, the area in front of the railroad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX> has been named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazzale dei Partigiani</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luigi Einaudi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> of postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> politics,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948 to 1955</TIMEX>,
when he was an octogenarian, has the unusual honor
of a street named for him in the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>,
near the central railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>.  This had previously
been called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Viale delle Terme</ENAMEX>, after the ruins of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adjacent Baths</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocletian</ENAMEX>, one corner of which
holds the present <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum of Antiquities</ENAMEX>.

            Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> should make
an excursion to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa Borghese</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> just outside
the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Veneto</ENAMEX>, where they will
find what used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viale dei Leoni</ENAMEX> `Street of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions</ENAMEX>,' now officially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viale Fiorello Laguardia</ENAMEX> .
         
         


            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Peterson</ENAMEX> writes [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XVII,1</NUMEX>] ‚Äú...<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Augustine</ENAMEX>...arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> bringing Christianity
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>...,‚Äù he may be correct about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, but Christianity beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Augustine</ENAMEX> there by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>.  There were, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
bishops at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Arles</ENAMEX>, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">314</NUMEX>.  See The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford Dictionary of the Christian Church</ENAMEX> , second
edition, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> repr., pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">290ff., ‚</ENAMEX>ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of England</ENAMEX>.‚Äù





         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Scandalous Yiddish</ENAMEX>
Guide of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>




            Every language deserves respect and reverence.
Every language is the creative expression of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the collective repository of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s legends, traditions, and history, and a
mighty potentiator of its national and cultural continuity.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> publishes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> foreign language
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guides</ENAMEX>, from (alphabetically) <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>,
to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> unfamiliar with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> in
answering the official <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Form</ENAMEX>.  I
took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> and my
eyes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-score-and-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX>, glazed over, not
because of their age but because what they saw was
totally unreadable--a heap of pure gibberish.  From
the very title of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> , to the first word, first
sentence, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph--every rule of spelling,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grammar</ENAMEX>, and syntax has been violated beyond recognition.
The entire document represents a veritable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rain</ENAMEX> of error--nay, a torrent, a deluge of gross
mistakes, outrageous misspellings, and just plain and
simple ignorance.

            To give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> an approximate idea of what
a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> is confronted with, imagine a
question like ‚ÄúHow many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?‚Äù
being translated as With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pensil</ENAMEX> say on these line how
much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">parssonalitys residue</ENAMEX> in yuore abodiement .
Even this fails to convey in full the nonsense of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> because with patience and some educated
guessing one could decipher the meaning of
the above sentence.  This, however, would be practically
impossible with the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> .  No
amount of patient effort and guessing to reconstruct
a sentence would be of any avail because the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> is garbled to the point of incoherence.

            One is reminded of the assembly instructions
that used to come with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> terms in those instructions were so
comically outlandish and the sentence <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> so
awkward that they became a source of hilarity.
There is nothing hilarious or mirthful, however,
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> .  To the very contrary: it
brings forth a deep sense of sadness because what
was supposed to be a serious attempt at facilitating
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> count, a sort of ‚Äúfirst aid‚Äù assistance in
answering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Form</ENAMEX>, looks like the work of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> pages from a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> book,
cut them up with his plastic scissors into tiny pieces
of various shapes and sizes and then playfully pasted
them together.

            How did such irresponsibility come about?
Why did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> not call up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for a referral to a responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>?  Instead, I imagine, whoever was in
charge of foreign language translations asked around
casually during a coffee break: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">‚ÄúAnyone</ENAMEX> here know
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish?‚</ENAMEX>Äù  And a chap piped up: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúWell</ENAMEX>, my mother
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> when they didn't want me
and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> to understand what they were saying,
but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> always spoke
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish...‚</ENAMEX>Äù

            The saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traduttore traditore</ENAMEX> expresses the
idea that no matter how gifted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> is, he can
never truly convey the subtle nuances and meanings
behind the original language, the many-layered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>
and allusions that the words in the original
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">connote</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish ‚Äútranslator‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> doesn't belong, of course, to the above class
of translators.  While professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translators</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">richly</ENAMEX> and deeply knowledgable in both languages,
the original language and the language they translate
into, the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Guide</ENAMEX>
is totally ignorant of the rudimentary rules of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>,
not to mention its spirit.  The end result of his
work therefore is tantamount to sabotage, albeit unintended,
since any native <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> starting
to answer the questionnaire with the help of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> would soon have to discard, in utter confusion,
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Form</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> as well.

            But this denigration alone would not make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yiddish Guide</ENAMEX> the travesty it is.  What made it a travesty,
indeed a tragedy, is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> upon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, many of them elderly and
poor, remained uncounted, and thus have fallen
‚Äúbetween the cracks,‚Äù so to speak, with grave political,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX>, and economic consequences.

            [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note : We shall send a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>
publication <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>) to anyone who requests
it and encloses a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">s.a.s.e.</ENAMEX>]
         
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barnhart Dictionary of New English</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnhart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have
been intimately involved in dictionary-making, certainly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most unusual family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> one
could imagine.  The tradition began with the influential
work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence L. Barnhart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
lexicography, who at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 89</TIMEX> is still active in
the profession.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.L.B.</ENAMEX> had much to do with the application
of modern linguistic theory to lexicography;
the list of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> he has edited includes
such landmarks as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of American English</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago Press</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thorndike</ENAMEX>-Barnhart
School <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dictionaries</ENAMEX> series (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Foresman</ENAMEX>;
the top-selling school dictionaries in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College Dictionary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Century Cyclopedia</ENAMEX> of Names (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appleton-Century-Crofts</ENAMEX>),
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World Book Dictionary</ENAMEX> (little
known, sadly, but one of the best unabridged dictionaries
still being kept current).  He also founded
and, with his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, still edits the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barnhart Dictionary</ENAMEX>
Companion [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDC</ENAMEX> ], a periodical report on
new words that features the staple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnhart</ENAMEX> lexicography--full,
dated citations.

            In addition to their work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary Companion</ENAMEX> ,
well regarded by lexicographers and other
serious word <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Barnhart</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have directed much effort over the years
to tracking and recording new <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and this latest
publication is another in that line.  This Third
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barnhart Dictionary of New English</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX>] follows
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others of similar purpose and style that appeared
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973 and 1980</TIMEX>, respectively, published
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX> & Row.  The intent of the series is to record
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúwords</ENAMEX> and meanings not entered or fully explained
in standard dictionaries... a supplement to
current dictionaries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">language‚Äù</ENAMEX> (from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preface</ENAMEX>).  In this latest addition to the series
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert K. Barnhart</ENAMEX> is listed first on the title page,
taking over his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s role in the previous books,
and, as before, they are joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sol Steinmetz</ENAMEX>.
The combined editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> books includes
the names of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no fewer than nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barnharts</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> is an amalgamation and continuation,
with ‚Äúmany of the entries found in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> earlier
books of this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX> (both now out of print)...included
to provide a revised and expanded record of
new words and meanings introduced into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three decades‚Äù</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preface</ENAMEX>).  Those
wishing to supplement their aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s Third
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New International</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>) and unwilling to
spend about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> dollars more for the recent editions
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Unabridged</ENAMEX> or World
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX> would be very well served by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> .  It should be noted, however, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> , in including the work of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>,
represents a departure from their approach.  The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> was totally independent of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>
book: the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> supplemented the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.  The
TBDNE consolidates the best of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> earlier dictionaries,
with revisions, then adds some new entries.
It is intended to replace its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, not
supplement them.

            Each entry contains a definition (occasionally
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more) followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more lengthy,
dated citations, plus a date, often different, of the
earliest citation on file for each sense.  The date is
often earlier than that of the citations given since
these were selected from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnhart</ENAMEX> files as most
illustrative of meaning and usage.  Indeed, the definition
is often provided in the citation itself.  Multiple
citations are arranged in an order of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>'
choosing, not necessarily chronological.  This approach
reflects editorial sifting of the evidence from
the citations and a subsequent presentation that best
befits clarity and sense development.  Strict chronological
presentation of dated citations is at best a lexicographic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Procrustean</ENAMEX> bed, at worst very misleading.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citations</ENAMEX>, being only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lexicographer</ENAMEX>'s raw
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, need to be carefully reviewed, weighed, selected,
and presented if a dictionary entry is to record
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of a word properly.  Sound citation
analysis is, like good definition-writing, a rare gift,
and requires, besides diligence, broad experience
and a firm sense of the idiom of the language:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprachgef√ºhl .</ENAMEX>  Fortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of TBDNE
have this in abundance, and the resulting excellence
is manifest on every page.

            A careful estimate indicates that the TBDNE
contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 9,000 headwords</NUMEX> with an additional
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000 or so</NUMEX> other entry words; of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000 or so</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entries</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some 2,300</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 21%</NUMEX>) are phrasal.  The
estimate suggests something less than the entry
count of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merriam-Webster 12,000 Words</ENAMEX> , which
is billed as a supplement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam Third</ENAMEX> , but
there the comparison ends.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> has well
over twice the information of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merriam</ENAMEX> book,
which lacks citations.  Citations are particularly important
in dictionaries of new words, not only in establishing
a dated record, but to furnish context and
thereby more clearly illustrate actual use--essential
for words that are by nature unfamiliar.

            Other features include special notes on usage,
word formation, and cultural or historical background.
Pronunciations are given as necessary, using
an adaptation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Phonetic Alphabet</ENAMEX>
developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnharts</ENAMEX> for this series.
Etymologies are provided for a small proportion of
entries.  Otherwise, the dictionary presents itself in
fairly standard, familiar fashion, with the sort of labeling
and cross-referencing that one expects in a
quality product.  One feature of the earlier books in
the series has unfortunately not been kept in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> --the use of centered dots within headwords
to show syllabication points.

            An analysis of the entries in two randomly selected
spans of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> suggests that the great
bulk of the entries are repeated, often with revision,
from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> earlier books, with less evidence of
new material than one might have hoped for.  A randomly
chosen span of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> full entries in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> ,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platinum</ENAMEX> , was compared against the
same alphabetic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963 and 1980</TIMEX> dictionaries:


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1963        1980        1990</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> entries  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> entries  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> entries

            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> entries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> from
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> book (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> were dropped) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> from the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> book (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> were dropped), with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> completely
new entries.  The new items, pinstriper and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Planet X</ENAMEX>, are, not surprisingly, both drawn from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDC</ENAMEX> , which provided the actual citation for pinstriper
and the date of earliest occurrence for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X.</ENAMEX>  It seems likely that the increasingly common acronym
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PIN</ENAMEX> , for personal identification number , issued
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> as a unique identifier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> who
use automatic teller machines (yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> is in),
which was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDC</ENAMEX> was passed over for TBDNE because
it appears as an entry in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabridged Second Edition</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>), though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> is
an entry in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>.

            To find such a low proportion of new entries
(<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>), was unexpected, so another random span of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>, from go to grammaticality , was compared, with
the following result:


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1963        1980        1990</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> entries  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> entries  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> entries

            

            Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> entries, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> come from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>
book (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> dropped), all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> were taken from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>,
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> new items were added: goldbug , golden parachute,
gold rush (new sense), golf ball (new sense),
and gomer .  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> are to be found in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDC</ENAMEX> , while entries for all appear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dictionary</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> edition), also produced by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnhart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.  So there was indeed a greater proportion
of new entries (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX> noted
first, but still a disappointingly small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> of the
whole.

            Of the entries left out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> that did
appear in the previous books, none was surprising.
Technical terms such as pinealectomy , planetology ,
and planktotrophic are of low frequency or have only
specialized use, so were understandably dropped in
compiling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> (indeed, it is more notable
that they were ever included at all).  Entries for pipe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX> , ( in the ) pipeline, pita , and placebo effect ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">plasma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> , and platform tennis , all in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> book,
were doubtless dropped because they all are entered
in current general-language dictionaries, and
so are no longer required in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX>, given its
stated intention.  The dropping of goulash communism
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> citation; economic approach in thencommunist
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> emphasizing greater production
of consumer goods) and gramadan (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> citation;
Hindi loanword applied to a Gandhian form of
land collectivization in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>), both in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> book
but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> , reflects the fact that, in a living
language, citations require different analysis and
judgment after the perspective of time is added.  It
may seem unfortunate to discard entries that, no
matter the frequency or currency of the term, are
part of the record of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, but such is necessary in
any commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictionary venture</ENAMEX>.  At least it does
appear, based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spans</ENAMEX> analyzed, that the discards
were judiciously chosen.

            A comparison reading of full entries in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> against the source entries from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>
reveals the marks of close editing to incorporate
better citations and record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> attestations.  Also,
the citational style has been tightened, undoubtedly
to create space for additional entries.  Where the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963 and 1980</TIMEX> dictionaries cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, article,
publication, and date (for a periodical), the same citation
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> gives only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> and date.
The space saved allowed for amalgamation and new
entries; yet, anyone interested in more background
on a particular citation is provided with enough information
to track it down, assuming that a good library
is at hand.

            I hesitate to quibble over a few items not found
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> , since even these should cause no
great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.  A dictionary of neologisms owes
nearly everything to the citation files behind it, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">citation</ENAMEX> files are very much a product of accident,
constrained by budget.  That the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> Unabridged
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Edition</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>) includes pimpmobile
and plain-vanilla probably means that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> files had citations for these, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnharts</ENAMEX>' not--or not enough.  Given the immense
quantity of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in use worldwide, it is simply
impossible for any single citation-gathering force to
see, much less collect, all that should be in the file.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Words</ENAMEX> has entries for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinteresque</ENAMEX>,
pistou , and place value , again a reflection of what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vast Merriam</ENAMEX> files have yielded up.  Still, none of the
new-words dictionaries I checked, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longman Register of New Words</ENAMEX> (edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayto; Longman</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Facts on File Dictionary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Words</ENAMEX> (edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeMay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lerner</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor; Facts on File</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>) had an entry for pixelization
`the appearance of pixels (dots that make up
a computer-screen image) in a computer graphic, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX> of lower resolution.'  An entry for it must await
citations entering the files, assuming the word
proves its usefulness to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of English over time.

            It is a bit dissatisfying to find fewer new entries
in the TBDNE than one might have expected.  Commercial
constraints are the likely explanation for
this, not, I strongly suspect, lack of new words and
senses in the ever-burgeoning <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> lexicon.  But
we should not judge too harshly on the basis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spans</ENAMEX> covering <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 1%</NUMEX> of the entries.
While it can truly be said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBDNE</ENAMEX> shows
more of the solid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> than
it does of newly laid work, this is hardly negative
criticism.  The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963 and 1980</TIMEX> books are both fine
dictionaries, and a book that combines the best of
those, carefully re-edited, with some solid, new lexicography
based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDC</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World Book Dictionary</ENAMEX> ,
and the substantial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnhart</ENAMEX> files, must be a
high-quality dictionary.  It is.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank R. Abate</ENAMEX>

         
         


            I'd like to add a word to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Cohen</ENAMEX>'s delightful
list in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúJingo Lingo‚</ENAMEX>Äù [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>].  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> words
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkie</ENAMEX> are toxoman and morphinman , neither of
which merits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> use.





         
         


            I must take issue with your quick dismissal of
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saussy</ENAMEX>'s claim that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> earned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s
degree ‚Äúat the behest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps‚</ENAMEX>Äù
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>].  To the extent that written orders constitute
military commands, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Corps</ENAMEX> do indeed issue ‚Äúbehests‚Äù for academic degrees.
In the past, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> has had programs
similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Degree Program</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDP</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy Enlisted Scientific Education Program</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NESEP</ENAMEX>).  Moreover, at any given time there
are many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> enrolled in graduate
study programs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Postgraduate School</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPS</ENAMEX>), in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.  They arrive at NPS
with orders in hand and usually complete degree requirements
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>--at the behest of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX>.





         
         
            To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbrev</ENAMEX>. or Not to Abbreviate



            There is a linguistic process in the evolution of
our vocabulary that is not functioning with a
high rate of efficiency.  Not that the language has
ever been highly logical or ever should be, but what
set out on a bon voyage is gradually abandoning ship
and heading back to shore.  What was to have happened
simply is not always happening.

            In the world of modern communication, it is evident
that it is often necessary to speed up the sending
of messages.  With the written language, this is
orthographically facilitated by the various processes
of word shortening--acronyms ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZIP for Zone Improvement</ENAMEX>
Plan ), contractions ( won't for will not ),
clipped words ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deli</ENAMEX> for delicatessen ) and abbreviations
( lb. for pound ).  However, the time- and space-saving
act of abbreviating is not always working with
the efficiency that was originally intended.  A few
examples will vividly illustrate this puzzling discrepancy.

            When we find ourselves with a long word or
phrase on our hands, we would normally expect to
find an abbreviation to come to the rescue.  In time,
that generally happens and, with few communication
difficulties, everything lives happily after.  The
expression, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the ceremonies , is earliest
found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1662</TIMEX>.  It is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a hundred years later</TIMEX>
before an efficient abbreviation for it is found.  In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1790 M.C.</ENAMEX> finally arrives in print to reduce the writing
wordload by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300 percent</NUMEX>.  Supposedly, everything
is firmly set.  For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost one and one half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.C.</ENAMEX> does the job it was called upon to do.  In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>, however, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> mysteriously decides
that a new word is needed to represent the pronunciation
of the abbreviation.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emcee</ENAMEX> is thus born, no
matter that this represents an increase from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> letters
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, a bulging <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">125%</NUMEX> growth.  Granted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emcee</ENAMEX>
is still more efficient than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of ceremonies , but
the need for spelling out the sound of letters seems
redundant, superfluous, and therefore useless.

            Nevertheless, the practice of changing from
term to abbreviation to phonetic spelling of the abbreviation
is an old and continuing oddity in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the need for a general-purpose vehicle
was satisfied with the development of a means
of transportation referred to by the government
with astonishing directness and candor as a general-purpose
vehicle .  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, quick to abbreviate everything,
began to refer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> as a g.p., but
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> g.p. had given way to the longer jeep .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice president</ENAMEX> (with no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> found in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1574</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> , referring to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> nibs,
is found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sometime later</TIMEX> VP shortened the
term by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">250%</NUMEX>, but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> veep , although abhorred
by many, was applied affectionately to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alben Barclay</ENAMEX>
and became part of the written and spoken
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocabulary</ENAMEX>.

            
               Junior varsity is found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, referring to the
secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>.
The date for the first use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.V.</ENAMEX> is unsure, but the
date for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">jayvee , 1937</TIMEX>, would seem to show a lack of
conclusive evidence since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior varsity</ENAMEX> must obviously
have preceded jayvee .

            
               Disc jockey is found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>, deejay in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>,
indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.J.</ENAMEX> might have been in between.

            Another inconsistency is to be found in the process
of knockout , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> term and later the metaphoric
term referring to anything that amazes or
shocks.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knockout</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recorded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1887</TIMEX>, and logically
following is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.O.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX>, but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appearance
of kayo is cited in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX>.

            Not to rehash the OK controversy, but oll korrect
is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1839</TIMEX> with OK also listed in that
same year.  Following reasonable suit, okeh appears
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>, and okay is charted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> of the armed forces is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Construction</ENAMEX>
Batallion, which was quickly abbreviated
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.B.</ENAMEX>  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> came to be known as the
Seabees , sporting uniforms with an appropriate insigne
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">seafaring bee</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the latest words to enter the Abbreviation
Cycle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redundancy Race</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> .  The
‚ÄúShow-Me‚Äù state gained statehood in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1821</TIMEX>.  It is not
clear when the inept <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX> became the official abbreviation.
However it is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> saw fit to
continue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MO.</ENAMEX>  The final stage is now
evident in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s motto regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúMO</ENAMEX>
SAYS NO TO <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DRUGS</ENAMEX>,‚Äù where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX> is obviously to be
rhymed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NO.</ENAMEX>

            What are the reasons for the apparent senselessness
in the preceding examples?  It must first be remembered
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> is not highly reliant on the
rules of logic.  Prescriptive dictionaries are becoming
fewer; descriptive dictionaries are gaining in
popularity.  Aside from generalizations, however,
the abbreviations considered here do present some
reason for their madness.  Mo rhyming with no certainly
makes the slogan easy to remember.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> and
veep , each containing only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> syllable, are easier to
pronounce than their ancestral abbreviations.  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Emcee</ENAMEX>
probably radiates a more euphemistic aura of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dignity than M.C.</ENAMEX>  Although there seems to be no
reason for jayvee , it must be noted that the date
given for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appearance of a word is actually a
record of when it was first found in print, and earlier
oral use could not distinguish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. V.</ENAMEX> from jayvee .  The
word was no doubt used orally much earlier.

            The problem with abbreviations as presented
here again illustrates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> demand that language
work the way they want to make it work.
Overall, the abbreviating process is alive and doing
exceptionally well.
         
         

            To supplement <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. T. Henry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúNifty Nomenclature‚</ENAMEX>Äù
[XVI<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX>], my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (nee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX> ) from
Beckenham offers the intelligence that when she
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s name was Death (pronounced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúDEETH‚Äù</ENAMEX>), her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>'s name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Screech</ENAMEX>,
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX>'s name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenshitt</ENAMEX> , and the local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pastor</ENAMEX> was Reverend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX> who married a Miss
Shorter.





         
         

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúThe Language</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Law‚Äù</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XVII,1</NUMEX>], one
phrase ran off the rails:


customs that runneth not to the contrary.

            

            Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> was not serious, because he
had a plural subject with a singular verb, runneth , in
the relative clause.  What ‚Äúrunneth not to the contrary‚Äù
is memory, rather than custom.  A better use
of the phrase would be:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Droit du</ENAMEX> seigneur has been the custom for so long
that the mind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> runneth not to the contrary.

            





         
         
            The Sounds of Inglish



            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Higgins</ENAMEX> liked to
vent his ire on his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> for ‚Äúthe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cold-blooded</ENAMEX> murder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> tongue.‚Äù  What
his views were on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> who spoke the language
less than perfectly we shall never know.  But I
imagine those views wouldn't have been complimentary
either, because many of his real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>,
devout worshipers of the Queen's <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>,
have expressed varying degrees of horror on the
subject.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would have thought that a little gratitude
would be in order, gratitude for living in a world
that largely speaks their language, however differently.
Assume for a moment that this were not the
case.  How would the predominantly monoglot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britons</ENAMEX> then cope?

            Now imagine for a moment that you are seated
on the verandah of a bungalow in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.  The impending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monsoon</ENAMEX> has darkened the skies, the breeze
is rustling the chintz curtains and the calico tablecloth.
Is a typhoon on its way?  A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motley crowd</ENAMEX> is
hurrying by--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">dungarees</TIMEX>; a yogi with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>; a noblewoman in purdah in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">palanquin</TIMEX>; a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of nautch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, attractive in their aniline-dyed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dresses</ENAMEX> and bright bandanas, their bangles jingling
and their long, shampooed hair streaming in the
breeze; a sepoy all smart in khaki on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, his
jodhpurs trim and neat; a scholarly pundit; a mahout
on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>, ambling like a juggernaut.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog barks</ENAMEX> at a bandicoot (or is it a mongoose?) in the
paddy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> while mynahs twitter in the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">adjoining</NUMEX>
jungle.  Fishermen secure their catamarans and dinghies
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> with thick coir ropes.  There's
have a dekko at.  Everything is so different from
good old Blighty...

            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Thirty-five</NUMEX> words in the preceding paragraph
are derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> languages and are listed in
standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> dictionaries as acceptable English
words.  Some of them strike us immediately as exotic
but others (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shampoo</ENAMEX>, for instance) are in such common
use that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are often astonished to learn
that they have a foreign origin.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> carried
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language to distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">climes</ENAMEX>.  These lands
were poles apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> in every possible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>.  There simply were no words in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
language to describe many local features and the local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of life.  New words, phrases, and idioms had
to be coined--out of necessity.  What better than to
borrow words and expressions from local languages
and anglicize them?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, in turn, made its impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> languages
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways: crossbreeding with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
words to produce unique amalgamations; and lending
words and expressions to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> languages.  As a
result, we now have hybrid words like gymkhana
and memsahib .  Gymkhana , a `<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">socialize</ENAMEX> and partake in sports and recreation,' is a
mixture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> gendkhana (meaning `ball
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>') and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> gymnasium .  Memsahib ,
meaning `<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> or white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>,' stems from sahib ,
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> title of respect often accorded to white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and mem , a corruption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madam</ENAMEX> .

            So too, words like shirt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, road ,
and light have become common in everyday vernacular
speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.  Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pronunciations</ENAMEX> have
been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indianized</ENAMEX>.  Pen is at times pronounced ‚Äúpenai‚Äù
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South India</ENAMEX>, and when somebody speaks of
krishnoil , he means kerosene <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>.  Expressions like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamil Then-nilavu</ENAMEX> , which is a literal translation
of `<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>' and `moon' and means `honeymoon,' have
also resulted.

            The permutations do not end there.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>
bring nuances from their own languages into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
This has resulted in a variant of English known
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inglish</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian English</ENAMEX>).  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Inglish</ENAMEX> differs from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> ways: words, expressions, grammar, pronunciation
and rhythm.  Inglish sentences are peppered
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> words.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yaar</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Da</ENAMEX> (meaning
`<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chum</ENAMEX>' or `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>'), often punctuate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Inglish</ENAMEX> speech.
Maha , meaning `great,' is another such word; an
irate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> chastises his `maha-lazy‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">enamoured</ENAMEX> youth woos his ‚Äúmaha-beautiful‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX>.
When the police control unruly mobs by
wielding wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batons</ENAMEX> (lathi in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX>), they make
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äúlathi-</NUMEX>charge.‚Äù  When you are introduced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s
‚Äúco-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>,‚Äù you infer that he is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> patterns of grammer are also adopted in
Inglish speech.  ‚ÄúWill you come?‚Äù changes to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúYou
will come?‚Äù and ‚ÄúWhy has she done this?‚Äù to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWhat
for she has done this?‚Äù because that's the right way
to structure those sentences grammatically in the
original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> languages.  Somebody answering the
telephone might be expected to say, ‚ÄúThis is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krishnaswami speaking</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Instead</ENAMEX>, you get a booming,‚Äù
‚ÄúI speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krishnaswami</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            The lilting rhythms and pronunciations of each
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> language are characteristic of the Inglish
spoken there.  Thus, we have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Inglish</ENAMEX> dialects
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinglish, Benglish, Punglish, Tamglish</ENAMEX>,
Malayanglish, and so forth.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inglish</ENAMEX> often
tells you which region of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> he or she hails from.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúTwinkle Twinkle Little Star‚</ENAMEX>Äù sung by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Indian</ENAMEX>
could have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">le</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">twinkle pronounced ‚Äúlay</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andhra Pradesh</ENAMEX> might come up with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telugu flavored Twinkulu Twinkulu Littlu Staru</ENAMEX> ,
while from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Kerala</ENAMEX> come the deeply resonant Malayalam
twangs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwingle Dwingle Liddle Sdar</ENAMEX> .‚Äù

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Inglish</ENAMEX> speech is not complete without
nodding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, some gesticulation, and an expressive
face.

            This may be more than sufficient, perhaps, to
drive the literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX> to suicide.  But before they
plunge the knife in, let them consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
spoken in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> around the world--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and especially
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States of America</ENAMEX>.  A majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> today as it should not be spoken
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX>.

            Languages that rigidly hold on to their purity
soon suffocate themselves.  Those that adapt and
change (and yes, get ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Äúcorrupted‚Äù</ENAMEX> once in a while)
survive and thrive.  It is this quality to adapt that
gives English its virility.  Its status as the most widely
spoken language in the world will take some challenging.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speakers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, this is reason enough
to rejoice.  Listen with an attentive ear to the sounds
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglish</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englishes</ENAMEX> of other lands.  The experience
can be maha-fascinating.
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Naming of Poisons</ENAMEX>



            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX> must be tough being a bartender,‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
would sometimes say to me, in the days
when I was practising the trade.  ‚ÄúHow can you
ever remember all those different drink recipes?‚Äù  It
is not really all that hard, I would explain to them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drinks</ENAMEX> are a lot like popular songs.  First, there are
the standards , like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martini</ENAMEX> and the Screwdriver
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloody Mary</ENAMEX> .  These are to bartender what
White <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Way</ENAMEX> are to a lounge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 20 or 30</NUMEX> of them, and they account
for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of all cocktail orders.

            Then there are the current hits , things like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melonball</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamikaze</ENAMEX> .  These are comparable
to this season's hit songs.  If you don't know how to
make one of them, someone can usually tell you--
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> who ordered it, a regular sitting at the
end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, or another bartender.  After this happens
a few times the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> gets pounded into your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, like the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX> on the juke
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">box.</ENAMEX>

            Finally, there are the oldies-but-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX> .  If you
don't know these, you can look them up in one of
the bartending reference books behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>.

            There is also--with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> as well as with
songs--a phenomenally large number of also-rans.
One can look through the promotional booklets
given out by the liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and the ads in
magazines like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> to find countless unlikely
sounding recipes concocted by marketing departments
in hopes of selling more of their products.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> rarely hears a ‚Äúreal‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> order one of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>.

            If one adds to these flops the unpublicized creations
of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bartenders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>,
it is apparent that in our culture there is an
immense and continual outpouring of mixologic creativity.
Only the tiniest fraction of this output, however,
actually achieves the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> level of popular acceptance,
and becomes a current hit .  Having
reached that level, it is almost as difficult to achieve
the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and become a standard , a drink that
will still be popular by the time the next generation
of current hits comes along.

            I occasionally wondered why, out of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> available, a certain few drinks
had managed to achieve favor with the popular
taste.  It was usually not , as one might have supposed,
because a newly discovered combination of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingredients</ENAMEX> had resulted in some completely unique
new flavor.  An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama Slammer</ENAMEX> , for instance, is
made from sweetish liquors and fruit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX>.  As far as
flavor goes, it offers nothing to the palate that could
not as easily be provided by, say, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore Sling</ENAMEX> .
But, for young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of certain backgrounds,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama Slammer</ENAMEX> is now chic, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sling</ENAMEX> is not.

            The liquor industry sometimes does come up
with new and different flavors.  During the period
when I was tending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, for instance, a honeydewmelon-flavored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liqueur</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midori</ENAMEX>, a product of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distiller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suntory</ENAMEX>, became very popular.
But one might still ask why certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midori</ENAMEX>-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melonball</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> ,
became widely accepted, while others-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddess</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early Spring</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> --languished in the
pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suntory</ENAMEX>'s promotional literature.  I have
concluded that by far the most important factor in
the success of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> is its name .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> where I used to work was located in the
train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>.  This is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> that has both a large naval <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and a private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, and I waited on great numbers
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in their early to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid twenties</TIMEX>.  This is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that, more than any other, serves as the
breeding ground for new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>.  Very often I would
take an order for a drink that was just coming into
popularity, and then, when I served the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>, I
would find out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> had expected
something different.  Frequently that was because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> came from a region of the country
where a different set of ingredients went by the
same name.  What had happened was that the recipe
had become garbled as it traveled across the country
by oral transmission from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> to bartender,
and bartender to bartender.  Yet the name had survived.

            Unlike most products, which may be slipped
across a counter (over or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under</NUMEX>) in silence, drinks
are usually ordered out loud.  Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, when
ordering a drink, like to give an indication, to themselves
and to others, that they are tough, or sexy, or
funny.  They also have a strong tendency to imitate
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and to order what they hear other order.
During the time that I was working as a bartender
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977-1984</TIMEX>), the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> that became
popular almost invariably contained references in
their names to images from the following categories:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) pleasant taste; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) destruction or self-destruction;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) irreverence; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) sexual innuendo.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasant Taste</ENAMEX> : Many young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not
like the taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> in its raw state.  They often
order a drink with a name that seems to promise a
sweet or non-alcoholic taste.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúA Creamsicle</ENAMEX> !?  That
sounds good!  I think I'll try one of those!‚Äù  In all of
the cases below, the name actually does reflect, to
some extent, the taste of the drink.


MELONBALL                  CREAMSICLE
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce Midori             1 ounce vodka</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce vodka              1 ounce</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Triple Sec</ENAMEX>
Fill with orange juice.    Fill with half <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, half
Glass: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>   orange juice; shake.
                           Glass: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with ice

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LONG ISLAND ICED TEA       CALIFORNIA ROOT BEER</ENAMEX>
¬Ω <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ounce vodka       1 ounce</NUMEX> Galliano
¬Ω <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ounce rum         1 ounce</NUMEX> coffee liqueur
¬Ω ounce gin         Fill with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola</ENAMEX>.
¬Ω ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triple Sec  Glass</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with ice
¬Ω ounce tequila     (A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Root Beer Float</ENAMEX>
Fill with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lemon mix</ENAMEX>, add   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Float</ENAMEX> is the same drink
squirt of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola</ENAMEX>.            with the addition of a
Glass: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>   splash of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.)

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAWAIIAN PUNCH             Splash</ENAMEX> of grenadine
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce</NUMEX> sloe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin</ENAMEX>           Fill with half orange 
¬æ ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX>      <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX>, half
      Comfort                <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pineapple juice</ENAMEX>. 
¬æ ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amaretto    Glass</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with ice

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Destruction</ENAMEX> or Self-Destruction : It is not always
clear which of these is referred to in the name
of a drink.  When someone orders a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cherry Bomb</ENAMEX> ,
for instance, is he saying, symbolically, that he is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> to drop a small explosive charge into his nervous
system?  Or is he saying that he is explosive?
Perhaps it is a little of each.  There are many drinks
in this category, as one might expect, since so many
of the euphemisms for drunk (smashed, bombed , etc.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>) also refer to destruction:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KAMIKAZE                   BLEEDING BRAIN</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX>              Fill a shot glass with half
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triple Sec</ENAMEX>         peppermint schnapps,
Few drops <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rose's Lime      half Irish cream liqueur</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Juice</ENAMEX>                      and add a few drops of
Glass: rocks glass, with   grenadine.  The resulting
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice                        curdled</ENAMEX> mess looks
                           like its name.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALABAMA SLAMMER</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern           CHERRY BOMB</ENAMEX>
  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Comfort                  1 ¬</ENAMEX>Ω ounce cherry
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce</NUMEX> sloe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin           brandy</ENAMEX>
Fill with orange juice.    Fill with beer
Glass: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice   Glass</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> mug

B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> part <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tia Maria           Float Irish cream on</ENAMEX> Tia
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> part <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> cream         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>
  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">liqueur                  Marier</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Cream</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> part <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Marnier       Glass</ENAMEX>: cordial pony

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Irreverence: Sometimes these categories
overlap a good deal.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> Motherfucker
could also be placed in the next category, but I think
the name is intended more for shock than anything
else.  It is a way of saying, ‚ÄúI am an outlaw, a mountain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man!‚</ENAMEX>Äù  As one might expect, it tastes like a syrupy
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> shake.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COLORADO MOTHER</ENAMEX>-            MUDSLIDE
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FUCKER                      ¬æ ounce vodka</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce tequila             ¬æ ounce</NUMEX> coffee liqueur
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee liqueur      ¬</ENAMEX>æ ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> cream
Fill with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>; shake;      liqueur
add splash of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola</ENAMEX>.         Glass: rocks glass, with
Glass: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice    ice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PURPLE JESUS</ENAMEX>                (This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> became pop-
¬Ω ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka        ular</ENAMEX> after a series of data-
Graps <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> to fill         strophic mudslides hit
Glass: highball, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>   the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">california</ENAMEX> coast.)

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sexual Innuendo : Leafing</ENAMEX> through old bartending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuals</ENAMEX>, one comes across things like the
Between-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sheets</ENAMEX> cocktail, so there is nothing radically
new about this category.  But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent times</TIMEX>
the references are increasingly blunt.  Much of the
appeal of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> lies in ordering them in such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> as to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">playfully ‚Äúgross out‚</ENAMEX>Äù the bartender.  It is
hard to imagine someone buying the ingredients for
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Orgasm</ENAMEX> at a liquor store and then going home and
mixing up a few to drink while reading mysteries in
bed.  The idea is to go into the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúHey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marybeth</ENAMEX>, can you give me an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orgasm</ENAMEX>?  I
haven't had a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Orgasm</ENAMEX>  for a long time! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HA</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s no wonder,‚Äù deadpans <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marybeth</ENAMEX>, mixing
his drink.


ORGASM                              SLOE SCREW
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">¬æ ounces vodka               1 ¬Ω ounces</NUMEX> sloe gine
¬æ ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee liqueur       Orange juice</ENAMEX> to fill
¬æ ounce amaretto             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>: highball, with ice
Fill with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>; shake.              (A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Screwdriver</ENAMEX> made
Glass: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>             with sole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin</ENAMEX> instead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOLE COMFORTABLE</ENAMEX>                    <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX>.)
  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCREW                             SOLE COMFORTABLE</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce</NUMEX> sloe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin</ENAMEX>                       SCREW AGAINST
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX>                       THE WALL
  Comfort                           <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce sloe</NUMEX> gin
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Orange juice</ENAMEX> to fill                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
Glass: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Comfort</ENAMEX>
(A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sole Screw</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Orange juice</ENAMEX> to fill
addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern                ¬</ENAMEX>Ω ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galliano</ENAMEX> floated
Comfort.)                              on top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLIPPERY NIPPLE                     Glass</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, with ice
¬æ ounce amaretto             (The logic of this is that a
¬æ ounce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream          Screwdriver</ENAMEX> with Galliano
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liqueur                              floated</ENAMEX> on top is
¬æ ounce ouzo                  known as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey</ENAMEX>
Glass: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martini                       Wallbanger</ENAMEX>.  Thus a
Garnish: skewer a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maraschino         Comfortable Screw</ENAMEX> with
cherry with a                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galliano</ENAMEX> floated on top
toothpick, and lay the               becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sole Comfortable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toothpick</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rim             Screw</ENAMEX> Against the
of the glass so that the             <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX>.  In bars it is rarely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cherry</ENAMEX> sits in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>            ordered but much discussed.)
of the drink.

            

         
         
            
‚ÄúWhereas sexologists have previously asked whether
the female gentilia resemble those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s sexual organs may be derived from
those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paladin/Grafton</ENAMEX> book advertisement
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Guardian</ENAMEX> , n.d., .  Submitted by ]

         
         
            
‚ÄúEach of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> rings were positioned inside each
other.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From an article on laser capability in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Job Shop</ENAMEX>
Technology , .  Submitted by 
]

         
         
            
‚ÄúState of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> charges for certified birth,
death, marriage or disillusion....<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Genealogists Newsletter, .</ENAMEX>  Submitted by ]

         
         



            There is no doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> names often provide
a source of amusement, and some well-known
place names persist in their references to things and
activities otherwise rarely broached in polite conversation--you
know, those places in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank R. Abate</ENAMEX>, who has been conducting research
for a comprehensive place-name catalogue,
has sent us a listing of some interesting names in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> that raises some questions.  For instance, why
is there a Why , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whynot</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>?
There is a Due West in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Due</ENAMEX>
West in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
also has a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yell</ENAMEX> , which is presumably connected
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Loud Township</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>.  Not far from Koko
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nankipoo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yum Yum</ENAMEX> , which has its
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lick Fork</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cheesequake</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoofly</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>, not the police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">informer</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodfood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot Coffee ,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nodine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cucumber</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gnaw Bone</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sugartit</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teaticket</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, and, possibly, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fruita</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>.  If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoffly</ENAMEX> is not a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>, it might go better with
Roaches , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bugtown</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mosquitoville</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vermont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bugscuffle</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tussle</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> must be truly humongous.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dinkytown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nebish</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embarrass</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, or in
Wartburg , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, ought to consider twinning
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braggadocio</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.K .</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>.
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> are asked
where they come from, do they tell the truth (or
only if they come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> or Consequences)?  Will
they admit to coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ding Dong</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Unthanks</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brainy Boro</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mudsock</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jackass Flats</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wahoo</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>,
Funkley , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Funkstown</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerk Tail</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zook Spur</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crapo</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúSonny</ENAMEX>, Ah'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ding-dong daddy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ding Dong</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'n'</ENAMEX>, consarn ya, Ah'll plug any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">varmint</ENAMEX> who
smiles.‚Äù  Should we introduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tightwad</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, to those in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Cash</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, and
Greenbackville , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>?  Notress , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> speaks for
itself.  Do any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>?
What can be said about the condition of denizens of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flipping</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Looneyville</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>?

            If you find any Peculiar (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>) names or
ones that comes as a Surprise (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>), just Jot 'Em
Down (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safely</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>)--unless, of course,
they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errata</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>).
