
   
      
         
            Word Law



            I saw an ad once in the back of a magazine promising
that if I sent in some money, I could have a star
in the firmament named after me.  For the same low
price I would receive a certificate and a photograph of
the galaxy where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> was located.  I might even be
able to see that star if I possessed suitable magnifying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>.  I was not tempted by the offer, but it did
occur to me that while I would not like to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>,
as a wordsmith I might like to own my own word.

            Is it possible to own your very own word?  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English language</ENAMEX> may belong to all of us, but some of
its words are the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> or, in most
cases of lexical ownership, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>.  I am referring
to the registered trademarks and service marks
protected under federal law from the infringement of
unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>.  Now, I am a language professional,
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, so if you
want competent advice in the latter areas you should
supplement the summary of the complex trademark
picture that follows.

            The law of trademarks, which fills <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than two</TIMEX>
volumes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Annotated U.S. Code</ENAMEX> in the local law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>--the source of the following information--gives
us some guidance as to what words can
and cannot be staked out as private property and what
that notion of privacy really means when it comes to
the use of language.

            For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, you cannot simply coin a word and
lay claim to it.  You must also sell the goods named by
your trademark or perform services named by your
service mark.  In law, a trademark is a name, logotype,
design, or any combination thereof adopted and used
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> to identify its goods and distinguish
them from articles sold by others.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> mark identifies
you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of specific services rather than
of vendable articles.  For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> is a trademark,
Fotomat , a service mark.  Your trademark or
service mark may be registered, but you may have
rights to the mark even if you have not registered it,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> you choose for your mark may be pictorial,
as the bearded representation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith Brothers</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cough</ENAMEX>-drop fame, who, as some would have it,
are named, respectively, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade and Mark</ENAMEX>.  But a trademark
may also be a word or a group of words.

            Sounds simple, really.  You come up with a no-nonsense
product designed to remove widgets, patent it,
and market it under the straightforward name Widget
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terminator</ENAMEX>.  Maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Widget Terminator</ENAMEX> does its job
well, finds a niche in the market, and over the years
even makes a little money for you.  Only now your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> decides he is going to get into the act
and beat your price.  Of course he calls his knock-off the
WidgetBuster, a much snappier moniker, and he packages
the product behind a picture of a widget inside a
barred red circle.  Since his product works differently
from yours, you cannot get him for violating patent
law, so you haul him into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and sue the pants off
him for infringing on the implied trademark you have
established with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Widget Terminator</ENAMEX>.

            Keeping it all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, you get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny</ENAMEX>, fresh out of law school and eager for work, to
argue that the public has come to love and trust the
Widget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be confused
and deceived by the similarity of the name of the rival
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WidgetBuster</ENAMEX>.  As a result of this confusion of products,
your reputation will be damaged and your sales hurt.
You ask that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WidgetBuster</ENAMEX> be withdrawn from the
market and that your brother-in-law pay you treble
damages and that he pay your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny</ENAMEX>, as well.

            Do you think you will win?  That depends on how
well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny</ENAMEX> did in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intellectual Property Law</ENAMEX>
course.  The law recognizes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic kinds of trademark,
though it allows for a measure of degree in their
definition: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äústrong trademark‚</ENAMEX>Äù is one used only in a
fictitious or fanciful manner, while a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúweak trademark‚</ENAMEX>Äù
is a meaningful word in common usage that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">doubles</ENAMEX> as a suggestive or descriptive trademark.  Weak
trademarks are more difficult to establish, and they
are entitled to narrower protection than strong ones.
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will argue that you may
have an invention, but its name is not a trademark,
because a trademark cannot be an ordinary word, particularly
a descriptive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, if that word is used in its
ordinary sense.  Both widget and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terminator</ENAMEX> are common
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words--a widget is a `gadget, or gizmo,'
in case you did not know--and they literally describe
the function of the product, which is to remove pesky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">widgets</ENAMEX>, so you cannot claim them as your own or
prevent others from using them.

            Of course, if you have ever talked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> you
know that things are never what they appear when it
comes to the law.  There have been trademarks that
were fairly literal, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> ,
which is a trademark of long standing, originally
contained both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and an extract from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola nut</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> went out when it was declared a
controlled substance early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>.  Interestingly,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> (which is also a registered mark)
once sought to prohibit the marketing of something
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tacola-Cola</ENAMEX> , as well as any other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> with the
word <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola</ENAMEX> in its name.  But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> ruled that because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cola</ENAMEX> was a common word describing what was in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage</ENAMEX>, any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola</ENAMEX> derivatives
could be called a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>'s trademark was upheld
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chero-Cola, Clio-Cola, Coca and Cola</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Cola ;</ENAMEX> ruled to be non-infringing were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dope</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherry-Cola, Roxa-Cola</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dixie-Cola</ENAMEX> .  As for other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sodas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moxie</ENAMEX> won its case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noxie</ENAMEX> , but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi-Cola</ENAMEX>
lost against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pep</ENAMEX> , as did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven-Up</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cheer Up</ENAMEX> .

            On the other hand, if the name of your product is
a common word which is applied in an arbitrary or
fanciful sense, you should be able to claim it as a
trademark.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cyclone</ENAMEX> , when
naming a fence, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Innocent</ENAMEX> , as a brand of hair
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coloring</ENAMEX> (suggesting, as the ruling noted, ‚Äúthe very
antithesis of innocence‚Äù) are legitimate trademarks;
but while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Pages</ENAMEX> was found to be a trademark
although it is clearly descriptive, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">raisin bran</ENAMEX> and
spearmint were not granted exclusive status.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Manufacturers</ENAMEX> are fond of deforming the spelling
of an ordinary word to make it distinctive, for example
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NU</ENAMEX> for new, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KWIK</ENAMEX> for quick , or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonz</ENAMEX> for bones (unfortunately,
this last, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> food lacking the so-called
silent e, is frequently mispronounced).  But a clever or
phonetic spelling of a common descriptive word does
not entitle you to own it as a trademark.  Rather, a
common word can become a trademark only if it acquires
a ‚Äúsecondary meaning,‚Äù if, in other words, it is
used so long and so exclusively by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> that it
has come to signal to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> that the product
in question is made by that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, and that
producer alone.  (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have insisted repeatedly
that to be a trademark, a word or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> must call up
not the product or service but its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, the producer
or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>.)

            If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> can afford to wait, time
may be on his side in the battle against widgets.  If you
stop selling a product for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or more years</TIMEX>, you may
lose the right to its trademark.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> frown on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> who pretend to sell a few samples of a
product <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> just to hold on to the name for
future use.  But you may be able to withhold the product
from the market while you experiment with ways
to improve it, and you can change the product significantly
and still retain possession of its name, as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabasco</ENAMEX> did when they altered the formula
of their hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> but successfully defended their right
to exclusive use of the trademark.

            Under the former trademark law, shredded wheat
was considered a generic term and, hence, not registrable.
But because the process for making it was patented,
no other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could produce it, hence the
patent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> had exclusive rights to the name of a
unique product.  When the patent expired, new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>
simply used shredded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> as a descriptive
term.  And although dictionary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah Webster</ENAMEX>
was instrumental in passing our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> federal copyright
laws to protect an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s intellectual property, the
name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> ceased to function as an exclusive trademark
when the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s copyright ran out.
As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as 1904</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. & C. Merriam</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, who claimed to be the literal publishing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah Webster</ENAMEX>'s lexicographical
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>, attempted to restrain the sale of other dictionaries
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> in the title.  In a series of decisions-- Merriam
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Ogilvie</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F 167</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merriam V.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saalfield</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">190</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F 927; 198 F 369</ENAMEX>)--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Circuit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> ruled partly for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam</ENAMEX>, partly for
the competition: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam</ENAMEX> lost its right to the exclusive
use of the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> , but since that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had
become known to the public as the publisher of Noah
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s dictionaries, would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Websters</ENAMEX> were ordered
to disclaim on their title pages any connection
with the original word book.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1940s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
Publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s New
World dictionaries, obtained a ruling to quash the disclaimer
requirement.  In a more recent action, initiated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> again
affirmed the right of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> in
dictionary titles and enjoined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> from
using any variation or combination of the words
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">world-famous</ENAMEX>, authentic, original, genuine , or renowned
to suggest a connection between their product
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Merriam-Webster</ENAMEX> line of dictionaries (Merriam
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">v. Webster Dictionary Co .</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">639</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F 2d 29</ENAMEX>).  It is clear
that for many, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster's</ENAMEX> has become a generic word.
Despite the fact that this synonymy is one that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have repeatedly upheld, no dictionary is willing
to define <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s simply as `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>.'

            Normally, a title cannot function as a trademark,
which is why different books can have the same title,
as long as their contents are different and there is no
intent to deceive the public.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> may
be allowed access to the same trademark if their products
are so different that their markets will not overlap
and if there is no indication that the public will be
confused by the names.  Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cond√©-Nast</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue</ENAMEX> , which is a trademark, were
unsuccessful in a suit to force the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue</ENAMEX>
School of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fashion Modeling</ENAMEX> to change its name.  And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>, the language <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX>, registered as a
trademark in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, failed in its suit against the manufacturer
of Verbatim floppy disks, introduced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>,
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verbatim</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disk</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> agreed never to
produce anything but blank recording <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX> is enjoined only from producing blank media.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of the popular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> movie title
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ghostbusters</ENAMEX> have extended the range of their trademark
with a television show, toys, and other licensed
products bearing its name and distinctive logo, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>, the language <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX>, is free to do likewise.

            Ironically, success can sometimes weaken your
right to a trademark, particularly if your product
name has become a generic term.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cellophane</ENAMEX> failed to
protect itself in an infringement suit when the defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cellophane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> for the
generic name of the product.  Unable to come up with
a synonym for cellophane, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> lost its
trademark.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celluloid</ENAMEX> remained a trademark much
longer, though it too has now become a generic term.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thermos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zipper</ENAMEX> were both originally trademarks.
But both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> became so popular that
their names began to function as generics in the public
mind, and because of that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have ruled that
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> could use these words, uncapitalized,
so long as they did not attempt to confuse or deceive
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>.  However, a design or distinctive style of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">typography</ENAMEX> can be a trademark, and the distinctive
manner of printing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thermos</ENAMEX> as a symbol remains
protected.

            Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law</ENAMEX> regulates only in the broadest sense
what words can or cannot serve as trademarks.  Prior
decisions have little value in trademark claims, and
each case must be argued on its own merits.  As a
result, trademark rulings may seem idiosyncratic or
contradictory.  The law clearly specifies, though, that a
trademark cannot be immoral, deceptive, scandalous,
or disparaging.  Glass <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wax</ENAMEX> , a glass cleaner which contains
no wax, successfully defended its trademark
against a charge that the name was deceptive, but in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1900s</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> refused to recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>
as a trademark for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> because it was ruled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scandalous</ENAMEX>.  (The soft drink <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Monk</ENAMEX> , which was not
perceived to threaten public morality, was permitted.)
Tastes change of course, in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> as well as scandals,
and though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Monk</ENAMEX> is gone from the shelves, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> seem not to be offended by the brand of wine
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Nun</ENAMEX> .

            Foreign words can serve as trademarks in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, but their legal status is determined the
same way as that of English words.  Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selchow</ENAMEX> &
Righter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of the game <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parcheesi</ENAMEX> , could not prohibit
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> from selling games under
such names as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pachisi, Parchisi</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parchesi</ENAMEX> , variant
spellings of the common <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hindi</ENAMEX> word for the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pastime</ENAMEX>.  Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duncan</ENAMEX> was unable to retain exclusive
rights to the name yo-yo because the toy is called
that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, where it originated, and because
it has no synonyms.  On the other hand, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scrabble and Monopoly</ENAMEX> are trademarks for games.  Despite
the fact that both are ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> words,
they meet the secondary meaning test, being easily
recognized as exclusive product names, although the
court also upheld the trademark rights of a game
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anti-Monopoly</ENAMEX> over the objection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monopoly</ENAMEX>-
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker Brothers</ENAMEX>.  That decision remains
confused.

            A trademark can be longer than a word, or even a
pair of words.  You can lay claim to an entire slogan if
it has become widely enough identified with your
product, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> do not let you monopolize the
language.  They will limit your power to control sentences
similar to yours, just as they stymied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of the slogan, ‚ÄúWhere there's life,
there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>,‚Äù who failed in their attempt to prevent use
of all slogans beginning, ‚ÄúWhere there's life...‚Äù including,
as far as I know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age-old</TIMEX> proverb, ‚ÄúWhere
there's life, there's hope.‚Äù

            At any rate, it seems that where there's a trademark,
there's hope for a lawsuit.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox Corporation</ENAMEX>,
recognizing the potential danger of success, has
in the past gone out of its way to protect its right to the
words it owns.  Though I have found no reference to
any trademark suits brought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> against other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has tried to regulate the
use of its trademark in ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>.  For example,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years ago</TIMEX> the xerography <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> took out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-page
ads in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> to remind us that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> is a trademark to be used only as a proper noun,
as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> machine , or a proper adjective, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX>
copy .  In either case, warned the ad, we must capitalize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> .  Despite such entreaties, the word xerox seems
to have become generic, if not according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>,
then at least according to current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> usage,
where it occurs freely as noun, adjective, and even
verb, with or without capitalization.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> persists
because unregulated use by others may cause a trademark
to be deemed abandoned.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, either fearing litigation or simply
because they are sensitive to questions of ownership
of the printed word, prefer to take a cautions approach
to trademarks, capitalizing words like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formica</ENAMEX> in print, though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> major dictionary
recognizes the uncapitalized form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xerox</ENAMEX> ,
and allows it to function as a verb.  But no contemporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lexicon</ENAMEX>, either desk-sized or unabridged, records
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s the commonly-found meaning `an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>, even one not actually attributable to
the lexicographer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Webster</ENAMEX>.'

            But back to the hypothetical case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widget Remover</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mfg. Co. of North America</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WidgetBuster</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S.A</ENAMEX> .  While you may not be able to restrain your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s trade, you can hope that his market
share will become so large as to draw the attention of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ghostbusters</ENAMEX> trademark and that
their battery of high-priced studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> might be
able to get the injunction that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> could not.

            Clearly, owning a trademark can be worth so
much that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> will object willy-nilly to
any and every use of it by another.  In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case the
court told a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> that there can be no monopoly
on love : <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúNo one may preempt the field with
respect to marks having `love' as a portion thereof and
thus exclude all others from the use of any mark composed
in part of such word.‚Äù  But owning a word can do
little for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> like me, except perhaps in the ego
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, since according to the law, a word can be
a trademark only if such status does not deprive others
of their right to the normal use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language.
So if you were planning to give someone a word
for his birthday, think again.  Words that do not fit
cannot be returned.  And owning a word is not like
owning a ball: even if the game is not going the way
you planned, you cannot just pick up your word and
go <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> said they would try to bury him again
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS Evening News</ENAMEX>, 
Submitted by ]
         
         
            
At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:35 a.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Steelman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX>
said: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúFor the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Galena Park</ENAMEX> school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> was found murdered.‚Äù  At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:26 a.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Saucedo</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel 11 News</ENAMEX> said, ‚ÄúFor the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Galena Park</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> has been murdered.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [Submitted
by ]
         
         
            THE STRANGE CASE OF <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOCTOR</ENAMEX> ROTCOD



            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are destined for greatness, some for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mediocrity</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto Rotcod</ENAMEX> was born to become the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palindrome</ENAMEX> made flesh.

            The date of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotcod</ENAMEX>'s nativity was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 3</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/3/39</NUMEX>, an arrangement of figures that read the
same left to right and right to left--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Danbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>, the only area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with a self-reflecting
zip code--03230.  His palindromic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>,
and palindromic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ava</ENAMEX>, named their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotcod</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>,
he wrote a history paper on the career of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
Goethals, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> who masterminded the
building of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX>.  At the end of his report,
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto summarized Goethals</ENAMEX>' achievement
by writing: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>!  A plan!  A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>!  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>!  Rotcod
surveyed his sentence with considerable pride, and discovered
that the statement was a palindrome, causing
him to exclaim: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú ` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A man</ENAMEX>!  A plan!  A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>!  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>!'
sides reversed is `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A man</ENAMEX>!  A plan!  A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>!  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>!‚Äù'
On a hunch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotcod</ENAMEX> wrote down that exclamation and
saw that it too was palindromic.  At that epiphanous
moment of fearful symmetry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotcod</ENAMEX> became a lifelong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cainamaniac</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ciloholic</ENAMEX> who spoke and wrote only in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palindromes</ENAMEX>.  ‚ÄúAh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha!‚</NUMEX>Äù he yelled.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years later</TIMEX>, Rotcod
became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> to realize the unfulfilled potential of
his surname.  Naturally he married a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah</ENAMEX>, and from their marriage issued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> well-balanced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lil</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan</ENAMEX>.

            Having heard about this strange case of linguistic
behavior, I visited the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and
conducted an interview.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEDERER</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotcod</ENAMEX>, I'll begin by asking you
about your preferences in life?  Whom
do you prefer, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, or your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ava</ENAMEX>?

            ROTCOD: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa</ENAMEX>'s a sap .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: So you like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> better?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> is as selfless as I am .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: What about your choice between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> is pep .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>?

            R: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And your second choice?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Is golf your favorite sport?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>?  No sir!  Prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>-flog .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Which do you like better, math or science?

            R: I prefer pi .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Odd</ENAMEX> or even numbers?

            R: Never odd or even .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Would you rather go to a movie or stay home
and watch TV?

            R: Same nice cinemas .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: I'd like to explore your political preferences.
What did you do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past November</TIMEX>?

            R: Rise to vote, sir .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And whom did you want to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?

            R: Name now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: All right.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>.

            R: Tut-tut.  Star comedy by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.  Tut-tut .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Then you voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, yeh .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Let's move on to your career in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>.  What
would you do first for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who came to
you with inflammed gums?

            R: Draw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupil</ENAMEX>'s lip upward .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And what tranquilizer would you recommend?

            R:  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Xanax</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And what do you tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who are sexually
worn out?

            R: Sex at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> taxes .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Is it true that you apply straw to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">warts</ENAMEX>?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Straw</ENAMEX>?  No.  Too stupid a fad.  I put soot on
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">warts</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: I understand that you were recently visited by a
hermit with stomach problems.

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recluse</ENAMEX>'s ulcer?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Yes, what kind of diet did you recommend?

            R: Stressed desserts .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: You emphasized desserts in that diet?

            R: I saw desserts; I'd no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lemons</ENAMEX>, alas, no melon;
distressed was I .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And it is true that you encouraged the patient
to consume alcoholic beverages?

            R: Yo!  Bottoms up--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motto</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boy</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Did you recommend lager or red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peel</ENAMEX>'s lager, red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX> did murder regal sleep .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: I understand that, when none of these ideas
worked, you recommended that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> try
to lose weight by fasting.  What did he say?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúDoc</ENAMEX>, note, I dissent.  A fast never prevents a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fatness</ENAMEX>.  I diet on cod.‚Äù
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctor Rotcod</ENAMEX>, in addition to your fame in
medical circles, you are well-known for your
passionate hatred of evil.

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> is a name of foeman, as I live .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Then what is your advice to those who seek the
good life?

            R: Live not on evil .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: How can one do that?

            R: Repel evil as a live leper .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Do you then wish to stamp out all lies?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX> on evasions?  No!  I save no evil .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: How should one treat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rail</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Can good and evil exist together in this world?

            R: No, it is opposition .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Did evil always exist?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, stone me!  Not so!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Then where did evil begin?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">And Adam</ENAMEX>, too?

            R:  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad Adam</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: What did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX> say when he met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madam</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX>, I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And what did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> say?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, maiden name.  Both sad in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX>?  I dash to
be manned.  I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: What happened when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> saw that jewel of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">forbidden fruit</ENAMEX>?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> saw diamond, erred.  No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And what happened when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> offered the fruit
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>?

            R: Won't lovers revolt now?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: So they sinned together?

            R: Named under a ban--a bared, nude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And the result was...?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> damned <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX>, mad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Can we ever escape the influence of that act?

            R<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Her Eve</ENAMEX>'s noose we soon sever, eh?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Well, can we?

            R: No, evils live on .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Did you yourself ever sin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctor</ENAMEX>?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lived</ENAMEX> as a devil .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: How so?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> did I dwell, lewd I did live .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And what was the result of that life?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reviled</ENAMEX> did I live; evil I did deliver .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Apparently, you began to despair of ever overcoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evil</ENAMEX>.  What did you think?

            R: Do good's deeds live on?  No, evil's deeds do, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
God .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: I imagine that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of affairs made you
quite miserable.

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egad</ENAMEX>, a base life defiles a bad age .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Did you ever despair that evil could be conquered?

            R: No, it can--action!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: So you dedicated your life to fighting evil?

            R: Now do I repay a period won .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And you have fought evil with good?

            R: Did I do, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> God, did I as I said I'd do?  Good, I
did!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Have you finally won your battle against sin?

            R: Now, sir, a war is won .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: Do you feel good about all this?

            R: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revered</ENAMEX> now I live on.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, did I do no evil, I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonder</ENAMEX>, ever?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: I understand that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in virtue have
no doubts that they will have their reward in
heaven.

            R: Nor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>, ah no!  We won halo--of iron!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: And what will happen to you few who have
seen the light?

            R: Are we not drawn onward, we few, drawn onward
to new era?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctor Rotcod</ENAMEX>, I thank you for this two-way
interview.  But how do you do it?  How are you
able to speak in palindromes so skillfully?

            R: Because if I didn't, I'd sound something like
this: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúsihte kilg niht emos dnuos ditn</ENAMEX> didifie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suaceb</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
            
         
         
            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grammatical Game: The Foregone Conclusion</ENAMEX>



            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Foregone Conclusion</ENAMEX> --I claim the capital letters
because I invented it, having beaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fowler</ENAMEX>
to it--is one of the trickiest little imps of social intercourse.
Sometimes it is the sneakiest, too.  Its legerdemain
can come close to infiltrating sexual intercourse
as well, you might say, as in the following tricky,
sneaky example:


Do you think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> should go to his or to her
apartment on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX>?  Not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, liberated
or not, would fail to see through that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foregone</ENAMEX>
Conclusion, I am sure; who said she should
go to any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?

            

            There are far more ingratiating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foregone Conclusions</ENAMEX>
than in such transparent ploys.  How often have
we heard or read statements to the effect that:


It is quicker and cheaper to ride the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> transit
system so why do you drive your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>?

            

            If you start explaining that you are going somewhere
other than home after work or...then you
have fallen into the trap.  To say that it is quicker or
cheaper...may or may not be true.  You should just
be sure that you recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Foregone Conclusion</ENAMEX> .

            Note well, though, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foregone Conclusion</ENAMEX> is
not the same as a false premise.  They are indeed quite
similar but the difference is that a false premise can
stand on its own: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúIt is essential that the government
run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  ‚ÄúAll</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are the same!‚Äù  ‚ÄúAll
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are the same!‚Äù  (We must give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> and the
colonel equal time.)  And the parenthetical comment is
not intended to be an example of a false premise!  You
see it is the element of persuasion that distinguishes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foregone Conclusion</ENAMEX> from the false premise.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foregone Conclusions</ENAMEX> are easy to spot once you
know they may be lurking out there in the verbal
jungle.  Let us go hunting.  Look out--here's one!

            Our brand has double the pain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> of brand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X.</ENAMEX>

            Conclude carefully here: medically a double dose of
pain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> does not always kill any more pain than
does a posological dose.


Which dress do you think you prefer then, madam
...?
            

            In the trade I believe they call this a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äútrial closing‚Äù</ENAMEX> and
it can be a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FC</ENAMEX> --who said she would prefer
any of the dresses?


It is only right that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> making excess profits
should be....
            

            Don't the little (italicized) blighters slip in smoothly?

            All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are created equal....

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>?  Equal?  To one another?  They are born
equally strong?  Or of the same color?  Of course, silly
of me, equal under law is what it means.  But laws
differ from place to place, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.

            I am not trying to make contentious points here
but merely showing how ubiquitous our persuasive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foregone Conclusions</ENAMEX> can be.  How persuasive is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>!

            Watch for more <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Favorite Grammatical Games</ENAMEX> in
following issues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            Word Droppings



            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon</ENAMEX> tabulated an attrition rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX> for
new meanings and new items originally admitted
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Merriam Addenda Sections</ENAMEX> which were cumulatively
included in reprints of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webster's Third New</ENAMEX>
International <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of the English Language</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> intervals in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966-81</TIMEX> period, but
then were excluded from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,000</NUMEX> Words
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>).  Thus a surprisingly high <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98.5%</NUMEX> of the main
entries were retained in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addenda Sections</ENAMEX> in
question.  These evidently possessed whatever qualities
of viability are required for an item to survive in at
least written <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> once it has experienced adequate
quantity and variety of printed occurrence to justify
initial listing in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.  Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> items that
were dropped, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> vanished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two to five years</TIMEX>,
suggesting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early years</TIMEX> of a word's temporary
admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> lexicon are the most critical.

            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this period</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hardcover versions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addenda Sections</ENAMEX> were published-- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Words</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>)
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,000</NUMEX> Words .  Now the hardcover version of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7873</TIMEX>-main-entry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addenda Section</ENAMEX>, appearing simultaneously
as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Words</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), permits an updating
of the statistics.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 164</NUMEX> previously listed main
entries did not appear in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addenda Section</ENAMEX>,
some of which had first been listed as long ago as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>,
but a high <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> of which were first listed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> and so
continue to indicate the critical quality of a new word's
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> in the lexicon.  If we compare these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX>
deletions to the retained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7873</NUMEX> entries, we find that the
updated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> attrition rate only trivially raises the earlier
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX> rate.  With the thought that word <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> will
be interested in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX> apparently unviable words,
we will list them below.  Since the word-formation
process by which they came into the vocabulary may
provide crucial information, the list is organized according
to that process.  Thus, we can see at a glance
that, for example, the highest mortality again appeared
in the new noun compounds, where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX> of
the deletions were noun compounds, whereas the only
variant form was tabbouli .  The deletions consisted of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX> nouns, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> adjectives, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> verbs, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> affixes.  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taxonomy</ENAMEX> is that determined by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,683</NUMEX>-item corpus
described in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>).


NEW MEANINGS                  periselenium             aposelene
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25</NUMEX>)                          scree                    aposelenium

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>                       ABBREVIATIONS            biotron
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bob</ENAMEX>                           (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)                      quadriphony
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter pat                    ADP</ENAMEX>                      reticulosis
delocalize, v.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAL</ENAMEX>                      technopolis
derrick, v.      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EEC                      INITIAL AFFIX</ENAMEX>-
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digger                        IDDD                     ATIONS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fat                           ACRONYM                  antienviron-</ENAMEX>
gate                          KWOC                     ment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX>, adj.     UNABBREVIATED            antimissile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laggard                       SHORTENINGS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)          antirheu-
lagger                        detox, v.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">matic</ENAMEX>, adj.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meson</ENAMEX>                         gox                      antisexist,
microelec-                    hydro                    adj.
trode                         immuno-,                 audiotypist
mu-meson                      comb.       bioelectro-
muon                          form        genesis
-on, suffix      jetavator                cryochemis-
paging                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">youthcult</ENAMEX>                try
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasma                        SHORTENING</ENAMEX> +             cytoecology
poach, v.        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BOUND FORM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor                      acrasin</ENAMEX>                  dehydrotes-
reduplicate,                  antiscientism            tosterone
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v.</ENAMEX>               apholate                 geoprobe
spinner                       astrionics               heliborne
standoff                      emulsible,               adj.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station                       adj</ENAMEX>.        helilift, v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zone                          Ovonic</ENAMEX>                   helispost
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VARIANT FORM                  xenate</ENAMEX>                   hexa-
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabbouli                      SHORTENING</ENAMEX> +             <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">methylene</NUMEX>-
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FUNCTIONAL                    WORD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>)                 tetramine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHIFT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)                     ambisextrous,            magneto-
decorative                    adj.        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fluid-</ENAMEX>
diplotene,                    autodrome                mechanic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adj</ENAMEX>.             birdyback                adj.
dirty                         colorcaster              neurokinin
dustoff                       gravisphere              parapolitical,
punch-up                      moonfall                 adj.
skim                          parakite                 protoconti-
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BORROWINGS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)                resistojet               nent
beef <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bourgui-                 BLENDS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)               telecture
gnon                          gayola                   xenobiology
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dynapolis                     plench                   TERMINAL AFFIX-</ENAMEX>
incendive,                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BOUND-MOR-               ATIONS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adj</ENAMEX>.             <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PHEME ITEMS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)          Africanity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">macchinetta                   Afrophile</ENAMEX>                audiophile
channery,                     air battery              kill ratio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adj</ENAMEX>.             <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Aquarian                 lepton num-</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">computerite                   Age</ENAMEX>                      ber
Dolbyized,                    arcjet                   lip-gloss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adj</ENAMEX>.             <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">arc-</ENAMEX>jet engine           media mix
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ductibility                   Bering</ENAMEX> time              memory
electro-                      bitch box                trace
hydraulics                    bodyclothes              new issue
fluidonics                    broken home              offtrack bet-
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluoridizer                   Colourpoint</ENAMEX>              ting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incapacitator                 Longhair</ENAMEX>                 pump jockey
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosleyite</ENAMEX>                     computerized
mysterium                     aerial to-               rap session
oceanologic,                  mography                 slack-fill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adj</ENAMEX>.             core city                special situa-
projectual                    cyclic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>             tion
psychedeli-                   death control            speed freak
cize, v.         dunk shot                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">surfer</ENAMEX>'s knot
quadriphon-                   eye <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>               teaching ma-
ics                           fly-cruise               chine
quantized,                    fractional or-           <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adj</ENAMEX>.             bital bom-               up quark
restartable,                  bardment                 wake surfing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adj</ENAMEX>.             system                   water tooth-
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIXED AFFIX-                  gamma</ENAMEX> decay              pick
ATIONS                        heat pollu-              xenic acid
antinatalist                  tion                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADJ</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMPOUND</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOUN COM</ENAMEX>-                     hemoglobin S             air-cushion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POUNDS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">46</NUMEX>)                   imitation                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">VERB COM-</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> art                       <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk                     POUNDS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)
adenosine                     ionic propul-            clock in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,5</NUMEX>'-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mono</NUMEX>-                   sion                     clock off
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX>                     isolated cam-            clock on
Age of                        era                      clock out
Aquarius                      juice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>                fuck around

            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>.  Historical Change and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
Word<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-Formation: Recent Vocabulary</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">340pp</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lang</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúKnowing the Fervor with Which You Speak...‚</ENAMEX>Äù



            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Rudman</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13, 1987</TIMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-contra</ENAMEX> hearings drenched us in a stunning
array of colorful words.  For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX>
an august <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> met in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Caucus Room</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>'s
Office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Building</ENAMEX>.  During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those several weeks</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early summer</TIMEX> the world could listen to articulate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> who have the ability to manipulate
our minds and twist our emotions with word-images.
Through the clever and sometimes masterful use of
language, the same activity or event was made to
sound logical, or patriotic, or it could appear to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sordid</ENAMEX> and bordering on treason.  For example, consider
this clever exchange between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> committee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Liman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lieutenant Colonel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>:


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liman</ENAMEX>: And, you therefore were told to get rid of
the memoranda that reflected that?

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>: I was told to clean up the files.
            

            One statement suggests concealing or hiding something;
the other implies good sound bookkeeping, running
a tidy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> wanted to convey the
notion that they were not concerned with language.
Rather, they were only concerned with getting at the
facts.  They wished to bring the message of what actually
happened and show a concerned world that truth
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> would triumph.  Still, for this to happen, all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> recognized that language was important
to ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> would understand acts and
events as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> wished them to be understood.

            During the hearings, we watched unfold before us
a variety of words and phrases to indicate the concept
of not telling the truth.  Seldom did anyone admit to
lying, but statements were often couched in terms colorfully
indicating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> had abandoned verity.
For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Nields, Jr.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s
majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, asked, ‚Äú...Are you saying
that he told you to write down a different version of
the facts?‚Äù  And <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> later he continued, ‚ÄúAre you
saying that you decided it was appropriate to put out a
false version of the facts?‚Äù  In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lieutenant Colonel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>'s response he used the words a version of the
chronology that was inaccurate .  Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX> used the
phrase the chronology with the false version in it .  He
then followed with a question, staying with this
stronger phrase false version .  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>'s response contained
the clause this version of the document was
wrong, intentionally misleading .  Earlier he had used
this version was incorrect .  Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX> had used false
version , he stayed with that for a while.  Then he used
false story .  This word story presents interesting possibilities.
Used in a straight forward positive sentence, it
carries a favorable connotation: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWe want to get out
the whole story,‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúCol. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> will tell his story to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>.‚Äù  But used with words with unfavorable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">connotations</ENAMEX>, it assumes a pernicious meaning of
make-believe, for example, ‚ÄúIs that still his story?‚Äù  or
‚ÄúWhat is his story now?‚Äù

            Other euphemisms for lying that were used included
excessive statements, outright misrepresentation,
dissembled, prudent to change those chronologies ,
and radically different from the facts .  The
concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúplausible deniability‚Äù</ENAMEX> is a variation on the
theme of avoiding the recognition or the admission of
lying.  Implicit in the term is the idea that one has
chosen to do something that one may want to deny
later.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> must then consider if such a denial is reasonable,
that is, believable.  If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> denies something, is
it possible that the denial, that is, the lie, could be
exposed?  It might be possible to establish an equation
to determine the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plausible Deniability Factor</ENAMEX> (PDF) of
any statement.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Psychologists</ENAMEX> and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> could
do a lot with that.

            The deleteriously loaded term elaborate scheme
popped into the hearings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' words, ‚Äú...this elaborate scheme was to
carry out these activities<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">...‚Äù  In American English</ENAMEX>
scheme strongly implies `craftiness, secret intent';
while not as strong as plot , it certainly lacks the neutral
qualities of plan and conveys a meaning far beyond
its dictionary definition.

            Near the close of the session <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July 8th</TIMEX>,
there arose a clever word game after Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX> characterized
some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>'s responses as several
speeches .  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Sullivan, Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>,
objected to the term, declaring it to be pejorative.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Inouye</ENAMEX> said, ‚Äú...some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consider lengthy statements to be speeches.‚Äù  Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX> replied, ‚ÄúI'm perfectly happy to use the expression
`lengthy statements.‚Äù'  And Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> came
back with, ‚ÄúHow about using lengthy answer...?‚Äù
Speeches in this context carries with it too much of the
idea of pontificating, which Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> did not want.
While statement is better, answer gives the mental picture
of completion.  Someone who knows can give an
answer; we are left with a positive image.  Response
would have been a good neutral word, but neither side
was thinking neturality that late in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX>.

            Another classic example of a loaded word jumped
up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days later</TIMEX> when Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liman</ENAMEX> asked a question
that began, ‚ÄúAnd after you became involved, linked
with...‚Äù This word linked is a sneaky little devil.
While it means simply to `couple or connect,' the connotation
is always negative.  No one is linked to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX>, but people
may be linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>.
When we hear that someone is linked to an organization
or cause of which we have never heard, we feel
ominously that this must be bad.

            Early in the proceedings we saw a cat-and-mouse
game develop over what to call `money that is excess
over expenses in a business transaction.'  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX>
asked, ‚Äú...what did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> know about the
diversion of the proceeds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> sale to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Contras?‚Äù  North</ENAMEX> responded, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> never personally
discussed the use of the residuals or profits from the
sale....‚Äù  This was one of the few times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>
used profit , choosing to stay with the more charming
residuals , as used here, meaning `remainder.'

            When Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX> used diversion again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>
responded with ‚ÄúWell, you insist on referring to it as
`diversion.'... my use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>...leads me to believe
that those were `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residuals</ENAMEX>' and not diverted--the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing we did was divert money out...and put it
to better use....<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Nields</ENAMEX> countered with ‚ÄúI'm not
asking about words, now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX>.  I'm asking you
whether you didn't continue to send memoranda seeking
approval of diversions or residuals, whatever the
word....‚Äù  While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX> seemed uninterested in
words, he, nevertheless, stayed with diversion
throughout the questioning, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX> continued with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">residuals</ENAMEX>.  Divert means to `change from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> or
use to another or to turn aside.'  In some contexts the
word can connote `secrecy and deception,' a diversion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tactic</ENAMEX> , for example.  Used in another context, it is perfectly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harmless</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> of a river, for instance, may be
diverted to prevent flooding.

            The words profit and proceeds are almost equal in
meaning.  When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX> used proceeds , he was passing
up a chance to irritate or challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>, for the
connotations are completely different.  It is much better
to refer to the proceeds of a raffle rather than the
profits.  Profit is deeply rooted in the world of business
and too often associated with money-grubbing and
greed.  Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> referred to a
profit-making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> , which sounds harsher than if
he had chosen to say profit-making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> .  But
‚Äúproceed-producing enterprise‚Äù would have sounded
even more innocuous.  Shortly after this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> used
the terms revenue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and deserving of fair just
reasonable compensation .  These phrases are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more
synonyms for profit that alter our perception a little.

            As with the myriad words surrounding profit ,
there was a plethora of words surrounding the Boland
Amendment.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> used the phrases complying
with those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boland Proscriptions</ENAMEX>, the constraints and
proscriptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boland</ENAMEX> , and working around the
problem that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boland</ENAMEX> would have created .  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liman</ENAMEX>
responded to this last phrase with, ‚ÄúWell, another
word for working around, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have had
some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, is `circumvent.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù'  Circumvent</ENAMEX> does mean
to `work around' and implies ingenuity and strategy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Circumvent</ENAMEX> is much more precise than the term work
around and suggests a planned detour to avoid the
law.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>'s statement that he ‚Äúsought a means of complying
with...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boland‚</ENAMEX>Äù and his work around remark
mean essentially the same, but complying sounds
much nicer, conveying the idea of adhering to regulations.
On the other hand, circumvent suggests avoiding
what is mandatory and at the same time returns a
more formal, legalistic atmosphere to the questioning.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> terms that surfaced during Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liman</ENAMEX>'s questioning
were fall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX> , both terms introduced
by him and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collegiate Dictionary</ENAMEX> tells us that a fall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is `one
who is easily duped.'  A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> definition reveals it to
be synonymous with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX> .  But fall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is a less
formal term and suggests ignorance.  Many of us recall
the old gangster movies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humphrey Bogart</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cagney</ENAMEX>.  Either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX> must have
said, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">‚ÄúYou</ENAMEX> ain't gonna pin this rap on me!  I ain't no
fall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>!‚Äù  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scapegoat</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, means `one
who bears the blame for others'; it is a political word
that carries with it a certain nobility and martyrdom
that fall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> doesn't imply.

            The rich and rewarding, and often necessary,
sport of quibbling over words arose early in the questioning
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>, responding to a question
from Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nields</ENAMEX>, replied, ‚Äú...the word `investigation'
wasn't used... Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX> had been asked to do
a fact-finding inquiry....‚Äù  Later during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attorney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>'s appearance before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, those two
words came up often.  Those who tended to be favorable
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX> used inquiry while those distrustful
of him were inclined to use investigation .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX> contended
that his actions took just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>, and investigation
implies a thoroughness that is missing in inquiry.
While some were prone to use the phrase
extensive or complete investigation , others used brief
or informal inquiry .

            Somewhere, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> must
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bestow</ENAMEX> upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX> a special commendation
for his creation of a description of a planned
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that would be ‚Äúa more or less off-the-shelf
independent, stand-alone, self-supporting
operation for covert operations.‚Äù  He used a noun, two
prepositional phrases and a string of adjectives that
would make anyone proud.

            So the hearings have come and gone, but the
repercussions will remain for some time.  Our judgments
may hinge on a well-turned phrase, a beautifully
nuanced sentence, a word-image that flashes
across our gray matter reminding us of childhood.  A
position that seemed logical a while ago now becomes
irrational.  A strong conviction is suddenly an indefensible
belief.  Some of us will hold to an idea or concept
regardless of the evidence; others will change positions.
Still others will simply marvel at the use of language
and wonder just where our analytical side ends
and our emotional side begins.  We may never know for
sure if our conclusions are based on cold, hard logic or
pure sentiment.
         
         
            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accent Matter</ENAMEX>?
            This interesting, readable book is probably the
most sensible work on the pronunciation of English
ever published.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honey</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> linguist
now on assignment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bophuthatswana</ENAMEX>, one of the less
easily pronounceable places in the world, writes in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">straightforward</ENAMEX>, simple, casual, friendly style totally
devoid of the off-putting symbols and technical jargon
that usually mark writing on pronunciation.  That is
not to say that the book's theme is casual, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>
comes to grips with social aspects of language that are
seldom treated, even in a clinical manner, by linguists.
A notable exception in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labov</ENAMEX>; but, despite his open, readable style, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labov</ENAMEX>'s
work is known mainly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> because it appears
in scholarly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and in books distributed largely to
the academic market.  For all that, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does Accent Matter</ENAMEX> ?
is not a whit less scholarly, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faber</ENAMEX> must be
congratulated for perceiving it as a work that deserves
a wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>.  The biggest concessions to make
the presentation more palatable for the general reader
is the elimination of footnote references within the
text: even superior numbers do not appear in the text,
and those who demand footnotes must refer to a brief
Appendix where they are arranged, chapter by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>,
with clear page references.  As one who understands
the importance of footnotes but loathes them
because of their continual, unsightly interruption of
normal reading, I applaud this treatment: they are
there if you want them, but they do not intrude.  The
index is quite thin on the ground: after reading such a
book, one naturally puts it aside till it is wanted for
reference to certain points, and the paucity of the index
will make the location of information something of
a chore at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later date</TIMEX>.  I have always felt that every
book on language should include, either in its index or
in a separate listing, all of the words and word elements
discussed in the text, for they often provide the
point of reference for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honey</ENAMEX> explains the distinction between dialiect
and accent :


If a regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> also uses the grammer, vocabularly,
and idiom that are distinctive of his region,
then we say he is speaking dialect.  But if he uses the
grammer, vocabularly, and idiom of the standard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> found in newspapers, books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, and
news bulletins, then all we notice about his speech is
his accent--and possibly his intonation.

            

            Most of this book is understandably concerned with
accent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, though other varieties
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> are discussed.  To better understand attitudes
toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> spoken in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> one must
be familiar with the term Received Pronunciation
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP</ENAMEX>), which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> describes as:


The accent most obviously associated with the standard
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> dialect..., [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP</ENAMEX>] echoes the rather
old-fashioned sense of `received' as meaning `generally
accepted' as in the terms `received opinion' and
`received wisdom,' especially by those who are
qualified to know.

            

            Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of English worldwide, either as a native
or an acquired language, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP</ENAMEX> is the most highly
regarded accent--indeed, some might well regard RP
as standing for `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revealed Pronunciation</ENAMEX>'--so it behooves
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to pay attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Professor Honey</ENAMEX>'s comments
about it, favorable and adverse.  The chapter
titles give a good indication of the subject matter
covered:


<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ONE</TIMEX>  What is `an accent'?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TWO</NUMEX>  Where did RP come from?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">THREE</NUMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking</ENAMEX> proper and talking posh
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOUR</ENAMEX>  Are some accents better than others?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">FIVE</NUMEX>  What is happening to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIX  Accent</ENAMEX> variety and the mass media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEVEN</ENAMEX>  The accents of politics
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIGHT  Changing</ENAMEX> patterns
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NINE  Accents</ENAMEX> and the future

            

            In the course of his treatment of these topics, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> provides a wealth of information that answers
numerous questions (and confronts many of the prejudices)
that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have about language:


Increasing literacy and pressures towards `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correctness</ENAMEX>'
led in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> to spelling-pronunciations
which caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to restore a whole range of
sounds which earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> had dropped, like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">l</ENAMEX> in fault, vault, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> w in
awkward and the sole w in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX>; the t at the
end of pageant, respect, and strict; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX> in
the middle of the word <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.  Over the same period <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of the
standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> accent learned to drop the final d
0which for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> had been attached when ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> talked of a scholard and his gownd.

            

            We all know about language prejudice, but it is nonetheless
interesting to read that:


...an RP accent was one of the foremost criteria
for being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>.  In Birmingham
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX> it was possible to buy a manual
designed to enable local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to correct their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accents</ENAMEX>, since, as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> claimed, ‚Äúto no one is
the absence of local dialect more important than to
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the army‚Äù.  Carnage at the
front forced that specification to be relaxed in
many cases, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had to be commissioned
whose voices betrayed their promotion from the
ranks.  When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> inspected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadets</ENAMEX>
at a public school (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lancing</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen-year-old</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Waugh</ENAMEX> helped to organize the
dropping of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> as a demonstration against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s accent....

[In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>] the public-school-educated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actor Dirk Bogarde</ENAMEX> (born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>) claims
that in that war the sole reason for his promotion
from the ranks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> status was his accent.

            

            And we know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Professor Honey</ENAMEX> has it right when
he writes about


...the tendency, which now pervades the whole
of our society, for us to attach to particular accents
certain generalized assumptions about the values
and attributes considered typical of certain social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.  In other words, we judge accents by
stereotypes which we already have about their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>....  One <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> has claimed that
non-standard features (grammer and vocabulary as
well as accent) have the power to close off a conversation
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>, bring job interviews to an
abrupt end and, when used on the telephone, to
render a flat advertised as vacant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that morning</TIMEX> suddenly
to be declared <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúalready let‚Äù</ENAMEX>.

            

            A curious aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP</ENAMEX> was (or is) its continual
shifting: as soon as some of its characteristics are
adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of a different social or educational
class, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, by consent that could
scarcely be tacit, change the rules of the game, coming
up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shootin</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">huntin</ENAMEX>'.  For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.S. Van Dine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> novels of the
1930s might have been mystified by the insertion into
the dialogue of its lordly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> expressions like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">don</ENAMEX>'tcher know and the anathematized ain't .


            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> may be pleased (or relieved) to learn
that


The American accent--any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> accent--can
expect a favourable reception in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
reasons.  First, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> is perceived as standing
outside the social-class hierarchy which partly explains
the scale of evaluation of our own <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> accents.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>, we are not able to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, on accent
alone, the features of `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educatedness</ENAMEX>' which might
be apparent to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>, so we
give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> the benefit of the doubt.  Thirdly,
the American accent is to some extent glamorized
by the film industry and by the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
programmes shown on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> television.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
English accents, which in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> cannot normally
be distinguished from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, share the
same generally favourable evaluation....  If the
greatest single influence on the current evolution of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English RP</ENAMEX> and of many non-standard accents in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> today is the `popular' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> accent, it is
also true that the greatest single influence on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grammar</ENAMEX>, vocabulary, and idiom of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as spoken
and written in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American English</ENAMEX>.

            

            Those who are not intimately familiar, from listening
to them on radio and television, with how specific
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>
since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX> sound may find themselves at sea in the
rather detailed descriptions (chapters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six and seven</TIMEX>) of
their pronunciations and their effects, good and bad,
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>.  Despite that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>'s treatment
is virtually self-explanatory, and anyone contemplating
a work on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> accents would do well to be
guided by the principles he has established.

            Inevitably, there are some slips regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pronunciation</ENAMEX> and accent, most if not all of which
can be charged to the failure to identify specific dialects
or the absence of a restrictive modifier like most
or many to precede <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> .  For example,


<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American English</ENAMEX> removes the y- from the yu-
sound when it turns new and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX> into noo and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dook</ENAMEX>...

            

            That is a pattern characteristic of only certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dialects (as a check in any good modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX> would reveal).  The same is true for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>'s
assumptions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> , which he implies is universally
pronounced in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AE</ENAMEX> with the vowel of boot ;
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> syllable of which is not
always rhymed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AE</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> ; about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> , which is
pronounced identically to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> (RP) way by
many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>; and about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-nam of</ENAMEX>
which, contrary to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s information, is pronounced
by many AE <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to rhyme with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX> , not
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">palm</ENAMEX> .  As for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> tend to give both a
sounds the same quality, whether they rhyme them
with that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> .  On the other hand, the
pronunciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> follows either
the pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> , which has the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> syllable and that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in the last, or, as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, is heard with the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in both positions.

            Again:


<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> pronounce a strong r in card, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, and
similar contexts...,

            

            an observation that does not apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Englanders</ENAMEX>.  And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> has been misled to
infer that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> say deTAIL, baTON, INquiry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adverTISEment</ENAMEX>, haRASS, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REsearch</ENAMEX>: both occur.
I, for one, say deTAIL, baTON, inQUIry or INquiry
(depending on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>), adVERtisement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HARass</ENAMEX>, and
reSEARCH, which leads me to think that these stress
patterns are not necessarily distributed along dialectal
lines.


...Britons get the impression that large numbers
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> go through their whole lives unable
to make confident distinction between a positive
and a negative statement of possibility, between `I
can do it' and `I can't do it'.

            

            It may not come as much of a revelation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>
Honey to learn that even I, a native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AE</ENAMEX>,
often have to ask whether an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> meant
to say can or can't when the word receives any emphasis;
but in normal, unstressed speech the former is
usually reduced to `k'n' while the latter is of longer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duration</ENAMEX>, even, than that of the noun can .  To be sure,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP</ENAMEX> practice of rhyming can with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a of</TIMEX>
can't with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> does neaten things up a bit.

            
               Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accent Matter</ENAMEX>?  has a sprinkling of amusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anecdotes</ENAMEX>, this being one of my favorities:


Around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> political figure was
made the subject of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> radio profile.  The programme
was the more interesting because of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s admirable fluency in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Listeners</ENAMEX>
were diverted to hear him explain, in answer to a
question about his personal life, that his pastimes
included ‚Äúmiddle-aged antics,‚Äù and they must have
wondered what innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">japes</ENAMEX>--or perhaps amorous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frolics</ENAMEX>--the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> got up to, until they
worked out that middle-aged was his very reasonable
attempt at translating du moyen age (medieval),
and that antics was his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gallic</ENAMEX> stress pattern
for `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">antiques'</ENAMEX>.

            

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AE</ENAMEX> sojourning for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past twenty years</TIMEX>, I
have been struck by the creeping changes I have perceived
in the RP pronunciation of some ordinary words
(controversy, disciplinary) and of proper names: news-readers
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Radio 4 and World Service</ENAMEX> tend to
stress <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khomeini</ENAMEX> on the last syllable
where formerly one heard it stressed on the sound.

            I had best curb my temptation to reproduce the
entire book here by stopping now, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with
a great deal to look forward to.  In the unlikely event
that my message has not come across, allow me to
repeat that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are sure to find it as
engaging as I did.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Urdang</ENAMEX>
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longman Register of New Words</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ayto</ENAMEX> has drawn on a world of English-language
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for the citations
in this interesting and useful book.  Most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX>-odd
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are, quite naturally, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> in origin and persuasion,
with a fair sprinkling of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX>; others
looked at include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> (for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> ).  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayto</ENAMEX> writes well, and his Introduction
(actually, to get fussy about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreword or Preface</ENAMEX>)
sets forth clearly the aims and purposes of this
collection of neologisms.  The selection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1200</NUMEX> entries
for inclusion seems a bit esoteric, but the general structure
of the work--entry word, part of speech, definition,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">citation</ENAMEX>(s), and, in many cases, an explanatory
comment on the origin of the term, its etymology, and
other information--is straightforward.

            Rather than skip through, picking up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúshowcase‚Äù
entries throughout the book, I chose to read thoroughly
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first quarter</TIMEX> (A<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-C</NUMEX>) and remark on specific
entries.  I have not commented on entries that are either
entirely satisfactory or out of my ken.


advance man The definition given, `someone who
makes arrangements for visits and appearances
by an eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and goes in advance to
ensure that they proceed smoothly...A word
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> origin.'

            

            This seems too specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American English</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AE</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> who associate the designation with the circus
and other entertainments.


amicus brief `<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> a legal submission by someone
who is not party to a case but has an interest
in its outcome...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amicus</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfriend</ENAMEX>.‚Äù '

            

            This shortened form may be rare in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British English</ENAMEX>
[BE], but the term amicus curiae , literally `friend
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>,' is well established in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">etymological</ENAMEX> note could be misunderstood.

