
   
      
         
            Zap the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BEMs</ENAMEX>!  Onward, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Cadets</ENAMEX>!



            -- The bumper sticker reads, ‚ÄúBeam me up, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotty</ENAMEX>.

            There is no intelligent life on this planet.‚Äù
            

            -- Trying once more to attract the ear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin</ENAMEX> the
daydreamer, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> says, ‚ÄúEarth to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin</ENAMEX>.  Earth
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin</ENAMEX>.  Come in, please!‚Äù
            

            -- After my infant son has done <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those cute
things that portend a definitely-not-ordinary childhood,
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> asks, ‚ÄúWhat would Mr. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Spock</ENAMEX> say?‚Äù  Without a beat missed, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>,
and I--alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> all--reply, ‚ÄúLive long and prosper.‚Äù

            

            If these vignettes strike sympathetic chords, then
science fiction's words, phrases, and lore have permeated
your thought and language.

            This will not be a discussion of the science fiction
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>) dialect, which is certainly a legitimate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, given
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> for whom blaster, phaser, warpdrive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyborg</ENAMEX> and the like are familiar terms.  It will,
rather, treat those words and phrases, created in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>,
which are now in common non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> use.

            There has been no entirely satisactory definition
of science fiction: all proposals seem to exclude some
work which individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> would include in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>.  It has been suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> include only those
stories which would be invalidated without their scientific
content;  that fiction which concerns science,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, and the impact of science on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>;  that
which explores alternate existences (whether future,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extraterrestrial</ENAMEX>, or only in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' minds) based on
facts and logical progression via scientific method.   As
hard-core pornography, so do I of science fiction: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúI</ENAMEX>
shall not attempt further to define the kind of material
...embraced within that short-hand description.
...But I know it when I see it.‚Äù  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> cited
here as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> have been classed as such by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX>
reputable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> alternate existence, the ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, was considered
by the ancients (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato's Republic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristophanes</ENAMEX>'
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Birds</ENAMEX> ).  However, it is Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas More</ENAMEX>'s
speculative work of political science and sociology-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utopia</ENAMEX>
(from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> ou - `not' + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">topos</NUMEX> -`place')--which
became, generically, the impossibly
perfect place.  The looking-glass image of utopia--dystopia--has
provided more numerous additions
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> lexicon.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldous Huxley</ENAMEX> excerpted
words from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Tempest (‚ÄúHow</ENAMEX> beauteous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mankind</ENAMEX> is!  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> brave new world,/ That has such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in 't.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>) for the ironic title of his dystopic novel.
The phrase brave new world is now synonymous with
a nightmarish, technically advanced society.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>

            This essay was selected as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sixth VERBATIM Essay Competition</ENAMEX>.

            Orwell constructed an alternative future in his vision
of the totalitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nineteen Eighty</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> .  The
work has given <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> a small lode of unpleasantries:
the title itself connotes a society marked by government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terror</ENAMEX> and propaganda destroying the public's
consciousness of reality (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED Supplement</ENAMEX> also accepts
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984 and 1984-ish</TIMEX> as adjective forms); that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
official language, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Newspeak</ENAMEX> , now indicates
the propagandistic or ambiguous language of, among
others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>
(‚Äúrevenue enhancement‚Äù for ‚Äútax increase,‚Äù etc.); the
twisting of minds to the capacity to accept the validity
of utterly contradictory opinions or beliefs, or double-think ;
the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX> , implies an
apparently benevolent, but really ruthless, omnipotent,
and omniscient state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>.

            Taking an uncomfortably short speculative step
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> film, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúDr</ENAMEX>. Strangelove, Or
The title character of this dark comedy seriously considered
plans for and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúbeneficial‚Äù</ENAMEX> results of nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">holocaust</ENAMEX>; such contemplation is strangelovian .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A. Heinlein</ENAMEX> envisaged a more optimistic
future in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stranger in a Strange Land</ENAMEX> .
Its Martian-reared main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character advocates</ENAMEX> advancing
the empathic capability of the human mind so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> can grok `embrace others with profound, intuitive
understanding.'  It is not clear why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heinlein</ENAMEX> chose
such an unpretty word for such a beautiful concept
(maybe it is euphonious to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX> auditory apparatus);
it has, nevertheless, caught on.

            Monsters have had starring roles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> from its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>.  The archetypal uncontrollable creation-gone-amok
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> , commonly familiarized
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incognizant</ENAMEX> who
thus disserve <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Shelley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Baron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Baron</ENAMEX> may have been misguided,
but at least he was not so mad a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> as to
experiment on himself.  That lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> was shown
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Louis Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dr. Jekyll</ENAMEX> ( The
Strange <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>), whose
impressive bodily transformations to his evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made Jekyll-and-Hyde</ENAMEX> descriptive of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who alternately
demonstrate good and evil behavior.

            The recurrent motif of time travel came to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fore in H.G. Wells</ENAMEX>'s The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Machine</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX>), considered
by some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first work</TIMEX> of true <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells</ENAMEX> prototype,
a controllable time-space <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>, is used allusively
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forecasters</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Day Lewis</ENAMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúHow Poetry Began‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>), wrote ‚ÄúTo find this out,
we'll have to jump into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Machine</ENAMEX>, put its gear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lever</ENAMEX> into reverse, and race backwards through many
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> into prehistoric time.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>).  Einsteinian
relativity theory, with its absolute maximum speed
limit (the speed of light), might have put an end to
such speculation had it not also included the concept
of curvature of space.  It was then but a small step to
the space warp, permitting faster-than-light (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTL</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX>) travel by straight-line shortcutting across the
curves of space.  Except for its origin, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interplanetary Society Journal</ENAMEX>, space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">warp</ENAMEX> has been
restricted to fictional use.  (After all, you can't have a
good intergalactic war when the next galaxy is, at the
speed of light, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,200,000 years</TIMEX> away.)  Not so its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> warp (fathered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter M. Miller</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThey</ENAMEX> showed me a dozen pictures of moppets with
LTR-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, moppets in time-warp suits, moppets wearing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Chronos</ENAMEX> costumes....<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>); originally another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTL</ENAMEX>, or time-travel device, it has entered standard
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, designating any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> of time travel,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> discontinuity, or suspension of time's progress.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> need not be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-heroes</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1934</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music Ho</ENAMEX>!,  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constant Lambert</ENAMEX> noted
‚ÄúThe most successful time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> was
undoubtedly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serge Diaghileff</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            The catchwords of the classic science fiction era
were space and robot.  Citations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED Supplement</ENAMEX>
for space technology terms yield a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's Who of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>: spacefaring (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poul Anderson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>); spacer `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spaceman</ENAMEX>'
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.M. Kornbluth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov</ENAMEX>, both in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>); spaceship (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jacob Astor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the fur
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.S. Lewis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Clarke</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>); space-flight (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Clarke</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>); space sickness
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>).  The moment of launch into space,
blast off, was created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Bradbury</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver</ENAMEX>
Locusts: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúYou could smell the hard, scorched smell
where the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX> blasted off when it went back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  Slang</ENAMEX>'s space cadet `an eccentric, especially one
who is stuporous or out of touch with reality' evolved
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúTom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corbett, Space Cadet</ENAMEX>,‚Äù a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> television
series depicting the adventures of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24th-century</TIMEX> cadet
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solar Guides</ENAMEX>, the interplanetary police force
keeping order in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solar Alliance</ENAMEX>.

            The properly dressed spaceman (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thrilling Wonder</ENAMEX>
Stories, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>) must have a space suit (from the pulp
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Science Wonder Stories</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>) for his rendezvous with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, of whom many are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BEMs</ENAMEX> (bug-eyed monsters)
or LGM (little green <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>).  (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientists</ENAMEX> currently
searching the radio frequency spectrum for signals indicative
of extraterrestrial intelligence refer to their
goal--positive intelligent signals--as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LGM</ENAMEX>.)  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alas,</ENAMEX>
such close encounters have not generally been friendly.

            The battles between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have featured
manifold armament.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors extrapolated</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roentgen</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX> discovery of x-rays and wrote of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heat-ray</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. G. Wells</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War of the Worlds</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>), and
disintegrator rays (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Griffith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Lord of Labour</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>), not to mention ray-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and blasters.  The
weight of this fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weaponry</ENAMEX> has popularized the
death ray from its pulp <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> origins to serious contemporary
consideration as laser technology has advanced.
Weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> have tried to euphemize and deromanticize
the terminology: death rays are called
‚Äúbeam weaponry,‚Äù and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> antimissile defense system
is SDI (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Strategic Defense Initiative</ENAMEX>), despite the
public acceptance of the catchier Star Wars (from the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> film).  We also should recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> as the
source of zap, which is used as noun, verb, and interjection
to indicate `sudden power' (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n.</ENAMEX>), to `kill in a
burst' (v.), or the `sound effect for sudden destruction'
(int.).  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED Supp</ENAMEX>. traces the word from an
episode of the comic strip ‚ÄúBuck <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX> in the 25th
Century‚Äù written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Francis Nowlan</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1929--‚</ENAMEX>ÄúAhead of me was one of those golden dragon
Mongols, with a deadly disintegrator ray...Br-r-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">rr</NUMEX>-r<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-z-zzz-zap</NUMEX>.‚Äù
--to its most notorious use (cited in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Speech in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>), ‚ÄúThe jokester, pretending to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> from outer space, pointed his cosmic ray gun
(finger) at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s genitals and exclaimed, `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zap</ENAMEX>!
You're sterile.' ‚Äù

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karel ƒàapek</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>
of robot a `machine which replaces a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>' in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.U.R. (for ‚ÄúRossum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Robots</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù 1920</ENAMEX>); the
word is from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> robota `forced labor.'  Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ƒåapek</ENAMEX> conceived robots, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov</ENAMEX> who nurtured
them into fully developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>.  While
doing so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asimov</ENAMEX> furnished <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> with robotic and
robotical, roboticist an `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in their production and
operation,' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">robotics the `</ENAMEX>science of their design and
function,' and roboticized `rendered mechanical.'  His
laws of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">robotics</ENAMEX>, which govern the relations of robots
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, were deemed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED Supp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">editors</ENAMEX>
to be of such significance that they are cited in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entirety</ENAMEX>.

            As technology advances, life imitates art.  Appropriate
words are adopted from fiction.  Those remote
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> arms with which laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> handle
toxic, radioactive, or infections <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> are called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waldos</ENAMEX> (from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Heinlein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldo</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>): the title
charcter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waldo F. Jones</ENAMEX>, who has a crippling <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>,
invents these devices to amplify the strength of his
wasted mucles.  Not yet a reality, but often seriously
discussed, is terraforming `aitering an extracterrestrial
body to make it capable of supporting  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s life
forms.'  )The word and concept are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack Williamson's</ENAMEX>,
from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX> story, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚ÄúSeetee Ship</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>)  In less commom use,
but a wonderful word all the same , is corpsicle , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niven</ENAMEX>'s term for a person frozen at death for future
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reuscitation</ENAMEX> and repair <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">(‚ÄúThe Defenseless Dead</ENAMEX>,‚Äù
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>).  When we read of the ongoing search for grav-
ity-carrying subatomic particles-- gravitons --and
anti-gravitons, we should recall that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Clarke</ENAMEX>
wrote of antigravity as a propulsive force in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>
(Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Stars‚Äù</ENAMEX>).

            I could go on, but my ansible (FTL message receiver)
is displaying a rpiority-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hyperspace is urgently required
to mediate some tiff between local mutant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reptillians</ENAMEX> and the invading rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positronic</ENAMEX> androids.
The matter transmitter has warmed up.  My copilot
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astrogator</ENAMEX> have arrived.  So long, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Cadets</ENAMEX>!
We're off to save the Galaxy!
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allusions to ‚ÄúStar Trek‚</ENAMEX>Äù television series, books, and
movies.
            ‚ÄúEarth to ...,‚Äù
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allusions to ‚ÄúStar Trek‚</ENAMEX>Äù television series, books, and
movies.
            per <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Sturgeon</ENAMEX>.
            per <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov</ENAMEX>.
            per <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A. Heinlein</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            
‚ÄúSerious crime down, but murders increase.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, .  Submitted
by .]
         
         
            ‚ÄúWe consider pornography to be a public problem, and
we feel it is an issue that demands a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> look.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From a
speech by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> on .  Submitted
by .]
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cryptic</ENAMEX> Toolbox



            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy-five years ago</TIMEX>, the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New, York World</ENAMEX>
presented its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with a new kind of puzzle
that consisted of a grid and a list of clues.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Word-Cross</ENAMEX>,
as it was called, started its existence as just
another little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> supplement feature, with no
pretensions to permanence.  Yet it was to become the
progenitor of the now ubiquitous crossword puzzle.
The make-up of the grid has undergone various modifications
in the course of time but the rules of the game
have remained unchanged.  As for the clues, they were
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúdefinitions</ENAMEX>,‚Äù and that indeed is what they
were.-- Or were they?  On closer inspection, classic
clues appear to be divisible into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.  First,
there are synonyms, like rooster for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COCK</ENAMEX>.  Admittedly,
there is no such thing as perfect synonymy, but the
meanings of many pairs of words are close enough for
this term to be used in the context of a pastime like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crosswords</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, a clue may name a class of objects
which includes the answer, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COCK</ENAMEX>.  A more
specific class, e.g., male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> , makes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> easier,
whereas a more general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, e.g., animal , would
complicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">puzzler</ENAMEX>'s task.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> comprises
definitions proper.  Such a clue for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COCK</ENAMEX> might
read: adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> of the domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX> .

            Crossword puzzles soon become very popular in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and perhaps even more so in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.  But
someone must have felt that all this was too simple for
our overtrained brains.  Straightforward definitions (of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> varieties were gradually replaced by play on
words, ambiguous phrasings, jumble games, and other
verbal pranks.  A clue for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COCK</ENAMEX> might thus come to
read: number one in the pecking order dominates hens
and crows (a quizzical statement, unless the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crows</ENAMEX> is read as a verb) or even: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and a bullock's rump found in a coop (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> letter
of cow plus last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> letters of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bullock</ENAMEX> ).

            The uninitiated may find these examples too bizarre
for words.  Still, the idea has caught on so well
that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> now offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> crossword
puzzles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>.  One is in the classic style, commonly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">labeled ‚Äúconcise‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúquick.‚Äù  The other is of the newer,
playful genre, often referred to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as ‚</NUMEX>Äúcryptic‚Äù; but this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">designation</ENAMEX> is by no means universal.  (A well-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> prefers the term ‚ÄúAnglo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>)
In some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, puzzles of this type are
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúcryptograms</ENAMEX>,‚Äù a name we shall use from here
on.  This article is an attempt to catalogue the main
tools currently applied by cryptic puzzle-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solvers</ENAMEX>.

            A cryptogram clue can be a simple pun, like

            
               A .  A message that goes from pole to pole (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> letters) =

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TELEGRAM</ENAMEX>

            In most cases, however, it consists, as the previous
examples suggest, of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>, each hinting at the
answer in its own way.  This construction makes sense
since each hint by itself is generally so vague or open-ended
that it evokes more potential answers than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">puzzler</ENAMEX>'s brain can handle.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> such hints, however,
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a few</NUMEX> possible answers in common, so that
the solver can concentrate on them and pick the most
probable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.  This quest for the correct answer rests
on intricate mental processes which require no elaboration.
Our purpose here is rather to devise a classification
of the various types of clue elements (CEs) currently
in use.

            Let us start with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of clues encountered
in the classical crossword puzzle: synonyms,
superordinates, and definitions.  Here are some examples
of their cryptic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>:

            
               B .  A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) = TWAIN

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> CE ( A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> ) indicates a class to which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWAIN</ENAMEX> belongs; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ( <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ) offers a synonym of
another possible meaning of the answer.

            
               C .  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> who counts and recounts (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TELLER</ENAMEX>

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEs</ENAMEX> are telescoped.  Each of them defines a
separate meaning of the answer.

            These are really old-time clues in new apparel; once
wise to the system and having enough vocabulary entries
in one's head (or a thesaurus handy on the shelf),
it is not too difficult to decode them and arrive at the
answer.  The going gets tougher, however, as the two
meanings of the answer move further apart:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.</ENAMEX>  
               This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> is quite a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) = LETTER

            The mechanism is clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LETTER</ENAMEX>, (`one
who lets'), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LETTER</ENAMEX>, but the two LETTERs
differ in both meaning and origin.  (Note that
some double-dealing has also gone on with the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> !)  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> layer of camouflage is added in:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX>  
               Straight commotion (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) = ROW

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROWs</ENAMEX> differ in pronunciation as well as in
meaning and origin.

            Just as disorienting are clues where the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> meanings
of the answer belong to different word classes:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.</ENAMEX>  
               A more successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gambler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) = BETTER

            To mystify solvers even more, puzzlers may use words
in an uncommon but perfectly legitimate sense, especially
by attributing to certain words ending in -er the
quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">noun</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomer</ENAMEX> (for `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">flower'</ENAMEX>), butter
(for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`ram</ENAMEX>'), or even flower (for `river') are recurrent
examples, but solvers must always be on the alert for
new traps of this type:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.</ENAMEX>  
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than one</NUMEX> anesthetic (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) = NUMBER

            All of the above techniques rest, in one way or
another, on the meanings of words.  They make up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">class of Semantic Clue Elements</ENAMEX>.  Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>,
equally important in cryptoland, is that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clue Elements</ENAMEX>.  Here, the object of play is the written
form of the answer, or, more precisely, the letters of
which that form consists.  The best known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
this class is undoubtedly the anagram:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.</ENAMEX>  
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victim</ENAMEX> of injustice could be grounded (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>) =
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNDERDOG</ENAMEX>

            The words could be which precede the anagram
grounded have a special function.  They inform solvers
(if they get the message!)  that an anagram is lurking
nearby.  Indeed, convention requires that anagrams
(and all other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphic CEs</ENAMEX>) be accompanied by such
flags.  On the other hand, the cryptogram <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> is
free to conceal these signals in all sorts of phrasal
hocus-pocus:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>  
               Overturned vote overturns all votes (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) = VETO

            Some other anagram flags are broken, strange, unorthodox,
maybe, kind of , and a source of .  There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of them, and new ones are being concocted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.

            Many anagrams spread over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more words:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>  
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brave Tim</ENAMEX> changed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>) = VERBATIM

            These are particularly tricky when short words, like
articles or pronouns, are involved:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K.</ENAMEX>  
               An event is organized for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>) = VENETIANS

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX>  
               You can't take it with you--neither can I, unfortunately
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>) = INHERITANCE

            A subvariant of the anagram is the inversion:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX>  
               On reflection, the parts will hold together (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) =
STRAP

            
               On reflection is a flag to indicate that parts is to be
read backwards.  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inversion</ENAMEX> flags are coming
back, returning , and going West .  Purists admit these
only for answers that run horizontally in the grid.  For
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúdown‚Äù</ENAMEX> words, they prefer turning up, traveling
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX> , etc.

            It is worth noting that the first element of clue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX>
consists of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> words On reflection the parts .  The
comma, correctly inserted between reflection and the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
may mislead, but such punctuational conflicts are considered
perfectly legitimate, or even a piquant little
feature.  We shall return to this point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>.

            Another type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphic CE</ENAMEX> is the acronym:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.</ENAMEX>  
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the unassuming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Knights Society</ENAMEX>
can be a source of delight (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURKS</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of is a flag intended to draw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solvers</ENAMEX>'
attention to the initial letters of the words following it,
where the answer lies for the taking.  The most common
flag for acronyms is, as one would expect, initially .

            The acronym does not stand by itself in the crypto
repertoire.  In fact, it is the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a whole
family of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphic CEs</ENAMEX>, all with their own specific
flags to indicate whether the answer is to be composed
from last letters, middle letters, or other word fragments.
An idea of the way they work has been given in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the introductory examples (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>-bullock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">creature</ENAMEX>).

            A relatively new graphic technique is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich</ENAMEX>.
The letters of the answer are left in their original order
but spread over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more words:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O.</ENAMEX>  
               Lakeside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> located inside the embankment or on
top of it (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) = <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TORONTO</ENAMEX>

            or contained in a single word:

            
               P.  
               A small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) = <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">OSLO</ENAMEX>

            Besides inside and in , common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich</ENAMEX> flags are part
of and some of .

            As the above clues demonstrate, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphic CE</ENAMEX> should
be accompanied not only by a flag but also by a Semantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CE</ENAMEX>.  This conventional rule also holds for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> class, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Phonic Clue Elements</ENAMEX>.
These are based, just like the traditional pun, on
homophony:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.</ENAMEX>  
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Critique</ENAMEX>, one hears, of a theatrical entertainment
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) = REVUE

            Somewhat more involved is:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.</ENAMEX>  
               It sounds in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense (or in none) like simplicity
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>) = INNOCENCE

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phonic CEs</ENAMEX> are not very often used, probably because
all suitable flags ( I hear, it sounds, say , etc.) are so
obvious that they threaten to give the game away.
In the above <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">tour d'horizon</ENAMEX>, not all aspects of clue
setting have passed in review.  Nothing has been said
about the artful ways in which abbreviations, chemical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">symbols</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> numerals, musical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, etc., may be used in clues.  Hardly any attention
has been paid to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-element clues.  (There are even
one-word clues, some of them particularly witty.)  No
examples have been given of answers that consist of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> word.  More important, no mention has
been made of the possibility of chopping the answer
into convenient pieces which are separately represented
in the clue by anagrams, synonyms, etc.

            Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> real-life example:

            
               S.  
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, home of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> without
perverse words (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>) = ?

            Solution:


words = terms (synonym)
perverse = flag for anagram
anagram of `terms' = MSTER
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADAM</ENAMEX>
without = outside (!)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ADAM</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MSTER</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AMSTERDAM</ENAMEX>
            

            Clue syntax deserves a more thorough examination
than space permits; but perhaps it would be best to
comment on some aspects of the ethics of compiling
clues.

            The first commandment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">puzzlers</ENAMEX>' bible
reads: Thou shalt not waste words.  A well-constructed
clue comprises <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> words necessary for conveying, in a
deceptive way, the information solvers require to find
the answer.  Adding fillers to distract them is considered
unfair.  As for the answer, it is better to avoid very
learned or rare words unknown to all but a few lexicographers.
The idea is to test the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solvers</ENAMEX>' skill in deciphering
clues rather than their familiarity with the
recondite recesses of the lexicon.  (This being said, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> does offer a special obscure-words
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">puzzle</ENAMEX>, probably for the benefit of glossarial masochists.
Little wonder it appears under the name of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mephisto</ENAMEX>.)

            On the other hand, it is admissible, as we have
already seen, to throw solvers off the scent with an
occasional comma in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">‚Äúwrong‚Äù place</ENAMEX>.  The same
holds for other dividers, such as colons, dashes, hyphens,
and blanks.  Likewise, a bit of juggling with
apostrophes, quotation marks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> is permitted,
always on the understanding that no punctuation
or spelling rules are infringed.  And it goes without
saying that clue texts may be arranged in such a way
that, at first sight, certain words appear to belong to a
different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inflectional form</ENAMEX> or word class than is actually
the case when the clue is unlocked.  In fact, this is
an essential part of the fun.  This feature has already
been demonstrated in the very first example (the cock
that crows) and also in clue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Clue J</ENAMEX> offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> further
instances: at first reading, changed is suggestive of being
a past tense but after analysis it is identified as a
past participle (serving as an anagram flag); likewise,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> shifts from adverb to noun.

            Let us end with a specimen in which several of the
above techniques are represented:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.</ENAMEX>  
               Part of his imprint appears in absurd Anglo-Saxon
rules, word for word (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) = ?



Solution: Replace in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> element (rules word
for word) the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> words by their synonym
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúverbatim.</ENAMEX>‚Äù  Well, who rules VERBATIM?
His name (= part of his imprint) appears
in absurd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX>.
            
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúMereu</ENAMEX> stayed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angius</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>, dressed in
dirty and ragged canvas clothing and shoes with holes.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Des Moines Sunday Register</ENAMEX> , .  Submitted
by .]
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúRobert Dole</ENAMEX> is way ahead, followed closely by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heard on WEEI</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>,
on .  Submitted by .]
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúVisitor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Smith, Jr.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 17</TIMEX>, fell in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
He was treated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.R.</ENAMEX> and released. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Smith</ENAMEX>, Sr.,
was notified who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> 622A due to his son's
age.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [A security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>'s accident report.  Submitted by
.]
         
         
            Money of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Realm</ENAMEX>



            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the privileges of national sovereignty is the
right to name your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s money, or to rename
it when the old name has acquired unpleasant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>.  The tourist struggling at each border
crossing with exchanging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s money for that
of another and trying to fix values may not have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> then to wonder why a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s money is called
what it is.  [Because so many languages are involved,
the names that follow are as used in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications of the International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>.]

            Money originated in the form of coins.  For many
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> the current names of what is now mostly
paper money are based on characteristics of the old
coins or refer to the fact that the weight of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> or
gold coin was often an indication of its value.  The
pound sterling (the money of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>),
for example, apparently derived from a pound weight
of silver pennies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> period which had a
star on them (Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>: steorling `coin with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>').
The concept continues through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> word for
`weight': peso (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolivia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uruguay</ENAMEX>); its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diminutive</ENAMEX>: peseta (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>), and the same word in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peso</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guinea</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bissau</ENAMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of money names with other
weights is common: ouguiya (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mauritania</ENAMEX>) means
`ounce.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burma</ENAMEX>) is the name for a measure of
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16.33 grams</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baht</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>) is a weight of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 grams</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drachma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>), which literally means a `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handful</ENAMEX>,'
is a weight of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3.2 grams</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emirates</ENAMEX>) derives from drachma .

            As in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, the currency names of
other economically powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have long historical
roots.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>) goes back to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14th-century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">coin inscribed ‚ÄúFrancorum rex</ENAMEX>,‚Äù `<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franks</ENAMEX>.'  Dollar (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and some other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>)
derives from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> Thaler , a coin of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th century</TIMEX> which was minted in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joachimsthal</ENAMEX>.  The word dollar was used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> to refer to the thaler and became the
official name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> monetary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> by an
Act of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental Congress</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6, 1785</TIMEX>.

            
               Denarius , a coin of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, evolved into
dinar , the name used by many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the eastern
Mediterrean which were once part of, or near, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ancient Roman Empire</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahrain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People's Democratic Republic of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tunisia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>).  Denarius was the source
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">abbreviation</ENAMEX> d for the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> penny.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shilling</ENAMEX> , another coin in the predecimal pound sterling
may take its name from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> coin, solidus ,
worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 25 denarii</NUMEX>.  It is the money name in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, and, spelt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilling</ENAMEX> ,
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metical</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mozambique</ENAMEX>) was a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of currency.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dobra</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S√£o Tom√©</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pr√</ENAMEX>≠n-

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cipe</ENAMEX>), meaning `double,' is the name of a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>
gold coin.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pataca</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX>) stems from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX> coin, the patacoon.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX>) originated from shell
money used for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> along their coast;
the cedi of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghana</ENAMEX> means `small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX>' after the former
use of the cowrie <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX> for money.  The complete panel
of cloth formerly used for money is the meaning behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dalasi</ENAMEX> (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gambia</ENAMEX>).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> was a common term used throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
for a weight of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ounces</ENAMEX>.  The name was adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX>
for a coin to replace the thaler.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> retained
the name even when its monetary value sank so low
that currency reform was necessary.  It was the reichsmark
that suffered through the hyperinflation of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922-23</TIMEX> when the cost of mailing a letter went from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reichsmark to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 months</TIMEX>.  The rentenmark ,
secured by the industrial and agricultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, was introduced in limited
amounts to stabilize the currency.  (This was the creation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Banker</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hjalmar Horace Greeley Schacht</ENAMEX>.)  The name continues
in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Deutsche mark</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">mark</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>).  When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> reformed its economy several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the former name of its currency was
changed from cruzeiro to cruzado , the meaning `little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>' to `crusade' being of less importance than the
similarity of the names in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX>.

            The names of some kinds of money are associated
with the metal originally used or some related feature.
`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gold</ENAMEX>' is the meaning of guilder (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ztoty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>).  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanskrit</ENAMEX> for `wrought <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>' is the
basis for rupee (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seychelles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sri</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lanka</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">rupiah</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>), and rufiyaa (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maldives</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birr</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX>) means `<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>' and was the name used
beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> to designate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>
Theresa thaler, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> coin which circulated in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringgit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>)
means `serrated, milled,' a characteristic of the edging
on coins.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kip</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX>) means `ingot.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruble</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>),
which literally means `stump,' might have denoted a
piece cut from a silver <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> name their currency to honor people
famous in their history: bolivar (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>) for the
liberator of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sim√≥n Bol√≠var; sucre</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Jos√© de Sucre</ENAMEX>, chief lieutenant
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bol√≠var</ENAMEX> and liberator of what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX> at the
battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pichincha</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1822</TIMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quito</ENAMEX>; col√≥n (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher Columbus</ENAMEX>; balboa
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vasco N√∫√±ez de Balboa</ENAMEX>, discoverer of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX>; lempira (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honduras</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th-century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> who is a national symbol of liberty
and valor for resisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> advance; and c√≥rdoba
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Hern√°ndez de C√≥r</ENAMEX>
doba, first acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.  Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balboa</ENAMEX> and C√≥rdoba
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arias Da</ENAMEX>\?\ila, who subsequently executed them.
The regional characteristic of using the same idea
as a basis for selecting a currency name is apparent
from these <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central American</ENAMEX> neighboring
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            It is true also in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scandinavia</ENAMEX> where the money
name is crown: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">krona</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX>), krone (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>).  The only non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> ‚Äúcrown‚Äù
is koruna (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>).  Regional patterns emerge
elsewhere: in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> the money names mean
`round, circular': <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">yen</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>), won (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>), tugrik
(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mongolia</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">yuan</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People's Republic of China</ENAMEX>).  In
the last, the currency name is actually renminbi , `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
money,' with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of account being the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">yuan</NUMEX> .
The meaning `royal' appears as riyal (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qatar</ENAMEX>), rial (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen Arab Republic</ENAMEX>), and
further south as lilangeni (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swaziland</ENAMEX>).

            History and myth provide another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for
names.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shekel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>) was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylonian</ENAMEX> weight which
became the coin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hebrews</ENAMEX>.  [Exodus <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:13 ‚</TIMEX>ÄúThis
they shall give...<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a shekel</NUMEX> after the shekel of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sanctuary</ENAMEX>: (a shekel is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty gerahs</TIMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> shekel
shall be the offering of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>]  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taka</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>),
literally `money,' derives from tonka of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX>
language which was the money of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th-century</TIMEX>
Mughal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in circulation in what was then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inti</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>) was the sun god in the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX>
religion; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>'s previous money was sol , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> for
`sun.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rand</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>) is the now common name
for the witwatersrand , the site of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> fields
found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th century</TIMEX> and the original source
of its wealth.

            For most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> the easiest source of a name for
their money has been to take that of another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
either because of proximity and association with a
strong economic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or because of a former colonial
relationship.  Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, and
Luxembourg use <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">franc</NUMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>
choose dollar .

            The name dollar is used by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbados</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belize</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fiji</ENAMEX>,
Guyana, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Solomon Islands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinidad</ENAMEX> and
Tobago, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>.  As the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Caribbean</ENAMEX> dollar ,
it is used by several small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> who do not have
their own money: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antigua, Dominica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nevis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>.

            The name pound is used by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
(as punt ), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lira</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>) is a contracted form of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
word for `pound' libra.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> traveled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as markka</NUMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>.

            The names franc and guilder spread only to their
former colonial areas.  The franc appears in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burundi</ENAMEX>,
Comoros, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Djibouti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Guiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guinea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malagasy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, and as a common currency of the CFA
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communaut√© Francaise Africaine</ENAMEX>), comprising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Benin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burkina Faso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cameroon, Chad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">C√¥te d'Ivoire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Equatorial Guinea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gabon</ENAMEX>,
Mali, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Niger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People's Republic of the Congo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Togo</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guilder</ENAMEX> is used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands Antilles</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suriname</ENAMEX>.

            Money has also derived its names from things or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lev</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX>) and leu (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX>) mean
`<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Escudo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Verde</ENAMEX>) means `shield.'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quetzal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX>) is the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> and guarani
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguay</ENAMEX>) the name of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forint</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>)
means `flower,' pula (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Botswana</ENAMEX>) `<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>,' austral
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>) `southern,' and kwanza (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>) `<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwacha</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malawi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zambia</ENAMEX>) means `<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX>' in reference
to the ‚Äúdawn of freedom.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Tala</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Samoa</ENAMEX>) is
derived from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> , while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pa'anga</ENAMEX> was selected by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonga</ENAMEX>.  As reported in The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , ‚ÄúTonga has
decided against calling its new decimal currency unit
the dollar because the native word tola also means a
`<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>'s snout,' the `soft end of a coconut,' or, in vulgar
language, a `mouth.'  The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>...has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
alternative meanings--a `coin-shaped <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>' and, not
surprisingly, `money.' ‚Äù

            When no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> seems suitable, nations
name their money after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naira</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>) is
derived from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s name as is probably Vatu
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanuatu</ENAMEX>).  More direct is afghani (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>), leone
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>), and the ultimate in directness, zaire
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>).
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">English Is A Crazy Language</ENAMEX>



            <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is the most widely spoken language in the
history of our planet.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> has acquired the
largest vocabulary and inspired one of the noblest bodies
of literature in the annals of the human race.

            Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is a crazy language.  In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">crazy English</ENAMEX> language, the blackbird hen is brown,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blackboards</ENAMEX> can be blue or green, and blackberries are
green and red before they are ripe.  To add to this
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX>, there is no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> in buttermilk , no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> in
eggplant , neither worms nor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> in wormwood , and
no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> in a hamburger .  (In fact, if somebody invented
a sandwich consisting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham patty</ENAMEX> in a bun, we
would have a hard time finding a name for it.)  And we
discover more culinary madness in the revelations that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">muffins</ENAMEX> weren't invented in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pastries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>.  In this
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">weird English</ENAMEX> language, greyhounds aren't always
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grey</ENAMEX> (or gray), a ladybug is a beetle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guinea pigs</ENAMEX> are
neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pigs</ENAMEX> nor from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guinea</ENAMEX>, and a titmouse is neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mammal</ENAMEX> nor mammaried.

            Language is like the air we breathe.  It is invisible,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inescapable</ENAMEX>, and indispensable; yet we take it for
granted.  But when we take time to explore the vagaries
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, we find that hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> can be cold, darkrooms
can be lit, nightmares can take place in broad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">daylight</ENAMEX>, midwives can be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>--especially
happy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hours</TIMEX>--can last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer than</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cubes</ENAMEX> can be noncubic, tablecloths
can be made of paper, silverware can be made of
plastic, most telephones are dialed by being punched
(or pushed?), and most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX> don't have any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">baths</ENAMEX>.  In fact, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> can go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> under a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>--no bath, no room--it is still ‚Äúgoing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            
Why is it that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> can man a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, but a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> cannot ‚Äúwoman‚Äù one, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can father a
movement, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> cannot ‚Äúmother‚Äù one, and
that a king rules a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> , but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> does not rule
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúqueendom‚Äù</ENAMEX>?  A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> is someone who writes, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stinger</ENAMEX> is something that stings.  But fingers do not
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúfing,‚Äù grocers ‚Äúgroce,‚Äù hammers ‚Äúham,‚Äù</ENAMEX> or humdingers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúhumding.</ENAMEX>‚Äù  If the plural of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse is mice</ENAMEX> , why
don't we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhice‚Äù</ENAMEX>?  One tooth , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> teeth ; so why
not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two ‚Äúbeeth‚Äù</NUMEX>?  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> index , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> indices --one
Kleenex , <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two ‚ÄúKleenices‚Äù</NUMEX>?  If someone rang a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bell</ENAMEX> , why don't we say that she also ‚Äúflang‚Äù a ball?  If
she wrote a letter, perhaps she also ‚Äúbote‚Äù her tongue.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> taught , why isn't it also true that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">preacher ‚Äúpraught‚Äù</ENAMEX>?  If she conceives a conception and
receives at a reception , why didn't she grieve a ‚Äúgreption‚Äù
and believe a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúbeleption‚Äù</ENAMEX>?

            If a horsehair <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX> is made from the hair of horses
and a camel's hair brush from the hair of camels, from
what is a mohair coat made?  If a vegetarian eats <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>,
what does a humanitarian eat?  If pro and con
are opposites, is congress the opposite of progress ?

            In this confusing language of ours noisome doesn't
mean `noisy,' meretricious is anything but meritorious,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penultimate</ENAMEX> is less ultimate than ultimate , but invaluable
is more valuable than valuable .

            No wonder that we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> are constantly
standing meaning on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.  We delete negatives
and say, I could care less , when we really mean, `I
couldn't care less,' and we add gratuitous negatives
and say, I miss not seeing her , when we really mean, `I
miss seeing her.'  Any book that keeps us literallly glued
to our seat actually keeps us figuratively glued to our
seat, a near miss (which is a`collision') is a `near hit,'
something that falls between the cracks would in reality
land on the planks or the concrete, a big traffic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bottleneck</ENAMEX> is a `small bottleneck,' and a hot cup of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> is really a `cup of hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>.'  We get up in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and put on our shoes and socks and then go
back and forth .  No, we put on our socks and shoes and
then go forth and back .

            Because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> seem to have our heads
screwed on backwards, they constantly misperceive
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>.  They fall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> over heels in love when we
really mean heels over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in love.  If they are disappointed
or afraid, they try to keep a stiff upper lip
when it is the lower lip they are trying to control.  They
complain that things are being done behind their
backs , but nothing can be done ‚Äúin front of their
backs.‚Äù  And they try to avoid doing things ass back-wards
when `ass backwards' is the only way that anyone
can do anything.

            Sometimes you have to believe that all English
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> should be committed to an asylum.  In what
other language do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drive in a parkway and park
in a driveway ?  In what other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> can the
weather be hot as hell <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and cold as hell the
next?  In what other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> can quite a lot and quite
few mean the same thing, as well as loosen and unloosen,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ravel</ENAMEX> and unravel, passive and impassive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flammable</ENAMEX> and inflammable, shameful and shameless
(behavior) and What won't he do next ?  and What will
he do next ?  In what other language are overlook and
oversee opposites but a slim chance and a fat chance
the same?  Why is it easier to assent than to dissent but
harder to ascend than to descend ?  Is it really true that
if you decide to be `bad forever,' you have chosen to be
bad for good , and if you are wearing only your right
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shoe</ENAMEX>, your right one is left.  Right?

            When the sun or moon or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> are out they are
visible, but when the lights are out , they are invisible.
A piece of cloth that wear may be the same as a piece
of cloth that won't wear .  Trimming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> may involve
cutting it away or, especially around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, adding
to it .  When we wind up a watch, we `start' it, but
when I wind up this disquisition, I shall `end' it.

            Does it not seem just a little bizarre that we can
make amends but never just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one ‚Äúamend‚Äù</NUMEX>; that no
matter how carefully we comb through history, we can
never discover just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one ‚Äúannal‚Äù</NUMEX>; that, sifting through
the wreckage of a disaster, we can never find just one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúsmithereen‚Äù</ENAMEX>; and that we never contract a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúheebie-jeebie‚Äù</ENAMEX>?  Which reminds me to ask a burning
linguistic question.  If you have a bunch of odds and
ends and you get rid of or sell off all but one of them,
what is left?

            What do you make of the fact that we can talk only
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the nonexistence</TIMEX>, never the existence, of certain
items and concepts?  Have you ever run into someone
who was ‚Äúcombobulated,<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù ‚Äúchalant,‚Äù ‚Äúsheveled,‚Äù ‚Äúgruntled,‚Äù</ENAMEX>
or ‚Äúgainly‚Äù?  We all know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spring chickens</ENAMEX> , but where, pray tell, are the people
who are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúspring chickens‚Äù</ENAMEX>?  Have you ever met someone
who was ‚Äúgreat shakes,‚Äù who could ‚Äúcut the mustard‚Äù
and ‚Äúdo squat,‚Äù who ‚Äúwas your cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>,‚Äù and whom
you ‚Äúwould touch with a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ten-foot pole‚Äù</NUMEX>?  Do you know
anyone who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúslouch‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúwould hurt a fly‚Äù?

            If the truth be told, all languages are a little
crazy.  As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Whitman</ENAMEX> might proclaim, they contradict
themselves.  That is because language is invented,
not discovered, and, as such, language reflects the creativity
and fearful asymmetry of the human mind.  In
his essay <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúThe Awful German Language</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Mark Twain</ENAMEX>
spoofs the confusion engendered by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> gender by
translating from a conversation in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
school book:


GRETCHEN: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilhelm</ENAMEX>, where is the turnip?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WILHELM</ENAMEX>: She has gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>.
GRETCHEN: Where is the accomplished and beautiful
English maiden?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WILHELM</ENAMEX>: It has gone to the opera.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twain</ENAMEX> continues:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúa tree</ENAMEX> is male, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">buds</ENAMEX> are female, its leaves are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuter</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> are sexless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are male, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are female--tomcats
included.‚Äù

            Still, you have to wonder about the crazy English
language, in which your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> can burn up and burn
down at the same time, in which you fill in a form by
filling out a form, in which you add up a column of
figures by adding them down , in which your alarm
clock goes off by going on , and in which you first chop
down a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>--and then chop up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Correspondents</ENAMEX>


            
It all began with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Russian Revolution</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, and journalistic expertise devoted
to these supremely important phenomena of the
twentieth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> began with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Ilich Lenin</ENAMEX>.
But as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism is concerned, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pronouncement</ENAMEX> is not quite correct, because more often
than not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> began and for an
embarrassingly long time continued not with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ilich</ENAMEX> (as the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bolshevik</ENAMEX> is sometime affectionately
called, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX>-fashion by his patronymic)
but with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikolai Lenin</ENAMEX>.  The error flawed the record
beyond newspaper reporting.  For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Columbia</ENAMEX>
Encyclopedia , in an edition last copyrighted in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, has an appropriately long entry for ‚Äúthe founder
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR‚</ENAMEX>Äù under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikolai</ENAMEX> .  How this mistake
came about in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place no one is certain.  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lenin</ENAMEX>
did use the pseudonym <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N. Lenin</ENAMEX> , among scores of
others, and maybe a self-styled authority assumed that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> . stood for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikolai</ENAMEX> , a name that may have been
suggested by that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">continental</ENAMEX> usage the letter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> , corresponding to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> in
the English-speaking world, is sometimes used for a
name an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> does not wish to reveal.  At any rate,
the mistake, trivial in itself, tended to discredit a good
deal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> reporting about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who knew better.  After all, if the bourgeois
press could not get even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>'s name right, how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reliable</ENAMEX> was it about anything else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Decades later</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> was assumed by Nikita
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergeevich Khrushchev</ENAMEX>.  By then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlinology</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">matured</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> had all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khrushchev</ENAMEX>'s
names right, though there were several ways to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transliterate</ENAMEX> and pronounce them in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  To the
horror of some Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, however, he was at
least once quoted out of context as having threatened
to ‚Äúbury‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.  And he did say that.  But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
verb he used in a sentence that was more a bellicose
boast than a threat was pokhoronit', which means
`bury,' all right, but in the sense of the verb in ‚Äúwe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">burried Grandma</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.‚Äù  When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikita Sergeevich</ENAMEX>
bragged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX> would bury the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, he meant
that technologically and economically the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>
would leave us in the dust, would be around for our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">funeral</ENAMEX>, not that they would put us <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six feet under</NUMEX>.

            If our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> would attain true excellence in selecting
English expressions to correspond to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">originals</ENAMEX>,
it should exercise more care about designating
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúRussia‚Äù</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúRussians</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSFSR</ENAMEX> (for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federated</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Republic</ENAMEX>) is only one of several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX>,
which are more like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
than what we generally mean by ‚Äúrepublic,‚Äù and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>
(sometimes redundantly called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúethnic Russians‚Äù</ENAMEX>)
make up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX>.  So referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúRussia‚Äù</ENAMEX> is a mistake
on the order of calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Britain ‚ÄúEngland.</ENAMEX>‚Äù  However, the boundaries of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tsar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> known as ‚ÄúRussia,‚Äù were
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> the same as those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>; it
was occasionally known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúthe Russias</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as in the formula
‚ÄúTsar of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russias‚Äù</ENAMEX>; thus, this particular
confusion comes naturally.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> himself is said
to have had to apologize while making a speech in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> when he referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúRussian</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
This faux pas might be likened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen of England</ENAMEX>'s
saying in an address before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Welsh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄúAs we
here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> well know ...‚Äù

            The problem of drawing a distinction between
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX> has been solved by
borrowing the word <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as an adjective
or a noun meaning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and not an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>,
except rarely as in the designation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Soviet</ENAMEX> .  In
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian Sov√</ENAMEX>©t means basically `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>' and `<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>'
and by extension `<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>'.  It never means a `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX>' or any other kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>,
though its adjectival derivative sovetskii can be used
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substantively</ENAMEX> alone or followed by chelovek `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>,' to
mean a `<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.'  So the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corresponds</ENAMEX> to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> noun sov√©t or much
more often to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> adjective sovetskii in their
many inflected forms.

            Currently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> words are challenging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correspondents</ENAMEX>, among others, to find English
equivalents: perestroika and glasnost '.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of
these Gorbachevian buzzwords can be handily calqued
into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as `restructuring.'  Glasnost ', though, is
more difficult.  As a calque it would come into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
as vocalness , which is no word.  It is not a new word in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>.  The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> edition of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-volume Tolkovyi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slovar' Russkogo Yazyka</ENAMEX> (`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explanatory Dictionary of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian Language</ENAMEX>') defines glasnost' as: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúAccessibility</ENAMEX>
to public discussion and evaluation; publicity.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  I</ENAMEX>
can think of no single <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word that quite corresponds
to this definition.  Publicity perhaps comes closest.
But since both perestroika and glasnost' from our
point of view do not mean `restructuring' and `publicity'
generally, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> words do to us, but rather
refer to reforms specifically initiated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> words, particularly glasnost', are usually
borrowed into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> unaltered (except in pronunciation).
There are, of course, precedents for this sort of
intact borrowing: pogrom, ukase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX> , and
muzhik for example.  And in the same way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> have helped themselves to our sex, jazz,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lynch</ENAMEX> , and business .

            Apropos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> too for
that matter--those es in their names pose a problem of
phonetic correspondence.  Though usually written in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> like any other e , just as in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, they are
pronounced like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">os</ENAMEX> .  Sometimes in textbooks for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
and beginners such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es</ENAMEX> are marked in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dots over them; they are sometimes transliterated
into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as os , so that occasionally you will see the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spelling Gorbachov</ENAMEX> , which in my opinion is preferable.
Then another variant in transliteration is
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-ov/-off, -ev/-eff .</ENAMEX>  The name ending in double f for
what in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> is invariably v is seldom seen nowadays;
but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few decades ago</TIMEX> or in documents or books
written then you might have seen the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>'
names transliterated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorbacheff</ENAMEX> or Gorbachoff
            
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lite/Light</ENAMEX>



            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately a thousand years</TIMEX>, the word
light has been used to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and wine
containing less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> than regular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>:


c <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ags</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voc</ENAMEX>. in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wr.</ENAMEX>- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Willcker 282/6</NUMEX>
Melle dulci, leoht beor.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dictionary</ENAMEX>)
c <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sax</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leechd</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">122 Drince</ENAMEX> leoht wyn.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX>)
            

            Currently, however, many a denizen of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> regards light (also spelled lite ) as a label that
indicates that a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> is lower in calories than its nonlight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>.

            and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khrushcheff</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khrushchoff</ENAMEX> .  I have seen both the
-ov and - off transliterations on the same page of a
book.  The reason for this variation is that when the
Cyrillic letter that represents our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> v -sound is
final in a word, as in the nominative case for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> , it is unvoiced and sounds like f (or ff for
good measure); when an inflectional ending is added,
as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gorbacheva</ENAMEX> (the genitive case), that same letter
is voiced, like v .

            Such variations in transliteration are practically
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX>, and hardly any variation can be called an
error, though consistency is obviously desirable.  The
most troublesome inconsistencies in transliteration
seem to be owing either to the human tendency to
conceal doubt behind abundance or to multiple naturalizations
as the name migrates across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.  For
instance, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>
is usually spelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tchaikovsky</ENAMEX> and sometimes as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tschaikovsky</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tschaikowsky</ENAMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> letters are used to represent a sound represented
by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> letter and more normally by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, ch .  The name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chaliapin</ENAMEX> was first
transliterated into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> spelling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chaliapine</ENAMEX> ; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>,
when most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
the e was dropped to Anglicize the spelling.  This was a
confusing half measure, however; the initial ch remained
as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> spelling, representing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
letter borrowed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> alphabet for the
sound represented in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> by sh .  As a result, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> innocently mispronounce the name of the
great operatic bass and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX>.  A certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessean</ENAMEX>,
who became a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Chaliapin</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, got off on the wrong foot
when he heard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s name as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charley Apin</ENAMEX> .
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX> was too polite to correct the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessean</ENAMEX>,
and others who knew better found the mistake too
amusing to rectify, that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> called
Boris good ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charley Apin</ENAMEX> as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> lived.

            The roots of the `reduced calorie' meaning of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">lite/</ENAMEX>light go back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> Meister Brau
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc. of Chicago</ENAMEX> initially marketed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meister Brau Lite</ENAMEX>, a
reduced-calorie <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> were targeted as the primary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>; but the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, which was promoted as
a diet drink, was not very successful.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris, Inc.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Brewing Co.</ENAMEX> acquired the Lite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">beer</ENAMEX> label in a buyout of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meister Brau Inc. Miller Lite</ENAMEX>
was introduced to test markets in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>; and the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lite</ENAMEX> commercial, which featured <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Snell</ENAMEX>, aired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July of that year</TIMEX>.  The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> Lite
commercial, which featured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Butkus</ENAMEX>,
was shot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1975</TIMEX> just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Lite</ENAMEX> was going
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Lite</ENAMEX> commercials were designed to convince
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> that it is all right to drink light beer.
Consequently, these commercials, which, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video Storyboard Tests Inc.</ENAMEX>, are among the most popular
ever to be shown on television, have featured former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">athletes</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bubba Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Uecker</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grier</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Spillane</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drummer Buddy Rich</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney Dangerfield</ENAMEX>).
The original theme of these commercials was:
‚ÄúEverything you always wanted in a light--and less.‚Äù
