
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redundancy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Languages</ENAMEX>



            In this fast-paced age when information is digitized,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faxed</ENAMEX>, uplinked, and downloaded, it is appropriate
to consider natural languages from the
point of view of information theory.  That is, we examine
the information content of text or messages
and the efficiency with which that information is
represented.  The idea here is not to convert language
into some sort of highly efficient, but inhuman,
stream of ones and zeroes!  That type of efficiency
is fine for computers, but not for human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>.  In fact, as we shall see, natural languages
contain a fair amount of redundancy.  While this
does not provide us with the most concise form of
communication possible, it is a form that is ideally
suited to human experience, which, after all, is why
it came to be as it is.

            It cannot be denied that some words are simply
longer than they strictly need to be.  This is perhaps
more noticeable in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>,
as new words are needed, they are often
formed from smaller words already existing.  Thus,
we have the words <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haupthandelsartikel</ENAMEX> , meaning
`staple,' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autoreparaturwerkstatt</ENAMEX> , meaning `<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>.'
If we were to construct a new vocabulary
from scratch from the point of view of an extremely
orderly, but over-zealous, cataloguer, we might
have as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words in our dictionary AAAA
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAAB</ENAMEX>.  We would continue in this manner until
we reached our last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZZZY</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZZZZ</ENAMEX> .
Our dictionary would contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">456,976</NUMEX> words.  This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lexicon</ENAMEX> is of sufficient size to form a rich written
language, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>.  In fact, we
could associate to each <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word one of our new
words.  Thus, the phrase To be, or not to be ?  might
become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THJL BDMN</ENAMEX>, OQRA NOOP THJL BDMN?
(So much for pronounceability!)  Of course, in this
example, our two-letter words become <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-letter
words, which hasn't helped keep things concise.  But
now there is no word longer than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> letters.  This
game of re-cataloguing all our words undoes a natural
process which occurs as languages evolve.  This is
the tendency to shorten frequently used words and
to allow less frequently used words to become
longer.  This trend, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Zipf's Law</ENAMEX> , causes
common words such as to, in, a , and it to be as short
as they are.  It would be unthinkable to replace
these with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-letter variants!  In this way, language
at least attempts to follow a path of least resistance,
in which the effort expended in writing or speech is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lessened</ENAMEX>.

            Despite the economies of effort introduced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Zipf's Law</ENAMEX>, natural languages nonetheless contain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redundancies</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example is the indefinite article
a in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  Many languages are inflected, which is
also a form of redundancy, since <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> gets by
nicely with little inflection.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, the function
of words within sentences is typically signaled by
word order.  The sentences I threw the dog the ball
and I threw the ball the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> are not equivalent.
Here, some of the semantic information is provided
by word order, and not simply from the words themselves.
In an inflected language, endings affixed to
the words for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and ball indicate which object is
direct and which is indirect.  Thus, it is possible to
rearrange words as in the example above.  The result
may not always be idiomatic, but it will probably get
the point across.  Such flexibility allows for a greater
degree of expression in poetry, for example.  Thus,
one has a romantic poem written in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> in which
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> line contains the words for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and woman
on opposite ends of the line.  By the end of the
poem, the words have gravitated toward the middle
of the line.  It can even be argued that word forms
used to show tense are superfluous, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
has no notion of tense.  A sentence may be in the
past, present, or future, depending on context.  One
wonders how a person translating into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
would deal with unexpected or unpredictable tense
shifts: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veni</ENAMEX>, video, vincam!
            

            Not only does the degree of redundancy vary
from language to language, but also from one writing
style to another.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> might have a more loquacious
bent than another.  Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> can be
said to have the better style.  A lengthy passage, if
written well, can be more expressive and have
greater effect than a simple, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-line statement of
fact.  On the other hand, brevity is what gives a pithy
aphorism its strength.  This is true of both poetry
and prose.  More so than prose, however, poetry
tends to explore both extremes--the concise and
the protracted.  Poe, for example, used repetition in
his poem <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bells</ENAMEX> to convey to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> a sense of
actually hearing the tolling of the bells, as though
the sounds themselves were imprinted on the page.
Somehow, it would not have been the same had Poe
written simply that “The bells rang a lot.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">”  Or</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“bells</ENAMEX>, bells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera.”  At the other extreme, some
poets attempt to carefully choose words in such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that the poem expresses a great deal in very
little space.  Thus, we have a verse form like haiku,
in which the totality of the poem is condensed into
only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">seventeen syllables</ENAMEX>.  If only certain genres of
prose could be as succinct!  A never-ending meeting
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> could be completed in plenty of time for
a coffee break.  Presidential debates could begin and
end with the introductory niceties, since very little
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> is ever said.  The civilized world would
be grateful indeed if lengthy advertising pitches
were instead given in haiku:


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudzo</ENAMEX> detergent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX> white garments full of fluff
Buy many boxes

            

            Notwithstanding certain benefits arising from
compactness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">redundancy</ENAMEX> actually plays an important
role in the communication process.  One is reminded
of an experiment in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> subjects
were placed in separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and allowed to communicate
only through a teletype.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was
given a box of parts to a wheelbarrow, as provided
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">factory (“some</ENAMEX> assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">required”</ENAMEX>).  The
other was given the assembly instructions.  The object
was to successfully assemble the wheelbarrow.
Sentences transmitted usually read something like
Put bolt into L-shaped part.  Such an imperative
might elicit the response Which bolt?  or  Which L?
Or perhaps the recipient of the message would insert
some bolt into some part, only to find later that
a needed part had already been attached.  When the
test is modified to allow phone conversation, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> required for assembly decreases dramatically.
Phrases become more verbose and more redundant,
but more communicative.  With very little effort, it
is possible to utter a terrific run-on sentence like,
“Put the medium-sized brass bolt--not the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with
the little black top, but the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--into the sort
of oblong L-shaped part with the green paint on one
end, but first make sure that you have the axle
pointed towards the side with the sort of wooden
handle.”  A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would not be inclined to type out
such a message verbatim.  More likely, he would remove
occasional words deemed to be redundant.
But in the process, the sentence would become less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colloquial</ENAMEX> and less intelligible.

            The presence of redundancy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> is perhaps
best observed when the communication process
breaks down.  The fact that a deaf <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can
determine a spoken phrase by reading lips demonstrates
that the information is simultaneously being
conveyed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different ways.  Those with normal
hearing can use visual clues to assist during the listening
process.  Thus, it is possible to pick out the
necessary morsels of information in noisy surroundings,
if facial expressions, gestures and other contextual
clues are taken into account.  But even in the
absence of visual clues, the very sounds of human
speech are overflowing with many times the volume
of data strictly required to convey the message.  Examining
a graph of a simple speech component, such
as the sound of a vowel, one sees a complex pattern
of superimposed waves, having myriad peaks and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valleys</ENAMEX>.  When such a pattern is recorded and stored
in computer-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">readable (“digitized”</ENAMEX>) form, it occupies
an inordinately large amount of storage.  This seems
all the more wasteful, considering that the only useful
information being conveyed in our example is a
single vowel sound.  This apparent redundancy,
once again, proves to be beneficial.  Conversing over
a noisy telephone line would be impossible were it
not for the complexity of speech sounds.  When one
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> “sound peaks” is altered by an electrical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX> or crackle, the sound of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX> does not suddenly
change to that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>; it simply sounds like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“noisy E.”  If</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, speech contained
“just enough” data, but no more, then the alteration
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> peak (or bit) would change the sound (or
character) entirely.  A moderately noisy phone line
would render messages as unintelligible gibberish
(even those messages that did not start out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>!).  For this reason, when computers “talk” to
one another over communication lines in their
highly efficient system of beeps, conventional phone
lines are seldom used, owing to the high error rate
that would result.  In any event, computers must use
an elaborate method of double-checking transmitted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, to ensure that no error is made.  In other
words, computers must introduce redundancy
where none previously existed in order to communicate
effectively.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Predictability</ENAMEX> is closely related to redundancy.
If the recipient of a message (such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of
text) is able to predict the next word before seeing
it, the word is apparently not conveying any additional
information.  In the following transmission, it
is easy to predict the concluding letter: WITH <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIBERTY</ENAMEX>
AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JUSTICE FOR AL</ENAMEX> . (The transmission has almost
certainly not ended there!)  On the other hand, only
the most avid trivia buff could complete the sentence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HARRY TRUMAN</ENAMEX>'S <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HAT SIZE WAS ....</ENAMEX>.  While it is
very unlikely that the final word is giraffe, the correct
completion of the sentence requires somewhat
more insight.  Similarly, the ability to infer the existence
of an omitted letter or word (such as the indefinite
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>) is a form of prediction.  It is hard to
ascertain the missing word in the sentence After
crash-landing on the planet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zartok</ENAMEX>, I saw the most
enormous -- I had ever seen!  The word in question
is probably not portfolio.  But lack of familiarity with
the planet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zartok</ENAMEX> precludes a more accurate guess.
Although these examples deal with predictability
based on semantic content, it is also possible to base
predictions on patterns within the text itself.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>,
a Q is almost never followed by anything but a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> .  Also, the letter E is the most frequently used letter
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  So if one had no other information
whatsoever about an omitted letter, guessing that
the letter might be E would probably be more reasonable
than guessing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X.</ENAMEX>  And if the missing letter
seemed to function as a vowel, the odds would be
greater still.  This is the type of predictability studied
in information theory.

            Effective communication must contain the
“right blend” of redundancy (predictability) and
new information (unpredictability).  If a message is
too redundant, it becomes tiresome.  (This calls to
mind a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> comedy sketch in which an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX>
speaks on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society for People</ENAMEX> Who Say
Things Twice Things Twice .)  But as we have seen, if a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communiqué</ENAMEX> has been compacted to maximize efficiency,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> must strive to receive each and
every morsel, a process which leaves no room for
error.  An analogy might be made with music.  If, on
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> hearing, a piece of music is entirely predictable,
droning on in endless clichés, then it lacks a certain
creative spark, and is not enjoyable.  Conversely, if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> continually finds himself disoriented
with each new note, unable to identify any underlying
pattern or theme, then the piece seems merely
a random collection of sounds and is equally uninteresting.
Such a composition would no doubt leave
the impression that the string section had suddenly
caught fire.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redundancy</ENAMEX> is itself a phenomenon worthy of
study, independent of the study of language or music.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> studies redundancy in the context
of order and disorder of physical systems.  The disorder
of a system is called its entropy .  The laws of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thermodynamics</ENAMEX> tell us that closed systems tend to
become more disorderly over time.  One such closed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is the universe itself.  We find that pockets of
heat in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and galaxies are spreading
out and cooling down over time.  Thus, we can imagine
a time in the distant future when the universe
will become almost uniformly cold, and very few
temperature gradients will exist which could serve
to provide a source of usable energy, such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>.  Without being drawn into these difficult questions,
which require many concepts and tools developed
in information theory, suffice it to say that redundancy
plays a central role in nature itself, and
not just in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>.  As we have seen, redundancy
is not the evil one might imagine it to be at first
glance.  Indeed, it is necessary for the very existence
of language.  But I repeat myself.
         
         
            
“And as for that better mousetrap, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>-terminator
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>) is humane--the mouse is trapped, not killed--and
can be reused.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">”</ENAMEX>  [From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Inquirer, .</ENAMEX>  Submitted by ]
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">“Suspected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> bomb shop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">”</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline</ENAMEX>
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Inquirer, .</ENAMEX>  Submitted
by ]

         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Waterloos</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language</ENAMEX> Frontiers



            The unification of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is a noble thought,
but what are you going to do about the language
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frontiers</ENAMEX>?  However bravely you sweep away
customs barriers and encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> to move
freely over the face of their continent, they will continue
to come terrible and humiliating croppers at
these invisible boundaries.  My own experience
bears this out only too painfully.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I ever ventured onto the Continent
from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the depths of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> was
when I went to work as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zugerberg</ENAMEX>,
a hilltop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>.  I got out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zug</ENAMEX>, still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-dazed from a night trip
across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and what did I see in the sleepy
square but a small tram in the window of which was
a placard reading--unmistakably-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zugerberg</ENAMEX> hell .
I very nearly turned tail and fled without further
investigation.  I even entertained the thought that
the placard might have been put there by the diabolical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> I was going to, who were not
at all keen on having a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>.  I was
not to know that, since hell in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> means
`bright,' this was merely an intimation to the townsfolk
that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> itself was plunged in fog,
the sun was shining on the nearby heights.

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> have no doubt suffered similar
shocks.  Those who travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Moritz</ENAMEX> by rail, for
instance, may well be shaken when, just before arriving
in their dream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>, they stop in a station
where a big sign tells them: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Moritz Bad</ENAMEX>!  Of
course, everyone knows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Moritz</ENAMEX> isn't really
so bad, so they probably conquer their apprehensions
and go ahead.  But what about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad Ragaz</ENAMEX> or
even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Endbach</ENAMEX>?  Many of those who visit country
towns in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">German-speaking</ENAMEX> parts will be proudly
shown the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rathaus</ENAMEX> .  They may well shudder at
the thought that such a fine old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> (actually a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town hall</ENAMEX>) is rodent-infested.  I feel even more
deeply for those expectant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who, turning a
corner on a small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in search of a public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>, have been faced by that one brutal,
laconic word: Abort!  After all, wouldn't WC serve
the purpose just as well?

            At this point the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> will notice that we are
here on delicate ground, straight among words that
may offend our most intimate sensibilities.  When we
meet them at a certain distance, we can usually manage
to take the sting out of them.  For instance, if a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">botánist</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuchs</ENAMEX> gave his name to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flower</ENAMEX>, which is therefore known as a fuchsia , we
can elegantly get round the issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> by pronouncing
it “FEW-sha.”  Or if there is a well-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kunz</ENAMEX> , we can avoid cataclysms
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX> by calling him “KOONDS.”  But
when you run into such things in real life, head-on
and with no warning, there is really no remedy: all
you can do is face the inevitable with whatever fortitude
you can summon.  An evil fate of this kind befell
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloucestershire</ENAMEX> who went
to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> near a town called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheidt</ENAMEX> , the
pronunciation of which proved to substantiate his
worst misgivings.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of his sojourn
in the area, he tells me, his voice used to break
with shame every time he went to a railway ticket
counter to ask for a return to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheidt</ENAMEX>.

            But to get to my own experience.  I had not been
on the Continent long when I wanted to buy some
nylons for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> word for silk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stockings</ENAMEX> escaped me, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word hose
promptly suggested itself to my mind.  So I went into
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>' lingerie and asked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damenhosen</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> behind the counter seemed slightly
taken aback, and when she came and dangled some
lacy panties before my eyes, I was taken aback too.
Perhaps she thought I was a transvestite and had to
be humored.  In fact, I was seriously embarrassed, for
I was still young enough to have a sense of shame.

            On another occasion I was in town with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Englishmen</ENAMEX> who had just arrived on the scene
and did not speak a word of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> between them.
We were feeling peckish although it was only mid
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, so we decided to go and have a snack in a
restaurant.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX>, who spoke a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>,
recommended a dish which happened to be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>.
It turned out to be a paste made from sweet
chestnuts which looked rather like a dish of worms.
We were somewhat intimidated by the look of it, but
we ate it--without enthusiasm, but with the stiff upper
lip we had imbibed, so to speak, with our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">An hour</TIMEX> or so later we still felt peckish,
so we tried another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>.  We decided
that this time we did not want anything sweet, but
rather something a little more substantial.  As a precautionary
measure I consulted the menu, and there
my eye fell on the vermicelles .  I explained to my
companions that this must be pasta, a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macaroni</ENAMEX> (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> macaroni was about
the only kind of pasta you ever saw in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, if
we mercifully forget the incredible invention of
spaghetti on toast).  They were all in favor, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> later we got our snack: it was that chestnut
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paste</ENAMEX> again, looking more like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX> than ever.
We felt that we had been tricked by a malicious fate.
We sat there, unable to start on the stuff, wishing
that we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timbuktoo</ENAMEX>, where we could at least
have had camels' eyes.

            The same malevolent powers also operate in the
opposite direction.  An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> of my acquaintance
was interned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One day</TIMEX> she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX> were
allowed to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> in a nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.  When
they came out, they needed to go to the toilet, so
they began to look round for a public convenience.
They had hardly turned into the high <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> when
their search appeared to be successful, for they
found a door that bore the sign Closed .  That, they
thought, could only be the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> for the German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">word Klosett</ENAMEX> .  But they were disappointed--the
door simply did not open.  It must have been a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, for all down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> there
were Closed signs--but no means of getting in anywhere.
They even began to suspect that the townspeople
were playing a mean practical joke on them.
By now they were nearly bursting--with indignation,
of course--but there was nothing for it: they
had to wait till they got back to their internment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarters</TIMEX>.  Continence, after all, is a virtue, or so say
those who do not have it imposed on them.

            Fortunately these linguistic snares land us in
trouble only for a brief moment, ignominious as that
moment may occasionally be.  Being saddled with a
wrong name is a more lasting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>.  I was once
called in to help a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had died in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, so that as next of kin he had to
handle the correspondence.  Knowing no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, he
obviously needed assistance.  He was called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schittli</ENAMEX> ,
which, believe it or not, is an absolutely good Swiss
name.  His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, strangely enough, was not called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schittli</ENAMEX>. Having emigrated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, he had discovered
that the family monicker, however respectable
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Appenzell</ENAMEX>, would never do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>.  He
had therefore had it changed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hittli</ENAMEX> , which involved
the sacrifice of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> consonants.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, it
was not long before the shadow of a certain Adolf
fell over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>:  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hittli</ENAMEX> was so near to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">likeness</ENAMEX> became, for an immigrant, decidedly uncomfortable.
Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hittli</ENAMEX> took the only course open
to him, and sacrificed a vowel.  He died a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hattli</ENAMEX> .

            The slings and arrows of the spoken language
may prove even more perfidious in writing.  When I
took my first office job in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, I had a secretary
who knew no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, so that I had to
write letters in these languages by hand for her to
type.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the first happened to be to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX>, and she opened with full diapason: Nous avons
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">l'horreur d'accuser</ENAMEX> réception de votre lettre... .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honour</ENAMEX> and horror are evidently very close in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.  Another opening gambit read like this: Nous
vous remercions de vos linges du <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> juillet ....  On
yet another occasion I had to write to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> by
the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX> who had had the effrontery to
criticize me, and I wanted to do so in a firm but
studiedly polite tone.  Once again, the catastrophe
came pat at the very outset: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Bob ...</ENAMEX>.

            Only too often the pitfalls awaiting the unsuspecting
on the language frontiers are downright
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scatological</ENAMEX>.  Why is it that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> wince when
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> informed of the location of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zurich Airport</ENAMEX>?
Why do the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> almost choke with mirth when
they overhear an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> calling his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">“My pet”</ENAMEX>?  And why did a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> acquaintance of
mine break into such coarse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">guffaws</ENAMEX> when he came
across a passage in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> novel in which lovers
were described as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">“lying</ENAMEX> among the furze”?  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Persons</ENAMEX>
not conversant with the languages involved will
probably have no answers to these rhetorical questions,
but I feel sure they will prefer to be spared the
obnoxious truth.

            Sometimes, however, the obnoxious truth just
cannot be suppressed, being explicit and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>.
Thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> canton drive round
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VD</ENAMEX> written in large letters on their number
plates, leaving you to believe it or not.  Similarly,
fine-feeling English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the Locarno
region will freeze with horror when they see the
initials of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrovie Autolinee Regionali Ticinesi</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ticinese Regional Railways</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bus Services</ENAMEX>--brazenly
displayed on the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, and I
once heard an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> murmur that he had never
seen anything quite as big and blue as that in his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.  Then there was the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had
come over from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX> to serve an apprenticeship
on the Continent.  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of his departure,
he proudly showed me a ticket issued by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway</ENAMEX>.  It indicated the price of a single
trip: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fahrt</ENAMEX> Fr. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.50</NUMEX>.  He was taking it home to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yorkshire</ENAMEX> to prove to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> just how high the
cost of living is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>.
         
         


            You have published a number of letters refuting
the idea that the difference in coefficient of thermal
expansion between brass and iron is responsible for
the balls/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> saying [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPISTOLA</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James T. Herron</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XVI,2</NUMEX>].  May I as a humble physicist
and, above all, a certified gas fitter, stir up a little
mud in this matter?

            All the arguments put forward assume an ideal
fit in the original pile and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> temperature change,
with detailed calculations based thereon: therein, I
suggest, lies the rub.  The radius of curvature of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depressions</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> must have been greater
than that of the balls or they would not pile in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.  Given this, the bottom layer of balls
would be pushed apart as far as possible by the
weight of those above.  The temperature rises; the
brass expands more than the bottom balls, which are
again pushed apart by the weight of those above.
The temperature drops, but the weight of those
above would prevent those in the bottom layer from
returning to their original positions.  Repeat this a
number of times, even from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and back,
and the pile becomes more and more unstable until
possibly one cold spell causes collapse.





         
         
            Milestones, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Footrocks</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inchpebbles</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Development</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formal Logic</ENAMEX> 
            




            The study of formal logic was begun in ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grease</ENAMEX>, in order to make the machinery of
reasoning operate more smoothly.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> figure
in this development was Dr. `<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arris Toddle</ENAMEX>, who
invented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syllogism</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX>, as well as those in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Harriet</ENAMEX>.  This form of reasoning
runs essentially as follows:


All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are mortal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
∴Socrates was mortal.

            

            However, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> was mortal, he must have
died by now, so he is no longer alive and thus is no
longer a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.  It follows that he is now no longer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mortal</ENAMEX> and thus will live forever.  This establishes
the immortality of the sole, as well as that of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heel</ENAMEX>, calf, ankle, and toe.  A similar argument can be
carried out for anyone at all, except, of course, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> herself, who was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to begin with.

            A refinement of this form of argument, worked
out by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross C. Knee</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX>,
which underlies much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville Rites</ENAMEX> legislation
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>'s.  These important practices grew out
of a popular mass movement composed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> ever to be awarded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degrees, after writing as many
theses,  and were inspired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville Shepherds</ENAMEX>,
who were led by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX> herself, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred ninety</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>, all but
at most a very few of which were entirely unaware
of the existence of most but not nearly all of the
remaining others.  As in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX>'s
reasoning can also be stated in the form of a
syllogism:


All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are mortal.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least two hundred ninety</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sevilles</ENAMEX>' distinct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">∴Seville</ENAMEX> is suffering from a severe identity crisis.
            

            However, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are mortal, the proportion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX> that comprises them will gradually decrease,
leading to here ventual recovery, just in time
to die from other causes.  This leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> the
sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX>, again establishing the immortality of
the sole.

            The next great development in logic was carried
out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muddyville School</ENAMEX>, also known as The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skull Ass</ENAMEX>-ticks, when they played rock music on the
side to make a living. 
These logicians specialized in
the counting of angels, which they found more effective
than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> in anesthetizing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.  It is
to these great minds that we owe the Fundamental
Theorem of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formal Logic</ENAMEX>, which reads as follows:

            Fundamental <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theorem of Formal Logic:</ENAMEX>


(a)  Exactly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2973</TIMEX> angels can dance on the head
of a pin.

(b)  Exactly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3874</TIMEX> angels can dance on the head
of a needle.

(c)  Exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">264</NUMEX> angels can dance on the head
of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-penny nail.


            

            Since angels tend to be of uncertain gender, neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX> will have anything to do
with them, so their status vis-à-vis mortality remains
an open question.  This is, in fact, the most important
unresolved issue in all of formal logic, because of
greatly inflated land values and a rapidly increasing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, both of which place dancing space
at a premium.

            Logic lay dormant for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many centuries</TIMEX> after being
worked over so brilliantly by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Skull Ass</ENAMEX>-ticks,
but it was finally rescued from angelic oblivion by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlob</ENAMEX> der <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friggin'</ENAMEX>, who proved
that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> star is not the same as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
star, even though both are <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX>. This invalidated
the previously unquestioned Principle of the Substitutability
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Identicals</ENAMEX>, which had been formulated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leibniz</ENAMEX> in his battle with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figby Newton</ENAMEX> for recognition
as the original discoverer of the infinitesimal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">calculus</ENAMEX>. This principle can be formulated as a
syllogism, as follows:


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibniz</ENAMEX> discovered the calculus.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibniz</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">∴Newton</ENAMEX> did not discover the calculus.

            

            However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gottlob</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figgin</ENAMEX>' work showed that this argument
was invalid, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibniz</ENAMEX> worked in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> worked in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>, and it was
really <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galileo</ENAMEX> that discovered the calculus while
looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX>, through his telescope.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galileo</ENAMEX> also disproved the principle that heavier objects
fall faster than lighter ones, by dropping an apple
and a watermelon off the top of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>.  It was
this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX> that gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>
Gravitation, when it landed conveniently on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, and it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Gravitation</ENAMEX> that suggested
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX> the concepts of the infinitesimal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">calculus</ENAMEX>.  Exactly the same thing happened to
Leibniz, except that he got hit by the watermelon
and so was unconscious for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX>.  This gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> time to get to the patent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and file his
claim for calculus, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibniz</ENAMEX> could figure out
what had happened.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gottlob</ENAMEX>'s discoveries laid the foundation for a
tremendous spurt of work in formal logic from the
beginning of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> to the present day.  First,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell N. Whitehead</ENAMEX> managed to derive all known
mathematics from logical principles, in contrast to
previous mathematicians, who had derived it from
illogical principles.  This led to the famous Gödel
theorem, which says that all mathematics cannot be
derived from logical principles.  Gödel proved this
theorem by showing that every sentence in a logical
language can be encoded as a statement about positive
numbers.  Since <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> is not a logical language,
it follows that sentences in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> can be
encoded only in non-positive numbers and thus that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> can make only negative statements about
mathematics.  Since the same is true of every natural
language, it follows that mathematics makes no
sense whatsoever and thus that it can be ignored
for all practical purposes.  This led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Tarski</ENAMEX> to the
discovery that logic itself depends only on the
weather,  as indicated in the following syllogism:


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> is white.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> is white.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">∴Snow</ENAMEX> is white.

            

            Since “snow is white” is true if and only if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX>, and since “snow is white” is true if
and only if “snow is white” is true, it follows that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">“ ` “snow</ENAMEX> is white” is true' is true” is true if and only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">if “</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> is white' is true” is true.  These discoveries
resulted in the theory of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, the clothing worn
by whom gradually shrank to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, thereby enabling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Robinson</ENAMEX> to prove the existence of infinitesimals,
with predictable consequences in the physiognomy
of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.  This reestablished
the intersubstitutability of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX> and
Leibniz, as long as it not snowing and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX> is still
visible.

            The most recent and, in many ways, the most
exciting development in formal logic is the new field
of fuzzy logic, in which precision is replaced with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vagueness</ENAMEX> and truth with maybe and perhaps.   This
was invented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lofty Zappa</ENAMEX>, who is also known,
frankly, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of invention, because of his
work on the logic of necessity.  Rather than taking
statements to be either true or false, fuzzy logic assumes
that statements are true or false to some
degree, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syllogism</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX>, for example,
would be reformulated as follows:


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> was more or less a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are usually mortal.

∴Socrates was most likely mortal to degree
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.86539</NUMEX>.

            

            Since the average lifespan in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51.86 years</TIMEX>, it follows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> would have
lived until he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44.8791254 years old</TIMEX>, if he had
not developed a taste for hemlock.  Unfortunately,
his addiction to this controlled substance led eventually
to his arrest on charges of drug abuse, thereby
enabling Play-dough to counterfeit all of his ideas.  It
was in critiquing Play-dough that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toddle</ENAMEX> developed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syllogism</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX>,  but this was where we
started.
            Preparation of this essay was supported, in part, by a grant from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Society for Skeptical Humorism</ENAMEX>.  I would like to
thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Trudeau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherlock Holmes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attila the Hun</ENAMEX> for
helpful comments on an earlier draft.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Toddle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">“Never Metaphysic I Didn't Like</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">” Chapter 1</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physics</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends or Enemas ?</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavers Free Press</ENAMEX>, for full
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">descriptions</ENAMEX> and telephone numbers.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.M. Luther et al.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation and Information</ENAMEX>: Prolegomena
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theology of Computational Processes , Wittenberg:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church Publishers</ENAMEX> (very) Ltd., for a complete list of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theses</ENAMEX>, with
Index.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Cushing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quantifier Meanings: A Study in the Dimensions of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semantic Competence</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, if you are having
difficulty deciphering the sentence to which this footnote is
attached.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Aquinas</ENAMEX>, “Talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heads</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ticking</ENAMEX>--s,” <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ,
-<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">842: 45-97</TIMEX>, for relevant commentary.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Ogden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. Richards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Meaning of Meaning</ENAMEX> .  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harcourt Brace & Co.</ENAMEX>  Also see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.C. Ogden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.I. Richards</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meaning of the Meaning of Meaning</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New New York</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harharcourt Brace & Co.</ENAMEX>  Also also see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.C.C. Ogden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.I.I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Meaning of the Meaning of the Meaning of Meaning</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New New New York</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harharharcourt Brace and Co.</ENAMEX>  Also also
also see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Cushing</ENAMEX>, “Not only only , but also also ,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">” Linguistic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Inquiry , 9:127-132</ENAMEX>.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N. Abisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Was Leibniz Crackers ?</ENAMEX>,  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxon</ENAMEX>, for
a tasteful discussion of this topic.
            Shocking as it may seem, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX> actually plagiarized the title
of his major work, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Principia Mathematica</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>, whose
major work was also entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Principia Mathematica</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX>,
however, plagiarized his title from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Machiavelli</ENAMEX>, whose major
work, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II Principe Mathematice</ENAMEX> , laid the groundwork for all future
studies in quantitative political science.  It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Machiavelli</ENAMEX>, in
fact, who invented the notion of disinformation , on which all contemporary
politics crucially depends.  See note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> for relevant discussion.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Tarski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. Dylan</ENAMEX>, Don't Need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Weatherman</ENAMEX> to Know
Which <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Way the Wind Blows</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow White & Dwarfs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Robinson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Zakon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">“A Set</ENAMEX>-theoretical Characterization
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enlargements,”</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.A.J. Luxemburg</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ed</ENAMEX>.), Applications
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model Theory</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algebra, Analysis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probability Theory</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holt Rinehart & Winston</ENAMEX>.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.R. Gaines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">“Foundations of Fuzzy Reasoning</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">” in M.M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gupta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.N. Saradis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.R. Gaines</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eds</ENAMEX>.), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuzzy Automata</ENAMEX> and
Decision Processes , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elsevier North-Holland</ENAMEX>.  Also see S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Robertson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">“Nature of Fuzz: A Diatribe,” Journal of the American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Information Science</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">304-307</ENAMEX>.
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Fonda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barbarella: Queen of the Gal Axis , Hollywood, CA:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexist Press, Inc.</ENAMEX>, for the cosmic significance of all this.
         
         


            I should like to correct <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> arithmetic errors
in the article, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“To Abbrev</ENAMEX>, or not to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbreviate,”</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> Sharp [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XVII,2</NUMEX>].

            First, a change from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> letters ( master
of ceremonies ) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> letters ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.C.</ENAMEX> ) is a reduction of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91.5%</NUMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300%</NUMEX>.  A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> reduction, incidentally,
is a change from any positive quantity to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, a change from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> letters ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.C.</ENAMEX> ) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
letters ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emcee</ENAMEX> ) is a growth of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150%</NUMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">125%</NUMEX>.

            Finally, a change from thirteen letters ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> )
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> letters ( VP ) is a reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84.6%</NUMEX>, not
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">250%</NUMEX>.

            Words matter, but so do numbers.





         
         


            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharp</ENAMEX>'s arithmetic is painful to behold.  Reducing
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> letters of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of ceremonies
to the two-letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.C.</ENAMEX> in no way represents a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300%</NUMEX> reduction in letter-load.  It's actually <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90.47%</NUMEX>,
give or take.  Similarly, reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> is a reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84.62%</NUMEX>.





         
         


            ...If from thirteen ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> ) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> ), the reduction would be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX>.





         
         


            ...Reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of ceremonies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.C.</ENAMEX> represents
an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88%</NUMEX> reduction, and reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> represents an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX> reduction.





         
         
            [I knew all that.... -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> ]
         
         


            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Dunkling</ENAMEX> writes [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XVII,1</NUMEX>], “In many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> [belief that use of a living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s name
would deprive him of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>] prevents the use of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relation</ENAMEX>'s name if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> concerned is still
alive.”  The belief is that giving a living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
name would deprive him of his full life.  It is found
among all orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ashkenazim</ENAMEX> and many of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX>.




         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Leave



            The title of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Malle</ENAMEX>'s movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Au Revoir</ENAMEX> les
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enfants</ENAMEX> is usually untranslated in reviews and
advertisements in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.  When it is
translated (as when an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> translation follows
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French</ENAMEX> title) it is rendered as “Goodbye, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Children</ENAMEX>.”
This translation is as good as any, but quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsatisfactory</ENAMEX>.  For that reason and because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
is closely related to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> (lexically anyhow, having
borrowed a great portion of its vocabulary from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>), the title can be left in the original as a title
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish or Polish</ENAMEX> could not be.

            Snob appeal may be involved here.  It is wondrous
the way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> is able to maintain its position
as the language of style and status, at least throughout
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> world.  In such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> as The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time French</ENAMEX> words and phrases appear
with much greater frequency <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">than bits</NUMEX> of any
other foreign language.  The issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 25, 1988</TIMEX>, taken at random, had in its “Dancing”
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79 two</NUMEX> whole sentences in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, untranslated.  The issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town & Country</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September, 1988</TIMEX>, had a full-page advertisement
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Island Cotton</ENAMEX> entrely in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> except for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novel S.</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> brief business letters in
likewise untranslated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.  I suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with some claim to international
sophistication are flattered by the assumption
of some ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> that a little French
will not be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> to them.

            However, the short phrase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Au</ENAMEX> revoir les enfants
would resist translation even if it were desirable to
put it into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  Only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> words
slips easily enough into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, as till .  But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> language I know that has no
calque for the expression au revoir , probably because
we have adopted this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> phrase, like
many others, intact, while other languages have the
phrase calqued as: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hasta la vista</ENAMEX>, a rivederci, do
svidaniya, do widzenia, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiedersehen</ENAMEX>, etc.  At any
rate, goodbye really does not translate au revoir,
Adieu, also borrowed intact into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, would do
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> equivalent of goodbye , and vice versa;
but that equivalence gets us nowhere with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">au revoir</ENAMEX> ,
except to point up the fact that goodbye does not
mean au revoir .

            I once heard a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> tell a couple
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> shop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> a joke that illustrates the
difference between adieu `goodbye' and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">au revoir</ENAMEX> :
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio de Janeiro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> of various
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were taking off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after another, and the
terminal was crowded with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> seeing loved ones off.  An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> took off, and the loved ones on the
ground waved and shouted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">“Au revoir</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Au revoir!”</ENAMEX>
Then an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> taxied away to shouts of “Hasta
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">la vista!</ENAMEX>  And then it was the turn of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> flown by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> with a notoriously poor safety record.
As it taxied away to take off, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> more
intoned than shouted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">“Adeus</ENAMEX>!  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adeus!”</ENAMEX>  (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>
for adieu ).

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> lacks a calque for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">au revoir</ENAMEX> , it
would be technically possible to make one, perhaps
on the model of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>'s (or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Dedalus</ENAMEX>')
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“agenbite</ENAMEX> (of inwit)” for remorse: till the agenseeing .
But of course such bitterly pedantic wordplay would
be unthinkable on the lips of the plain-spoken priest
whose words give the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malle</ENAMEX> film its title and some of
its poignancy.  And if agenseeing is too far-fetched
and pedantic, so long is a shade too informal, slangy.

            And what about the simple definite article in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX>?  Surely it should pose no problem.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Au</ENAMEX> contraire ,
I suspect it is the most meaningful and untranslatable
word in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-word phrase.  It is not
strictly standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> before a common noun in
the vocative case, but seems borrowed from the
folksy language of camaraderie, the slang of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">barracks</ENAMEX>, and campus.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> does not sing, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">“Allons,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">les enfants de la</ENAMEX> patrie....”  In modern <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French</ENAMEX>
novels about military experiences, however, one
may find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> proposing to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">“Allons,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">les</ENAMEX> gars....”  In such usage the plural definit article
seems to imply a sense of solidarity, of togetherness,
of addressing not just any or all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or
whatever but of specifying a particular group.  Further,
since les in this special usage has its origin in
boyish slang, it implies masculinity, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> might in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  In the title in question les might be translated
by the pronoun you and the whole title as: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">“So</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.”  This translation conveys the meaning
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French</ENAMEX> title, all right, but is nevertheless
unacceptable because such jaunty informality would
be totally out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> whose warm
yet solemn farewell at a tragic parting gives the
movie its title.

            Nor does enfants always mean `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,' exactly.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Cassell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Dictionary</ENAMEX> defines
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enfant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">“Child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX>; ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>,
issue.”  Then some of the following examples
given in the dictionary show that in some contexts
the word does not mean `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>' at all: c'est un bon
enfant `he is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>'; l'enfant prodigue `the
prodigal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.'  Moreover, some of the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
addressed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> in the movie are past childhood,
though in priestly parlance anyone, even a nonagenarian,
may be called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.  So perhaps children
will do here, though arguably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> might be a
nuance better.

            It may be that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, because it so rich in connotation
and nuance, is harder to translate than most
languages.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> has a much larger vocabulary, a
fact that has been adduced to support the argument
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> is inferior to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  But the larger vocabulary
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is irrelevant in two respects:
much of this larger vocabulary is esoteric, exotic,
pedantic, or otherwise as foreign to everyday English
usage as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>; and whereas vocabulary is
quantified by words, the expressive units of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
tend to be phrases, such as chemin de fer, joie de
vivre , and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">raton laveur</ENAMEX> .  By the usual lexical reckoning
one could say that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> has no word for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail</ENAMEX>-road
or raccoon .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phrases</ENAMEX>, being more semantically complex than
single words, are usually harder to translate.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
too has its untranslatable phrases composed of words
that are individually translatable.  For instance, try
turning these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>: Is you is, or
is you ain't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>? and Why'd you bring that old
book I didn't want to be read to out of up for?  Generally
speaking, a phrase or clause is difficult to translate
in proportion as it diverges from the standard, or as
some would say, as it is ungrammatical.  To paraphrase
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy</ENAMEX> paraphrasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pushkin</ENAMEX>: All grammatical expressions
resemble each other; each ungrammatical expression
is ungrammatical in its own way.
         
         
            “If I were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>...” I'd be in a subjunctive mood

            We shall have to wait and see if the changes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>'s political fortunes are reflected
in the language as spoken in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, for one might
be tempted to infer that the assertiveness of her tenure
was partly responsible for the demise of the subjunctive
in contrary-to-fact constructions--at least
in those perceived by her to be contrary to what she
perceived as fact.  Although it is not impossible to
find a subjunctive in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> writing of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, it is
becoming increasingly difficult; indeed, in a book I
recently completed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University Press</ENAMEX>, virtually
all subjunctives were replaced by indicatives
(which, because of the solecisms created in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, occasioned my rewriting of the text to
avoid the problem).  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> (among whom I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number journalists</ENAMEX>, who, after all, probably write
more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>) sometimes go to
great lengths to avoid using the subjunctive, resulting
in writing that jars what poor sensibilities might
remain to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>:


...[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]he cancelled all his interviews after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and insisted he flew home... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape</ENAMEX> dared
suggest he travelled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">From “Books</ENAMEX>,”
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 October 90</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8:9</ENAMEX>.]


            

            This is not impossible to say, but it means `She
insisted that he had already flown home [though it
is unlikely that he had].'  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“She</ENAMEX> insisted that he fly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">home”</ENAMEX> means `She wanted him to fly home,' though
whether he actually did or not would be revealed in
a later chapter.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cape</ENAMEX> dared suggest he travelled by
train conjures up an image of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape (“his</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>)
having the effrontery to put forward the theory that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">absent “he”</ENAMEX> absconded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail</ENAMEX>.  Had the subjunctive
been invoked, these mysterious motives
would have vanished in a trice.


Because we were an alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and mum
were very keen that we learnt how to compose
ourselves in this new society.  [From an article by
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Magnus Magnusson in “Saturday Review,”  The</ENAMEX>
Times, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 October</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90:70</TIMEX>.]

We advise that the above items are not used
until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has been contacted.
[<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Customer Safety Warning Advt</ENAMEX>. by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leisuretime Products Ltd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundial House</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89-93</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldsworth Road, Woking</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Surrey GU21 1LT</ENAMEX>, in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29 May 1988</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B2</TIMEX>.]


            

            The practice is neither consistent nor universal:


It failed to be manufactured because she insisted
it be made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>...  [From an article
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Connolly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Times</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90:19</TIMEX>]

Someone on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Isle of Wight</ENAMEX> complains that
you couldn't get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> off to bed if it were
still light at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>,...  [From the op-ed column,
“...and moreover,” The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29 October</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90:12</TIMEX>.]

            

            Although it has nothing to do with subjunctives,
I cannot resist the temptation to reproduce the following
sentence from an article by Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Strong</ENAMEX>,
presumed aesthete and literatus, yet evidently victim
of the universal virus that afflicts many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> when they scent the proximity of like :


The paper used to smell in the same way that
books from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> still do today.  [From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">“Saturday Review</ENAMEX>,”  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 October</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX>.]


            

            Whatever consolation it might afford <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> are with them in their ignorance of
the difference between fewer and less:

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maher</ENAMEX> points out that his Dillons <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">flagship</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gower Street</ENAMEX> carries no less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> titles
and his other bookshops average <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX>.  [From
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“Books</ENAMEX>,” The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 October 90</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8:9</ENAMEX>.]


            

            And some have trouble with the sequence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tenses</ENAMEX> (not a trivial problem, I admit), yielding in
this instance what might be called the “son-for-a-day”
syndrome:


I now know them to have been Mr and Mrs
Powrie-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, and a chap I take to have been
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.  [From the op-ed column, “...and
moreover,” by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Parris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Times</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90:12</TIMEX>.]


            

         
         
            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Types of Ambiguity: Minimalist Language</ENAMEX>



            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Bernstein</ENAMEX>, when he was assistant managing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> , published a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> organ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“Winners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinners</ENAMEX>,” that offered kudos for
the occasional “bright passage” or deft metaphor
and cited questionable and nonstandard grammar
and usage that appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>.  Among
the items that he enjoyed catching were the ambiguous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headlines</ENAMEX>, which he dubbed “two-faced heads.”
These are not very hard to find in newspapers (as
of the headline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (who is not, usually,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of the article) is to come up with something
that is a telegraphically brief inkling of the
substance of the article.  Headline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are often
given to paronomasia (which they would probably
call punning, as paronomasia , which would not fit
into most headlines, is not in their vocabulary).
Gleaned from the current collection:


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.  Cost of food scares mounts.  [The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 October</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>]

I was not under the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> worried
much about the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fodder</ENAMEX>.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> may supply <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ibid.</ENAMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>]
Arms is always ripe for ambiguity.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> taken on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¥500</NUMEX> raid.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ibid.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 October</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>]

The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were not captured on the raid: the
story was about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who had his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (and,
as I recall, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>) wait in the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> while he
went off to commit a robery.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> filmed in secret. [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ibid.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 October 90</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>]
Filmed is here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a past participle</TIMEX>, not the past of an
active verb.  This grammatical ambiguity is a frequent
source of confusion, one cleverly exploited
by those who write clues for crosswords.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.  Prices fear as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> shortage puts pressure on refining.
[<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ibid.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 October 90</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>]

Prices is an unusual noun to find in attrubutive position
before a word like fear (in contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">noun/</ENAMEX>
verb ambiguities like drop, rise, increase, decline,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>).  In any event, it is still not clear why an oil
shortage should put pressure on refining (one
would expect the reverse) and why the prices resulting
ought to rise (for fear would scarcely suggest
`reduction' except in a petroleum trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX> or oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> annual report).

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.  Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Want Sex Changes as You Age</ENAMEX>.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 January 1990</TIMEX>.  Submitted
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Alfred</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>]

Self-evident problem in which sex rears its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            

            That is not to say that ambiguity is confined to
headlines.  In the following quotation, the reader
may have difficulty in determining how far from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> this ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> lives, why he isn't bankrupt
from feeding parking <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meters</NUMEX>, and what circumstance
might have afflicted him with muteness:


[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Odette</ENAMEX>] lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walton</ENAMEX>-on-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hallowes</ENAMEX>], a tall, courteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX>
retired from the wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> who seems content
to write her letters, listen while she tells her
stories, feed one's parking <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX>, and altogether
to be as attentive as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> could wish.  [The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
Times, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 October 90</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3:3</ENAMEX>]

            

         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“Lithium</ENAMEX> was not effective in either depressed or
non-depressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX> in significantly reducing the
numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> who were not abstinent, number of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of reported drinking, number of alcohol-related hospitalizations,
severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>, or severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>.”
[<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Drug Therapy,</ENAMEX> .  Submitted
by ]
         
         
            
“There is no residency requirement for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Senate</ENAMEX>
other than that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of the state he
is running from at the time of his election.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">”</ENAMEX>  [From the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX>, .  Submitted by ]
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“The Brundtland</ENAMEX> report celebrated by many at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'90</NUMEX>, while hard-hitting in its analysis of the global environmental
crisis, is profoundly shallow in its prescriptions.”
[From comments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Tester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York University</ENAMEX>, quoted in the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Oil Bulletin,</ENAMEX> .  Submitted by ]

         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instant Welsh</ENAMEX>



            I broke imaginary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> on the rim of a non-existent
frying pan and made sizzling noises.  I pretended
to fill tumblers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and to drink
them with apparent delight.  I beat the air with my
arms and clucked like a hen and mooed deep and
long.  But the features of the old, old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
had opened the door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way up
the mountain and who had answered my polite request
for a few <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> with a steady
flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX>, remained blank.  As blank as mine
had been when she had been speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Welsh</ENAMEX>.  My
miming must have been wanting as I got neither egg
nor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.  But the humiliating thing was that I, relatively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bilingual</ENAMEX> and with a smattering of a few other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languages</ENAMEX>, have been able to make myself understood
in most part of western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, but was thoroughly
checkmated not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> miles as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow flies</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>...  I decided to learn Welsh
forthwith, there and then, without more ado.

            Of course, it was not going to be plain sailing.  I
knew that.  We--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and
I--had been invited to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten blissful days</TIMEX> in an
idyllic white cottage in the middle of a field near a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of lakes in the depth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caernarvonshire</ENAMEX>.
The nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> was a couple of valleys away; our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> were sheep and lambs.  It was definitely
known that a road-mender did sleep in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-room
cabin near the abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slate quarry</ENAMEX>.  These were
perhaps not the best conditions in which to learn the
Welsh language, but what I lacked in amenities I
thought I would make up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">“ambiance”</ENAMEX> for there
we would be for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX>, practically incommunicado.

            My only tutor was one of those paper napkins
on which are printed some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> brightly colored
pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> and things in common use, such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, sea, sun, chair, etc., with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> name above and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> underneath.
You know the sort of thing.  Very useful in its way no
doubt, but rather limiting to someone of scholarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disposition</ENAMEX>.

            It was then that Chance took a hand.  Would
you believe that I found in the rafters of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>'s
cottage a dusty <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Welsh-English Dictionary</ENAMEX> compiled
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Richards</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">L1</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX>, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1890..</NUMEX>.?  It was like
reaching that peak in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darien</ENAMEX>.  A whole new world
was about to be revealed to me.  And into this unknown
land, this strangely melodious language, with
its roots dating back to the time when the world was
young, I set forth, with my paper napkin and my
pocket dictionary compiled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>.

            As I read on, picking out a word here and a
phrase there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> began
to appear.  The aims of a lexicographer, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>,
is undoubtedly to be as objective and exact as possible
when dealing with concepts as intangible as
the meanings of words.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> himself was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roundly</ENAMEX> criticized for letting his prejudices interfere
with his definitions.  We do not go to a dictionary for
opinions or for subjective judgment, and the more
remote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">compiler</ENAMEX>, the better.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> obviously entertained a different idea
of his mission.

            His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> quickly became clear.  That he was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX> there can be little doubt, and anyone
would have been able with the help of his dictionary
to plough through a sermon on predestination or a
debate on the difference between transubstantiation
and consubstantiation.  This in a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">POCKET dictionary</ENAMEX>,
you understand.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> must also have been
interested in demonology, witchcraft, familiars,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhabdomancy</ENAMEX>.  (You wish to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhabdomancy</ENAMEX> ?  Well, another time perhaps.)  Then
there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>'s interest in diseases.  Far
from simply giving us the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> for rheumatism , he
goes into details of the symptoms and I will spare
you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-line description of the scabs in a case of
blue jaundice .  If you should catch blue jaundice in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, I strongly advise you to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX> at hand.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, since jaundice
means the `yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>,' how can it be blue?  But
let it pass.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> never stops astonishing us.  You
would think that the word bye-laws was not one
which in a pocket dictionary would be given much
space.  But wrong you would be.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> gives
us a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-treatise</ENAMEX> on the application of bye-laws in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX>, which is not particularly
useful if you are lost in a fog and, on knocking
at the door of an isolated Welsh cottage, you are
faced by an aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX> who has no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.

            I fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> did not have us in mind
when he set to work, for he omitted to include such
words as tomato, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, cutlet, cauliflower , and
railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> .  Yet let no one say he was not a mundane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, for he gives us the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">port</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sherry</ENAMEX>,
whisky, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brandy</ENAMEX>, burgundy, claret , and even Rhenish
wine .  And do you know that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> words in
Welsh for fashion ?  But none, apparently, for tomato,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bathroom</ENAMEX>, cutlet , etc.

            It quickly appeared, on perusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh-English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> was
somewhat idiosyncratic, for he gives us an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
translation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Welsh</ENAMEX> word, `to render prospective.'
I have pondered on this phrase, and the only person
I can imagine using it is the secretary of the local
branch of a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> who, having handed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> a short list of would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>,
asks: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"></NUMEX>Which of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shall we render
prospective?”

            Then there is the word arfogwl which apparently
means `a dried skin on a post with pebbles in
it,' with no further explanations as to why it should
be hanging on a post and why, in heaven's name, it
should contain pebbles.  I therefore went out to try
to find one in the hope that the object might reveal
its raison <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d'être</ENAMEX>.  I was not successful and I must
warn would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">searchers</ENAMEX> that I very much doubt
whether there is a dried skin with pebbles in it hanging
on a post within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Llanrust</ENAMEX>.  They
had better look elsewhere.

            A closer study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-Welsh section soon
brought to light the fact that not only did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX>
know a large number of English words which do
not appear in recognized dictionaries I consulted
but that, clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that he was, he was able to
translate them into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX>.  Words like dishersion, extillation,
restagnate, claricord, contramure , and, of
course, discubitory .  All these words look as if they
meant something.  The word discubitory took my
fancy; neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> having been
able to enlighten me, I consulted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> himself,
by the simple process of looking up in the
Welsh-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> section the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Welsh</ENAMEX> word which Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> had given as the translation of discubitory
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-Welsh section.  I looked up therefore
the word lledorweddle and was informed that it
meant... `discubitory.'  However, there was an alternative
definition: `partly lying down.'  This I took
to mean `in a semi-recumbent position.'  I had it
now, of course.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discubitory</ENAMEX> means `lying down
whilst propping oneself on one's elbow.'  This word
has now taken its place in my vocabulary and I use it
now and then nonchalantly in conversation.  To date,
no one has asked me what it meant.

            To mark the centenary of this remarkable book
and help revive interest in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, I hereby undertake
to hand over a prize of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¥100</NUMEX> to the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who challenges me with the words: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"></NUMEX>You are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel Vercambre</ENAMEX> the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> who discovered
the meaning of the word discubitory and I
claim the prize of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¥100</NUMEX>.”  The challenger must be
carrying at the time a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX>'s Welsh-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">pocket dictionary</ENAMEX>.  The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX> edition.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bloomsbury Dictionary of Word Origins</ENAMEX>,
            Although one might be led to believe that all
dictionaries of etymology are alike, the truth is that
they differ in a number of respects, and it is useful
for those interested in language to have several
types available.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> , for example, has very
long and elaborate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">etymologies</ENAMEX>, some of which
might have been superseded (presumably in
OED2e ), which means you have to have the latest
edition.  Then, too, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> does not always transliterate
foreign scripts, which might put those who
cannot read <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyrillic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>, etc., at a
disadvantage when examining cognates or loanwords.
Some of the smaller dictionaries, from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">MW-III</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Unabridged</ENAMEX> on down
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and desk sizes, contain etymologies
reflecting up-to-date scholarship but these
works may not be particularly user-friendly: after all,
surveys have shown that etymological information is
that least frequently sought by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictionary users</ENAMEX>, so it
ill behooves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> to devote a great deal of expensive
space to it.  In contrast to these standard
works, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ayto</ENAMEX> has compiled a very commendable,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">user-friendly</ENAMEX> book which is eminently readable
(as is all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayto</ENAMEX>'s writing).

            I do have a few reservations--(naturally!  How
could a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> identify an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urdang</ENAMEX> review if it did not
have reservations?)  First, I found the system of cross
references inconsistent.  In the front matter we are
told that if “a related word is mentioned but no date
is shown for it,...the word has its own article....”
That is not consistently the case, though it would be
too boring to cite examples.  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, (in the entry
for albatross ), <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcatraz</ENAMEX> ought to have been identified
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">“former” prison</ENAMEX>-island (it is still an island, of
course), and the generalization that ail is “virtually
obsolete except in the metaphorical use of its present
participial adjective ailing ....<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">”</ENAMEX> fails to take account
of the common expression, What ails you/
him/her/it/them?, and fails to explain what is metaphorical
about She is ailing .  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>--though here
we might not be dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayto</ENAMEX>'s decision as
much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s--it is simply not convenient
to have a dictionary of etymology that excludes all
bound prefixes and suffixes, though these are
glossed, as required, when they are part of an entry.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, I think it a mistake to merge under one
headword words of distinctly different provenances
(that is, homographs), as in gloss .  And, finally, there
are far too many typographical errors for a book of
this sort: under absent : <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4nt”</TIMEX>; after: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">“millenium”</ENAMEX>;
loo: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">“existance.</ENAMEX>”

            Notwithstanding, there are many cogent observations,
among them:


glitz... “Its fortuitous resemblance to a blend of
glamour and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz</ENAMEX> contributes to its expressiveness.”

glass [The entire entry is a gem.]

know [A well-constructed short essay on its cognates.]

            

            The chief virtue of the book is that it presents a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal of information about word origins in
highly readable form.  Indeed, there is so much information
buried in the entries that the publisher
would have been well advised to prepare an index to
afford <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> better access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nether</ENAMEX> reaches of
the language.  Perhaps in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second edition</TIMEX>...?
