
   
      
         
            Abusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s English



            
               ...here will be an old abusing of God's patience
and the king's <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windsor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">i.4.5-6</ENAMEX>)
            

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Harrison</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a year ago</TIMEX>,
some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> still regret that, apart from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> try in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Much Ado About Nothing</ENAMEX> , he had never
done a Shakespearean comedy.  With what acerbic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suavity</ENAMEX> would he have retorted to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Katherina's ‚Äú</ENAMEX>...
and so farewell,<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù with ‚ÄúWhat</ENAMEX>! with my tongue in
your tail<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?‚Äù  The Taming of the Shrew</ENAMEX> (ii.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.217</NUMEX>).  Indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> would have been delighted by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> rendition of many of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a thousand</NUMEX>
naughty passages that have so diligently been
compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Partridge</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bawdry</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partridge's</ENAMEX> are all instances of intentionally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">naughty</ENAMEX> entries.  But far more hilarious are those
items penned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX> that were never intended
to shock or amuse a future evil-minded generation
such as ours with indelicate, let alone indecent, suggestiveness,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rex Harrison</ENAMEX> or no!

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Othello</ENAMEX> (v.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.266</NUMEX>), even the most unflappable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> must gasp at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moor</ENAMEX>'s offer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gratiano</ENAMEX>:
‚ÄúHere is my journey's end, here is my butt,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> nor
will his guffaws entirely abate after he learns that
butt here means goal .  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twelfth Night</ENAMEX> (v.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.126</NUMEX>), it
would appear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke Orsino</ENAMEX> was not fully aware
of what was befalling him when he admitted to
Olivia that ‚ÄúI partly know the instrument that
screws me.<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù  In Sonnets to Sundry Notes of Music</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I.15</ENAMEX>), we find the puzzling howler, ‚ÄúThen lullaby,
the learned man hath got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> gay.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Gay</ENAMEX> is used
here as a compliment, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s jaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> will
snicker at the line.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Lear</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">iii.3.15 et seq</TIMEX>.),
one is comforted to note that the generous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gloucester</ENAMEX>
is eager to become the wretched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lear</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, as he assures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund that ‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> will seek him and
privily relieve him...the king, my old master,
must be relieved.‚Äù  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macbeth</ENAMEX> (v.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.54</NUMEX>), your normally
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">prurient</ENAMEX> theater-goer may well sense a hint of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onan</ENAMEX> when Macbeth orders the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctor</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúPull't
off, I say.<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù  In Hamlet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv.7.85</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> seems to be
hinting rather indelicately to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laertes</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamord</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> horseman, had beefed up a bit, when he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">picturesquely</ENAMEX> notes that ‚Äú...he grew into his
seat.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù  Similarly</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Troilus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cressida</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">i.3.31-33</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestor</ENAMEX> offers Agamemnon this flattering description
of a monarch's royal behind:


With due observance of thy god-like seat,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Agamemnon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestor</ENAMEX> shall apply
Thy latest words.

            

            And never mind that seat in both quotes means
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throne</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> (ii.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.413</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>), even the gentlest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> may be forgiven for wondering what in
the name of propriety is going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bastard</ENAMEX> informs King
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> that


From north to south
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> shoot in each other's mouth.

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> should note another category made up of
various terms and phrases that have a decidedly
modern flavor that is not quite what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>
had intended for them.  These are items that may
raise the stiffest eyebrows, as in Cymbeline
(iii<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3.21</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> may infer that the
mail service was just as deficient then as it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarius</ENAMEX> gripes to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guiderius</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arvigarus</ENAMEX>,


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>! this life
Is nobler than attending for a check,

            

            --or maybe the check was not even in the mail.

            Were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, he might have
to revise some passages in order to avoid misunderstanding,
as might be the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarus</ENAMEX>'s declaration
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony in Antony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv.7.9-10</ENAMEX>)
that


I have yet
Room for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">scotches</ENAMEX> more.

            

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarus</ENAMEX>'s reference is to cuts or gashes, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
in genuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> might well assume that
Scarus was preparing to go on a bender.  In the
opening chorus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> , lines <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-12</NUMEX>, there
is asked


can this cockpit hold
The vasty fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>?

            

            No anachronism here, of course, as cockpit refers,
not to a part of an airplane, but to an enclosed place
for fighting cocks and, in a transferred sense, to a
circular theater.  When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharina</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petruchio</ENAMEX> in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taming of the Shrew</ENAMEX> (iii<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2.214</NUMEX>) ‚ÄúYou may be jogging
whiles your boots are green,‚Äù she was referring
to transportation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and not to our current
physical fitness mania.  And the ‚Äúpuke-stocking‚Äù
mentioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry IV</ENAMEX>
(ii.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.79</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>) is not a reference to the hosiery worn
by our kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jogger</ENAMEX>, but to a dark woolen cloth.  Is
there a more up-to-date clich√© than tender loving
care?  In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VI</ENAMEX> (iii<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2.279</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>), the king issues
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>:


Go, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salisbury</ENAMEX>, and tell them all from me,
I thank them for their tender loving care.

            

            Here are some other noteworthy current terms
used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>:

            
               good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> -- this expression of common present
usage is found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv.3.236</ENAMEX>) where,
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassius</ENAMEX> had bidden him good-night, Brutus
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">replies, ‚ÄúGood-</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            
               not so hot -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goneril</ENAMEX> says this to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Lear</ENAMEX>
(v. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.67</NUMEX>).

            
               pent-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macbeth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">i.3.19-20</ENAMEX>):


Sleep shall neither night nor day
Hang upon his pent-house lid.

            

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pent-house</ENAMEX> here refers to eyelids, not to a lavish
apartment.

            
               eye-sore -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taming of the Shrew</ENAMEX> (iii<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2.103</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baptista</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petrucchio</ENAMEX>:


Fie! doff this habit, shame to your estate,
eye-sore to our solemn festival.

            

            Also, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rape of Lucrece</ENAMEX> (lines <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">204-5</ENAMEX>):


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yea</ENAMEX>, though I die, the scandal will survive,
be an eye-sore in my golden coat.

            

            This contemporary term, incidentally, was first recorded,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Edition of The Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Unabridged</ENAMEX> , around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1250-1300</TIMEX>.

            
               to do (someone) wrong -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rape of Lucrece</ENAMEX> , line
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1462</TIMEX>:


And therefore Lucrece swears he did her wrong,

            

            and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Lear</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">i.2.186</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar</ENAMEX> complaints:


Some villain hath done me wrong.

            

            Both lines anteceded by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> , not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mae West</ENAMEX>.

            
               turn off -- in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleapatra</ENAMEX> (iii<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6.93</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), Mecaenas
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tells Octavia</ENAMEX>:


Only the adulterous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX>, most large
In his abominations, turns you off.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">RH-II</ENAMEX> notes that turn off is slang for ‚Äúsomething or
someone that makes one unsympathetic or antagonistic,‚Äù
dating the entry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1680-90</TIMEX>.

            
               like to -- In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pericles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv.2.80</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marina</ENAMEX> says, ‚ÄúTo
'scape his hands where I was like to die.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù  RH-II</ENAMEX>
labels this current expression to be of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Midland</ENAMEX>
and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> origin and means ‚Äúto be on
the verge of.‚Äù

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poop</ENAMEX> -- In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pericles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv.2.25</ENAMEX>), as he relates what the
‚Äúlittle baggage‚Äù did to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transylvanian</ENAMEX> in the
brothel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boult</ENAMEX> says that ‚Äúshe quickly pooped
him,‚Äù meaning that she overwhelmed him.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
slang, pooped has the sense of exhausted , and
sometimes worse.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> even managed to insert a bit of
what sounds like current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> slang.  In
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> instances, both found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adonis</ENAMEX> ,
namely, line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">617</TIMEX>:

            Whose tushes never sheath's he whetteth still,
and line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">624</TIMEX>:

            And whom he strikes his crooked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tushes slay</ENAMEX>,

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tushes</ENAMEX> means tusks .  But tush , or tushie , is current
slang for buttocks , an apparent alteration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
tokhes , of like meaning.

            Ah, but it is the unintentional humor we return
to for our heartiest laughs!  In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rape of Lucrece</ENAMEX> ,
lines <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">780-81</ENAMEX>, we know that ‚Äúhe‚Äù refers to the sun,
but we may be forgiven if we assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarquin</ENAMEX> is
meant, considering that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>'s passionate activities
of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucrece</ENAMEX>:


The life of purity, the supreme fair,
Ere he arrive his weary', noontide prick.

            

            Then there is this passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Troilus</ENAMEX> and Cressida
(i.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.343</NUMEX>) that has been distinguished by being
placed just before the index to the eleventh edition
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Familiar Quotations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collier & Son</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>):


And in such indexes, although small pricks
To their subsequent volumes, there is seen
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby figure</ENAMEX> of the giant mass
Of things to come at large.

            

            Could this be a commentary on what an arousal can
do for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s morale?

            Ah, but one final image remains ever green!  It is
that of a future <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Harrison</ENAMEX> in the role of Armado
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love's Labour's Lost</ENAMEX> (v.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.111</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>) expressing to
Holofernes his feelings toward his monarch, as he
avows how he would gladly permit his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king ‚Äúto</ENAMEX> lean
upon my poor shoulder, and with his royal finger,
thus dally with my excrement.‚Äù  Nor is the vividness
of this tableau entirely diminished when one notes
that, as here used, excrement is a synonym for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX> .

            It is too cynical to foresee that some irreverent
smarty-pants will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> pry and dig and garner
further items of unintentional humor out of our supreme
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poet</ENAMEX>'s writings?  Is it too fanciful to predict
that many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX>'s words are, even now, lying
low awaiting the coming of the inevitable day when
they shall become of the bright, new-minted, contemporary
expressions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>?
         
         
            
‚ÄúSerious crime down, but murders increase.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, .  Submitted by ]

         
         
            
‚ÄúOther <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> will sponsor crime
prevention awareness activities <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, but not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Olean</ENAMEX>.
Candlelight marches, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s activities and block parties
will take place as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> unite to speak out against
crime prevention across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Olean</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> , .  Submitted by 
]

         
         
            
‚ÄúOne <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand marijuana</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> have been seized in
a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> investigation near here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From the
Kitchener-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waterloo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>) Record , .
Submitted by ]

         
         
            
‚ÄúThe podium erected in front of building A was surrounded
by a semicircle of spectators on wooden chairs.‚Äù
[From <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Segal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 316</ENAMEX>. Submitted by ]
         
         
            
‚ÄúEach of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> rings were positioned inside each
other.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From an article on laser capability in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Job Shop</ENAMEX>
Technology , .  Submitted by 
]
         
         
            Names of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>



            According to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, when the present
capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> was founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colonizers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1610</TIMEX>, it was named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Villa Real de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe de San Francisco de As√≠s .</ENAMEX>  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> versions
this grandiloquent title, really more a dedication
than a name, sometimes has the definite article la
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">inserted</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between de</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> , which changes the
meaning from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Francis of Assisi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal City of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holy Faith</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal City</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Faith of Saint</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assisi</ENAMEX> .  In modern times at least, and possibly
since its founding, the capital, no longer royal,
has been known simply as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> .  Since Romance
derivatives of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> sanctus mean holy as well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saint</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> name <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, like the same name
for several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> culture,
means in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holy Faith</ENAMEX>.'  Incidentally, English-speaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> more used to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> than to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
names often misspell the name: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚ÄúSante Fe</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            By whatever name, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> is nestled in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foothills</ENAMEX> of a cordilleran spur called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sangre de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cristos</ENAMEX> .  No one really knows how this mountain
range came to be named for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood of Christ</ENAMEX>, but
educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guesses</ENAMEX> are not lacking.  At sunset these
mountains are sometimes suffused with a rosy glow
that some romantis <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> like to think could have
inspired the descriptive name.  However, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">sixteenth-century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaniards</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> were too
literal about their religion and too indifferent to nature
to be inspired by sunsets.  A more probable explanation
attributed to a thoughtful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Tate</ENAMEX> is that cruciform crevasses, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> filled
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>, that are visible on the mountainside from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Gabriel</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> capital, reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de O√±ate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the first successful <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
colonizing expedition, of the cross he wore to symbolize
membership in a lay religious order devoted
to reverence for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Precious Blood of Christ</ENAMEX>.  The
trouble here is that according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.M. Pearce</ENAMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> Place Names as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late as 1790</TIMEX> the range was
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Madre</ENAMEX> and has been called by its present
name only since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early nineteenth century</TIMEX>.
The most plausible etymology, in my opinion, suggested
by the learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fr. Benedicto Cuesta</ENAMEX> among
others, is that the range took its name from penitente
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chapels</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> in its foothills consecrated
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Redeeming Blood of Christ</ENAMEX> at a time when in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> such chapels were so numerous
that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood of Christ</ENAMEX> was practically synonymous with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chapel</ENAMEX> .

            By modern standards the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> colonial and
briefly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> was more a
village than a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.  Almost as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spaniards</ENAMEX> founded
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> on the ruins of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pueblo</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conquerors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> built their territorial
capital on and around a dilapidated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
core, little of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 55,000</NUMEX> as it exists <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> derives much
more from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglos</ENAMEX> who have been
attracted here since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid nineteenth century</TIMEX>
than from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> who populated the tiny frontier capital
for over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX> previously.

            The names and architecture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> have
gone through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parallel stages in a parabolic
course.  The original architecture was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andalusian</ENAMEX> filtered
through the tastes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
(then called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Spain</ENAMEX>) and further modified by the
materials available and the centuries-old experience
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pueblo Indians</ENAMEX>.  The walls were of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adobe</ENAMEX>,
which to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglos</ENAMEX> was mud, pure and simple.
In north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> adobe bricks were even called ‚ÄúDallas
stiff-muds.‚Äù  The roofs were flat and supported
by trimmed logs called vigas , and they leaked.  To
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fe</ENAMEX>, even the sprawling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, were at
best unrefined and at worst squalid.  So in the second
stage of construction the ‚Äúprimitive‚Äù structures
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-colonial past were gradually replaced
and surrounded by more ‚Äúproper‚Äù architecture.
The relatively grand new cathedral, for instance,
was built in the style of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamy</ENAMEX>'s native
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provence</ENAMEX>.  Aside from a scattering of historic colonial
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> around and near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX>, the oldest
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> tend to be in a style that owes
more to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">American Midwest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> than to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> origins.  Then came the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> stage
early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twentieth century</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> was
invaded by a more sophisticated, in some cases artistic,
cosmopolitan kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX> that recognized
the esthetic value and appreciated the exotic
charm of the surviving <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of the colonial town
and began to cultivate a revival.  Others, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>, came to see in this revival commercial
potential, and modified versions of the old Pueblo
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Territorial</ENAMEX> styles have dominated, indeed monopolized,
architecture in the capital ever since.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nomenclature</ENAMEX> has tended to parallel the physical
metamorphoses of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>.  At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and
throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventeenth century</TIMEX> there were no
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> to bear names, only a nameless quasi-street
leading a short way from the parish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dominguez</ENAMEX> is quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian H. Bustamente</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>--History of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient City</ENAMEX> as describing
the villa in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> independence
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> rule, as consisting of ‚Äúmany small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ranches</ENAMEX> at various distances from one another, with
no plan as to their location, for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> built as
he was able, wished to, or found convenient, now for
the little farms they have there, now for small herds
of clattle which they keep in corrals of stakes, or else
for other reasons.‚Äù  Such place names as there were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to clusters of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, such as casas reales
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">(‚Äúroyal houses‚Äù</ENAMEX>), renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governors</ENAMEX>
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrio de Analco</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cluster</ENAMEX> that housed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>.  ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analco</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nahuatl</ENAMEX>,
the language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aztecs</ENAMEX>, and means `on the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX>' [of the river].)  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Roads</ENAMEX> entering the settlement
were called by the names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> or
places to which they led, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camino de Pecos</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camino del Alamo</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camino de la Canada</ENAMEX> .  And
eventually physical features such a main irrigation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ditch</ENAMEX> ( acequia madre ) or the wall that enclosed the
official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> gave their names to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> associated
with these features.  But the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in
the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> date back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">occupation and reconstruction</ENAMEX> and therefore have
such basically <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> names as: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace Avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Francisco Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX>
Place , and so on.  These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and their names correspond
to the architecture of the first wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX>
occupation.  Likewise the period of
revival of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pueblo</ENAMEX>-colonial architecture in the twentieth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> corresponds to an attempt to revive
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, or at least historic nomenclature.  So the
recently constructed loop around the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has
been named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paseo de Peralta</ENAMEX> .  The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX> entering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> from the south that was originally called
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph Street</ENAMEX> because the telegraph line ran along
it and was later renamed College Street because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> was built there is now romantically
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Santa Fe Trail</ENAMEX> .

            It is in the often hastily constructed and hastily
named developments on the edges of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> that
the names are most feverishly given.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>,
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> heritage and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> remain
considerable, the new pseudo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> names are
more apt to be correct than in, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucson</ENAMEX>.  Nevertheless, there are many cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pidgin</ENAMEX>.  The most common solecisms are
those of syntax and grammatical gender.  Though
there are plenty of examples to show that some
namers of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> are aware that in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
a definitive modifier follows the modified word,
so that there are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> properly named, for instance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camino Cerrito, Calle Lorca</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Plaza Fatima ,</ENAMEX>
there are other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> names that betray oblivion to
this grammatical rule, for example: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte Vista</ENAMEX>
Place or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cielo Vista Court</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte Vista</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cielo Vista</ENAMEX> are supposed to mean respectively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX>
View and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sky View</ENAMEX> but, so far as they signify
anything, really mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">View Mountain and View Sky</ENAMEX>
or Heaven .  Even more common in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> are
names in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adjectives</ENAMEX> fail to agree as to gender
with the nouns they modify, for example: Calle
Largo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calle Lejano</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calle Contento</ENAMEX> .  This error
may be due in part to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> tendency to reduce
all unaccented final vowels to schwa and in
part due to the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adjectives</ENAMEX> are listed
in dictionaries in their masculine forms only.  Also,
out of context <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adjectives</ENAMEX> are thought of as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masculine</ENAMEX>.

            One can imagine a bulldozer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> as he
blades out a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">development</ENAMEX> being
hailed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> thus: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúHey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Loyd</ENAMEX> ...‚Äù
(Here I should explain that there is a fairly recent
new tendency to give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-surnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> jarringly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names, which results in such
oddities as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loyd Martinez</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priscilla Chavez</ENAMEX>.  In
this practice, I believe, we are happily lagging behind
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilians</ENAMEX>.)  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúHey Loyd</ENAMEX>, how do you say
long in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish?‚</ENAMEX>Äù  To which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loyd Martinez</ENAMEX>, bilingual,
might reply, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúLargo</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúSo Long Street would be Largo Calle</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  (To the
Anglo ear the final o , an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX> , and perhaps the e of calle
are schwa.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúNo</ENAMEX>, turn it around: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calle Larga</ENAMEX> .‚Äù

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúOh</ENAMEX>, yeah, now I see it here, in this pocket dictionary-- largo .‚Äù
And knowing calle from previous
experience, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> jots on his pad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calle Largo</ENAMEX> .  The phonemic distinction between unaccented
final a and o goes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> ear and out
the other.

            Finally, there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> names that are simply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretentious</ENAMEX> or inept.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio Grande</ENAMEX>, the river
in whose valley the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> lies, has been called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great River</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, maybe partly because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grande</ENAMEX> suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English Grand</ENAMEX> , but in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grande</ENAMEX> means simply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big River</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great River</ENAMEX> would
be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gran Rio</ENAMEX> .  (That tricky syntax again.)  Formally
correct but pretentious is the street name Camino
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">del Monte</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sol</ENAMEX> , which before it was paved was sometimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irreverently</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camino del Muddy Soil</ENAMEX> .
Then there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Fonda</ENAMEX>, the rather famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey</ENAMEX>
hotel that superseded the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Hotel</ENAMEX> when
the local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Anglos</ENAMEX> woke up to the touristic value of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nomenclature</ENAMEX> and architecture.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
newcomer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> once told me that he had
been much puzzled by hearing rich <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>
extol the charm of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Fonda</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> pronounced
like fond plus schwa).  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, he explained, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fonda</ENAMEX> is the cheapest, grubbiest sort of dive.
         
         
            
‚ÄúWhereas sexologists have previously asked whether
the female gentilia resemble those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s sexual organs may be derived from
those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [From a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paladin/Grafton</ENAMEX> book advertisement
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Guardian</ENAMEX> , n.d., .  Submitted by ]
         
         
            To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foot</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letter</ENAMEX>, I'm Listening to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> Sermon!



            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles V</ENAMEX> held that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> should be spoken to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> to the ladies,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> to geese, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungarian</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohemian</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Devil</ENAMEX> ...  We
take it for granted that our language is the most
natural mode of expression and we look upon
others with tolerant amusement if not hostility.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Jonathan Jacobs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Naming Day</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> is so much shaped by the language he
speaks that he tends to get locked into that
particular language structure.  As Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobs</ENAMEX> affirms,
what does not conform to the rules of one's native
tongue is not just different, it is wrong or at the very
least, odd.  When I took my first foreign language in
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, I clearly remember being intolerantly
amused by the peculiar way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> say
certain things, which I learned were called idiomatic
expressions.  They often seemed like idiotic expressions
to me.

            For example, why would anyone in his right
mind ask, ‚ÄúHow do you call yourself?‚Äù instead of
the perfectly sensible, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúWhat</ENAMEX>'s your name<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">?‚Äù</ENAMEX> and put
a question mark not only where it belonged at the
end but at the beginning of the sentence--and up-side-down--to
boot?  Why make a crazy statement
like ‚ÄúIt makes beautiful,‚Äù for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s nice weather‚Äù?
And so on.

            I was recently reminded of all this while boning
up on my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> before traveling with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> no tengo pelos en la lengua
(`And I don't have hair on my tongue: I'm telling you
what I think'), that is, llamo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al pan pan, y al</ENAMEX> vino vino
(`I'm calling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine wine</ENAMEX>: I'm calling
a spade a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spade</ENAMEX>')--it's a muy fascinating language!

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> since my youthful folly, I have become
entranced with the splendid beauty of the
Spanish tongue.  And once again, as I have refreshed
my memory, I have savored the picturesque idiosyncratic
verbal constructions of the language.  Who
cannot become enmeshed in the rich rolling of r's in
a word like `railroad,' ferrocarril?  How could one
not be astounded by the funny logic of, say, meeting
one's match by encountering the shoestring of one's
shoe: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">encontrarse con la herma de su zapato</ENAMEX>?  Or
who could fail to be entertained while attempting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trabalenguas</ENAMEX> (`troubled tongues: tongue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twisters</ENAMEX>')
like: Yo no compro coco.  Porque como poco coco,
poco coco compro .  (`I don't buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coconut</ENAMEX>.  Since I eat
little coconut, I buy little coconut.'), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mi</ENAMEX> mama
me mima mucho .  (`My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> spoils me a lot.')?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Jonathan Jacobs</ENAMEX> speaks about ‚Äúthe universality
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">linguistic chauvinism‚Äù</ENAMEX>:


We characterize unintelligible speech by saying,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> to me,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and Rumanians
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> to me,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX> to me,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThat</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> to me,‚Äù and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Poles</ENAMEX> by ‚ÄúI'm listening
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sermon</ENAMEX>.‚Äù

[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Naming Day</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Jonathon Jacobs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>]

            

            Casting aspersions on them, as opposed to us,
finds <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> no exceptions to the rule.
Take, for instance, the various ways they characterize
the concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúplaying dumb‚Äù</ENAMEX>: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolivia</ENAMEX> it is
‚Äúto become an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian‚Äù</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hacerse el italiano</ENAMEX> ; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> get it with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hacerse el ingl√©s</ENAMEX> ; in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> one becomes a gourd-- hacerse guaje --and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX>'s hacerse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el</ENAMEX> papo equates playing the
fool with one who has a double chin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hacerse chino</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equador</ENAMEX> means `to fool someone [by acting like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>].'

            On the Continent it is bad' cess to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>,
for in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> if you are `surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englishmen</ENAMEX>'
you are being dunned to pay your bills.  ‚ÄúWorking
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English‚</ENAMEX>Äù means you earn a mere pittance.  Ir
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">la alemana</ENAMEX> `to go <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>' is the equivalent of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX> treat .  And dull wit is un chiste alem√°n `a German
joke.'

            If one `has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>' or `catches a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turk</ENAMEX>' in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tener un rat√≥n</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">coger una turca</ENAMEX> ) he gets drunk.  ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Una</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">turca</ENAMEX> is also `a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>.')  Getting drunk in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>, on
the other hand, is estar en fuego `to be on fire.'

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basques</ENAMEX> take verbal beating too, for in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> una basqueria is `a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basque</ENAMEX> [a dirty trick].' Vasconcear
translates `to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Basque</ENAMEX>, to jabber.' I suspect
basquear `to be nauseated' has the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.
And if the cost is not clear, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> moros en la costa
`there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moors</ENAMEX> on the coast.'

            Insult is not limited just to other nationalities,
either.  To a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-speaker</ENAMEX>, a noisy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is una
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boda de negros</ENAMEX> `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">a Negro wedding</ENAMEX>.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Se arm√≥ la de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Quintin</ENAMEX> indicates a terrible row has taken place.

            Adding diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">suffixes</ENAMEX> is often a disparaging
tactic.  For instance, add- illo to a respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>,
abogado , and you have an ignorant one, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">un abogadillo</ENAMEX> .
The small-town mentality is derided in the
use of aldeanismo , an aldea being a `small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>.'

            And there is a whole array of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> barrio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slang</ENAMEX> to tickle one's fancy.  For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX> chata is
an affectionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slang</ENAMEX> term meaning `funny face,'
`<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>,' or `cutie,' but in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> a
fellow would probably be punched out if he were to
call his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> a `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bedpan</ENAMEX>' or `barge'!

            The animal world figures prominently in many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idioms</ENAMEX>.  If you want to be the life of the
party, it is necessary ser <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el pato de la</ENAMEX> boda `to be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wedding duck</ENAMEX>.'  There is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Que</ENAMEX> mosca te <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha</NUMEX> picado?
`What fly has bitten you?: What is eating you?' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gusano de la</ENAMEX> conciencia is `the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worm</ENAMEX> of the conscience,'
remorse.  `To play the red <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX>' ( tocar el
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mochelo</ENAMEX> ) is to get the worst end of something.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Aqu√≠ hay</ENAMEX> gato encerrado `There is a locked-up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat</ENAMEX> here'=`I smell a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>,' <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> gato por liebre `to
put a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> in the place of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hare</ENAMEX>'=`to be taken in,'
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">buscar tres pies al</ENAMEX> gato `to look for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> feet on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'=`to look for trouble' are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> feline
phrases.

            Spanish cursing and swearing is inventive--
echar sapos y culebras literally, means `to throw out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>.'  Such behaviour usually ends up
with having to pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">piper</ENAMEX>, that is, pagar los platos
rotos `to pay for the broken plates.'

            Lest we forget, the ‚Äúclass‚Äù way to play hooky is
hacer vaca , `to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>.'

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picture una boca de agua</ENAMEX> `a water mouth'=`a
fire hydrant,' A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with a closed head (` cerrado
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabeza</ENAMEX> ') is certainly narrow-minded.  The title
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX> could well be translated as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Pie de la</ENAMEX>
Letra `to the foot of the letter'=`word for word'!

            Avoid una media cuchara `<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half spoon</TIMEX>,' for he is
a mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> indeed.  `Give a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pumpkin</ENAMEX>' dar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">calabazas</ENAMEX> if you want to turn down an unsuitable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suitor</ENAMEX>.  Making decisions sometimes requires `sleeping
on it,' that is, `conferring with one's pillow,' consultar
con <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">la almohada</ENAMEX> .  Speaking of sleeping, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> sleeping soundly is `to sleep like a loose leg'
dormir a pierna suelta .

            You will be, likely to jump for joy ( dar zapatetas
`to give shoe sole slaps') and go on a spree ( echar una
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cana al</ENAMEX> aire `to toss gray hair into the air') if you can
go shopping `<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">un d√≠a s√≠ y un d√</ENAMEX>≠a no at
your `rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>'s.' <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">i.e. t√≠a rica</ENAMEX> ([<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Am</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>] `rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>'=`pawn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>').  That is, unless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> canta alto
`sings high'=`asks too much.'

            Many phrases slip over the tongue like liquid
velvet.  There is a tontas y a locas `stupidly and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crazily</ENAMEX>'=`<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">helter-skelter</ENAMEX>'
and the similar a troche y
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moche</ENAMEX> (or trochemoche) , meaning `in complete confusion.'
Or sin ton no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> `without tone or
sound'=`without rhyme or reason.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Un</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runr√</ENAMEX>∫n is `a
rumor.'  A popular alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage</ENAMEX>, chicha , figures
in the saying, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ne</ENAMEX> chicha ni limonada `neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish nor fowl</ENAMEX>.'  `Look high and low' andar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Ceca</ENAMEX>
a la <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meca</ENAMEX> and `in every nook and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cranny</ENAMEX>' de cabo a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabo</ENAMEX> =`from tip to tail.'  Show your `guts', which in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spanish is el h√≠gado</ENAMEX> =`the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>.'  To give una
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dedada de miel</ENAMEX> `a pinch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>,' or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dar jab√≥n</ENAMEX> (or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enjabonar</ENAMEX>) literally `to give soap' or `to wash with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soap</ENAMEX>' you can flatter someone or `soft<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-soap</ENAMEX>' him.

            If your word is no good, you `paint someone a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">violin' pintarle un viol√≠n</ENAMEX> .  Empty, idle words are
`white words' las palabras blancas ; I could just be
`pulling your leg' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomar el pelo</ENAMEX> , literally, `to take the
hair.'

            I can remember being greatly embarrassed once
when I was trying to explain in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> about my
being embarrassed, and how shocked my high
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amigos</ENAMEX> were when I announced, they
thought, that I was pregnant ( embarazada ).  Incidentally,
the last time we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX> we often
heard the beautiful expression for `being pregnant,'
tener gracia `to have grace' or `to be blessed.'

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> recalled a time when in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> restaurant
he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had waited an overly long
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for their order.  He was astonished when his cry
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúServesa!‚Äù</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> instead.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Servesa</ENAMEX> certainly seemed a reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> way
of saying, ‚ÄúI want service!‚Äù but ‚Äú <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cervesa !‚Äù</ENAMEX> will
bring a brew every time.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> die laughing--that is, they laugh a
mand√≠bula batiente `with their lower jaw beating'--
when we tell them of' the pleasures of living a short
distance out of town.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> would
say we live en los quintos infiernos `in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> hell.'
And <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> would say we live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">donde el</ENAMEX> diablo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">di√≥ los</ENAMEX> tres gritos `where the devil gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hoots</ENAMEX>'
or simply, `You live in the sticks' ‚Äú Vive en las
quimbambas !‚Äù

            Well, `inside of a little' dentro de poco , actually,
`of a slap' de sopent√≥n , I mean, `in less than what
sings a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rooster</ENAMEX>' en menos de lo <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">que un gallo</ENAMEX> , here it is
time to stop.  It would be such fun to discuss other
things, but eso <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es</ENAMEX> harina de otro costal `That is flour
from another sack!'
         
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin Supreme Court Dictionary</ENAMEX>



            
               To fit in with the change of events, words, too,
had to change their usual meanings.

               Thucydides, The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Peloponnesian War</ENAMEX>
               
            

            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin Supreme Court</ENAMEX> writes an
opinion in which it does not interpret a statute,
words have their usual meanings.  However,
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> does interpret a statute, that change
of events causes words to change their meanings.
Therefore, writing a complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court dictionary would be a useful, but daunting,
project.  The following entries are only part of such
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>, based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s statutory interpretation
cases during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> period beginning in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>.

            
               after After or before (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheely</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHSS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX> 2d
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               any mortgage Any mortgage except one for future advances
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colonial Bank</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.A.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis. 2d 444</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               any other The same but under extraordinary circumstances
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> ex rel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.L.B.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.G.H.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">122</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>
2d 536 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>)).

            
               any party Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that has not presented its views
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carkel, Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cir</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ct., 141 Wis. 2d 257</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            
               are May be (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington Northern</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">131</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>
2d 564 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>)).

            
               comply Agree to (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ziegler Co., Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rexnord</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">147</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>
2d 308 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               continuing financial interest Continuing financial interest
and interdependence (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ziegler Co., Inc.</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rexnord, Inc.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">139 Wis. 2d 593</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">custody Building</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sugden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">143 Wis. 2d 728</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">dam Dam</ENAMEX> except a cranberry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenpas</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNR</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">148</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis. 2d 579</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant Possible defendant</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richards</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis. 2d 549</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               destitute Having someone who has a duty to support one
and who could provide for one's needs (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cissell</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">127 Wis. 2d 205</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>)).

            
               entered Said to be entered (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matter of Estate of Ristow</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">144 Wis. 2d 421</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               equally In some fashion (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In re Marriage of: Lutzke</ENAMEX> v.
Lutzke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">122 Wis. 2d 24</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>)).

            
               establish Establish or modify (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> ex rel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeske</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeske</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">144 Wis. 2d 364</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> Every adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanson</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">149</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis. 2d 474</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evident Possible</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spooner Dist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. N.W. Educators</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis. 2d 263</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            
               exclusive One of several (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henning</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors Assembly</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">143 Wis. 2d 1</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express Implied</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local Union No. 487</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eau Claire</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">147</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis. 2d 519</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extraneous Extraneous</ENAMEX> or personal (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V. Stewart</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">143</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wis. 2d 28</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               injury <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of future harm (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Moise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossignol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ski Co., Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">122 Wis. 2d 51</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judgement Judgement</ENAMEX> except a divorse judgement (Parrish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">v. Kenosha County Circuit Ct.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">148 Wis. 2d 700</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">may Shall</ENAMEX> in the case of disinterested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Matter</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Estate of Trotalli</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">123 Wis. 2d 340</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>)).

            
               no suit No suit except a contract suit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Complexes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Eau Claire County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">152 Wis. 2d 453</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               obligations undertaken Obligations undertaken separately
from rent (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Univest Corp.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Split</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">148 Wis. 2d 29</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               offer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seperate</ENAMEX> offer (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeMars</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaOur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">123 Wis. 2d 366</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>)).

            
               order Order except a bail forfeiture order (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wickstrom</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">134 Wis. 2d 158</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>)).

            
               paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traceable</ENAMEX> to (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremer Bros.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulaski State Bank</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">138 Wis. 2d 395</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandparents Parents</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandparents</ENAMEX>, greatgrandparents and aunts (In re
Custody of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.M.M.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">137 Wis. 2d 375</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person Person</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moretto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">144 Wis. 2d 171</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               presence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">131 Wis. 2d 153</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>)).

            
               preserving order Punishing disorder (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contempt</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Dewerth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">139 Wis. 2d 544</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">property Property</ENAMEX> except personal injury claims (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriage</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">139 Wis. 2d 778</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            
               property Personal property (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pulsfus Farms</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leeds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">149 Wis. 2d 797</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecuted Holds</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.L.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinickle</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">144</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX> 2d
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repealed Amended</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">In re Paternity of D.L.T.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">137</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>
2d <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            
               shall Shall unless there is a good reason not to (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employees</ENAMEX>
Local <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">146 Wis. 2d 728</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse Spouse</ENAMEX> except a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinbarth</ENAMEX> v.
Johannes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">144 Wis. 2d 159</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               substantial Substantial and protected by law (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste Management</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">144 Wis. 2d 499</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>)).

            
               to From (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worgull</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">128 Wis. 2d 1</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>)).

            
               wire Wire except the wire part of a cordless telephone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transmission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">149</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX> 2d 89
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>)).

            
               with particularity Not at all (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomaz</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">141</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>
2d 302 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appellate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> differ significantly from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that generate material for their own specialized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dictionaries</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> difference is that other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> need to do so because in order to function
they must either attach new meanings to existing
words and phrases or coin new words and pharases.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> go too far, partly because the obscurity
of their jargon sets them apart from others, thereby
increasing their prestige.  For example, although
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> properly coined byte to represent
a new concept, they could have used the everyday
expression turn off instead of inventing a new
meaning for take down .  In contrast, in virtually all
the cases I read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who wrote the opinion did
not have to invent a new meaning for a word or
phrase; the relevant statute yielded a clear meaning
that would have resolved the case.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who
wrote the opinion, however, did not necessarily like
that resolution.

            Judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jargoan</ENAMEX> also differs from other jargoan in
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of the latter do so openly.  They do
not pretend that they are merely reading ordinary
language as anyone else would read it.  After they
produce enough new meanings or newly defined
terms they are likely to publish a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>.  They
expect the definitions in it to supplement, not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supplant</ENAMEX> secretly, the definitions that are in common
use.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX>, however, claim merely to be interpreting
words and phrases in statutes either in the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that anyone else would or in a way that effectuates
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>'s intent.  They never acknowledge
that they are in effect writing their own dictionary
in order to arrive at the results they favor.
Therefore, they implicitly replace existing definitions,
and, because in the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> will accept
as precedents the cases in which they do so, they
truly do change the meanings of words and phrases.

            The most important difference between nonjudicial
and judicial dictionary making is the magnitude
of the adverse consequences.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who are
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> can do little harm beyond mildly degrading
the language and annoying linguistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX>.  In
contrast, the statutory interpretation practices of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> threaten rights and property.  In fact, they
even threaten freedom; in a significant number of the
cases I read the invention of meaning resulted in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> conviction.  Also, because those practices
make it nearly impossible to predict the outcome of a
case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> litigate even though the plain meaning
of the relevant statute is not in their favor, and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> run up huge bills looking for ways to induce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to ignore the plain meaning of statutes.  Those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interpretive</ENAMEX> practices thus have enormous social and
financial costs.  They also have institutional costs because,
to the extent that they subvert clear meaning
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> created, they usurp legislative authority
and diminish the separation of powers, one of
the bedrocks of our system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            Despite these practices, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are not evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>.
They are operating as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have operated for
a long time.  They also reflect their legal education.
If law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> recognized the importance of statutory
law and advocated interpreting statutes only so as to
reveal their plain meanings, they would have even
less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> to teach.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX>--who, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense,
are merely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in robes--when they are on the
bench also continue the lawyerly practice of begining
with a desired result and then working backwards
to arguments that perhaps support it.  Nevertheless,
clandestine judicial dictionary making, in
addition to its serious social and political consequences,
has deleterious linguistic consequences.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in preventing those consequences is to
realize that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> words are losing their meanings.
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äú</ENAMEX>(The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclist</ENAMEX>) hopes to survive the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,020-mile</NUMEX> race
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> countryside and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> to ride
down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>' eloquent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champs Elys√©es.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX> [From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , .  Submitted by ]
         
         
            
‚Äú... You have to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Side Story</ENAMEX> in performance,
preferably on stage, to fully appreciate the enormity
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s achievement.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">From ‚ÄúSaturday</ENAMEX>'s
Television and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Peter Davalle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Times</ENAMEX> , :<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>]
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúWandering</ENAMEX> around the transformed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> in search of old haunts, I felt like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gulliver</ENAMEX> waking
from a long sleep.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From ‚ÄúGoing Home</ENAMEX> to/Retour √°
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergen</ENAMEX>,‚Äù by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helga Loverseed</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.P. Airlines</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>), :<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>.  Submitted by ]

         
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menagerie of Words</ENAMEX>



            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metaphor</ENAMEX>, the literary process that makes a direct
comparison of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing to another, has
a dual personality in word formation.  Its facilitating
role is to create a new word from an existing one
owing to some similarity in their referents.  Thus, kite
was aptly made from Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> c√°ta `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>,' since a
kit hovers in the air in the manner of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>.

            With the passing of time, however, metaphor
also has a debilitating effect.  Only an etymologist
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would be expected to know of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">kite/hawk</ENAMEX>
kinship , and only he is able to see a kite in a spring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sky</ENAMEX> and appreciate it as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> it once was.

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are so common, they are often
used in metaphorically formed words.  Some animals
are named from a comparison to another animal.
Aardvark was borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afrikaans</ENAMEX> aard `<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>'
plus vark <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`pig</ENAMEX>,' the similarity being the snouts.  Alligator
is from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish el</ENAMEX> lagarto `the lizard,' since the
general configuration of both reptiles is horizontal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chameleon</ENAMEX> originated as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> chama√≠ ` on the
ground' plus l√©oacute;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> ,' `<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>,' from the shape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manelike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.  Hippopotamus , from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`horse</ENAMEX> that swims in a river.'  Porcupine , from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`pig</ENAMEX> with thorns.'

            The metaphor in canary is senseless, though,
because the word is actually a misnomer.  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">canarie</ENAMEX> designated the principal isle of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of islands.  The word had come through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spanish</TIMEX>
Canaria , originating as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin CanƒÅria</ENAMEX> Insula `<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isle</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dogs</ENAMEX>.'  Early explorers on the islands found
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> numbers of large <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> there and named the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">archipelago</ENAMEX> after them, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">canis `dog</ENAMEX>.'
Later, there came to be a demand for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>.  They were called canaries, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> were
soon forgotten.

            Original animal metaphors are all but obliterated
in words that have no reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.  An
asinine , human action is the one only an ass should
commit, since ass <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`animal</ENAMEX> known for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupidity</ENAMEX>' is
based on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> asinus `ass.'  To play a bugle is to
blow on the horn of a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>, through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old French</ENAMEX>
bugle , from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">b≈çs `ox</ENAMEX>.'  Butter hides the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bo√ªs `ox</ENAMEX>' plus t\?\r√≥s `<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>.'  A canard is a false story
fabricated to deceive.  The lost metaphor in canard
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>, from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> expression vendre un canard
√° moiti√© `to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-sell a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>.'  To <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-sell anything is
not to sell it at all, but to make it seem as if it had
been sold, that is, `to deceive.'

            From <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">k√≥n≈çps `mosquito</ENAMEX>' the Romans
formed conopium `<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> with a net' (to keep mosquitoes
away).  The canopy used as an elegant covering
over a modern bed, then, is a metaphoric net to
keep the lowly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mosquito</ENAMEX> at a distance.  The ultimate
origin of the word is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> Canopus , evidently
well known for the notorious insect.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caper</ENAMEX> is
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> capriolo <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`male roe deer</ENAMEX>.'  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> who capers
around is likened to leaping like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>.  A cavalier
is tied to his steed through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> caballus
`<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chenille</ENAMEX> was so called from its comparison
to a hairy caterpillar, from the fabric's hairy texture.
The ultimate origin of the word is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> canis <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`dog</ENAMEX>.'
The forgotten animal in columbine is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX>, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> columba .  The flower of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> resembles a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cluster</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five doves</NUMEX>.  The original cynics were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> who made fun of wealth.  Their name
came from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">k√Ω≈çn</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> word meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`dog</ENAMEX>.'  Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cynics</ENAMEX> actually lived barely better than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>.

            The animal completing the metaphor in dandelion
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>.  It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> who established the
comparison in dent de <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion `tooth</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>,' from the
tooth-shaped leaves of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.  Easel was borrowed
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> ezel `ass.'  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s easel supports
his canvas in the manner an ass carries a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>'s
belongings on his back.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gossamer</ENAMEX> is a collection
of weblike material seen floating through the
air in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX>.  Gossamer was formed from early
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">English g≈çs `goose</ENAMEX>' plus summer `<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.'  The reference
is either to the similiarity of drifting goose
feathers or to the time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> when geese begin to
migrate.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">m≈´s `mouse</ENAMEX>' is the origin of muscle
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> is due to some muscles' shapes being
similar to that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>.  Also, the movement of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">flexed</ENAMEX> muscle was thought to resemble the creeping
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> in hiding in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX>,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">papilionem `butterfly</ENAMEX>.'  Early pavilions
were tents, which were shaped like the spread wings
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> is far removed
from a tent.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pedigree</ENAMEX> completes its metaphor
with the Old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> pied de grue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">`crane</ENAMEX>'s foot,' the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-branched print of the foot of a crane being
similar to the lines showing ancestry on a genealogical
chart.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porcelain</ENAMEX> was borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian</ENAMEX>
porcelaine `cowrie <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX>,' from a similarity of the surfaces
of each.  The origin of the word, however, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">porcus `pig</ENAMEX>,' since the curve of the shell resembles
the curve of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.

            
               Ukulele , from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX>, is a metaphor from `uku
`<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flea</ENAMEX>' plus lele `to jump.'  Since ukuleles often provide
music for dancing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> might be
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flea</ENAMEX>-like movements, or there
could be a connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Purvis</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who popularized the instrument in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metaphor</ENAMEX>, as can be seen in this menagerie of
words, is ironic in that it is a great help in the creation
of a word, but in a certain sense, it is also an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accomplice</ENAMEX> in its death.
         
         


            Dear Sir:

            Having lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> for some time, I believe I
may be able to answer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Bassett</ENAMEX>'s letter regarding
the color of Italian <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XVIII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>].  She wondered
why an art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX> said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> had used the red ( rosso ) of an egg
in his preparation for the frescoes.  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> use almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exclusively brown-</ENAMEX>shelled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>.  These eggs
are harder shelled and the yolk is really quite red or
reddish-orange.  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> look quite anemic
next to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>.  Another word for yolk is tuorlo ,
but rosso is more accurate if you want to describe
the color.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, why do we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>
talk of the egg white when it is really clear until it is
cooked or beaten?  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Italian the albumen</TIMEX> is albume
or chiaro (`clear').





         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúRachel Perry</ENAMEX> cosmetics offer a natural alternative to
skin care.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>  [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subheadline</ENAMEX> of article in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tab</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, which prints in its masthead, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> number
beside each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s name is their extension.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù  Submitted</ENAMEX>
by ]

         
         
            Wine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vocabulary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine Description</ENAMEX>



            Drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> can be a lot of fun, and talking
about the taste and aroma of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> while
drinking it can make it even more fun.  My scientific
interest in wine description grew out of watching
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, hold a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> up to a
candle, swish it around, sniff it, taste it, and utter
some wonderfully poetic-sounding remark, such as,
‚ÄúThe burnt fruity nose a bit overpowers the buttery
lushness of the finish.‚Äù  I was certainly impressed by
the language, and I wondered <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, what these
words meant, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, if I, too, could learn to
talk that way.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of my study involved collecting
and analyzing those descriptions used by wine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
and enologists to characterize <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>.  Although the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocabulary</ENAMEX> can be indefinitely expanded, I collected
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200</NUMEX> words that I found to be commonly used.
(A list of the commonest appears at the end.)

            Some of these terms are straightforwardly descriptive,
such as sweet, dry , or woody ; but much of
the vocabulary combined both a descriptive and an
evaluative element.  If we consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> , for example,
which corresponds to the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and
dissolved solids in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, we find neutral words
like light and heavy , but more evaluatively loaded
words, like thin or coarse , meaning `too light' or `too
heavy' respectively.  Some of the wine descriptors
are purely--or at least mostly--evaluative, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>, noble , and elegant , or hollow and bland .

            Especially interesting are the descriptors that
are taken over from very different semantic domains,
such as words that describe personality and
character: aggressive, charming, diffident, honest,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminine</ENAMEX>, masculine .  How can these descriptions be
meaningful?  In order to understand how a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> can
taste feminine or aggressive , we rely on intralinguistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>.  Since feminine is semantically related
to words like sweet, perfumed, light , and delicate ,
which can be related to the smell, taste, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúfeel‚Äù</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> in the mouth, we can understand
how a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> might be described as feminine .

            The next phase of my study was designed to determine
how descriptive language is applied to
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> drinkers served as subjects
for a variety of experiments.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> consisted of nonexperts from different
parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> who had never
drunk or discussed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> with each other.  At each of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> sessions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were given <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> perceptibly
different red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different white
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, typically from different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and from
different varietals (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> made primarily from a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grape</ENAMEX> variety), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were asked to describe
each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>.  Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> sometimes
protested that they did not know any wine
terms, once they got going they often wrote lengthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">descriptions</ENAMEX>.  As a related task I gave them a list of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine descriptors</ENAMEX>, collected from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase
of my study, and asked them to circle all the words
they considered appropriate for each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>.  Results
showed not only that the descriptions were different,
but that they were inconsistent.  One particular
wine was described as ‚Äúsweet, a bubbly, flowery,
light fizzy feeling in the mouth‚Äù by one subject,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúquite</ENAMEX> dry, quite tangy‚Äù by another, and ‚Äúharsh
odor, pungent, unpleasant, bitter, sharp‚Äù by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> observations on the vocabulary may explain
part of the problem.  First, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prefer
some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> to others and because many of the words
are value-laden, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> who like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> used terms
to describe it that differed from the words of those
who did not like it: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> who liked a light wine
would not select a negative term like thin .  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
most of the terms involve a reference to some implicit
scale: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> may be termed light or heavy ,
sweet or dry with respect to all other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, to wines
of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> (red or white), or to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> of that varietal.
Each subject was making an implicit comparison,
but the reference was never made explicit.  Furthermore,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are used to relatively heavy
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chianti</ENAMEX>, for example, might find Beaujolais
light, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> used to light <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Austrian reds</ENAMEX>, might judge that same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beaujolais</ENAMEX> to
be heavy.

            Another set of experiments used a matching
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paradigm</ENAMEX>.  A pair of subjects was given the same
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> perceptibly different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> had
to describe and differentiate them so that his partner
could identify them on the basis of the descriptions.
Overall, the success level for correct matches was no
better than chance.

            Subjects in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, also nonexperts,
met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two weeks</TIMEX> over a period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX>
to taste and talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>.  Tasks similar to those
previously described were performed, but the goal
with this group was to see whether they would develop
a consensual vocabulary and come to understand
what the others meant by the words they used.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Records</ENAMEX> on consensus were taken at the beginning
and end of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-month</TIMEX> study.  Subjects did not
do much better on the matching task at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> than
at the beginning, showing that no group consensus
emerged; yet they reported that they felt subjectively
that they communicated better.  They learned
which of the others shared their own preferences
and whose judgement they could trust.  Moreover,
the words they used changed with experience: when
it became clear that earthy was used in very different
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> by different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, its use dropped significantly.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> consisted of wine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>--
graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">winery</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California at Davis Department of Viticulture</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enology</ENAMEX>.  Among this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> there was greater
agreement in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> descriptors--but only with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, that is, those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> with which the subjects
had the most experience.  On the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, their agreement was
no better than that of the nonexperts.  This shows
that training and experience contribute to consensual
use of language but do not automatically generalize
to the descriptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unfamiliar wines</ENAMEX>.  The
reason is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> first identify the wine and then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> it according to the relevant norms for that
type: if the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> is unfamiliar, they lack the relevant
standards for judging.
