
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee Dime</ENAMEX> and Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reginal Expressions</ENAMEX>



            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years ago</TIMEX>, when sportscaster <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Barber</ENAMEX>
used Southern expressions like sitting in the catbird
seat and tearing up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pea</ENAMEX> patch , there was a degree
of national amusement.  Unfortunately, much of
this colorful speech has been lost as the language has
become homogenized through raido and television.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigmund Freud</ENAMEX> is not blameless.  Thanks to him, we
are all nowadays more or less selfconscious.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> that came of age in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
decades of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> was probably the last of the
unselfconscious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX>.  And because there was much
less travel in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, the regions retained their
speechways much more completely than they do now.
Later, however, especially during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, there
was considerable mobility from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> who went up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> were quickly made
aware of curiosities of speech like I'm fixing to do
something or go somewhere.  And there was hilarity
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northerners</ENAMEX>, for instance, when a Southerner
asked, Who's carrying you to the dance?  Carry in
Southernese meant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hush puppies</ENAMEX> and hoe
cakes were also terms sure to attact attention fifty
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, but are now in common use.  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hoe cakes ,</ENAMEX>
originally baked on hoe, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hush puppies</ENAMEX> , allegedly
so named because pieces of them were fed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> to
keep them quite, are variations of what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX>
call corn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Englanders</ENAMEX> call (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spider</ENAMEX>)
johnnycake: spider because it was baked in a spider , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>, cast-iron skillet.  And when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South</ENAMEX> first saw black-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX>, they were puzzled.
We call these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> , they would say.  When
we say <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX>, we mean what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> call English
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX> or green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX>.  Northerners were also amused
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> matriarch's saying to a tardy arrival at
the dinner table, We've waited for you the way one
pig waits for another.

            Those were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of the enormous <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX>
meal.  Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> worked close to home, and the paterfamilias
as well as all school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> came home
for dinner.  It was the custom to cook large quantities
of many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> breads for this
meal.  Yeast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> was called light <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and corn
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> was corn pone, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn dodgers</ENAMEX>, hoecake, or hush
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> .  Even in small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, large <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> were
prepared at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX>.  One could never tell how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might drop in.  In big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, the cook customarily
went to her own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> or to the curb market ,
now called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>' marker , to lay in a big
supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and fruit.  Usually, enough was
cooked for supper, too.  However, if everything came
out even with nothing left over, the meal came out like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Ross</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> .  If some foold was particularly tasty,
beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious</ENAMEX>, it was larruping .  If someone ate too
much, he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX>'s bait .  The word bait used as a
noun meaning sufficiency is given in few language
references.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> parlance, a bait ment more
than enough.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX>'s bait was a gluttonous plenty.
She has more than she can say grace over, was another
expression which seems to have disappeared.
Even though it refers to grace before <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and thus
means that the materfamilias has more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to feed
than she can manage, the term was used in many situations
of someone whose load was too heavy.

            If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, in early attempts at cookery, made a
mess, it was a mommick or a begarm , both of which
were used as noun and verb.  However, the word bollix ,
meaning to bungle, was used only as a verb.  Bollix
is the only one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> terms listed in most language
references.  It is a safe bet that many who use
the term bollix (informal) do not know that it is a variant
spelling of ballocks (vulgar) testes.

            Before store-bought clothing was available, homemade
was the rule.  During a fitting, if something was
too tight,  it was as tight as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>'s hat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and would
have to be altered.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls</ENAMEX> learned to sew at an early
age.  For some it was a slow and tedious business, but
others picked it up fast and sewed with a red hot needle
and a burning thread .  Although it is standard to
use the adverb directly for right away, it is not used as
much now in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American English</ENAMEX> as formerly.  I'll be
there directly, sometimes contracted to treckly, was
frequently heard as was in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> shakes of a dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sheep</ENAMEX>'s tail , a colorful hunorous variant on the usual in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> shakes of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>'s tail .

            A bossy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was the old ballyo (bell ewe?),
and of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who put on airs, it was said, She's got
a b-i-g place .  If plans went haywire, they went skywest
and crooked .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> were warned not to go at
some task with main strength and awkwardness or
not to go whalestaving at some job.  When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>
overdid some subject, they were told not to make
a blowing horn of it .

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of TV, dancing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> blanketed
the air waves.  This early dancing was fairly frenzied
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gyrating which S.J. Perelman</ENAMEX> labeled fire-in-awhorehouse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">choreography</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsters</ENAMEX> called it didapping :
Why are they didapping all over the place like
that, some would ask.

            Few things are as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> as antiquated slang; consider
the terms dandy-funk and hambeaters , circa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>.  Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, it was said, wore dandy-funk on
their hambeaters.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dandy-funk</ENAMEX> is perfume and hambeaters
are the long tails of a swallow-tailed coat,
widely worn during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>.  Another relic of that
period, not heard any more, is the call to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for
household help: Come quick and see old Ringdie!
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> is unknown; perhaps it originated when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ring</ENAMEX> was in his death throes and the family
were being called.  Ringdie was said as one word,
and the call was made if one wanted quick response.

            Some of the common comparisons were: slow as
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> itch, mad as a biting sow, though as
withleather, fierce as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">boar hog</ENAMEX>, flat as a flitter , and
hot as flugens .  Neither fitter (in this sense) nor flugens
appears in any readily available <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dialect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reference</ENAMEX>, nor do they appear to be related to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> words of similar sound.  Nor does the prized
gold <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> .  If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, an employee, for example,
was highly valued, it was said, His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> wouldn't trade
him of a gold <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>.

            Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> learned the right way to spell <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>, i, crooked letter, crooked letter, i, crooked letter,
crooked letter, i, humpback, humpback, i .

            The earlier generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> wanted hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biscuits</ENAMEX>
for breakfast and spoke disparagingly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wasps</ENAMEX>' nests .  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Skim milk</ENAMEX> was blue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> , a
widely used term.  Also common was the term <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dime</ENAMEX> , as in not worth a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> dime.  This regionalism
was used mainly at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>: if a person
wanted to make it clear he had not given a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> (?)
a gift, he would say, I gave him a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> dime.  The
term means a kiss but was used disparagingly, as in to
kiss off .  Not in any reference work I checked, it is
probably a relic of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
War, as is the term gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> .  The latter refers
to property which had been appropriated because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home ovwner</ENAMEX> had not paid taxes on it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> was indeed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bible Belt</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mencken</ENAMEX> labeled it.  However not only the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, but
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was caught up in religious revivalism
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early decades of the century</TIMEX>.  The best-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> revivalists were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jennings Bryan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William A.  Billie</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.  But there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of lesser-known revivalists whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> blanketed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.  These revivals usually lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and were also called rotracted meetings .
During the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> had
its revival tent where repentant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sinners</ENAMEX> walked down
the aisle, the sawdust trail , to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mourners</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bench</ENAMEX> for
prayer and sometimes emotional repentance.  Ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, genuinely tried to be
good in word and deed.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were probably
damaged beyond repair because they were not allowed
to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>'s name in vain, or to swear, i.e., use
words like devil and hell .  Instead of devil , they were to
say the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> , and instead of hell, the bad place .
Churchgoers were told not to call anyone a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> no
matter how justified the label because there was an injuction
against it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:22</TIMEX>)

            Keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX> was also important.  Respectable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> never did a washing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.  And as
for sewing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the old superstition stated that if
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> sewed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the devil would make the
sinner rip every stitch with his/her nose.  Of course,
no one took this seriously.  However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superstitions</ENAMEX> were taken seriously.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, known also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, warned against giving knives as gifts: they
would cut the friendship.  The other warned against
watching a parting guest out of sight: bad luick would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ensue</ENAMEX>.  Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstition</ENAMEX> warned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> contemplating
marriage, Change the name and not the letter,
change for worse and not for better.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, a standard farewell was, You
keep out of meanness, hear?  Though it was often
used jokingly, it was the equivalent of the current
Have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX>.
         
         
            If you cannot afford <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie's</ENAMEX> Auction price
Â<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">¥1,761,500</NUMEX> To buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Anglesey Desk British Antique</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Replicas</ENAMEX> will make you an exact copy almost indistinguishable
from the original at less than a fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie's</ENAMEX>
price.  [From an advertisement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> ,
.  Submitted by .]
         
         
            Anti-Language


            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> use of language is to communicate, it
might come as a surprise to note a few of the
times when language is used specially to confuse
and alienate.

            Anti-languages do just this: their reason for existence
is to ensure secrecy by being understood by
only a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.  Once too many people
have cracked the code â€” most important, when those
who have done so are in some way opposed to the
anti-language's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> â€” the language becomes obsolete
and dies.

            Linguistically speaking, an anti-language is
formed by a process of relexicalization, which is substituting
new words for old.  The grammar of the original
language is kept, but a distinctive vocabulary
develops, quite often when referring to activities or
areas important to the subculture that the creating the
language.  Established society usually has its nose put
slightly out of joint in the process.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John S. Farmer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Its Analogues</ENAMEX> ,
wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>, The borderland between slang
and the Queen's <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is an ill-defined territory, the
limits of which have never been clearly mapped out.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linguists</ENAMEX> who have taken on the chalenge of
doing so include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Green</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotten, Grose</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wentworth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flexner</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Partridge</ENAMEX>, who published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first</TIMEX> edition of
his enormous <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of Slag</ENAMEX> and Unconvential
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>.  Further back, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long ago as 1792</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedrich Ch. Laukhard</ENAMEX> wrote, It is common knowledge
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have a language that is quite peculiar
to them and that is not understood very well
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> society....  But if the code of behaviour
somewhere is particularly lievly, then the language
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> is all the richer for itâ€”and vice
versa.

            Convicts shipped to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> spoke a criminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">argot</ENAMEX> described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hardy Vaux</ENAMEX> as flash language
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">New and Comprehensive Vocabulary</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Flash Language</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1812</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaux</ENAMEX>, in fact, was criminal
himself, but also a linguist; transported to the
colonies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times, he used the journeys as opportunities
for research.  Most of the words he lists (swag
being a notable exception) did not pass into mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian English</ENAMEX>.  Possibly some exist in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal underword</ENAMEX> to this day.

            Let us look at the modern underworld.  In a
friendly manner <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are talking in the presence
of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, an impostor â€” a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> or an investigative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter â€”</ENAMEX> who believes he has infiltrated their
ranks.  His problem is that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are aware of
his deception.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> says to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, Shall
we clear up this mess?  No, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> replies,
we'll leave it for the cleaner.  Little does the impostor
know that he has just been sentenced to death,
for what was really said was, Shall we kill him?  No,
we'll leave it to a professional.  A cleaner is a hired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gun</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> â€” or at least it was until recently.
Now the definition is too well known, and it will
shortly be dropping away.  Cleaner is a word which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adheres</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> principle of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>:
the word employed in the process of relexicalzation
should not itself be conspicuous.

            A great deal of argot appears to be ordinary language
â€” not only in the English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sunderworld</ENAMEX>.
In india a sentence that translates into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as Go
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> the bowl is used by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> to an associate in
front of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>.  It means Prepare a grave.  (Note
the similar links between murder and hygiene.) Few
studies, however, have been made into the language
of underground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, not least because of the dangers
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>.  We know that the language of the
Calcuttan underworld contains <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than forty</NUMEX> words
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> .  Often,
the meanings of such code words are detected and
then they promptly go out of use; sometimes, they
are not detected at all.

            The same is true of the anti-language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>.
Considerably more is known about grypserka â€”
the anti-language of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> â€” than about any
English-speaking system, but even that knowledge is
incomplete and out-of-date.

            The alternative, second life inside <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>
involves a complex caste system of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> ,
categories determined by the type of offence involved
and the length of incarceration.  Movement within
the hierarchy depends on sticking to the rules of a
game in which grypserka figures prominently.  An inmate
is downgraded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> by breaking the rules,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of which is never, ever, to reveal the secrets of the
anti-language, no matter what pardon or privilege is
offered.  It is a concept well known in all prison systems.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> would be grassing .
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> slang is readily enough available in any
prison drama or comedy: screw is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>, snout is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX>, nonce is a child molester or other sex offender,
and nick or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porridge</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> itself.  This is
not anti-language, for we all understand it.  This outdated
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison slang</ENAMEX> is used almost nostalgically, in the
same way that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still employ Cockney
rhyming slag (which was once itself an anti-language).

            Anti-language is not easy to define as it does not
have rigid rules to which a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subculture</ENAMEX>'s inventions
must conform.  Nor is it easy to determine its origins,
although historically an argot known as pelting speech
was employed by bands of ne'er-do-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> in Elizabethan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>.  There were over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> terms for
varying types of vagabond: rogue, prigger of prancers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>, counterfeit crank , and bawdy basket are
but a few.

            Both then and now, new vocabulary in key areas
lead to finer distinctions in meaning than are found
in the parent language.  There are many synonyms,
and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> there is the comfort that comes
with the freedom to discuss illegal acts in public
places.

            While slang is not itself anti-language, it exhibits
some of its tendencies.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slag</ENAMEX> has as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language has dialects.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth slag</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>
slang, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> slang, gay slang, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> slang â€” the list is
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX>.  And every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> wants its own argot, a test by
which a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit</ENAMEX> can be measured: if you don't
know the language, very often you cannot get in; or, if
you are already in, not knowing the latest key words
can be disastrous for your credibility.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slang</ENAMEX> is a means of unification; for those who use
it, it is fun, unconventional, and sassy.  What is more,
it can be witty, picturesque, metaphoric.  How it differs
from anti-language is that while it often intends to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subvert</ENAMEX>, it does so by being understood (at least in
part) by the world at large.  Where the purpose of
anti-language is to be secretive, slang is often offensive.
It is used by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those4</TIMEX> who want it to be known that
they are a clique â€” not dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>,
row.

            It is important to remember, however, that what
survives of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s slang may bacome the
next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>.  Bus was the slang
term for omnibus, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> for zoological gardens , and
piano for pianoforte .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> slang once used on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band</ENAMEX>
radio has similarities with anti-language, although
even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> more often regarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> as eccentric
nuisances than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revelled</ENAMEX> in their outlawed status; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> were well
represented in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> lexis.  They were bears or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smokeys</ENAMEX> ; police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, a bear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> or cave ; a police
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">helicopter</ENAMEX>, a bear in the air .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> using radar were
kojaks with kadaks .  More confusingly, a police car
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jam sandwich</ENAMEX> or a bubble<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-gum</ENAMEX> machine .  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> expressions run along metaphorical pathways
is reminiscent of pelting speech.  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood wagon</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon ambulance</ENAMEX> and dragging wagon tow
truck are like the much earlier crashing cheats teeth,
smelling-cheat nose, and belly cheat apron, where
cheat means thing to do with.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage</ENAMEX> slang in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX> has been
strongly influenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cultures,
by immigration, and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>.  Wrongly accused of
being a lazy language, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> slag is, in fact, as complex
and rhythmic as any dialect.  The words <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
well hard, wicked , and swear-words are not simply
idle padding for a sentence, they are an
intrinsic part of the language.  That so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
disapprove of the way the youth communicate is precisely
what keeps this variety of slang going.

            This leads to the issue of talking Black.  Linguistically,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black English</ENAMEX> has origins in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
(mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creole</ENAMEX>.  Black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, a patois,
does not vary much from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> and belongs
to an ethnically defined social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
sittings its use ensures soldarity between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>; in
White or mixed sittings the use of the patois symbolizes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> distance from mainstream society and an
assertion of ethnic identity.  The more linguistically
distinct the sounds of a patois, the more it can come
to symbolize social distance.  Here is approaches the
status of anti-language.  For some Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>,
talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> provides a system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> on a linguistic
level to a powerful social order.

            It has long since been noted that when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> people
who come from different social backgrounds
meet, there is often a tendency for their speech to
alter, so that they become more alike, a process known
as accommodation or convergence.  Its opposite â€” divergence
â€” occurs when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wish to stress their
personal, social, religious, or sexual identity; divergence
takes on a position of confrontation, though is
often said to be a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s pride.  Anti-language
is divergence on a grand scale, and most varieties
of slang are at least sympathetic to the
philosophy and purposes of anti-language.

            Are we faced with the paradox in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> effectively use different languages?
Very unlikely.  But perhaps there will be a rethinking
of the word communication and an instinctive scintilla
of caution when communicating outside one's social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grockles</ENAMEX> of Goodrington



            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 25th</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1995</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in The
Archers , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Radio</ENAMEX>'s long-running country
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soap</ENAMEX>, mentioned spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> preparing
Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Loxley</ENAMEX> for an influx of grockles on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archers</ENAMEX> is set in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midlands</ENAMEX>, but it seems the
word grockle has trqanscended its southwestern connections
and become a widely distributed informal
term for tourist, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>, or holidaymaker.
By extension, it can mean nonresident, nonlocal, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Thorne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bloomsbury Dictionary of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contemporary Slang</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>) claims that it has been
adopted by non-native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travellers</ENAMEX> living in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West Country</ENAMEX> to refer to anyone who is not approved
of.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">OED2e</NUMEX> labels grockle as dialect and slang, of
uncertain origin , and mildly disparaging , as well as associating
it especially with southwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>.  It provides
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> citations from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964 to 1986</TIMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Fowels</ENAMEX>' novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Martin</ENAMEX> , and another referring
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Isle of Weight</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cornwall</ENAMEX> the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emmet</ENAMEX> is used with exactly the same meaning and is
likewise labelled mildly disparaging by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> ,
which gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> citations, both of which include
grockle , from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975 and 1984</TIMEX>.  Its meaning is presumably
transferred from the basic sense <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX>.  Indeed, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> quoted in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> citation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Listener 20</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">23/1</ENAMEX>] regarded it, in comparison with grockle , as less
difficult and more vivid because its true meaning is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bloomsbury Dictionary</ENAMEX> claims it has been
used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cornwall</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>.

            There have been various attempts to illuminate
the uncertain origin of grockle , from the fanciful to
the plausible.  An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exeter University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> once
speculated, perhaps tongue-in-cheek, that it might come
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> graeculus , translated as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greekling</ENAMEX> with
a derogatory flavour.  It has often been derives from the
name of the clown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grock</ENAMEX>, an allusion to the red sunburnt
noses of seaside holidaymakers.  That is the version
given in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dictionary of Contemporary Slang</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonathon Green</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Books</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rev. ed</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>):



The term originated in the West Country, specifically
Torbay, where a local remarked that the stream of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> resembled little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grocks</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX>...
            

            A most detailed and circumstantial account of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genesis</ENAMEX>, which more than a little impresses me, also
traces its origin to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Torbay</ENAMEX> area and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic</ENAMEX>, but
not of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grock</ENAMEX> variety.  This version claims that
grockle was the spontaneous coinage of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in
the southwest holiday trade, prompted by an early
memory of a picture story in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s comic.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1952 and 1960</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Rivers</ENAMEX>, then in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">twenties</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Londoner</ENAMEX> by birth, was in charge of
the boating-lake at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodrington</ENAMEX>, a district of Paignton
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Devon</ENAMEX>, now part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torbay</ENAMEX>.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1955</TIMEX>
or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivers</ENAMEX> saw among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> a tiny
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> with beady eyes, a pointed nose and a ruddy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weatherbeaten</ENAMEX>, pinched-up face.  He was so struck by
her appearance that he observed to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> that
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was like a little grockle.  His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>,
not surprisingly, replied, What the hell's a grockle?
Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivers</ENAMEX> explained that he had been reminded of a
figure from a picture serial he had once read, called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grockle</ENAMEX> .  The grockle was a small dragonlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> with magic powers.  Mr rivers tells
me that he could not recall the name of the comic,
when he had seen it, and even whether it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
or an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> import.

            The old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> equally diminutive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Country</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> regularly visited the boating-lake during their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> took a fancy to the expression Mr
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivers</ENAMEX> had used and would say things like Your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grockle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s here and so on.  The term survived
the departure of the originals and was soon consciously
adopted for all the holidaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX>, mainly
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midlands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>, by the large number of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at the lake.  Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie Fly</ENAMEX>, wrote an Ode to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grockle</ENAMEX> and the
coaches bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> were christened grockle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wagons</ENAMEX> .  Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivers</ENAMEX> has emphasized to me that the
word was not then used in a disparaging way, but
more as a kind of professional in-joke, with about the
same force as the now universal punter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>,
part of the verbal comaraderie of a lively band
of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            The word became current among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of
the boating-lake's local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and outlasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>
to be acquired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> by other holiday trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
the area, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paignton</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Carter</ENAMEX>.  In an article in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Torbay</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald Express</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1993</TIMEX>), he remembered hearing
grockle for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX> when working
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodrington</ENAMEX> promenade.  From there it
would inevitably spread to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paignton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torquay</ENAMEX>, the
towns which, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brixham</ENAMEX>, now make up Torbay.

            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie Fly</ENAMEX> had become a
barman at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brixham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> and there met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Draper</ENAMEX>, who was working on a screenplay for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flim</ENAMEX> based on the adventures of seasonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in
the holiday industry.  He picked up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie Fly</ENAMEX>'s use
of grockle to add authenticity to his script.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flim</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">starring Oliver Reed</ENAMEX>, was released in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The System â</ENAMEX>€” the system being one to pull
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds â€”</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Girl-Getters</ENAMEX> , a more
explicit rendering of the same idea.  This was the first
national publicity for the hitherto local expression,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> citation of grockle is, in fact, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flims & Fliming</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 October 1964</TIMEX>, extracted from a
review of what is presumably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The System</ENAMEX> .

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Books</ENAMEX> published a halfcrown
paperback novelization by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Burke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Draper</ENAMEX>'s screenplay.  The text contained the film's extended
dialogue explanation of grockle (including
grockle-comforter for transistor raido and grocklebox
for cheap camera) as well as its other passing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">references</ENAMEX>, but added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about fifteen</NUMEX> more in the narrative,
with an example between quotation marks in
the back-cover blurb.  It may be that in pre-video
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days these</TIMEX> appearances in print, after the film had
ended its run in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>, played a part in the
spread of the expression during the res of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>.

            The word was certainly hard to escape in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Torbay</ENAMEX> area in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>, and by then often had
a derisive flavour, as friction increased between young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> and young <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.  Hence Look at
those bloody grockles! from some trawlerman was
my own first encounter with it as I took a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> round <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brixham</ENAMEX>.  Stickers reading Nongrockle
could sometimes be seen in the rear windows
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> as an assertion of local identity.  The word had
also spawned more extensions, like grock-trap shop
selling tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sovenirs</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1986</TIMEX> (the last of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX>'s citations) also gives
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">grockle fodder fish</ENAMEX> and chips, grockle bait tourist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">souvenirs</ENAMEX>, and grockle nests <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp sites</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Rivers</ENAMEX>, who had become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Paignton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>, took part in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Four</ENAMEX> programme
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Draper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Carter</ENAMEX>, and an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>.  At the end, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX>
handed Mr Rivers a photocopy from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> issue of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dandy</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s comic.  The
page heading was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">His Grockle</ENAMEX> , so Mr
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivers</ENAMEX> was able to validate and localize the memory
that had floated to the surface of his mind in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX>
1950s.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grockle</ENAMEX> turned out to be onomatopoeic, being
all the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dragon</ENAMEX> ever said.

            The first number of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dandy</ENAMEX> , published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Thomson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dundee</ENAMEX>, was dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 December 1937</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Rivers</ENAMEX> would have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX>.  However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grockle</ENAMEX> had
started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX> as a conventional serial story in another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rover</ENAMEX> , before
being tracslated into picture strip form in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>.
It ran again in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C. Thomson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sparky</ENAMEX> from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966 to 1976</TIMEX>.

            Perhaps it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The System</ENAMEX> that helped grockle
to beome so far-flung and win out over the allegedly
more vivid but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> still <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cornwall</ENAMEX>-confined emmet .
But I personally would speculate that the unknown
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jimmy</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grockle</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1930s</TIMEX>
keew the sort of word that resonates in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX>.  Could a further reason for the word's success
be that it rhymes with the name of a kind of edible
molluse that is a traditional feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
seaside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX>?  It clearly seems to have appealed to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of some verses in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shooting Times</ENAMEX> &
Country Magazine for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 August 1975</TIMEX> â€” not spotted
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> â€” which ran in part:



There are the like in other lands,
But here they call them grockles
And feed them on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> sands
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice-cream</ENAMEX> and rock and cockles.
            
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latter-day English</ENAMEX>



            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Smith</ENAMEX> announced to the world in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 19th century</TIMEX> that he had seen God, and gave
to the world his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Golden Bible</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book of Mormon</ENAMEX>) , he
certainly introduced some radical new theologh.  However,
as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>, presecuted and harried out of the estern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> to the godforsaken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wastes</ENAMEX> of what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, then
proceeded in build <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zion</ENAMEX> as they made the desert bloom,
they and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> have also contributed some
unique words to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language (or, in some cases,
some unique twists on existing words).

            A full exposition of strictly doctrinal terms is beyond
the scope of this article because such a listing would entail
a detailed examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX> doctrine.  Speaking of
Mormon doctrine, the term, used as a general-purpose
noun, adjective, and adverb, as an unofficial designation for
and comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book of Mormon</ENAMEX> , a book
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Smith</ENAMEX> claims to have translated from gold
plates goven to him by an angle.  The book claims to be a
parallel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, but pertaining to the New World, and
relates the religious history of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Talking about the book in a scholarly way in somewhat
like discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolkien</ENAMEX>'s works, which also contain a richly
developed cultural world.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tolkien</ENAMEX>'s case it is self-evident
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rings</ENAMEX> trilogy is a work of fiction, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-Moromons</ENAMEX> would probably assign the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX> to the same category; but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormons</ENAMEX> take
its truth seriously (whether strictly historical on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one end of</TIMEX>
a spectrum to mythologically symbolic on the other end),
albeit of faith.  This is by way of pointing out that Mormon
was the name of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the book, and it was
named after him, although he did not write the whole
book.

            Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormon</ENAMEX> was historical figure or a fictional
Character is a matter of faith, but many of the
names in the book do have roots in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Near Estern</ENAMEX> languages,
for whatever reason.  Several of the personal
names in the book are popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' names amongst
Mormon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>; especially popular are Jared
(which is also the name of an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Biblical personage</ENAMEX>,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Mormon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> has a far
greater profile), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helaman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nephi</ENAMEX> .  Current place
names in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> that come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Mormon</ENAMEX> include:
Bountiful, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehi, Nephi, Manti, Moroni</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deseret</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, not the territory).  There are numerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical</ENAMEX> names as well: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goshen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ephraim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zion National Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Carmel</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moab</ENAMEX> , as well as places named after
early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brigham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grantsville</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heber City</ENAMEX> and others.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan River</ENAMEX> is so called
because the geography of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> resembles that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Utah</ENAMEX> drains via the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan River</ENAMEX> into the
Great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>, just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX> drains via the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan River</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">salty Dead Sea</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old World</ENAMEX> Zion
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World Zion</ENAMEX> are thus mirror images of each
other.  The names of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Fork</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish Fork</ENAMEX> bear special mention because of a peculiarity
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> pronunciation especially rural pronunciation:
locally these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> are known as American Fark
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish Fark</ENAMEX>, respectively.

            An intriguing example of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Mormon</ENAMEX> place
name is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert</ENAMEX> , which was a very popular name in Mormondom
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> was not allowed to
enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> until long after it had achieved the minimum
requirements for statehood (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896</TIMEX>) because
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> at the time abhorred the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mormon</ENAMEX> practice of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polygamy</ENAMEX> (called plural marriage in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latter-day English</ENAMEX>).
Having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was all right: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentiles</ENAMEX> (nonMormons)
just disapproved of having them all at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>!  Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentiles</ENAMEX> , there is a story (perhaps apocryphal)
that the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> and archaeologist,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yigael Yadin</ENAMEX>, once prefaced a speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> with the observation, You know, this is probably the
only place I can come and be a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gentile</ENAMEX>!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> that preceded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
(named after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ute Indians</ENAMEX>) was called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Territory</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert</ENAMEX> .  It is a term for the promised land in the
Book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX> and is supposed to mean land of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">honeybee</ENAMEX>.  It has been speculated that the word is related
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dâ</ENAMEX>€rt , a term for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Crown</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Upper Egypt</ENAMEX>, whose emblem was the bee.  In the 19th
century these was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deseret Industries</ENAMEX> .  The hive is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and appears on its coat-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert</ENAMEX> covered an area much larger
than the modern-day state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>: parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idoho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
were all part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time.  A non-contiguous
part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mormon Country</ENAMEX> , an
area of southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, which was settled by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormons</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marshals</ENAMEX> looking for polygamists).

            Several doctrinal terms bear mentioning.  Mormons
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">or Latter-day Saints</ENAMEX> , as well call ourselves-not out of a
sense of spiritual superiority, it is to be hoped, but because
of a reference of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Paul's</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> being called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX>) have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic types of
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>: chapels and temples and they are as different
as synogogues and temples are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>.  A chapel
is a meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, but the area of assembly for worship
withinthe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chapel building</ENAMEX> is alson called a chapel .
Traditionally there is also a cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> , which serves as
everything from an overflow for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX>, a basketball
court, an area for dramatic and musical productions, and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding receptions</TIMEX>.  The main <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> meeting
â€” the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass â</ENAMEX>€” is called sacrament
meeting , sacrament in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mormon</ENAMEX> sense being
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> specific sacrament only: what other christians called
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX>.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where, as a rule, no
meetings are held but where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormons</ENAMEX> go for certain ceremonies,
including vicarious ordinances (ordinances on be
half of one's ancestors), for celestial marriages (technically,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">celestial</ENAMEX> marriage is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of marriage that extends
past death, as generally understood, and the wedding
ceremony itself is called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> marriage ), and a
place where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> receives one's endowment .  An endowment
in this case is a ceremony at which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ritualizes
one's place in the universe, both with respect to God and
with respect to one's extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.  There are also tabernacles ,
which are large meeting places for special-purpose
meetings-the best-known one is; of course, the tabernacle
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormon Tabernacle Choir</ENAMEX> is based, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square</ENAMEX> , in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Smith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young</ENAMEX>,
founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert/Utah</ENAMEX>, he sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> out to places as far
away as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colonia Juarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alberta</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, and all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>,
Idoho, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>.  All of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> were set
up in the same way, with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> wide enough to ensure a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of oxen could turn around.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> were organized
politically in a way presious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mormon colonies</ENAMEX> in
the estern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirtland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nauvoo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>)
were, into stakes and words .  The image of the stake comes
from the stakes used to hold up the tabernacle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old</ENAMEX>
Testament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it corresponds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> to a diocese,
and is a collection of words.  The word started out as a political
subdivision, just like wards in most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, but became the equivalent of a parish.  Stakes are
headed by a stake <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> , a volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> (there is no
professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX>), and wards are headed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> .

            All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> from twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years of age</TIMEX> are eligible to
hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">priesthood ant</ENAMEX> it is this semi-universal priesthood
that governs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> (with participation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
some administrative roles, but outside the context of the
priesthood itself) and conducts its rituals.  The priesthood
is divided into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aaronic Priesthood</ENAMEX> , for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
from twelve to eighteen, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Melchizedek</ENAMEX> Priesthood
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult males</ENAMEX>.  Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> is divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>:
Decons are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-13</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teachers</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14-15</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Priest</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16-17</NUMEX>;
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melchizedek Priesthood</ENAMEX> is divided horizontally
into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elders</ENAMEX> (you might have met some awfully
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yound Elders</ENAMEX> on your doorstep... ), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seventies</ENAMEX> , and
high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Priests</ENAMEX> .  The imagery comes from the time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> went up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Sinai</ENAMEX>, leaving a group of seventy at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point and the edlers of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> behind them.  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Moses</ENAMEX>
himself was, of course, the high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>.

            Slang terms, unofficial terms and humour abounds
within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormondom</ENAMEX>.  The humour column of an unofficial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scholarly</ENAMEX> publication, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunstone</ENAMEX> , in called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Oxymormons</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> are referred to institutionally as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief Society</ENAMEX> ,
after the name of their auxiliary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> (founded by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Smith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX>, it claims to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s oldest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>).  To hold the priesthood is a euphemism
for any sort of physical affection displayed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women towards men</ENAMEX> (since all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, at least in principle,
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the priesthood); the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Word of Wisdom</ENAMEX> is a
reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormons</ENAMEX>' dietary laws (which prohibit smoking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and caffeine-containing hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>);
Primary is a reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> up to the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
(as with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief Society</ENAMEX>, this is an example of the name
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> being extended generally to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormonism</ENAMEX> has a relatively well-defined theology,
but even in such a centralized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of thought there is
bound to be a specturm of beliefs and social attitudes.
What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentiles</ENAMEX> would call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and called liahonas by
Mormons, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are called iron-rodders ,
both terms coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Mormon</ENAMEX> images.

            And finally, what about splinter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, without which
no self-respecting religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> would be complete?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mormons</ENAMEX> who do not practice their religion are called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mormons</ENAMEX> , the largest schismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, The
(note the difference in spelling of latter-day) who did not
follow what they call the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> Mormons out west, but
stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, are called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reorganites</ENAMEX> , and although
Mormons have their share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX>, to call
someone a fundamentalist in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mormondom</ENAMEX> is to accuse
him of being a closet polygamist.  The practice of polygamy
was outlawed just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>, but
polygamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> persist down to the present day.  One
has to admit, these terms represent an improvement over
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> term that used to be applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missourians</ENAMEX> during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of persecution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19th century</TIMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> still had an official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX> extermination
order on its books until someone discovered it in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archives</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>): they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">affectionat4ely</NUMEX> known as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pukes</ENAMEX> .
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meaning of Murder</ENAMEX>



            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussien</ENAMEX>
cheered when <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SCUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> fell on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, calling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> for having bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>.
At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, who had
cheered when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> for bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>.
Both sides agreed on what they meant by the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">murderer</ENAMEX> , mut they made opposite judgments as to
whom it applied and why.  How is that possible and
what does it tell us about how language works?

            
               Murder differs from kill in involving the notion of
justification.  To say that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> kills another is to
say that the first deprives the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of life; but to say
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> murders another is to say the depriving is
unjustified.  This raises the questions, What does justified
mean and How does one justify judgments about it?

            
               Justified falls among a class of words that also includes
what linguists call modals ; the most notable of
these are must, should , and can .  Despite their apparent
definiteness, the meanings of such words involve
an element of indeterminacy that someewhat
resembles ambiguity.

            
               Must assets that there are laws and facts that
jointly necessitate some occurrence, either already
completed or yet to be brought about, without specifying
exactly what those laws and facts are.  For example,
the context in which sentence (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) originally
appears makes it clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> intends it to express
a historical necessity already in place, based on
the law that time moves forward and on the fact that
a lot of time has passed.



(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)  Although precise figures must remain elusive,
according to the best current estimates a total of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 to 11 million</NUMEX> living slaves crossed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean</ENAMEX> from the sixteenth through the nineteenth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>.

[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolchin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Slavery</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1619-1877</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.]
            

            However, the sentence could just as well have
appeared in a government report expressing an admonition
to keep the numbers secret, based on the
fact that numbers of such magnitude would anger the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slaves</ENAMEX>' descendents and on an assumed law to the effect
that sufficient provocation caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>.
Neither must itself nor the sentence as a whole provides
the slightest clue as to which of these inter pretation
is intended.  Only the context makes that clear.

            
               Should means the same as must , except that it
leaves room for loopholes that avoid the asserted necessity
in new or unusual circumstances.  For example,
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) progvide ways around the necessities
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)  asserts, on its reprective historical and admonitory
interpretations.



(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)  Although precise figures should remain elusive
(under normal circumstances), major new discoveries
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave-holders</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and artifacts
will enable us to compute exact totals.

(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)  Although precise figures should remain elusive
(under normal circumstances), publishing the
figures in the current climate of suspicion will
clear the air, defuse anger, and enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
move on.
            

            
               Can is related to must in being what logicians
call its dual .  Whereas must says there are laws and
facts that necessitate some occurrence, can asserts
that whatever laws and facts there are, some occurrence
is permitted (or possible).  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> consequence of
this relation is the fact that though can and must have
very different meanings, cannot and must not are synonymous.
For example, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) has can where (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) has
must , but the meanings of their respective sentences
are the same.



(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larssen</ENAMEX>, you cannot let it get you down to
the point where it affects your work.  You can
not.

[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turtledove</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>: Tilting the
Balance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballantine</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.]

(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larssen</ENAMEX>, you must not let it get you down
to the point where it affects your work.  You
must not.
            

            Negating a sentence containing must keep the
necessity claim intact, negating only the verb, whereas
negating a sentence containing can keep the verb intact,
negating only the permission (or possibility).  To
say x cannot v is to say x must not-v.  To say x can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v</ENAMEX> is to deny x must not-v.

            
               Justified is, in effect, a hybrid of must and can .
Like must , it asserts the existence of laws and facts,
but like can it expresses permission, rather than necessity.
To say that some action is justified is to say
there are laws and facts that permit it, whereas can expresses
permission for whatever laws and facts there
are.  To say that some action is not justified is to say
that the action is prohibited whatever the laws and
facts are.

            So to murder is to kill in a way that is prohibited
whatever the laws and facts are.  To deny that a killing
is murder is to claim there are laws and factsa that permit
it.  Those who cheered for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, instead
of calling him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>, based their judgment on
what they took to be a law regarding the sanctity of
national borders and on the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> had
violated such a border by invading a neighboring
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Thoses</ENAMEX> who cheered for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>,
instead of calling him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>, based their judgment
on a law regarding the sovereignty of national
government and on what they took to be the fact
that the borders his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> had crossed were imposed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonialists</ENAMEX> without the consent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>.

            
Obviously, none of this sheds any light at all on
which of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>, if either, was correct.  It does help
to explain how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can talk past each other, using
the same words in the same language expressing the
same meanings, but interpreting those meanings in
relation to very different frameworks of concepts, beliefs,
expectations, and values.
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kudirat Abiola</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>, was in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when she was shot
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close</NUMEX> range by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.  She died of
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> wounds <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours later</TIMEX>, as did her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX>.
[From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milwaukee Journal</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sentinel</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">, p. 10a.</ENAMEX>
Submitted by .]
         
         
            
The caretakers must be physically strong, and have
enough stamina to tote <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and supplies up hill, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">garbage</ENAMEX> down hill.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weedeating</ENAMEX> is mandatory.  [From the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Lighthouse Society Bulletin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">, p. 1</ENAMEX>.
Submitted by ]
         
         
            
The truth is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX> consists of...<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who have
fought and died in the western desert, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borneo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaya</ENAMEX>...
[From an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy McNab</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , .  Submitted by .]
         
         
            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Court</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Sunday Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apologised</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tengku Razaleigh Hamzah</ENAMEX>, the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of finance and now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
main opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, over an article published in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX> in which it was alledged that as a representative
of the then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, he had sought to
procure special payments from a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to
secure the continued progress of a construction project in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>.  In a further feature on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Malaysian Affair</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13, 1994</TIMEX>), the allegation was repeated and the article
further suggested that he might have had a corrupt connection
with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600m</NUMEX> banking fraud in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the
death of a bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> and the false imprisonment of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> as part of a cover-up.
         
         
            
...We now accept without reservation that the serious
allegations mentioned above should never have been
made and as stated in open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, apologise unreservedly
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tengku Razaleigh Hamzah</ENAMEX> for any distress
and embarrassment caused by the articles.  We have furthere
agreed to pay him a substaintial sum by way of compensation
and his costs and have undertaken not to repeat
the allegations.  [From The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">, p.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/21</NUMEX>.]
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staff of Life</ENAMEX>



            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travellers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">teh centuries</TIMEX> have always,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consciously</ENAMEX> or not, emphasized the deep division
existing between townsman and peasant, especially
reflected in the food eaten by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the other.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX>'s fare always consisted basically of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bread â€” V.S. Pritchett</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marching Spain</ENAMEX> , a journey
made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, seems to have eaten nothing between
towns but hard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and the occasional doubtful
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>; although paying for it, little else could be offered
him.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> themselves often had nothing but
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and coarse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>.  As the faced each
new day, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thought was survival for
himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another twenty-four hours</TIMEX>.
For them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> was life.  Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> popular
sayings grew up reflecting this obsession with that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> food, applied to the daily philosophy of life.
Passed from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, from hearthside to field
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tavern</ENAMEX>, losing a word here, gaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> there,
sometimes so badly pronounced as to change sound,
though not sense, the refrÃ¡in or saying having the almost
sacred pan <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> as its foundation came to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">form an integral part</ENAMEX> of country life.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanish Popular Saying</ENAMEX> or refrÃ¡n              
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Literal Meaning</ENAMEX>                    
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Approximate English</ENAMEX> Proverb
               
                                                                                                                                
                  equivalent
               
               
                  MÃ¡s bueno que <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">el pan                          Better</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>                              As good as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>)
                                                                                                                                To be kindness itself (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>)
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Guardar pan para mayo y le</ENAMEX> para                      To put aside <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and wood            To look at both side of a panny
               
                  abril                                                for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
               
                  Coger a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uno con las</ENAMEX> manos en la masa                 To catch someone with his hands in the         To be caught in the act
                                                                                 dough
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al pan, y al</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vino</ENAMEX>, vino                              To <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, wine              To call a spade a spade
               
                  Amasando se hace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el pan                              Kneading</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>                           All things come to those who wait
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tan</ENAMEX> buen pan hacen aqui como en                      As good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is made here as in               There are as good fish in the sea as
               
                  Francia                                              <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>                                         ever came out of it
               
                  Con pan y queso nadie se pone obeso                  Nobody gets fat on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>            Too much of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing is good for
                                                                                                                                nothing
               
                  Quien con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hambre</ENAMEX> se acuesta con pan                  Whoever goes to bed hungry dreams of           To have a bee in one's bonnet
               
                  sueÃ±a                                         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>
               
                  Quien con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hambre</ENAMEX> se acuesta con pan sueÃ±a     Whoever is hungry dreams of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>              Same as above
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Quien</ENAMEX> do pan a perro ajeno, pierde <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el                Whoever</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> to an unknown              <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land</ENAMEX> and lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">â</NUMEX>€” so play fools
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pan y el</ENAMEX> perro                                       <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> loses <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and dog
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>, pan, muchos lo <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toman y pocos lo                 Bread</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, many take it, few give it        Charity begins at home
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dan</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  Por dinero baila <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el</ENAMEX> can, y por pan, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">si se            The dog</ENAMEX> dances for money and for               <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Needs</ENAMEX> must when the devid drives and
               
               
                  lo <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dan                                               bread</ENAMEX> if given it                              Money talks
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> vida <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">es la candela; pan y vino la              Half</ENAMEX> of life is fire; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> the       Count your blessing
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">otra</ENAMEX> media                                           other half
               
                  Mucho te quiero, perrito, pero pan                   I love you well, little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, but with little   A long tongue is a sign of a short hand
               
                  poquito                                              <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>
               
                  No <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> vida <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">como la del pobre</ENAMEX>,                       There is no life like the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s who       The greatest wealth is contentment
               
                  teniendo pan que <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">le</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sobre</ENAMEX>                            has too much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>                             with a little
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX> con pan, comida de tontos                        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bread</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for fools               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> is the spice of life
               
                  Nunca buen pan de mala harina                        Never good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> from bad flour                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill</ENAMEX> beef ne'er made good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">broth</ENAMEX>
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bien</ENAMEX> sÃ© lo que dogo cuando pan pido           I well know what I say when I ask for          Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is best known to himself
                                                                                 <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bread</ENAMEX>
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El</ENAMEX> pobre que pide pan, carne toma si se              The poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> asking for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> will             They that have no other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lo dan</ENAMEX>                                               take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> if it is given                       and butt are glad to eat
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Desde los tiempos de AdÃ¡n</ENAMEX>, unos recogen       Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, some gather the             Some reap what others have sown
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">el</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">trigo y otros se comen el pan                     wheat</ENAMEX> and others eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX> ajeno ilunca <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es</ENAMEX> tierno                           Another's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is never fresh                 Envy never enriched any man
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX> ajeno caro cuesta                                Another's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> costs dear                     Another's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> costs dear
               
                  Agua <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fria y pan caliente</ENAMEX>, nunca                      Cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> never made a          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Oil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> never mix
               
                  hicieron buen vientre                                good belly
               
                  A pan dure, diente agudo                             To hard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> a sharp tooth                    Necessity is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of invention
               
                  Abuen hambre no <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay pan duro ni</ENAMEX>                      To a good hunger no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is hard nor          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beggars</ENAMEX> can't be choosers or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunger</ENAMEX> is
               
                  falta salsa ninguna                                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> is needed                                the best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>
               
                  A buen hambre no hay pan duro                        To a sharp hunger no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is hard             Hunger is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> of many
               
                  Para viuda hambriento no hay pan                     For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> and the hungry no                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunger</ENAMEX> finds no fault with the cooking
               
                  duro                                                 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is hard
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX> no mÃ­o me quitta <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">el hastÃ­o         Bread</ENAMEX> that isn't mine takes away               He that serves everybody is paid by
                                                                                 bordeom                                        nobody
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Eso es pan para hoy y hambre</ENAMEX> para                    This is <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and hunder for         A short-sighted policy
               
                  maÃ±ana                                        tomorrow
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX> tierno <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">y leÃ±a verde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">las casa pierde      Fresh bread</ENAMEX> and green firewood lose            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> wrongs don't make a right
                                                                                 the house
               
                  Contigo pan y cabolla                                With you, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and onion                      Love will find a way
               
                  Can pan <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">y vino se anda el camino</ENAMEX>                     With <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> the way is walked          A full stomach makes short work
               
                  A falta de pan, buenas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> tortas                    When <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is lacking, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pancakes</ENAMEX> are            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half</NUMEX> a loaf is better than none
                                                                                 good
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Los</ENAMEX> muchos <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hijos y el poca pan enseÃ±an</ENAMEX>        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> teach           Cut your coat accoring to your cloth
               
                  a remendar                                           mending
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Es un</ENAMEX> pedazo de pan                                  He/she/you is/are a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>             A good person
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ganarse el</ENAMEX> pan                                       To earn the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>                              To be the breadwinner
               
                  Con su pan se lo coma !                               May he eat it with it with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>!              Good luck to him/her/you!
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El pan</ENAMEX> nuestro de cade dia                           Our everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>                             Our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>
               
                  Es pan comido                                        It is eaten <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>                              It's as easy as pie
               
                  Por un mendrugo de pan                               For a scrap of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>                           For a bite of eat
               
                  Repartirse como el pan bendito                       To distribute like holy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>                  To sell like hotcakes
               
                  No <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es</ENAMEX> lo mismo predicar que dar pan                  It is not the same to preach as to give        Actions speak louder than words
                                                                                 <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bread</ENAMEX>
               
                  Estar a pan y agua                                   To be on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and water                       To be on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and water
               
                  No solo <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">del pan vive el hombre</ENAMEX>                       Not only of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> does <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> live                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> does not live by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> alone
            
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fo Er Si Guo Er and The Cross-Eyed Bear</ENAMEX> (or: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OfOronyms</ENAMEX> and Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literary Trompes l'Oeil/Oreille</ENAMEX>)




            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singlish</ENAMEX>.  Sort of (but not really) single?  Contemplating
marriage or divorce?  Actually Singlish
has nothing to do with one's marital status.  It is the
system of writing that the victorious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> wanted
to impose on the defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealanders</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>,
forcing them to abandon <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> letters and use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
logographs as phonetic equivalents of English words
instead.  As a foretaste of things to come to committee
responsible for implementing this innovation proffered
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singlish</ENAMEX> rendition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>
Address: (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of er si guo er</ENAMEX>) Four score...

            Obviously, this plan never got off the ground.  How
could it?  Historical facts aside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Singlish Affair</ENAMEX>
is the brain-child of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John DeFrancis</ENAMEX> ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
Language, Fact and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fantasy</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), a
parodying bulesque pointing up certain features of languages
in general and of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> in particular.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Languages</ENAMEX>, though glibly spoken and written, often present
formidable problems of perception, both visual
and aural.  Thus fo <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">er si guo er</ENAMEX> , to all appearances
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, is actually pseudo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> nonsense.  Only
when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> realize its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Singlish â€”</ENAMEX> that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> masquerading
as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese â€”</ENAMEX> does it become intelligible.
