
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Insulting Nicknames Give Journalists Something to Be Proud of</ENAMEX>




            Raffish louts, cigar-sucking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who wear their
hats indoors, chain-smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with
voices like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rusty gates</ENAMEX>, cynical muckrakers with one
eye poised on the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">keyhole</ENAMEX>, one ear on the
latest whispered gossip, one nose on the nearest free
lunch.  In short, news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            Or, earnest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> fresh from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>,
technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> on the cusp between computer
games and the Internet, dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of society
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protectors</ENAMEX> of truth, middle-class guardians
of all that is good and nice, power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> and culture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">groupies</ENAMEX> urgently seeking out the newest trend so
they can play hipper-than-thou at the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> it.  In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>.

            Take your pick.  But if you're in the modern
newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX>, you are more likely to encounter
the latter than the former.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpeted</ENAMEX>, air-conditioned,
ergonometrically designed office decor
discourages floor spitting.  Computer technology
discourages smoking, advances in interpersonal sensitivity
discourage profanity or even loudness, enlightenment
in personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> discourages
the proverbial <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX> in the lower
desk drawer.

            From time to time, mind you, someone spills a
cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocoa</ENAMEX> onto the keyboard of a workstation and
utters something untoward.  In the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX>,
it stands to replace the legendary shout of
Stop the presses!  But this is not to say that newspapers
do not maintain refreshingly cynical traditions--if
quietly.  It if still dangerous to invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
to free lunches.  And with notes of pride,
those rags that have earned pejorative names in the
local lore use those sobriquets in private correspondence,
saloon chat, and unofficial <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">r√©sum√©s</ENAMEX>.  No other
profession has so rich a tradition of self-deprecation.
Newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have no self-respect, and they're
proud of it.

            Some nicknames are promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, of
course, though for other reasons.  It may be a sop for
the few remaining grizzled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, sweating out
their pensions in the corners of the world's city
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> at papers taken over by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perrier</ENAMEX>-quaffing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>.
Where once reputations rose and fell on the
ability to jump a fence in the stormy dark, now
something called a performance review scores
their affability in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> meetings.  It isn't lost
on these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> that with respectability came vast
declines in newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>.  That, and insulting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nicknames</ENAMEX>, are all that is left of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>'
pride.

            So there is no danger that these names, no matter
how vigorously opposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> marketing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>, will pass from use.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton Daily News</ENAMEX>?  No, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton Barely</ENAMEX>
News.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Gazette</ENAMEX>?  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Guess</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At</NUMEX>-It.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Slimes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>).

The defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Journal</ENAMEX> was an attempt
to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-styled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-paper tabloid
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">journalism to the City of Brotherly Shove--er</ENAMEX>,
Love.  It did not go over and became known as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Urinal</ENAMEX>.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grauniad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>: the pejorative is said to
reflect something wrong with its proofreading).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Screws</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indescribablyboring</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>).

            

            Journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> readers
are not exempt from the cynicism.  Consider the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Florida's Independent Florida</ENAMEX> Aggravator
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alligator</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U. of F.</ENAMEX> mascot); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Tech</ENAMEX>'s
Dependent (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>) ; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX>'
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illiterate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illini</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina State U.</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tackynician</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technician</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North Carolina</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tar Hole</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tar Heel</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dime-a-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stack</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamondback</ENAMEX>; in fact they're
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">free</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Methodist University's Daily</ENAMEX> Compost
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Post</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> Thrasher
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice Thresher</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State University</ENAMEX>'s Latrine
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lantern</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilariat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lariat</ENAMEX>);
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan State University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stale News</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State News</ENAMEX>);
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX>'s Spotted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doily</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spartan</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Illinois U.'s Daily Erection</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX>);
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana U.'s Daily Stupid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX>) .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>, supports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The York Disgrace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch</ENAMEX>),
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">York Sunday Snooze</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>) , and the York
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wreckage</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Record</ENAMEX>) ...


The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurora Be Confused</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beacon News</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland Boregonian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregonian</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Jose Murky News</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury News</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Monica Evening Outrage</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Comical</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halifax Chronically Horrid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle-Herald</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara News</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suppress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News-Press</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio Excuse</ENAMEX>-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express-News</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Snooze</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Real Estatesman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statesman</ENAMEX>;
the pejorative reflects the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun Belt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> that has sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>' housing market
into a boom).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilfered Daily News</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>,
which may no longer deserve its reputation for
copying stories from other papers).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worcester Dullagram</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegram</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation Leak and Space Mythology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Technology</ENAMEX>: it isn't good at
guarding secrets).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orillia Racket and Crimes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packet and Times</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Sin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwall Standard Freeloader</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard-Freeholder</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kingston Substandard</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whig-Standard</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Sound Stun Crimes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Times</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington Horrible</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Terrible</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald-Telephone</ENAMEX>,
an arcane name from a time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana</ENAMEX> was impressed by telephones.  It is now
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald-Times</ENAMEX>.  Old timers recall when a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl</ENAMEX> Magazine
worked there and they could listen to her
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and saying, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl</ENAMEX>
Magazine at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald-Telephone</ENAMEX> ... no, the
newspaper, not the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> ... Magazine
... no, it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, it's a newspaper.
I'm Magazine ... hello?  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>?).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chattanooga News</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masthead</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News-Free Press</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Repulsive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Grope</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flail</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX>).

Green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Press-Gannett</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press-Gazette</ENAMEX>; it is one
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laramie Daily Boomerag</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boomerang</ENAMEX>, said to be
named after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s mule, but
some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> say it's because
when the newsboy tossed copies onto the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">porches</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> threw it back).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carbondale Southern Illusion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illioisan</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryan-College Station Buzzard</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Stun</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louisville Curious Jumble</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courier-Journal</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toledo Bland</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blade</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bend Bullshit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulletin; Oregonians</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">westerners</ENAMEX>' tradition, are frank).

West <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester Lack</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Chester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>,
Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntington Herald Disgrace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald Dispatch</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston Daily Snail</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Bay Brays</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breeze</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangor Daily Snooze</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portland Pressed Herring</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press Herald</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego Onion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albuquerque Urinal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte Disturber</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX>).

Busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christiansburg News Mess</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Press</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redding Wretched Flashlight</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Record Searchlight</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Son</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>, a dynastic ownership situation).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saskatoon Star Kleenex</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Star Phoenix</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Houston Pest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orlando Slantinel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sentinel</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Euphoria Gazelle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emporia Gazette</ENAMEX>, but its
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in the flower-child era of the 1960s
settled on something more melodious).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay Bimbos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Windows</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
newspaper serving homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fitchburg</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leominster Emptyprize</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Useless News & World Distort</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chesterton Ribtoon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Wayne News Senile</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sentinel</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlottesville Regress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent Wretched Courier</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Record Courier</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh News Gets Absurder</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & Observer</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester Demagogue & Comical</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus Distort</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dover</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Philadelphia Times</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Distorter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times-Reporter</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springfield Nuisance</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Manurian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missourian</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manassas Messy Journal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal Messenger</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omaha Weird Harold</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Herald</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco Tribulation-Herald</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune-Herald</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Escondido Times-Adequate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times-Advocate</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Rosa Depressed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Press Democrat</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Glob</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Hairball</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>, but a newspaper given
to coughing up scandal and sin).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Crimes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timeses</ENAMEX> are
Slimeses, but important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
were delighted when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> administration
arms merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> called it the
Crimes, so it stuck).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia Inky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquirer</ENAMEX>, as opposed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati Inky</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati Conspirer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>, when it's not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inky</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsdaze</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Startlegram</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star-Telegram</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan Turkey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canton Suppository</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repository</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placerville Mountain Democrap</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gripes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stars and Stripes</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Orleans Times</ENAMEX>-Picka-You-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nose</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times-Picayune</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis Post-Disgrace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Dispatch</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Horrid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sioux Falls Argus Liar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte Disturber</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Bedford Substandard</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard-Times</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boulder Daily Chimera</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camera</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Haven Rag</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Springs Desperate Sun</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Sun</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPaper</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>; some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX> consider it
somewhat overdesigned, overmarketed, and
occasionally arch).

            
         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PULL TO RIGHT WHEN FLASHING [Road</ENAMEX> sign on highway
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>.  Submitted by ,
who reports that no light is visible in the vicinity of the sign.]

         
         
            
Due to the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> and is
responding poorly to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> will be taken immediately
to the operating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where exploratory laparotomy
will be done.  [From a  hospital chart
review.  Submitted by  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologist</ENAMEX>.]

         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Endearment Elucidation</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love By Any Other Name</ENAMEX>




            A news item published in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> national
newspaper in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February, 1995</TIMEX>, gave details of a
ban applied to a northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> city council's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">telephonists</ENAMEX> working in the environmental services
department by a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, stating the telephonists
should no longer add the endearment luv
while greeting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Mayor</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, was forthright in her condemnation
of the ban as petty.  She said the word
would stay firmly in her vocabulary and added:  I
use the word all the time.  When I come into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Hall I</ENAMEX> say Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, luv to whomever I
meet, from the cleaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.  To ban
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luv</ENAMEX> would be like stopping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Geordies</ENAMEX> using the
term pet and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nottingham</ENAMEX> folk addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as
duck.  My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire miner</ENAMEX> and he addressed
folk as old luv whether they were young or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>.  Its a term of endearment and a word we have
used for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            This situation brings to public notice what
words are used as terms of endearment in direct address
between the sexes, more so a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
Some examples, however, are not quite what they
seem.  It is more than likely that at least some of the
male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> using them are innocently unaware of
the true meaning of a word or words they perhaps
use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>.  The word or words so used may not suit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being addressed, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> or anatomical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">description</ENAMEX>, but, fortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> thus
spoken to may also be equally unaware.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweetheart</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words, known to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaucer</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troylus</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1374</TIMEX>), as swete herte and in general can
now logically be accurate in statements: Yes, I
know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX> , when applied to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with
whom one is in love, be she girl <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or a
female who by her actions and looks sweetens the
affection in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s heart.  However, a previous
meaning is given in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of the Vulgar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tongue</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1796</TIMEX>): sweet heart, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>.  Not quite the same thing, the OED
takes this further as one who is loved illicitly, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paramour</ENAMEX>.  Few married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweethearts</ENAMEX> will consider
they are loved illicitly as a paramour or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>!
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweetie</ENAMEX> or sweety is a short corruption of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX>,
being in this sense a lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, a sweetie, or a
willing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in certain situations: Be a sweetie
and fetch me the mail.  Sweet was also used as dear,
Yes, my sweet?  I will do so, my sweet.  That other
sweet commodity, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, got itself associated with
endearments for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with combinations, as sugar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar babe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar pie</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> is still often used in endearing address, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">slang</ENAMEX> chiefly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, for a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> or girl
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, as in (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, babe .

            
               Honey fits here into an endearment classification,
perhaps also used more in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>,
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> equivalent is darling.  Yes, I
agree, honey‚Äù Yes, I agree, darling .  Formerly, it
was chiefly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX>, used in the form
of hinnie, hinney , but back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1386</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chaucer</ENAMEX>, in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tale wrote of Alisoun</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey deare</ENAMEX>.
As with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> there are also honey-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, honey
bunch, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey bun</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Dear is very, very common in use and overheard
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> in many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>, or shopping center
conversations.  It was formerly applied to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had an endearing personality, who was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beloved</ENAMEX>, esteemed, a person on whom to lavish affection,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s cherished dear.  But do they always
mean this when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> uses it now?  Or is it, as
seems to be, often said Yes, dear.  No, dear, to
obtain uncontradictory agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>?

            Now, as dear, darling is in common use by anybody
for anyone: Yes, I know, darling, it is such a
bore.  It is also used in the same context as sweetie:
Be a darling and fetch me the mail.  A darling was
a young, lovable, charming, usually young, woman
who was admired and desired, prized among eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was (supposedly) of good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">morals</ENAMEX>, thus chaste and a good catch to woo and
win as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dearing</ENAMEX> and dearling are both forms
of darling, but much less often heard nowadays.

            
               Popsy, popsie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popsy-wopsy</ENAMEX> may sound North
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> in origin because of their use in radio and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">music-hall</ENAMEX> songs, but they are much older than that.
Popsies date back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1862</TIMEX> as an endearing designation:
 Popsy have you seen my toothbrush?  and,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> is a kind of running extension
of pop , an endearing appellation for a girl
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, a casual female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">acquaintance</ENAMEX>.
 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX>, have you seen my toothbrush does not have
the same endearment to it somehow, possibly because
of its use as a term of address for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or an
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.  It is also possible they are a corruption of
poppet, poppit, poppette, poopet, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">poupette</ENAMEX> doll, an endearment still used though ancient,
poppet being the name for a pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or
a dainty young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.  Just a minute, poppet, and I
will mend it.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1386</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chaucer</ENAMEX>, in Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thopas</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>: This were a popet ....  For any womman
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smal</ENAMEX> and fayre of face.

            Yes, my precious is a term of endearment occasionally
used, precious being from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old French</ENAMEX>
precios, precieus valuable, having a high price and a
beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> held very dear.  When applied to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> could this be what the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> means when it
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>: A good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is above rubies?

            As a term of endearment girlie and girly are in
the same category as popsy: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girlie</ENAMEX>, have you seen
my toothbrush?  in the sense of being less often
heard, although it goes back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>.  A
reference to it is in a book, The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX> and Craftsman
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>), which has a mysterious comment: The little
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> clad girlies ran off to hide themselves.  With
tongue in cheek I am tempted to suggest this may be
the origin of the name for certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> that
feature <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-clad and nude young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and known
now as girlie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Geordies</ENAMEX> do use pet as an endearment for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX>: I won't forget, pet, also in
more general terms in conversing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of all
ages.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pet</ENAMEX> is a name for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> treated with special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kindness</ENAMEX>, indulged as a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> possibly had something similar in mind for
his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1755</TIMEX>), when he classified  peat , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">darling</ENAMEX>, a little fondling, a dear plaything.

            
               Duck, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nottinghamshire</ENAMEX> and elsewhere in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, seems an odd word to use as an expression of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affection</ENAMEX>.  However, it has been around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>,
too.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1590</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> used it in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Midsummer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night's Dream</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">v. i 282</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> dainty ducke, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deere</ENAMEX>.  Duck, sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX>, tended to be used
by older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, sometimes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of casual acquaintance, such as a barmaid or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">waitress</ENAMEX>.  Duckie, duckey, ducky is a diminutive of
duck.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is used occasionally in affected, familiar
speech: Yes, I know, duckie, exactly how you
felt, here being in place of dear or darling .  A
sweet, pretty affectionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> or young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was
said to be duckie.
            

            So we come back to where we started, with luv
and love.  It has had a varied history.  Originally a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX> was only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, the love of the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> burial records often contain entries
as paid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stokeley</ENAMEX>'s love <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two pence</NUMEX>.  A
later use was for an attractive, lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, then in
another context as a paramour, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">par</ENAMEX> amour by love, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of passion.  Then it
came into general use, as it still is, for a beloved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, in particular a sweetheart, but also as a term
of endearing address to a casual acquaintance, as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady Lord Mayor</ENAMEX> of the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.

            There are, of course, many words used by men
in actual reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>, dolly ,
doll, tart, boot, plum, strumpet, jade, quean, and so
on.  Being a gentleman I wouldn't think or dare to
explain them here.
         
         
            Crossing




            Crossing language boundaries is not uncommon
in literature, the performing arts, or for that
matter in everyday speech.  There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of doing it.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Caesar</ENAMEX> used to
utter gibberish that sounded like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> or German
without meaning anything in any language.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> in such books as For Whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Man</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX> wrote some
dialogue in language that was phonetically English
but suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> by its simpler, more formal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grammar</ENAMEX>.

            More common, however, is the insertion into a
work in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> language the words, phrases, or passages
from another language.  In literature this kind of inclusion,
besides having snob value for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, lends authenticity.  These are the
very words; e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lama sabach</ENAMEX> thani?  (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">27.46</NUMEX>).  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> included some dialogue in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Act III</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scene V</ENAMEX>:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KATHE</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX>, tu as este en <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angleterre</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">et tu bien</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">parlas le Langage</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALICE</ENAMEX>.  En peu <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madame</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KATHE</ENAMEX>.  Ie te <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prie m ensigniez</ENAMEX>, il faut que ie apprend
a parlen: comient appelle vous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">le</ENAMEX> main en
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglois</ENAMEX>?

            

            (The errors in this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> dialogue as it appears in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Folio</ENAMEX>, some or all of which may be typos,
have been edited out of subsequent editions, such as
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annotated Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.L. Rowse</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolstoi</ENAMEX> introduced whole pages of impeccable
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> text of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> , as did
Goytisolo, for a more recent example, into his Se√±as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Identidad</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, perhaps because it is a language
of prestige, seems to be transplanted more
carefully than other modern languages.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ram√≥n J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sender</ENAMEX> has quotations in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> languages on the
frontispiece of his novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Tesis de Nancy</ENAMEX>:

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Es</ENAMEX> tarea de discretos hacer re√≠r.

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cervantes</ENAMEX>

Je me presse de rire de tout, de peur <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d'√</ENAMEX>™tre
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oblig√© d'en</ENAMEX> pleurer.

Beaumarchais

(So far, so good; but:)

Does thou laugh to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> are vexed?

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Dekker</ENAMEX>

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> generally fares rather poorly in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">texts</ENAMEX>, and vice versa.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezra Pound</ENAMEX>, for all his provincial pedantry, in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canto LXXXI</ENAMEX> as printed on p. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">526</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford Book of American Verse</ENAMEX>, writes didactically:


<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Hay aqu√≠ mucho catolicismo</ENAMEX> [pronounced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">catolithismo</ENAMEX>] y muy poco reliHion

            

            The o in reliHion ought to carry a written accent, as
does the i of aqu√≠ , and poco ought to be poca.
            

            As far as I know, the most recent example of
extensive switching to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>--or for that matter
to any foreign language--in an English-language
text is to be found in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> already published
books of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cormac McCarthy</ENAMEX>'s much-acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border</ENAMEX>
Trilogy, All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pretty Horses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crossing</ENAMEX>,
especially the latter.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> excels in the laconic,
colloquial dialogue of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cowboys</ENAMEX>, and the untranslated lingo of his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> generally rings true as well.  He does
occasionally err, though, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> cannot help wondering
what arrogance keeps an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> like Sender
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> from having his text proofread by a
competent native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> let us scan the first
novel of the trilogy, All the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pretty Horses</ENAMEX>.

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cu√°nto</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grady</ENAMEX>.
Para todo?  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 51</ENAMEX>]

            

            
               Por todo? is correct and usual.  Since almost any
grammatical rule that can be broken in any language
is sometimes broken, I cannot say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> has
never heard a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Para</ENAMEX> todo, meaning for
the whole [purchase]?  But I tested the two phrases
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> of about the same type as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> in the book and confirmed that por , not
para , is not only the correct word but also the usual
word in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> meaning for in the sense of in payment
of.


Soy comandante de las yegunas ... yo y yo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">s√≥lo</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sin la</ENAMEX> caridad de estas manos no tengas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nada</ENAMEX>.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 128</ENAMEX>]

            

            I see no reason to use the present subjunctive ( tengas )
here.  No tendr√≠as or possibly even no tuvieras
sounds more grammatical and more likely.  Here
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> spells comandante right, but on pages 208
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">228</NUMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> misleads him into misspelling
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> word with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m's</ENAMEX> .


Digame, he said.  <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cu√°l es lo peor</ENAMEX>.  Que soy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pobre o que soy americano</ENAMEX>.

The vaquero shook his head.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Una</ENAMEX> llave de oro
abre cualquier puerta, he said.

Tienes raz√≥n, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grady</ENAMEX>.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 147</ENAMEX>]

            

            Here and elsewhere in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> novels we find a
shuttling between familiar and formal verb forms
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digame/Tienes</ENAMEX> ) that certainly happens in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>,
as it did in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Elizabethan English</ENAMEX> as evidenced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry IV</ENAMEX>, Part <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">II, Act II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scene IV</ENAMEX>:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dol</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Captain</ENAMEX>!  thou abominable damned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cheater</ENAMEX>,
art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thou</ENAMEX> not ashamed to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>!  An
captains were of my mind, they would truncheon
you out, for taking their names upon you before
you have earned them.  You a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>!

            

            And I once heard a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segovian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of Salamanca
University say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venga</ENAMEX> to a small, timid <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.  Still, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> dialogue he shuttles between
familiar and formal verb forms with an abandon that
I find a bit excessive.  There are other examples of
this inconsistency on pages <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">202 and 259 in the first</TIMEX>
novel.

            On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151</NUMEX> and on pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">174 and 175</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ci√©naga</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberian</ENAMEX> form of the noun appears instead
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> form, ci√©nega .  Also, the place
name that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> has as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuatro Ci√©nagas</ENAMEX> appears
on the AAA map of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuatrocienegas</ENAMEX>.

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Qui√©n √©s usted</ENAMEX>?  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 205</ENAMEX>]

            

            The written accent on the verb is wrong here.  As we
shall see, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> gets quite wild with his accents
in the more extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> novel.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gracias</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De</ENAMEX> nada.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 222</ENAMEX>]

            

            I have heard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> say de nada (you're welcome),
but por nada is particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>.  I have
had Spaniards identify my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> as of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
variety, more or less, because of my saying por nada ,
the more typical expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.


C√∫al caballo?  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 262</ENAMEX>]

            

            Now, here is an expression where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> is at
odds with grammar-book usage, which would prescribe
Qu√© caballo? , but right for popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
usage.

            In The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossing McCarthy</ENAMEX> hits his stride in dialogue
in colloquial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican Spanish</ENAMEX> and does himself
proud.  Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> might think him a bit presumptuous.
I am not sure that his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> here, any
more than in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel, is faulty at all, except
for incorrect written accents, in the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX>
would never say what he has them saying.
Sometimes, as noted above, his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> dialogue in
being technically ungrammatical faithfully reflects
popular usage, as is the case with his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> dialogue.
For instance Estoy regres√°ndole a mi pa√≠s
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 412</ENAMEX>].  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peque√±o Larousse Ilustrado dictionary</ENAMEX>
brands this transitive use of the verb regresar as a
 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">barbarismo</ENAMEX> .  But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are barbaric--sometimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nobly</ENAMEX> so--if nothing else, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regresar</ENAMEX> is exactly right here.  And speaking of popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expressions</ENAMEX>, on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275</NUMEX> we find blanquillos , the
euphemism for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> that has been the subject of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPISTOLAE</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>.

            On pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43 and 414</TIMEX> appears the more common
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> expression por nada instead of de nada .

            On pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44 and 47</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">matr√≠z.</ENAMEX>  There should be
no written accent here.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>, who seems to be
contemptuous of punctuation in any language,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rarely</ENAMEX> writes accents where they are not needed but
often omits them where they are, e.g., mia [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pp</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX>]; borrachon [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 227</ENAMEX>]; mascara [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 229</ENAMEX>]; perdida
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 283</ENAMEX>]; asi [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 284</ENAMEX>]; haran [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pt</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">290</NUMEX>]; and que
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 318</ENAMEX>].


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tan</ENAMEX> como <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">preguntar lo que saben las piedras</ENAMEX>.

[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 45</ENAMEX>]

            

            I think that the substantive tanto ought to be here
instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">adverbial tan</ENAMEX> .


Todos que vengas alrededor. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 88</ENAMEX>]

            

            To agree with its subject the verb should be vengan .
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-person singular form is probably a typographic
error.


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Es</ENAMEX> lejos? [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 102</ENAMEX>]

            

            I think that est√° for location should be here, as it is in
a similar context on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">236</NUMEX>.


No le molesta. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 123</ENAMEX>]

            

            I cannot say that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> never use the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-person
imperative negatively in real life as here and
on pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">281, 305</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">312</NUMEX>.  But correctly and popularly,
too, and as on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">306</NUMEX> (No te preocupes) , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subjunctive</ENAMEX> is used for a negative imperative in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-person singular.  Canta y no llores ... the
old song goes.


Tengo <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">miedo es verdad</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 138</ENAMEX>]

            

            Here the subjunctive sea is called for.


<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Los</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hombres</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">han</ENAMEX> salido por <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madero</ENAMEX>? [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 225</ENAMEX>]

            

            Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madero</ENAMEX> here the same place as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madera</ENAMEX> on
page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">404</NUMEX>?  In any case, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madero</ENAMEX> is a place, para or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pa</ENAMEX> ' should be here instead of por .  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madero</ENAMEX>
died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>.


Ya nos hemos <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">encontrado la mujer y el hombre</ENAMEX>.
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 284</ENAMEX>]

            

            Here, on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">292</NUMEX> (... no podemos ver <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el</ENAMEX> buen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dios</ENAMEX> ), and on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">297</NUMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busca el</ENAMEX> herido, no ?), both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grammar</ENAMEX> and custom call for an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX> before the personal
object of the verb.


<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Los</ENAMEX> aspectos de las cosas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> enga√±osas. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 290</ENAMEX>]

            

            Here the adjective fails to agree in gender with the
noun it modifies.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Quiz√°s hay</ENAMEX> poca de justicia... [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 293</ENAMEX>]

            

            Either the de should be omitted or poco instead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poca</ENAMEX> should be here.


Que <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">joven tan enforzado</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 318</ENAMEX>]

            

            The adjective here may be a dialect form unknown
to me, but more likely it is a typographical error for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">esforzado</ENAMEX>.
            

            In a way this essay is complimentary.  If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> dialogue were not so close to perfection
as it is, one would not be challenged to nitpick
through it but would simply dismiss it as incompetent.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Arrivals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>




            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarians</ENAMEX> have always been fiercely proud of
their language, a non Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> in
a sea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavic, Germanic</ENAMEX>, and Romance tongues.  Its
origins are obscure, but we know that it is distantly
related to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> and belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finno</ENAMEX>-Ugric
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of languages.

            Part of the fun for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> is the
battle to understand anything at all, whether the
words are spoken or written.  I remember how
delighted I was, on my first visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Budapest</ENAMEX> some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, when I spotted the word szendvics on the
menu of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>.  Yes, it meant sandwich
and was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> word I could recognize.  Mind
you, it was difficult to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in the first
place, the word for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> being √©tterem in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX>.

            Until recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarians</ENAMEX> accepted foreign
words only grudgingly, preferring to create new
ones of their own.  At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time they even invented a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> word for telephone: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">t√°vbesz√©l√∂</ENAMEX> (literally,
distance talker; a calque of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> Fernsprecher).
But, although this word can be found in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>, it is hardly ever heard.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telefon</ENAMEX> is the
more popular term and the one which, fortunately
for the tourist, can be seen on every kiosk.

            Since the fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Berlin wall</ENAMEX> and all that came
after, there has been an unstoppable flood of English
words pouring into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>.  It is no surprise to
find that the new language of computers has been
fully integrated into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hungarian</ENAMEX>: words like hardver
and softver are commonplace.  But over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> a stream of everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words has
stormed through the language barrier.  This is not
only because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is now bombarded with
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English language</ENAMEX> TV programs on various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
channels, but also because western pop culture has
taken such a strong hold among the young.

            A random selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> loanwords--with
no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hungarian</ENAMEX> translation given--taken from recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, and conversations, includes
the following:


mani money; kes cash; menedzser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>;
deler <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>; biznisz business; marketing; lizing
leasing; frencsajz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>; holding; diszkont
discount

b√©bi szitter; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>; heppening; hostess; New Age;
jogging; dizajn design; toples; jackpot; horror;
tinedzer teenager; fitness club

And on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Budapest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> fronts you can now see
strange szlogans displayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>: Non-Stop
open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>; and the mysterious Goods Made
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>

            

            It will be interesting to see how many of these
words, reflecting current preoccupations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>,
will be accepted permanently.  I think most of
them will, and I, for one, regret this.  Something of
the uniqueness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hungarian language</ENAMEX> will be
lost for ever.  Besides, what challenge will there be
for the enterprising tourist?
         
         
            
The sound of snoring is due to vibration of the soft
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">palate</ENAMEX> and the vulva at the back of the throat.  [From the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Times Globe of St. John</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N.B.,</ENAMEX> .
Submitted by ]

         
         
            Bespeaking a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muse</ENAMEX> or What?




            Surely a lot of the joy of learning a new language
lies in observing how it expresses everyday objects
and operations.  (This does not apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pupils</ENAMEX> forced to learn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> by rote in mediocre
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and vice versa, nor to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> learning English
in the same way, for that matter.)  This is particularly
true for me of a language like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>, which is
geographically and grammatically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a world away
from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> tongue, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, such that many
Thai locutions give pause and delight.


In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight Guides</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> one reads:

Many common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> words when translated bespeak
a muse or a minstrel.  Some examples:
spirit's clothes = <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX>; slow forest = <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sky</ENAMEX> cries out = thunder; sky fire = electricity;
walking stomach = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diarrhoea</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> scarce and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX> dear = famine.

            

            Hyperbole or not?  Some may see the prosaic
where others see the poetic.  I tend towards the latter.
And when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>-language wrestles with new
words for alien imports like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice hard water</ENAMEX> or parachute
umbrella for supporting life, some might be
amused at how downright literal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> can be or impressed
at how admirably sensible it so often is.

            In the following list, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> words are glossed
literally, then are given their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> equivalents.  A
little imagination may be all that is required in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">minstrelly</ENAMEX> mode to discern the poetic connection.
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N.B.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> is very economical with articles, prepostions,
and conjunctions so I have added these where
necessary for the sake of clarity.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. = literally;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euph</ENAMEX>. = euphemism; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sl</ENAMEX>. = slang; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obs</ENAMEX>. = obsolete]


see daeng <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leuat nok</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bird</ENAMEX>'s-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood red</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crimson</ENAMEX>

see leuat moo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>'s-blood color: scarlet

see chompoo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. rose-apple color: pink

see fah, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sky</ENAMEX> color: light blue

see nam tarn, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">palm</ENAMEX>-sugar color: brown (Before
white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> arrived from the West, Thais
refined <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> from the tarn <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>: nam tarn water
of the tarn <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, and, the
Thai word for brown refers to the color of the
water of the tarn <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>)
.bqe

see kee mah, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-shit color: dark green

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fuk tong, Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">squashed gold</ENAMEX>: pumpkin

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare nam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>: river

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare lek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of iron: magnet

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare bahn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>: housewife

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare [pore</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> [or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>] of trade:
street vendor

ying rap chai, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who is the recipient of
use: maid

look peun, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of a gun: bullet

look fai, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of fire: spark

more doo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who can see: fortuneteller

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yah</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. medicine for rubbing the teeth:
toothpaste

yah soop, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. sucking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>: tobacco

yah mah, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sl</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">horse medicine</ENAMEX>: amphetamines
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presumably</ENAMEX> because they give one the
strength and endurance of a horse.)

noey keng, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. hard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>: cheese

malaeng wan, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. day insect: fly (They are
seen only in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>)

malaeng mum, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">corner insect: spider</ENAMEX>

malaeng sahb, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">foul-smelling insect: cockroach</ENAMEX>
(After being crushed.)

pla meuk, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ink fish</ENAMEX>: squid

kreuang len jarn siang, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obs</ENAMEX>.), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. machine for
playing a sound plate: record <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> (Now hifi
or sataireo is used.)

kreuang yep kradart, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obs</ENAMEX>.), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. machine for
sewing paper: stapler (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mak</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAX</ENAMEX> is now used.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
for stapler is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>.)

rok <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poo ying</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>: syphilis
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formerly</ENAMEX>, syphilis was transmitted through
brothels, where it was spontaneously generated.
This has been replaced by sifilit.)

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">nam nom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. water of the breast: milk

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hua</ENAMEX> nom, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the breast: nipple

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hua mare meua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head mother</ENAMEX> of the hand:
thumb

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">nam man, Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oily water</ENAMEX>: gasoline

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">nam man moo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oily water</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>: lard

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">seua nam man, Lit</ENAMEX>. oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX>: linoleum

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang geng</ENAMEX> nai, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. inner trousers: underpants

<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gang geng ling</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sl</ENAMEX>.), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey trousers</ENAMEX>: underpants
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formerly</ENAMEX>, traveling shows featured
monkeys dressed in diapers/nappies.)

seua nork, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. outer shirt: jacket

seua nao, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. cold shirt: sweater, pullover,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">jumper</ENAMEX>

seua kloom, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">enveloping</ENAMEX> shirt: overcoat

seua yok song, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. shirt for raising or supporting
the figure: brassiere (Now blah, from bra, is
almost universal.)

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arkart sia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. broken air: air pollution

look kit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. thinking balls; abacus

dao nee sin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of debt: creditor

look nee sin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of debt: debtor

ngern cheua, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. money believed in: credit

ngern sot, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. fresh money: cash

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">nam tarng</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stranded water</ENAMEX>: dew

fah poh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. flash of the sky: lighting

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reva</ENAMEX> bai, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. boat with a leaf: sailboat

tung yahng arnamai, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euph</ENAMEX>.), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. hygienic
rubber bag: condom

pah arnamai, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euph</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. hygienic cloth: sanitary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">napkin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kotek</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kotex</ENAMEX> was generic for
a time, as was earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tam</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampax</ENAMEX>; with
so many rival brands available, path arnamai has
been reverted to.)

nang seua dern tahng, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. book for walking a
path or route: passport

dtit gap, (conjunction), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. stuck with: next to

ngern sin bon, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euph</ENAMEX>.), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. money for increasing
wealth: bribe

            
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classic Wit</ENAMEX>




            At a time when dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">one-liners</ENAMEX> and tasteless
jokes can be tossed off on TV and elsewhere as
examples of wit without causing anyone to cringe,
perhaps the moment has arrived to make some distinctions
and straighten out the nomenclature among
those terms that fall under the umbrella of eliciting
laughter.

            We might start with the criteria for classic wit ,
the highest form of humor, that is set up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Companion</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Language</ENAMEX> .
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>, true wit must meet the
following standards: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The practitioner must have
a quick mind, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) The witticism must be stated
within a very tight framework, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) It is characterized
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> common rhetorical devices: parallelism,
antithesis, definition, and quasi-philosophical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">propositions</ENAMEX>, an example being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s line,
Not only is God dead, but try getting a plumber on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.  One might add that classic wit is usually
motivated by malice, which must be stated artfully,
and the malice is frequently at someone else's expense.
To this, I would attach my own definition: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
qualify as wit, a retort must be no more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
words.

            Clearly, then, what sets wit apart from humor is
its cerebral quality and its verbal conciseness.  Other
terms that elicit laughter are lower on the pecking
order because, although they may display quick
thinking, they may lack the tight framework.  Others
pass the conciseness test but may be too contrived.
Gentle or kindly humor fails the test for obvious
reasons.

            Scores of lines that meet these criteria come to
mind.  My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> is a retort by former college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>
coach, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duffy Dougherty</ENAMEX>, to a remark that football
is a contact sport.  Duffy cracked,  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dancing</ENAMEX> is
a contact sport.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> is a collision sport.  This
strikes me as remarkable because, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dougherty</ENAMEX>
was not a literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, he managed to combine
an ironic analogy and parallelism to come up
with a line that could be called pure wit.

            Another broad term under the eliciting laughter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise</ENAMEX> is joke .  In a way a joke, in its structure,
is the antithesis of a witticism in that is usually
placed within a narrative framework and withholds
any response until the punch line is reached.  In this
sense, timing is extremely important.  We know that
if any joke begins with A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> walks into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> with
an iguana on a leash, sits down, and orders a zombie
..., we may be in for a long detailed narrative that
may or may not be funny.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> terms that come close to being classic wit
are quip and wisecrack , both of them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americanisms</ENAMEX>.
These slangy expressions meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>'s standard of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conciseness</ENAMEX> in that they are pointed come-backs to a
situation or a remark.  However, they fall short in
that their tone is sarcastic rather than malicious.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Parker</ENAMEX> once noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wit</ENAMEX> has truth in it;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wisecracking</ENAMEX> is simply calisthenics with words.  Although
the quip and the wisecrack are usually quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shallow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George S. Kaufman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algonquin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Round Table</ENAMEX>, managed to turn the wisecrack
into an art form.  At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groucho</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> that a line he was supposed to deliver in a
movie which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> had scripted was not funny.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groucho</ENAMEX>, urging patience, replied, Remember,
they laughed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fulton</ENAMEX> when he invented the steamboat.
To which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> cracked, Not at matin√©es.

            Even farther down in the pecking order is the
term, gag.  Again, some distinctions are called for.  In
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> theater parlance, the term gag is used frequently
to differentiate funny lines in a movie
script or stage comedy from mere jokes that are exchanged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscriminately</ENAMEX> in everyday life.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon</ENAMEX>,
the chief practitioner of the theatrical gag, has
given this form of humor a new respect, if only because
of its frequency in his comedies.  In fact,
punchy ripostes are sprinkled so heavily throughout
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>'s comedies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been led to believe
that he writes the gags <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, then fleshes out
the rest of the play around them.  All this has placed
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>'s back.  He would like to be considered
a wit, perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Johnson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
letters, but he will never achieve such eminence
so long as he churns out gags, assembly-line fashion.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> terms, now considered somewhat archaic,
that fit into the category of eliciting laughter are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jest</ENAMEX> and sally .  Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jest</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clowns</ENAMEX> and that over-quoted line from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Juliet</ENAMEX> , He jests at scars that never felt a
wound.  In current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> usage, the term resembles
what we call kidding: that is, making fun
of someone or some thing in a frivolous manner,
such as in the obligatory banter at roasts of famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.  What separates a jest from a witticism
is its lack of malice.  A jest is never uttered at someone
else's expense.

            A sally is defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heritage Dictionary</ENAMEX>
as a sudden quick witticism.  In other
words, it is a line that is uttered off the top of one's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and, therefore, may or may not be funny.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>, the expression <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX>
has developed into an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">all-purpose</ENAMEX> usage.  It seems to
be an outgrowth of sound bite , a phenomenon of
television communication in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are required to reduce complex ideas to one
concise sentence.  For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> expressed
his disapproval of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> by saying
that, relative to jobs in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, these trade
agreements would create a giant sucking sound.
In a political context, You're just rearranging the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">deck chairs</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> is another sound bite
that now seems firmly established in the language.
While the leap from a sound bite to a witticism appears
to be easy to manage, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have
been inclined to take the risk and be labeled as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wise</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> or a smart-ass .

            To conclude, we might note that there is no
shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who have an urge to say
something funny.  What is missing is a standard for
judging funniness.  Perhaps these distinctions I
have made will help in that direction.
         
         
            No Nicknames in the Valleys




            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones The Meat, Dai Scab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans Above</ENAMEX> should
be preserved for posterity, says a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Welsh</ENAMEX> nicknames, on the decline
with population changes and the break-up of communities
once dominated by the coal industry, need
to be collected before they are lost forever, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Davies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sociology</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>.  Increased migration, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> people
moving out and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> moving in, has
played a large part in the demise of the nicknames
which were once in widespread use and which many
regard as a unique art form.

            Humorous nicknames such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dai Bungalow</ENAMEX> for
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with little upstairs mentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dai Bolical</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miner</ENAMEX> who never washed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans Above</ENAMEX>, the undertaker,
are the most savoured examples.  Others
stem from events or habits, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dai Scab</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandfather</ENAMEX> worked during a strike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years ago</TIMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amen Jones</ENAMEX>, who made the loudest responses in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>.

            Traditional nicknames in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dusty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chalky White</ENAMEX> tended to disappear some
time ago, and it is simply happening later in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>,
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prof Davies</ENAMEX>.  There is not the need for them
that there was.  I would very much like to see them
recorded.

            The nicknames developed from the need to distinguish
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> with the
same name.  It was not unknown for a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,
for instance, to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, largely as a result of the limited choice of surnames,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>, coupled with a
passion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical Christian</ENAMEX> names, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>.

            As a result of this need to distinguish, some
very humorous names developed.  There was one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> front teeth in the middle and
was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dai Central Eating</ENAMEX>.  Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who keep repeating the same
word in almost every sentence and he as known as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans Absolutely</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Professor Davies</ENAMEX>.  In many
of the valley communities the nicknames, usually reserved
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, arose from their
job, or an unfortunate incident, or a physical or
speech defect.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Gwyndaf</ENAMEX>, assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keeper</ENAMEX> at the Welsh
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folk Museum</ENAMEX>, said: In the old coal mining communities
you had to distinguish between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joneses</ENAMEX>.  They were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and they did not
mind being called nicknames; it added colour to life.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Areas</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have moved away or commute
to work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> are the most likely
to be affected.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Walter Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> of the Welsh
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Language Board</ENAMEX>, says that widened horizons may
also be to blame: The world has widened and some
of the things that used to be local have been lost in
that widening process.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gus Jones</ENAMEX>, a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardiff</ENAMEX> who has
studied the nicknames, said: They are on the decline.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX> people jump into their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, go to
work out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and you don't have this
close-knit society which breeds these nicknames.
He added: We have quite a few examples of humorous
names.  There was, for instance, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">miner</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Swansea valley</ENAMEX> who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX> started playing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>, which was something unheard of.  He was ever
after known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dai Swank</ENAMEX>.  There was also a fashion
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with common surnames were known by
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>' names.  There was a mine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Evans</ENAMEX>, who was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dai Hannah</ENAMEX>.  One
day he was working underground and ordered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> to replace all the ventilation doors.  After
that he was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dai Hannah Dors</ENAMEX>.

            An example that I particularly like is a man
who got married during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirties recession</TIMEX> and
wore daps, or plimsolls, during the ceremony.  He
has always been known as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dai Quiet Wedding</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¬©Copyright 1994</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Independent</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1994</TIMEX>.
Reprinted by permission.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Tyndale</ENAMEX>: A Biography
            In his immensely popular <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Short History of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Richard Green</ENAMEX> described
the profound moral and cultural change that
transformed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 16th</TIMEX> and early
17th <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of a
book, he wrote, and that book was the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.
Although he does not specify, it seems likely Green
means the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1611 Authorized</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James) Version</ENAMEX>,
for he goes on: As a mere literary monument, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> remains the noblest example
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> tongue, while its perpetual use
made it from the instant of its appearance the standard
of our language.

            Green was neither the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> nor last to sing hosannas
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AV</ENAMEX>, and most extollers have especially
praised the awesome consistency of its excellence,
considering it was the work of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and divers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">divines</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astonishment</ENAMEX> is still voiced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dignitaries</ENAMEX>
... spoke so often with one voice, says <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholar David Daniell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> emeritus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.  And the reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniell</ENAMEX> quickly
adds, is that it was virtually one voice: that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
Tyndale, one of the most influential--and certainly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the least known--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> history.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unsung Tyndale</ENAMEX> certainly is.  According to a chronology
of significant literary works, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> important
book was published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1520s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Skelton</ENAMEX>'s The
Garlande of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurell</ENAMEX> , in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> allegorically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enthrones</ENAMEX> himself among the great poets of the
world.  But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1526</TIMEX>, smuggled copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heretical</ENAMEX> translation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Testament</ENAMEX> began
appearing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, to the great consternation of
the establishment, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardinal</ENAMEX>
Wolsey, and Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas More</ENAMEX>, and to the lasting
glory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language.

            To those lucky and adventurous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who got
their hands on copies before they were seized and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">burned</ENAMEX> (the books, that is, but also sometimes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizens</ENAMEX>), this was a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> with a belt.  It was lively
and colloquial, meaningful and memorable.  But most
of all, it was in plain but powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>.  Until this
point, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> that anyone knew was the Vulgate
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> version translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX> a millennium
before.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wycliffe</ENAMEX> had rendered this in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1382</TIMEX>, but that was pre-printing press, and
hand copies of this stilted, verbatim <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lollard</ENAMEX> construction
were scarce.

            But here, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1526</TIMEX>, was a book that
rang out the scriptures as sounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>.  Here
was gospel that cut to the chase: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ask</ENAMEX>, and it shall be
given you; seek and ye shall find; filthy lucre;
Eat, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> and be merry; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>; signs
of the times; a law unto themselves.  In the beginning
came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years later</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyndale</ENAMEX>'s similarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contraband Pentateuch</ENAMEX> started arriving from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
In this, too, the stunning simplicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX>'s
words caught the public's imagination.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of a book and that
book was the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, then that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> was for the most
part <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale's</ENAMEX>--a claim argued persuasively and passionately
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Daniell in William Tyndale</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> ,
published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1994</TIMEX>, the quincentenary
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>'s birth.  Daniell warmed up to
the task by publishing modern-spelling versions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Testament</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pentateuch</ENAMEX>, also produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale University Press</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989 and 1992</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniell</ENAMEX>'s book, the first serious biography since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mozley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Tyndale</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>, travels familiar
paths.  But it is like cruising a smoothly paved freeway
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>, as opposed to jolting down a
country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX>-A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>.  The same can be
said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX>'s poetic prose.  In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vulgate, Genesis</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:3</TIMEX> says: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dixitque Deus: Fiat lux</ENAMEX>!  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">et facta est</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lux</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wycliffe</ENAMEX>'s painfully literal <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> edition has this:
And God said, Be made light; and made is light.
Compare that to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX>'s enduring rendition: Then
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX> said: Let there be light and there was light.

            Tyndale was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gloucestershire</ENAMEX> and attended
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, where the spirit of
the recently departed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erasmus</ENAMEX> still glowed.  He became
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>, but his reformist zeal soon earned him
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enmity</ENAMEX> in high places.  He believed religion was atrophying
under the deadly dogmatism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>.  What proved even more dangerous to his
health was his frequently and loudly aired opinion
that the truth lay in the scripture, not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>.
The only way to regenerate a flagging faith was to
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to read The Word in their own language.
This could not safely be done in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>--
nor, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, even in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, in spite of its more
advanced reform, mainly under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX> had finished the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Jonah</ENAMEX>, on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to completing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX>, when he was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">betrayed</ENAMEX>, arrested, and convicted of heresy.  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 1536</TIMEX>, he was strangled at the stake, and his body
burnt.  His last words were, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, open the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>'s eyes.  Shortly afterward, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>,
whether in answer to that prayer or because of his
own marriage-related difficulties with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, made
himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of his first
acts was to commission an English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.  It,
and all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>, bore the unmistakable imprint
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX>.

            What distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX>'s work from earlier
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> efforts was that he translated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Testament</ENAMEX>
straight from its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Greek</ENAMEX> and his Pentateuch
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>, without the distorting filter of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>.  Aside from setting down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">enduring clich√©s.</ENAMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyndale</ENAMEX> wrote in a timeless vernacular,
not all of it echoed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AV</ENAMEX>.  When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> decide to climb to heaven, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AV</ENAMEX> tells it in
this archaic, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Elizabethan</ENAMEX> way: And they said to one
another, Go to, let us build a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>.  In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale's</ENAMEX> version, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Babel</ENAMEX>, with surprising
modernity, say: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come on</ENAMEX>, let us build a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tower</ENAMEX>.

            Fortunately, and contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>' instructions,
the compilers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AV</ENAMEX> did keep a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX>,
while taking care not to divulge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.
Some say <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 80 per cent</NUMEX> of that glorious text is
from the pen of the great but uncelebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>.
Others say that, of the really glorious parts, it is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cent</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson Cochrane</ENAMEX>
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>
            
         
         
            Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who have been paying attention
know that I have high praise for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary Second Edition on Compact Disc</ENAMEX> , a CD-ROM
edition of the great dictionary that enables users
to search the entire text in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>--
depending on the complexity of the search and the
number of results turned up--far less time than it
takes to get up, walk over to the bookshelf, take
down a volume, and find what one is seeking.  Now
something called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version 1.1 Upgrade</ENAMEX> has been
made available for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about ¬•60</NUMEX> (including shipping),
and I have been using it.  To quote from the manual:


There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> principal enhancements: (i) the
addition of a Windows installation program, (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
the ability to display and print out using
True Type‚Ñ¢ fonts, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iii</ENAMEX>) the inclusion of an RTF
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rich Text Format copying</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSWord</ENAMEX> for
Windows <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.0</NUMEX> (or higher) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Exchange</ENAMEX>) link to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSWord</ENAMEX> for Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>
(or higher).

            

            As I do not have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MSWord 2.0</NUMEX> (or higher), the last
item means nothing to me; as the system is already
installed into Windows on my computers, some installation
program must have come with the original,
so I do not know what item (i) refers to.  Item (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) is a
marvelous addition, though, for I have been able, in
the past, to get some data printed out from the file,
but it seemed to work at whim, and I could never be
sure that I would get anything, let alone what I was
after.  Now all doubt in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> is at an end:
call up an entry on the screen, invoke the FILE, and a
menu opens to reveal a number of choices that allow
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to print the entire entry or only the part that has
been highlighted.  It is extremely rapid, and the entries
are printed out fully styled typographically.
