
   
      
         
            Power <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Users Dump Baudy Language: The Ambivalent Nature of Computer</ENAMEX> Slang




            What happens when power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">users</ENAMEX> dump baudy
language ?  Should they abort, retry, ignore ,
or admit failure?  They might boot up again, but they
could experience a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> crash .  Would Kermit prevent
them from being munged ?  What should a poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technoweenie</ENAMEX> do when threatened by thrashing between
disk and memory?  Nerdettes better hope their
motherboards are user-friendly .  If all else fails, they
could hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWIM</ENAMEX> key.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackers</ENAMEX> , or just plain droupies , probably have
no trouble translating what I just wrote out of computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jargon</ENAMEX> and slang into more conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>.
But even if you do not understand the preceding,
you probably feel the tension between words
conveying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, strength, and menace, such as
power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, abort, dump, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> crash , and munged ,
with words suggesting vulnerability, frailty, and humor
as a defense against such powerlessness, in
words like technoweenie, nerdettes, user-friendly ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWIM</ENAMEX> (for do what I mean, a mythological key
that would make the computer do what you cannot
figure out yourself).

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use computers feel ambivalent
about them.  It should not, therefore, be surprising
that computer slang conveys divided, and sometimes
radically conflicting feelings.  As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> I see evidence
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> of this ambivalence in the slang
used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slang</ENAMEX> is a reliable
gauge of attitudes because it is usually used in an
unguarded way to express unedited feelings.

            I am using the word slang as it is defined on
page xi in the latest scholarly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary of American</ENAMEX>
slang, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.E. Lighter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Dictionary of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Slang</ENAMEX> , Volume I, A-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>): an informal,
nonsubstandard, nontechnical vocabulary composed
chiefly of novel-sounding synonyms for standard
words and phrases.  I am assuming, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
this dictionary argues, that slang is not just colloquial
language, but that it is often aggressively informal,
that it doesn't tolerate pretense, that it is often
crude, blunt, ribald, egalitarian--in short, very unpretentious
and honest language.  [ ibid , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">xii</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slang</ENAMEX> is similar to, but rather different from
computer jargon, which is the specialized language
used by tekkies.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jargon</ENAMEX> is the in language used
by any profession, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, or class.  The word default
is jargon for something automatically carried out
unless you change it.  This term does not qualify as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slang</ENAMEX> because it is a legitimate, formal term, rather
easy to define denotatively, quite fit for use in polite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and equally at home in written and spoken
language.  By contrast, the neologism droupie a person
who likes to spend time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of programmers
and data processing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, is slang
because it is very informal language.  In fact, it is so
casual as to suggest an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-grown-up</ENAMEX> rebelliousness
because of its probable derivation from the word
groupie , and it is definitely more frequent in speech
than in writing.

            Because slang is up front and sometimes deliberately
in your face language, we can learn
more about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really feel about computers
by examining slang rather than jargon.  A good way
to remember the difference between slang and jargon
is that jargon serves to indicate a referent, usually
with great precision, while slang characterizes
and often makes light of what is referred to, and
nonslang synonyms are almost always readily available.
Technical language develops among specialists
for the purpose of cooperation; slang develops
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> for purposes of expressiveness,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companionability</ENAMEX> and to some extent exclusivity.
[ ibid . xvi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">xvii</ENAMEX>]

            We can learn a lot about what is on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
minds when we analyze jargon, but we can learn
how they feel when we analyze slang.  Thus, it is not
surprising that a great deal of computer jargon is a
quick way to say otherwise complicated things.  For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIPS</ENAMEX> is a convenient acronym for millions
of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">instructions per second</NUMEX>, point and click is a quick
and direct way of describing basic mouse techniques,
and run-around , borrowed from typesetting,
is an apt metaphor for the way text flows around the
outside edges of a graphic image.  Jargon like this is
very good at precisely describing actions and things,
but these words do not convey any obvious attitudes
about their referents.

            My analysis of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">slang</ENAMEX> has revealed a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal of ambivalence about these often mysterious
and seemingly omnipotent machines.  Some
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">slang</ENAMEX> suggests a love-fear conflict.  One
does not have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudian</ENAMEX> to wonder about the
double message implied in some of these terms.

            On the one hand, there are quite a number of
words and phrases suggesting that computers are
powerful and frightening.  We definitely want to do
all we can to avoid causing a computer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> or
crash.  It is true that many computer applications began
in the military but many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not conscious
of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> use expressions like
command language or launch a program.  Because
computers simulate many human activities, it is not
surprising that we should attribute all kinds of human
characteristics to them.  They do seem to possess artificial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>; some of them create virtual reality;
and they are so efficient that they make us
wonder about why we would want to do anything in
real time any more.  When I am feeling especially
organized at work I like to tell coworkers that I'm in
the batch mode.  Computers are so seemingly lifelike
that we worry when they catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">viruses</ENAMEX>; we seek
to debug programs; and we do not have to be right-to-lifers
to worry if a computer application is suddenly
aborted.  Our fears are often suggested when
we say that some repetitious human activity looks
as if it is programmed.  We sometimes want to
deprogram <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who belong to dogmatic cults.

            As if to counteract or reduce the frightening
power suggested by many of these words, other
slang expressions suggest that computers are really
quite harmless.  Some of these terms go to the opposite
extreme, suggesting a warm and fuzzy, childlike
relationship that seems all too naively trusting, as if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Red Riding Hood</ENAMEX> really could trust the wolf
dressed as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.  Surely we must expect
that the normal state of affairs is for computers to be
hostile, or at least unfriendly.  Why else would we so
frequently use the term user-friendly to describe operations
that are not easy to do?  And how did such a
cold and unhuman thing like a telecommunications
protocol for transferring files between a mainframe
and a microcomputer get dubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kermit</ENAMEX>?  It seems
incongruous that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s television
show should be identified with such an impersonal
thing.  At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Michigan University</ENAMEX> two
names for areas within our mainframe are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Piglet</ENAMEX> and
Winnie, suggesting that all the hard, serious data and
big-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> research is really not daunting at
all.  On the contrary, that world is as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blithe</ENAMEX> and carefree
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Winnie the Pooh</ENAMEX> stories.  Similar words
for computer services at my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> are grog,
gumby, roo, tigger, kanga, ninny, thumper, mickey
and minnie (for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Mouse</ENAMEX>), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel and Hardy</ENAMEX>.  Surely the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who coined
these names are of the same mindset as those who
call miniature programs applets or refer to diagonal
or circular lines in a text as jaggies.  Reference librarians
who regularly contribute to the Stumpers
list on the Internet refer to themselves as wombats.
This apparently originated because one of the
reference questions involved these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> marsupials,
noted for their burrowing qualities.  Surely
the nickname has stuck not only because of the metaphorical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians burrowing</ENAMEX> for
answers, but also because the name sounds cute,
personalizing what otherwise might seem to be the
overly mechanical activity of finding answers to reference
questions.  So many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>'
names for passwords that these are among the first
names a decoder would try to learn.

            I want to suggest that there is a very understandable
reason for the apparent conflict between words
like power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kermit</ENAMEX>.  The soft, warm, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
words allow us to allay our fears about computers
that crash and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> and abort.  It is as if the
cute words undemonized the scary ones.  I do not
have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker</ENAMEX> or a tekkie in order to manage
efficiently my user-friendly computer, In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> version
of reality, those ubiquitous computers are going to
take over all aspects of life, doing away with my job
or changing it into something a robot should do,
rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>.  Another version of reality
offends <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> and is just as exaggerated, but
it is very useful as a defense mechanism.  In this view
of the world, I can feel very safe indeed--in fact, I
am more than simply safe--I am nurtured in the
warm and cuddly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s world of fun things like
floppy disks, where I can cozy up to my motherboard,
and pretend that I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dogcow</ENAMEX> (a trademark symbol
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX>) for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that can say
words like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moof</ENAMEX> when it is asked to list <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laser-Writer</ENAMEX>
options.  Fortunately, the real world of computers,
notwithstanding slang words to the contrary,
exists somewhere between the opposing fantasies of
the cold impersonality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX> and the
carefree innocence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Winnie the Pooh</ENAMEX>.

            [NOTE: In this article, I have consulted The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer</ENAMEX>
Glossary: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Complete Illustrated Desk Reference</ENAMEX>,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Freedman</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Management</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6th ed., 1993</ENAMEX>), and computer dictionaries:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jargon: An Informal Dictionary of Computer</ENAMEX>
Terms, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peachpit Press</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>);
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prentice Hall</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illustrated Dictionary of Computing</ENAMEX>,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonar C. Nader</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prentice Hall</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s
New <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World Dictionary of Computer Terms</ENAMEX>, by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Spencer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prentice Hall</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>).]
         
         
            
During this, the Year of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts in Education</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>,
budget cutbacks have reeked havoc with many
school arts programs.  [From From the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Station Manager</ENAMEX>,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Berky</ENAMEX>, in Applause , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Newsletter, .</ENAMEX>  Submitted by
.]

         
         
            
A middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">muslim man</ENAMEX> looking for a muslim
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--object, matrimoney.  [From The [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail , .</ENAMEX>  Submitted by
.]

         
         
            From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>: An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oriental Odyssey</ENAMEX>



            Where have you been on your travels lately?
They say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> is her best in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX>, but
you may prefer somewhere warmer, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yadian</ENAMEX>.
Myself, I can't wait to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eluosi</ENAMEX> again, although all
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> traditionally lead to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luoma</ENAMEX>, even if you are
travelling from as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meizhou</ENAMEX>.  They are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
names for, respectively, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> .

            Where in the world are these places, you may
wonder.  Maybe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>?  Well, yes and no.  They
are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transliterations</ENAMEX> of those names, rather
than translations, and strictly speaking in the Romanization
system known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinyin</ENAMEX> should be written
with tone signs and without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
has pictographs, not letters as we understand
them.  They would then appear as bÄlÄ«, yË˜diË˜n,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ã©luÃ³sÄ«</ENAMEX>, luÃ³mË˜ , and mÄ›izhÅu .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> names of places in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> itself are of
course actually meaningful, although many have become
distorted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking</ENAMEX> ,
now familiar to most in the West in its more accurate
form, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> , has a name meaning northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>,
by contrast with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanking</ENAMEX> , southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canton</ENAMEX> ,
or as it now appears on modern maps, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guangzhou</ENAMEX> ,
means broad region, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai</ENAMEX> means over
the sea.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> names of neighbouring places in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> are also often similarly meaningful and
may be translated from their language of origin.
Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gu\symbol\ngd\symbol</ENAMEX>\o means broad <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and translates
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> name of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX> , while dÂ¯ngjÄ«ng ,
meaning eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">capital</ENAMEX>, translates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
original of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> itself is ribÄ›n , literally sun
root.  (Hence its Western byname, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of the Rising</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>.)  The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> is tÃ ipÃ­ngyÃ¡ng peaceful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ocean</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> name of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> itself is
zhÅngguÃ³ middle <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> name
is traditionally associated with that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ts</ENAMEX>'in dynasty
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">221-206</ENAMEX> BC), although actually recorded
much <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>.  (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> for middle , a rectangular
figure bisected by a vertical line, represents a
square target pierced by an arrow.)

            Places further from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> may also sometimes
have their names translated, assuming they are already
meaningful.  Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port-au-Prince</ENAMEX> , capital of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, is tÃ iz<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">\isymbol\gÄƒng</ENAMEX> , literally great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> port, but Haiti
itself is hÄƒidi , clearly a transliteration.  However, it so
happens that this name is actually (though coincidentally)
both meaningful and appropriate, since it translates
as sea land.

            Such serendipity sends <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on a voyage of discovery,
to see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meanings</ENAMEX> can be aptly found in
other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> transliterated names.  The transliterations
themselves, as instanced above, may at first
seem strange.  However, once one appreciates certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conventions</ENAMEX>, the forms of the names fall into
shape.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> do not distinguish l from r in
Western words or names, for example, so that these
letters when transliterated may appear as either.
Hence luÃ³mÄƒ for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and bÄlÃ­ for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">l\isymbol\sÄ«bÄ›n</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX>, and lÃºndÃ¹n for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.  Similarly,
initial b or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> can give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese m</ENAMEX> , so that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>
(with Western r as well) is milÅ­ and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> mÃ ngÅ­ .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> r itself is closer to Western sh [\?\] or zh
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>].  Hence ruÃ¬diÄƒn for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> and rÃ¬nÃ¨iwÄƒ for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX>.
Generally, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> does not have consonant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or words ending in a vowel (except the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nasal -ng [Î·</ENAMEX>] as in bÄ›ijÄ«ng ).  This means that vowels
appear in transliterations where one does not expect
them.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> is therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bÄgÃ©dÃ¡</ENAMEX> .  The transliteration
itself is often from the native form of the name.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> is thus xÄ«bÄnyÃ¡ , from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EspaÃ±a</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dÃ©yÃ¬zhÃ¬</ENAMEX> , from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deutschland</ENAMEX> .

            Not all names produce a fortuitous literal meaning
as apt as that for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> .  But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, as mÄ›izhÅu ,
has a name that happens to mean beautiful
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">continent--America the Beautiful</ENAMEX>, after all--while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> is yÄ«ngguÃ³ , brave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.  (This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
never did, nor never shall, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lie</ENAMEX> at the proud foot
of a conqueror, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX> penned.)  Even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
seems to have a historic reference, since bÄlÃ­ literally
means clayball multitude: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> name of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lutetia</ENAMEX> , comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaulish</ENAMEX> luto <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX>.

            In the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> the second
element is not part of the transliteration but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> word for, respectively, continent and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">continents</ENAMEX> also have names that are
part transliteration, part zhÅu : <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is oÅ«zhÅu ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, yÄzhÅu , and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> fÄ“izhÅu .  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of these have names that could literally be interpreted,
hardly flatteringly, as inferior continent
and wrong continent, but the first element of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s
name has no corresponding sense.

            There are some curiosities.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> name
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX> is bÄ«ngdÄƒo .  This is clearly not a transliteration
but a translation: it literally means ice island,
with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> element apparently mistranslating
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Icelandic</ENAMEX> name for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, Äªsland ice
land as island.  Nearer home, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> name for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> is chÃ¡oxiÃ¤n .  This literally means seatide
fresh, not inappropriately, but is actually a transliteration
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chosÃ¶n</ENAMEX> , which means land of the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> name for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is quite different: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dÃ xÄ«yÃ¡ng</ENAMEX>
great western ocean.

            It has to be said that if one attempts a literal
translation of many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> placenames one simply
ends up with a sense that is surreal rather than suitable.
Many cannot be meaningfully translated at all.
Of those that yield some sense, the following handful
may be considered poetic coincidences:


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> yÄƒdiÄƒn proper law
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> zhÃ¬lÃ¬ wisdom benefit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Delhi dÃ©l\</ENAMEX>isynbol\ virtue hometown
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> fÄƒguÃ³ method country
Ganges hÃ©nghÃ© everlasting river
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX> hÄƒiyÃ¡ sea tooth
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> lÃºndÃ¹n matching honest
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> niÅ­yuÄ“ bond agreement
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> tÃ iguÃ³ peaceful country

            
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Group</ENAMEX>
Nomenclature




            The names that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> adopt
would, at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, appear to be as vacuous
and bland as the worst of the western pop their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers/producers</ENAMEX>/arrangers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plagiarize</ENAMEX> and instruct/
command them to play.  Not for them the teen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> angst, rebellion and outrage expressed
by such band names as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sex Pistols, The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nipple Erectors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Slits</ENAMEX> (all-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ho ho Hemingway</ENAMEX>),
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Kennedys, The Butthole Surfers, Kid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kommode</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bidet Boys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pogue Mahone</ENAMEX> (now
knows as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Pogues</ENAMEX> since being dropped from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>'s playlist because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>
that pogue mahone meant kiss my arse in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish</ENAMEX>), and
so on.  What is interesting about some of these purveyors
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> pap--I mean pop--is how their
names appear on CD, cassette, and other labels and
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>.

            For this to be appreciated I must first briefly
describe the complex <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> system of writing.  It
consists of borrowed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideograms</ENAMEX> (characters
known as kanji , the hiragana syllabary used for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
words not covered by kanji , the katakana syllabary
used for foreign words, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> alphabet
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">romanji</ENAMEX> usually used for abbreviations
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> and acronyms like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> .  You can see the
whole consort effortlessly dancing together on the
front page of any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>.  In the case
of the names of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop groups</ENAMEX>, this concatenation,
however, assumes truly awesome and bizarre proportions,
surely unknown, indeed not even possible,
in any other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">â€¢ Meaningless</ENAMEX> names written in romanji: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B'z</ENAMEX> (pronounced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lindberg, Qlair</ENAMEX> (pronounced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kler</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAYEÂ·S</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMAP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-Bolan</ENAMEX> (probably from the
late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Bolan</ENAMEX> and his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'70</TIMEX>'s group
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.Rex</ENAMEX>), trf (pronounced truf), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zard</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€¢ English</ENAMEX> names written in romanji: a (always glossed
in parentheses as alpha), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Access</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CoCo, Damn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dreams Come True, Escalators Vanilla</ENAMEX>
(possibly inspired by the `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60's American bands Vanilla</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fudge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mood Elevators</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strawberry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alarm Clock</ENAMEX>, though made ludicrous in conforming
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> grammar which requires the adjective
to follow the noun), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hound Dog, Jigger's Son</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> backing a girl
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">singer</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tube</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wink</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoo</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€¢ Japanese</ENAMEX> name written in romanji: Mi-ke (a winsome,
snaggle-toothed teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warbler</ENAMEX>.  Mi-ke is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX> name for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€¢ English</ENAMEX> names written in katakana: The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Ducks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J-League Downtown</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> is a soccer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physical</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cruising, Omnibus, Original Love</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> (twin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern All-Stars</ENAMEX>, The
Tempters, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo Performance Doll</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tulip</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tunnels</ENAMEX> (pronounced toenails), Zutorobi
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> pronounced backwards, syllabically
rather than alphabetically!  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seltaeb</ENAMEX>?  Nah!).

<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€¢ Partly Japanese</ENAMEX> and partly Western name written in
romanji: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakufu Slump</ENAMEX> (literally, blast, as in explosion,
slump.  Slump is a loanword used in baseball
and economics).

<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€¢ Partly Japanese</ENAMEX> and partly Western name written in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kanji</ENAMEX> and romanji: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ComÃ© ComÃ© Club</ENAMEX> (literally, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€¢ Pure Japanese</ENAMEX> name written in khanji and romanji:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hikaru GENJI</ENAMEX> (The kanji component, hikaru,
means light (as illumination); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GENJI</ENAMEX>, always capitalized,
seems to be a literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allusion</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shikumi Murasaki</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">c. A.D.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> novel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tale of</ENAMEX>
Genji, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genji</ENAMEX> being the male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>.)

<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€¢ Pure Japanese</ENAMEX> name written in kanji: Otokogumi
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warriors' Group</ENAMEX>)

<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€¢ Pure Japanese</ENAMEX> name written in kanji and hiragana:
Kaguya-hime (literally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sparkle</ENAMEX>, from a
classic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> nursery tale.)

            

            From all this we can clearly deduce that in no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> can the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> be accused of xenophobia--
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguistic</ENAMEX>, anyway!  Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'AcadÃ©mie</ENAMEX> franÃ§aise
might do well to note the above and the albeit absurd
names of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discos</ENAMEX> rendered in
romanji: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maharaja Saloon Sahara King & Queen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disco Maebashi</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maharaja Tokushima Space</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disco Liberazione</ENAMEX> .
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casanova</ENAMEX>'s English




            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years ago</TIMEX> I worked as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> not far from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adriatic Riviera</ENAMEX>,
which is flooded with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>.  Not
surprisingly, some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> came along primarily
to acquire a smattering of spoken <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> to
help them chat up holidaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.  For such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the somewhat tedious rules of English spelling
were of scant interest, I lav you, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pleas com</ENAMEX> and
leave whit me in my aus was typical of the kind of
useful phrase that they might jot down in their
notebooks.  This devil-may-care attitude to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quaint</ENAMEX> rules of English spelling follows firmly in the
illustrious footsteps (or perhaps penstrokes) of the
greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of them all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giacomo Casanova</ENAMEX>.

            Born a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian, Casanova</ENAMEX> led a peripatetic life
which took him through almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
in search of fame, fortune, and female attractions.
In his day <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> was the international language,
spoken by anyone who aspired to a place in
high society in any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but during his brief visit
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1763-64</TIMEX> he made an attempt to pick
up a smattering of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  In his autobiography,
written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years later</TIMEX>, he proudly demonstrates
his knowledge, casually throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> words into
the middle of his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> text with an easy confidence
and some bizarre spelling.

            He arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dover</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1763</TIMEX> in a paq-bot
which he shared with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedfort</ENAMEX>.  His
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen-hour</TIMEX> coach journey took him through
Cantorberi before reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, where he
called on a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of his who now lived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soho Squarre</ENAMEX>.  She did not give him a particularly
warm reception, however, and he was soon on the
lookout for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to rent for himself.  With the help
of an English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, he examined the columns
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertisser</ENAMEX> and quickly found the ideal
bachelor pad--a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pale</ENAMEX>-Male--which he
moved into at once, making sure that the Auskeper
would take on a French-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maidservant</ENAMEX>.

            He was keen to get to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> society soon showed him the
sights.  Being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, he was
naturally interested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, such as those at
Covengarde, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Drurilaine</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hai</ENAMEX>-marcket.
Casanova was also a fervent card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and was
soon invited to play a few robers of visk (or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wisk</ENAMEX>).  Not being accustomed to that particularly
English form of cards, he lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> pounds in his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> game to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Covendri</ENAMEX>.  He was also not entirely
familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> money and mistakenly
paid her fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">guineas</NUMEX>, thus leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Coventry</ENAMEX>
smiling at her unexpected gain of a further fifteen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scheling</ENAMEX> (or was it shelin, seling, or even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chelin</ENAMEX>?).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Casanova</ENAMEX> enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.  He lived near such
attractions as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grim</ENAMEX>-pare and the new royal residence
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bukingan Aus</ENAMEX>.  A brief stroll up WiteAle
took him towards <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chirincras</ENAMEX>.  He could enjoy
lunch at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Staren</ENAMEX>-taverne in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pique</ENAMEX>-Dille
with his good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milord Pimbrock</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pembroke</ENAMEX>],
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> might offer him a plate of
traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> Rochebif and a mug of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strombir</ENAMEX>.  Afterwards they might venture out to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boulingrin</ENAMEX> or, if he needed ready money
quickly, to pawn some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">possessions</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pingbros</ENAMEX>.
He could also admire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wren</ENAMEX>'s splendid new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church of St. Pol</ENAMEX> and the wonderfully efficient
Penni-post which delivered letters around the
capital.

            Casanova was a highly intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a
competent linguist.  Much of his prodigious literary
output, including his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX>-page autobiography, was
written in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, which was a foreign language to
him.  So why was his written <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> so haphazard?
Part of the answer lies in the spell-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-you-like
nature of our language at a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s dictionary
was still a novelty, though while some of his
variant spellings of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">shilling</NUMEX> , for example, are typical
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casanova</ENAMEX>'s spelling
would look more at home in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaucerian</ENAMEX> text than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Englishtenment</ENAMEX>.  Besides, he did
not write his life story till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> after his visit to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, with no more than his memory to rely on
when writing a language he had spoken but, very
likely, not written before.  But most important of all is
that the situation did not worry him.  He loved to
communicate and was happy to charge headlong at
the language and have a go regardless of the risk of
mistakes--an attitude which many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> today
might do well to learn from.

            Maybe it would bring a smile to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casanova</ENAMEX>'s lips
to know that even now, although the world and the
relative importance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language have
changed so much, those of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> who style
themselves as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> retain his enthusiastic disregard
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> spelling.  As he would doubtless
have observed in his perfectly idiomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>,
Plus ca change, plus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">c'est la mÃ</ENAMEX>ªme chose.
         
         
            
Our Hopes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">For The New Year Are Soaring</ENAMEX>!  [From
an advertisement for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Swan Funeral Homes</ENAMEX>, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pictorial Gazette East, .</ENAMEX>  Submitted by
.]

         
         
            
There isn't room to list them all, except it must be
noted that they included the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right to Die Society</ENAMEX> apologizing
for accidentally calling itself the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right to Life Society</ENAMEX>
in a previous letter, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right to Life Society</ENAMEX> objecting
to the theft of its name.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From The Toronto Star,</ENAMEX> .  Submitted by .]

         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire's Syndrome</ENAMEX>




            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>, the political and language columnist
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , has been
concerned about the correct use of the apostrophe
and s with proper nouns ending in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">s</ENAMEX> , particularly
with eponyms, so concerned that he has named a
syndrome for himself: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Safire's syndrome</ENAMEX> --the urge
to correct.  His compulsion emerged when both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> were diagnosed as having
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Graves's disease</ENAMEX>, one of several eponyms for hyperthyroidism,
a common condition caused by excessive
secretion of thyroid hormone.

            Which leads to the use of medical eponyms,
proper names, usually of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> or places, to designate
diseases; their signs and symptoms, alone or in
combination; reflexes, and a host of other medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phenomena</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorland's Medical Dictionary</ENAMEX> , 26th
edition (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>), devotes more than nineteen columns
to short definitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, the vast majority eponymous,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> named for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> who early described
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperthyroidism</ENAMEX>.  Fortunately, only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>'s
name ends in s but his is the overwhelmingly favored
eponym of English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>.  Dorland
also listed 488 signs, again mostly eponymous,
of different diseases, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in thyrotoxicosis.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-five</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> commemorated were
western <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> active between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860 and 1920</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of intensive correlation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bedside</ENAMEX> and pathological findings, whose names now
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">linger</ENAMEX> as historical markers.

            But historical background offers little help in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Safire's syndrome</ENAMEX>, because criteria
for correct use of apostrophes and s 's for
proper nouns ending in s are lacking.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fowler</ENAMEX> noted
the problem favoring s 's but made no specific reference
to the conversion of proper possessive nouns to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjectives; Strunk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> affirmed the propriety
of s's , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gowers</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Complete Plain Words</ENAMEX> ,
prefers s's , a choice of some importance because his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurologist</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gowers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1845-1915</TIMEX>), is remembered for his column,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, fasciculus, sign, solution, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>,
and tract by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorland</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> may sensibly ask, Who owns the eponym?
Some processes are named for early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>,
as is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>, and some for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lou Gehrig</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</ENAMEX>), usually without their
permission or even awareness.  Should the earliest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, the most accurate one or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> most
widely known today be memorialized?  One might
look to modern medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> for guidance but
little is to be had.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annals of Internal Medicine</ENAMEX> ,
organ of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of Physicians</ENAMEX>, abandoned
the possessive form totally in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, protesting
that eponyms are inappropriate when a directly
descriptive synonym is available.  Many medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX>, however, have declined to follow its lead
and medical dictionaries are neither particularly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">helpful</ENAMEX> nor consistent.  By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorland</ENAMEX>'s
28th edition had deleted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> eponymous
entries for hyperthyroidism, retaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> but
now as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Graves disease</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> s and its possessive
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apostrophe</ENAMEX> banished.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stedman's Medical Dictionary</ENAMEX> ,
26th edition (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> ' is
correct, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> lexicon (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>) omits
both apostrophe and s with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> but keeps both
with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parry's disease</ENAMEX> , another eponym for hyperthyroidism.

            Those who prescribe written usage offer no
guide at all as to how to handle the problem posed
by the spoken word.  How can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> let his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> know when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> suffers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eponymously</ENAMEX>?  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scriptwriter</ENAMEX>,
and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> might have thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> were ill with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Grave disease</ENAMEX>.
And there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> , used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to
identify chronic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney disease</ENAMEX> of any cause which
might be called <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Bright disease</ENAMEX> by some.  And what of


Best's <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>--congenital macular degeneration
of the eye

Gross<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">'s disease</ENAMEX>--saccular dilatation of the anal
wall with retained inspissated feces (What
is a directly descriptive synonym for this
process?)

His<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">'s disease</ENAMEX>--trench fever

Little<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">'s disease</ENAMEX>--spastic palsy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX> disease
would pose a nice problem for the TV or radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX>)

<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tooth's disease</ENAMEX>--progressive personeal muscular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">atrophy</ENAMEX> (usually compounded as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charcot-Marie-Tooth</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX>)?

            

            Consider these without 's

            What if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prichard</ENAMEX> were asked to present his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX> article, Whatever Happened to Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beriberi?</ENAMEX>, before an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>?  He reported that
the late, lamented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney J. Perelman</ENAMEX> confessed that
he had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's disease</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson</ENAMEX> had
mine, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenberg</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American</ENAMEX>, asserted
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perelman</ENAMEX> said he had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX>'s disease
and he has <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Parkinson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1755-1824</TIMEX>,
described paralysis agitans and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bright</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1789-1858</TIMEX>, chronic glomerulonephritis).  Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perelman</ENAMEX>
!  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, however, assert that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX>
had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groucho Marx</ENAMEX> disease and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groucho</ENAMEX> had his.
Which then is correct, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s problem, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>, too, are avoided in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linnaean</ENAMEX> nomenclature for biological classification
in that the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> and places are latinized
or otherwise altered, as


<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Salmonella typhi</ENAMEX>, the microbial cause of typhoid
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fever</ENAMEX>, recalls the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bacteriologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmer Salmon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1850-1914</TIMEX>)

Rickettsia rickettsia, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain</ENAMEX> spotted
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fever</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard T. Ricketts</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871-1910</TIMEX>)

Neisseria gonorrhoeae, the German <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.L.S. Neisser</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1855-1916</TIMEX>).

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Safire's syndrome</ENAMEX> would have been of little concern
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>, before eponyms became
fashionable, and, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Language</ENAMEX>, before the adjective possessive
would modify case.  There, possessive is defined
as having possession and apostrophe as In rhetoric,
a diversion of speech to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grammar</ENAMEX>, the contraction of a word; as, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tho</ENAMEX>', for
though.  Use of the apostrophe to indicate possession
or in combining short words, as, isn't for is not,
is not considered.

            However, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Chicago Manual of Style</ENAMEX>, 14th
edition (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), does offer comfort and guidance to
the perplexed, proclaiming that Most proper nouns
including most names ending in sibilants take 's as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>'s poems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>'s theories, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berlioz</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX>.  Among the exceptions are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>', <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>', and names of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> syllable
whose unaccented endings are pronounced eez,
as in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Euripides' or Xerxes'</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Safire's syndrome</ENAMEX> is not limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>.  A
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine Talk</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> tried to
answer the question <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stags Leap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stag's Leap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stags</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leap</ENAMEX>--Which of these spellings is correct in referring
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> of a particular section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Napa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>?  The answer: All of the
above.  The advice to the consumer, Just keep the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apostrophes</ENAMEX> straight.  Just so.
         
         
            
There is not a finite number, I am sure, but it must
be a large number.  [From a review by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Urdang</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Verbatim ,</ENAMEX> , page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>.  Submitted by .]

         
         
            
Lingerie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> works with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Extension</ENAMEX>
to improve bottom line.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subheadline</ENAMEX> in Exclaimer
(published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Missouri System</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln University</ENAMEX>),
.  Submitted by .]

         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Way That They Tell 'em</ENAMEX>




            Total absence of humor, remarked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colette</ENAMEX>,
Renders life impossible.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was correct.  Humor and the ability to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> it have been a fundamental part of human
life from the beginning.  But, as sure as there are
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> that do not travel well, so, too, is there a type
of humor and a form of language that is best appreciated
in the land of its origin.  Or, to be more specific,
in its region of origin.

            My own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, is a classic example.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> humor can be an acquired taste.  It is so distinctly
regional, and it is peculiar to its particular
region as is the language through which it is expressed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> to the region laugh, not so much at
what is said, but at the way in which it is said.  The
listener laughs at the reconteur as much as at the
story itself.

            Listen to the lugubrious drollery of the western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlander</ENAMEX>.  His stories are long and involved, and
they are best heard when you have lots of time on
your hands.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlander</ENAMEX> is a consummate storyteller.
Whether he is relating one in his native
Gaelic or in the lilting <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> that he learned at
school, you can almost hear the sough of the sea on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">far-off</ENAMEX>, never-to-be-seen-again Hebridean machairs
as he speaks.  There is an innocent humor to be
found in his stories, to be sure, but they are stories
that are invariably tinged with a brooding sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sadness</ENAMEX>.  You are glad that you listened, but you are
left with a louring aura of melancholy around you
long after you have taken your leave of him.

            Over on the east coast the humor is sharp and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incisive</ENAMEX>.  It is a sardonic wit, a wit that can be as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savage</ENAMEX> and biting as the dry northern winds that sear
this land for a goodly part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.  It has much of
the pawky vulgarity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glasgow</ENAMEX> wit, but it is different
somehow, much more personal.  It is wit between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.  On the other hand, listening
to the banter between gaggles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glaswegians</ENAMEX> at<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
say, their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barras</ENAMEX> market on any <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> of the year
is like listening to the discordant yakking of jackdaws
around derelict tenement chimneys in the
nesting season.

            Far away from all those, down at the southernmost
tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, both humour and dialect have a
decidedly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> flavor.  With the green glens of Antrim
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a short</TIMEX> hop across the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, this might not,
on the face of it, seem so surprising.  But there is
more to it than that.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigtownshire</ENAMEX> (as the county
was called until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehall</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> dropped
the ancient name in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> and decreed that it be
merged with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dumfries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galloway</ENAMEX>) has been relucant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> to many incomers.  The earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>,
the shy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mesolithic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> and the mysterious
Picts, vanished for ever into the moorland mists before
the invaders.  With them, they took their language.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> came and went, leaving not so much
as a place name behind him.  Indeed, had not his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> been adopted by the scholastic monks of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, little would have remained to show that he had
ever been there in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VENI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIDI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VICI</ENAMEX>,
he crowed smugly.  And then, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian friend</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> so succinctly put it, He just buggered off.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celt</ENAMEX> brought religion and the Gaelic.  In
fact, the eccelesiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninian</ENAMEX> brought Christianity
here long before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columba</ENAMEX> reached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iona</ENAMEX> in AD 563.
Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celt</ENAMEX> left his mark in the many
place names of Gaelic origin scattered around southern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> to this day.  Stranraer, the largest town
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wigtownshire</ENAMEX>, is one such.  Its name means, literally,
fat peninsula, from the Gaelic srÃ²n reamhar .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaelic</ENAMEX> was the mother tongue in Wigtownshire
for twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, but little trace of it remains
in the spoken language <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  It was the pervasive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> who really set the foundation for the
dialect spoken by the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of Wigtown
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>.

            But it was with nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ulster</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>
had the greatest affinity.  Indeed, to this day
they call themselves, and their dialect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galloway</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>.
It is as good a name as any.  Although it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> that they speak, you would hardly think so
when you first hear them in full flow.  It is a lingo
that has little in common with either the slow, precise
enunciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlander</ENAMEX> or the clipped
phraseology of Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NoÃ«l Coward</ENAMEX>.  It is a thick macedoine
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broad Scots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Ulster English</ENAMEX>, and it has a
harsh and uncompromising rasp to it, especially if
you don't understand a word that is being said to
you--which, it might be added, is quite often the
case if you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newcomer</ENAMEX> to that part of the world.
Simple phrases like I wish to dismantle it become
Ah'm gaan <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tae tak</ENAMEX>' it sinnery , and even simpler words
like foolish become glaikit , so that by the end of
your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first day</TIMEX> you are desperately searching for
strong <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreter</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galloway</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of humor.
There can, admittedly, be a bitterly Schadenfreude
quality to some of it, for theirs is a hard life.  But,
more often than not, it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> that surfaces.
Occasionally--and particularly for those not accustomed
to the dialect--their pronunciation of certain
words can lead to embarrassing misunderstandings,
as the following tale from my youth may illustrate:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aul' Wullie</ENAMEX> was a smallholder.  His only interest
in life was his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, and he labored long and hard
among the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> and the whins to wrest a living of
sorts from the reluctant soil.  It was a way of life that
would have crippled many a lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but Wullie
was a tough old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>: when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of his hundredth
birthday dawned he was still maintaining a keen interest
in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> affairs of his little place.

            The old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> would have been content to allow
the occasion of his centenary to pass unremarked,
but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had other ideas.  They arranged a
mighty soiree for the great day, and they invited a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> from the county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> to be there to
interview him.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>--a demurely austere
product of colonial missionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--was on her
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> assignment and she was, in fact, completely new
to this area.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wullie</ENAMEX> seemed preoccupied and the interview
was not going well.  In desperation, she asked him if
there was anything she could do to make his day
complete.  A spark of life glimmered at last in the
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s rheumy eyes.

            Aye, he replied with sudden interest, There
is that, lassie.  Ye cud gie me some sex.

            She recoiled in shock.  When she had recovered
somewhat, her messianic zeal got the better of her
and she reminded him that, at his age, he should be
more concerned with thoughts of the afterlife than
with the prurient temptations of this one.  She would
probably have pursued this subject at some length
had not the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> interrupted her.

            Mebbee ye're richt, lassie, he said, But ah
still need the sex.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ye</ENAMEX> see, ah've got foarty-fower
hunnerwecht o' tatties oot there ahint the byre, an'
ah've nae sex tae pit them in.

            It's the way that they tell'em, as Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Carson</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX>, would no doubt remark.

            It is a peaceful place.  There have been no battles
on its soil since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> times.  Although many of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> have died on foreign shores under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">banner</ENAMEX>, the land itself has slumbered undisturbed.
A single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> jettisoned by a fleeing German
bomber during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1939-45</TIMEX> war plopped into a
remote bog, scaring the living daylights out of a
nesting moorhen, but that was about all.  The horrors
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> blitz belonged to another planet:
things that were read about in newspapers but
which were barely comprehended by the majority in
this tranquil little backwater.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> had entered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> and the European
conflict was drawing to a close.  I was standing
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigtownshire</ENAMEX> forest, eavesdropping on a conversation
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.  They were cynics,
as most old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> are, and neither could be
convinced that the war just ending would be the war
to end all wars.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them, an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>
with the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Guard</ENAMEX>, was particularly eloquent.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tak</ENAMEX>' heed o' whut ah tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Erchie</ENAMEX>,
warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX>, They'll be anither waar yit.  An'
whun it dis stert, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ah wud wadjir ma</ENAMEX> wumman an'
weans <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agin yours</ENAMEX> that it 'ull be a faar waar waar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th'n</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>' last waar wur.

            Indeed it will.  But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">invader</ENAMEX> had better come
prepared if he ventures beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hadrian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX>.  He
is in for a long, long haul in the wind and the rain
and the sleet if he wishes to master the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galloway</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANTIPODEAN ENGLISH</ENAMEX>
            
         
         
            More Famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> Etymologies




            A little learning has always been a dangerous
tool in the mind of the amateur etymologizer, and
early acquaintance with one or more of the languages
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> Aborigines not infrequently
proved seductive.  Take that universally popular
caged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>, the budgerigar , first encountered in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inland of New South Wales</ENAMEX> and known to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the 1840s</TIMEX>.  Its name was first written
down as betcherrygah , that being a transliteration of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yuwaalaraay</ENAMEX> word gijirrigaa (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yuwaalaraay</ENAMEX> being
a language similar to the better-known <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamilaroi</ENAMEX>),
but the temptation to explain the word had triumphed
over the etymologizing process as early as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848</TIMEX>, when the spelling budgery garr was preferred,
and the first element explained as meaning in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>'s language--good or handsome.  It is true
enough that budgerry (or bujari as it is more correctly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcribed</ENAMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> language Dharuk
meant good.  But in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> language only, its
familiarity to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> ears being the result of its taking
on in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> pidgin as a term of approbation
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 1790</TIMEX>.  What more natural than that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> perception of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> destined to become a
plaything of the western world--as evidenced by
another of its names, the lovebird --should become
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paramount</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> now the shortened form
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budgie</ENAMEX> is in more common use--but that is another
story.

            Another world that exercised the etymological
imagination is billabong , which owes its currency
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> to the familiarity of the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waltzing Matilda</ENAMEX> , of which it is a crucial part.
Here again a word was broken down into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billa creek</ENAMEX> and bang or bung dead, and
little thought given to the fact of their independent
origin.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billabong</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recorded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1830s</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southeastern New South Wales</ENAMEX> as a name in the
Wiradhuri language for a watercourse which flows
after rain, and hence any backwater, blind creek, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anabranch</ENAMEX> left in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> of a river, a pool which is
left when the connecting stream dries up.  It is not
the source of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">billy</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> dialect word for a milk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pail</ENAMEX>, nor does it have anything to do with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Queensland Aboriginal</ENAMEX> word bung dead, which
passed into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> pidgin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1840s</TIMEX> and which
developed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1880s</TIMEX> the application bankrupt,
as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s gone bung .  Tempting as this suggestion
may be, it is geographically and chronologically
impossible.

            Yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> word, borak , was held by
some to be the etymon of barrack , although the probability
has to be that this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> regional dialect
word given a new lease of life in fresh circumstances.
Borak was a negative in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> language
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wathawurung</ENAMEX> and was one of a comparatively small
number of words which the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> languages collectively
contributed to an on-the-whole short-lived
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> pidgin.  Borak was borrowed in the late
1830s and, perhaps because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharuk</ENAMEX> negative
baal was already in use, did not last long in its primary
sense.  But it almost simultaneously developed a
secondary sense as a noun meaning nonsense, rubbish,
a synonym for the more frequently used gammon ,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> cant word for guile or deceit that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convicts</ENAMEX> brought with them and which also moved in
the direction of nonsense or humbug.  Oddly,
borak was coupled with the verb poke in the phrase to
poke borak at , meaning to deride, and this was close
enough to the transitive use of the verb barrack ridicule,
jeer at, verbally abuse to suggest that the two
might be connected.  And, in the absence of a memory
of its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> use, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aboriginal</ENAMEX>, being to hand,
seemed to some a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.

            Again, what needs to be taken into account is
the balance of probabilities.  It is unlikely that a borrowed
word would undergo a significant change in
form so quickly and, with hindsight, it is more likely
that an impreciseness of meaning caused by unfamiliarity
should attend the bringing into vogue of a
word amongst those who did not have a dialect
memory of it.  So barrack , attested as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> term for bragging, shifts slightly but not contextually
in meaning to the vociferous denigration of
a sporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in a fight, and admits
the converse of this in the intransitive verb barrack
for support.  And the less said the better about another
conjectural etymology which would have it
that this partisan practice began in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> and
characterized the behavior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> at the police
barracks end of the ground.

            Such behavior was often associated with larrikins .
And the etymology of this word has also been
hotly disputed, even if mostly by the lunatic fringe.
The golden rule has to be that, if there is a historically
valid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, it is to be preferred unless the circumstantial
evidence makes a mockery of it.  In this
case the presence of a high proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> regional
dialect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> amongst the convicts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>
who emigrated or were transported to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
argues incontrovertibly in favor of a dialect origin if a
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">etymon</ENAMEX> can be shown to exist.  One can,
even if there is a perceptible difference between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">benign OED</ENAMEX> definition a mischievous or frolicsome
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> a young urban rough.
The circumstantial evidence provided by the historical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>'s quotations documents the shift, and
there is no case for resorting to the fable that the
word derives from the description of such youths
larking about.
         
         
            Some Secrets of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Nicknames</ENAMEX>



            Names are a tricky subject in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as in any
language, but happily a very few facts go a
long way towards explaining the origins of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> nicknames and family names.  Many family
names are patronymics, so called because they
are based on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name of some long-ago <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> patronymics fall into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> common types:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s name alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Will</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
name plus possessive -s , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Williams</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wills</ENAMEX> ,
meaning, in effect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
name plus -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Williamson or Wilson</ENAMEX> .
(Sometimes spelling disguises the clarity of these
forms: for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davies</ENAMEX> is really <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davy</ENAMEX>'s
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> .)  Not all patronymic-like
names are based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s name; they might also
recall an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lord</ENAMEX> , or a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX>,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jillian</ENAMEX> (from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juliana</ENAMEX> ).

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patronymic</ENAMEX> can be based on a full name ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>-s )
or a nickname ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>-s ).  That is important because
many familiar patronymics are based on otherwise
obsolete nicknames, as we shall see.  A lot of
these ancient nicknames had cute diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">suffixes</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> of these remains productive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">- y or - ie</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy or Willie</ENAMEX> , but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle English</ENAMEX>
had several others at hand.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> provided
- kin , as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>-kin and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom-kin</ENAMEX> , whence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tompkins</ENAMEX> ; and - cock , as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>-cock , whence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilcox</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> provided - ot , as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>-ot and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip-ot</ENAMEX> ,
whence the surnames <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philpott</ENAMEX> ; and -in
or -on , which could turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary to Marion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick to Dickon</ENAMEX> (whence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> (whence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robbins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> ).  All of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suffixes</ENAMEX> show up again and again in surnames, so
they can be quickly recognized.

            Harder to recognize are certain distortions imposed
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names when they are
clipped down to nicknames.  Usually, to make a first
name into a nickname we just pluck out the most
prominent syllable, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue from Susan</ENAMEX> , and either
leave it plain or make a diminutive out of it by adding
- ie or - y: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susie</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzy</ENAMEX> .  Some names refuse one or
both of these tricks ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX> makes only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie</ENAMEX> , not
* <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laur</ENAMEX> ); but they are about the only ones left to us in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Modern English</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle English</ENAMEX>, however, had
many other ways to play around with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name to
make new nicknames, including the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> patterns
of consonant substitution discussed below.  Many of
the resulting forms remain current as nicknames (or
indeed as names in their own right), others are preserved
only in patronymics, and still others have
vanished entirely.  Listed below by consonant category
are all the forms I have been able to find, regardless
of their modern currency.  Some of the
stranger ones are from a list in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas Nugent</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Pocket Dictionary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Languages</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1834</TIMEX>).  Note that a few names
fall into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> category.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)  r becomes d or h.  This affects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just three</NUMEX>
names: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dob</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hob</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX> makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodge</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX> , or
Hitch --though not * <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ditch</ENAMEX> , apparently!  This is the
origin of the surnames <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobbes and Hopkins</ENAMEX> (i.e.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobkins</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Hitchcock</ENAMEX> ,
among other things, including some famous sobriquets.
Yokels, for example, are called hicks in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and hodges in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>; and because workhorses
once often sported the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX> , we call a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prototype horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Old Dobbin</ENAMEX> and our ancestors
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rocking horses hobby horses</ENAMEX> .  Pursuing a favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pastime</ENAMEX> was known as riding one's hobby <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> ,
the origin of hobbies .  There are also some similarlooking
names that merit attention.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
seems to have been created by phonological assimilation,
the final b attracting an initial b , but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX> have no corresponding nicknames * <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bick</ENAMEX>
and * Bodgee .  The surname <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodd</ENAMEX> is rooted in an obsolete
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodda</ENAMEX> (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodson</ENAMEX> seems to
be a variant of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgson</ENAMEX> ).  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hud of Hudson</ENAMEX> was a
nickname for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh</ENAMEX> ; another name
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rooted in Hugh</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchins</ENAMEX> , via the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> diminutive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huchon</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)  r becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">l.  Thus Dorothy to Dolly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal</ENAMEX> (and also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry to Hal</ENAMEX> , via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mal</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peregrine to Pel , and Sarah to Sally</ENAMEX> .  It
is comforting to find that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolley Madison</ENAMEX> was christened
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothea</ENAMEX> , and perhaps not so comforting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX> shows up also in gun molls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters girlfriends</ENAMEX>.'

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)  r vanishes.  This was happening long before r-
dropping became common in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> accents: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Babs, Bartholomew to Bat, Bridget to Biddy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher to Kit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy to Dot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances to Fanny</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harriet to Hat, Herbert to Hab or Hub</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> to
Judd, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret to Maggie</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meg, Margery</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madge</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattie</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theresa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tess</ENAMEX> .


            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)  I vanishes.  Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice to Assy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gib</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melissa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip to Phip</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pip</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wat</ENAMEX> --and perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles to Chaz</ENAMEX> , though I think
that is just a joke pronunciation for the abbreviation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chas</ENAMEX> .  As nicknames, most forms in this set are obsolete,
and perhaps for good reason: I knew a Melissa
who absolutely hated being called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Missy</ENAMEX>.  But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gib</ENAMEX>,
Phip , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wat</ENAMEX> survive in patronymics: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibbons</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibbs</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phipps; Watson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> .  Electrical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">watts</ENAMEX> were named for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> engineer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Watt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will recall <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wat Tyler's Rebellion</ENAMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1381</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> or h becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">n.  Thus Abigail to Nab</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambrose</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne to Nan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ned</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eleanor or Helen to Nell, Humphrey to Nump</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac to Nykin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nib, Obadiah</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nobs</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver to Noll</ENAMEX> .  These nicknames originated as possessives,
since <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle English</ENAMEX> words beginning with
a vowel or silent h took the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">possessive mine</ENAMEX> instead
of my ; so instead of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>,  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said mine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>,  which was reinterpreted as my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan</ENAMEX>,  just
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> once called an eft or an ewt is
now known as a newt.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of these nicknames
developed notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Cromwell</ENAMEX>
was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron Noll</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s verses of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambrose Philips</ENAMEX> ensured the everlasting fame of his
nickname, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Namby Pamby</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)  m becomes p.  This applies to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> names:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meg</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Margery</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">makes Paige</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattie</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mal</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pal</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polly</ENAMEX> .  All Pattys
nowadays are probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricias</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nugent</ENAMEX> did list
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty for Martha</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>)  th becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">t.  Thus Anthony to Tony</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartholomew</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart or Bat</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cat</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kitty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy to Dot</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Dorrit</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth to Betty</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bet</ENAMEX> (whence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bessie</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martie</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattie</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nathaniel to Nat or Nate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theresa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tess</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas to Tom</ENAMEX> .  In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1600s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classical</ENAMEX>
words and names such as these was pronounced
as plain t after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> fashion, as is still the case
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and the other nicknames in this
set are partly just phonetic spellings of the old
sounds of the full names.  Note that the old t-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
sound survives also in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Theresa</ENAMEX>, the river
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> pronunciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX>, and the name of the spice thyme , usually
called time.

            In the nicknames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nobs</ENAMEX>, the suffix -s is
an old diminutive suffix like - y; in fact, a few nicknames
apparently combine the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suffix</ENAMEX> still surfaces occasionally, as for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wills</ENAMEX>.  (This is
distinct from the patronymic - s of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wills</ENAMEX> .)  One
last diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">suffix</ENAMEX> is - o , a macho one for boys
only-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tommo for Tommy</ENAMEX> .  This has a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>,
but it is older than it looks: in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Butler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudibras</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the late 1600s</TIMEX>, I find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralpho</ENAMEX> .
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Badges Redux</ENAMEX>




            Everyone remembers the classic scence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Treasure</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Madre</ENAMEX> in which the banditos
encounter that dark-minded prospector, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humphrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX>, in the rugged <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains of Mexico</ENAMEX>.

            I found a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha ha ha ha</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ha</ENAMEX>!, reports a subordinate bandito (in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>) to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.  She was hidden.

            Bandito Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso</ENAMEX>
Bedoya, calls out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oiga SeÃ±or</ENAMEX>: We are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federales</ENAMEX>.  You know, the mounted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.  (He
pronounces it mohnted.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX>: If you're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, where're your
badges?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedoya</ENAMEX>'s smooth <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mayan</ENAMEX> face contorts into a
sneer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Badges</ENAMEX>?  We ain't got no badges.  We don't
need no badges.  And, shouting angrily, I don't
have to show you any stinking badges!

            This brief soliloquy is notable in several respects.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> and most obvious is its use of repetition,
perhaps the simplest poetic device.  And it
might also be considered an example of pleonasm,
the use of more words than those necessary to denote
mere sense; redundancy, or tautology.

            But most remarkable is that only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> sentence
is grammatically correct.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are
merely slang, but by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedoya</ENAMEX> has become
so enraged that he resorts to speaking correct
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.

            I submit that he does so because he knows he will
thereby communicate more effectively.  As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood Crutch</ENAMEX> remarked, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> were taught standard
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> instead of that acceptable to their peer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> in order to facilitate communication between
class and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> .
... [his emphasis]  In this instance, standard English
serves to bridge the gap between bandito and gringo .
(But lest we succumb to the modern fantasy that open
and honest communication will solve all disputes, we
must also recall that soon after Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedoya</ENAMEX>'s last assertion
the shooting starts.  Perhaps if he had displayed
some badges, authentic or otherwise, he might
have more easily achieved his objective.)

            Furthermore, in speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">correct English</ENAMEX>, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedoya</ENAMEX> also reveals his identity as a relatively learned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, undoubtedly a major reason that he is the jefe of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>.  Emotion will betray character every time,
and education is power.
         
         
            
All but a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who confessed,
and later hung himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>--were soon set
free.  [From The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , .
Submitted by .]
         
         

            Inflation rears its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in the strangest places.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Flanders</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Treasures</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,21</NUMEX>] includes
a face like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37 days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>.  When I first
undertook the study of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>) the expression was ein <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gesicht</ENAMEX> wie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drei Tage Regenwetter</ENAMEX> haben .





         
         

