
   
      
         
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dia</ENAMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>'s Corner




            A letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> once accused The [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> and
Mail , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of record, of setting a
new record for splitting an infinitive.  A front-page article
ended in the phrase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX> said that in order
to after which the notice SEE <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. A16</ENAMEX> was inserted, and
on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A16</NUMEX> the sentence was indeed completed as
promised: balance the budget, expectations would have
to be lowered.  That is some split!

            However, writing letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to complain about
split infinitives is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s play for the truly obsessed.  As a
self-confessed obsessive when it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>'
errors, my own pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeveâ</ENAMEX>€”one which all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX>
news services and most of its major news magazines
seem to be guilty ofâ€”is leaving diacritical marks off foreign
words.  To their credit, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> news services (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , are usually quite careful to get it right.  Sometimes
these omissions are genuinely trivial.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montreal</ENAMEX> is
quite acceptable; MontrÃ©al would be pretentious except
perhaps in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>.  But sometimes they are not trivial at
all, because a diacritical mark can change the pronunciation,
the spelling and therefore even the meaning of a word.

            In general, diacritical marks are all those little jots
and tittles that appear over, under, and even through various
letters.  We don't have many in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>; the only common
one I can think of offhand is the diaeresis (as in the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dots over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">naÃ¯ve</TIMEX> ). where it indicates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> vowels
side by side are not a diphthong but separate, distinct
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vowels</ENAMEX>.  IsraÃ«l is an example which is not seen much any
more; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ZaÃ¯re</ENAMEX> is seen occasionally; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HaÃ¯ti</ENAMEX> is common in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, where it is pronounced as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> syllables, but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> standard seems to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> syllables).  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> still insists on coÃ¶perate .

            Related to diacritical marks are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> constructs, the
ligature , which is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> resulting from tying together
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more standard letters, and the digraph , which is
a special case of the ligature .  The term ligature is usually
reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>'s conventions (that is, where combinations
like fi, ffi, fl , and ffl are linked together to form a
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>), whereas the digraph .  while graphically
tying together <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, actually represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
diphthongs which were common in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>: after the invention
of printing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin/Romance</ENAMEX> ae became Ã¦,
and oe became Å“.  These are almost never seen in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but they are still occasionally encountered in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and other varieties of English influenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
practice, although it is usually the unligated form that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> encounters, not the digraphs.
The most common example used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> encyclopedia
vs. traditional non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">encyclopaedia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">encyclopÃ¦dia</ENAMEX> ).
However, as even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> spell this word the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> way
now, the best examples of current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>/non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> dichotomies
in the use of the digraphs can be gleaned from the world
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and science, as in gynÅ“cology/gynecology,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hÅ“matology/hematology, Å“sophagus/esophagus, Å“strogen/</ENAMEX>
estrogen, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cÅ“sium/cesium, Å“dema/edema, Å“strus/estrus,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pÅ“diatrics/pediatrics .</ENAMEX>  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, one rarely encounters
in common usage the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spellings</ENAMEX> listed, but, while
they continue to be widely used by medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>,
even that practice has come under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> influence.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diacritical</ENAMEX> marks can be broken down into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accents</ENAMEX>, which affect, roughly speaking, pronunciation
only; and umlauts, which affect spelling as well as pronunciation.
As already mentioned, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is relatively
sterile when it comes to diacritical marks; true <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> can
best be struck in foreign fields, where the accent grave,
accent aigu , and the circonflexe .  The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> accents are used
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> to change the value of e , which is the most common
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vowel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>) and which comes in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> varieties as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s soupâ€”hence the need for
some kind of regulation by diacritical marks.  The circonflexe ,
on the other hand, is really a sign of orthography ,
not pronunciation, being a reminder of a dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sâ</NUMEX>€”it
is usually there for historical reasons but connoting a reason
which has long since ceased to make sense and which
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> have probably been blithely
unaware of.  Thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Ã®le reminds us that the word
was once spelled isle , from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> insula; the name of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AoÃ»t</ENAMEX> , reminds us that it came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">augustus</ENAMEX>; and Ãªtre betrays its origins as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> esse with
the same orthographical scar.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, being a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>-derived language, is also very
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> in digraphs, which are often still retained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, but are dying out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>: cÅ“ur and Å“uvre are
common examples.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> has no pure accents that I can think of (other
than the occasional diaeresis in foreign proper nouns,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IsraÃ«l</ENAMEX> ), but it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very common ligature and,
of course, the umlaut which is much like a digraphâ€”in
fact, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are essential to proper spelling, and
it is for that reason that a dropped umlaut may be seen
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>.  The common ligature in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> orthography
is the esszet (Î², <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î²</NUMEX>) and there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> vowels which
can take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">umlaut (Ã¤</ENAMEX>, Ã¶, and Ã¼ ).  The esszet (pronounced
ess-tset) was formed when mediÃ¦val (for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medieval</ENAMEX>) humanists got carried away and tried to force
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GrÃ</ENAMEX>¦co-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mould</ENAMEX> of grammar and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spelling</ENAMEX> (a disease that spread to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Isles</ENAMEX>, too).

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, the sigma that is written in the middle of a word
(Ïƒ, called <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medial sigma</ENAMEX>) is different from the sigma at the
end of a word (Ï‚, called final, or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal sigma</ENAMEX>).  In
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">mediÃ¦val Latin</ENAMEX> the two s's were also differentiated: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">âˆ</NUMEX>« was
the medial s, and s the terminal s.  This convention persisted
until recently.  In microfilms of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1881</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">census</ENAMEX>, I have come across names like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agneâˆ«s</ENAMEX>, who was
sometimes noted as being a dreâˆ«smaker.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, this
double-s, âˆ«s, eventually evolved into Î².  The diphthongs
ae, oe, and ue appear so often in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> that mediÃ¦val
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scribes</ENAMEX> started writing the e above the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> vowel, something
like this: \?\.  As they were writing with flat-pointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pens</ENAMEX>, which tended to emphasize the vertical strokes
(especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fraktur</ENAMEX>, the so-called gothie script of old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>) the little superior e came to be represented by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> short, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">vertical strokes</ENAMEX>, which then became <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> square
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dots</ENAMEX>.  Then, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX> adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> letters during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">pre-World War II</ENAMEX> era, they became <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> round dots.
I have always thought that the Ã¼ was a perky little characterâ€”draw
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> around it and you get that ubiquitous
Californianism, \?\.

            
The convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is to transcribe the
umlautâ€”to restore, as it were, the lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">e. Hence</ENAMEX>, the
Hanseatic port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LÃ</ENAMEX>¼beck is properly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luebeck</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
Similarly, the esszet should be transcribed as ss, never
as B, which I see often.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> languages also have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> similar
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> umlauts: besides the Ã¤ and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Ã¶</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> have Å“ (a + e as in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> also have Î¸ (o + e) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
use a (a + a).  The rules for transcription are similar to
those for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> words: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alborg</ENAMEX>=<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aalborg; KÎ¸benhavn</ENAMEX>=
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koebenhavn</ENAMEX> (of course, in this case there's a perfectly
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">acceptable English</ENAMEX> equivalent, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copenhagen</ENAMEX>).  As an interesting
aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> alphabetizes words as if the umlauts
were transcribed (so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KÃ¶ln</ENAMEX> would come before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>, for
instance), but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> languages treat their
umlauts as trans-z <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (so in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> phone books,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ã–dlund</ENAMEX> would come after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZetterstrÃ¶m</ENAMEX>).

            
News <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that drop umlauts might deserve some
sympathy; given the isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX>, the
assumption is easily made here that the umlaut is an extraneous
character that can be droppedâ€”as accents in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
often are when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> words are transcribed into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englishâ</ENAMEX>€”without
doing bodily harm to the word in question.
However, dropping umlauts is less forgivable than dropping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accents</ENAMEX>, because accents describe pronunciation,
and anyone who is familiar with the word will know how
it is supposed to be pronounced, regardless of the accent.
If you have heard the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean ChrÃ©tien</ENAMEX>) pronounced correctly, or if you are sufficiently
acquainted with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> to know this fairly common
name (which means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>), you do not need to
know that an acute accent is usually put over an e to indicate
that it is a long e in an unstressed syllable.  Hence,
its omission will probably not stop you from pronouncing
ChrÃ©tien correctly (that is, with the emphasis on the second
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">syllable</ENAMEX>).

            
Umlauts are not simply accents, however: they are
fundamental to the spelling of a word and should always
be transcribed as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ae</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">oe</ENAMEX>/ue (or aa in the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scandinavian</ENAMEX>
a) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> sets that do not provide umlauts.
In any case, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> place names
have English equivalents: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MÃ¼nchen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cologne for KÃ¶ln</ENAMEX>, the aforementioned Copenhagen
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KÎ¸benhavn, Gothenburg</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GÃ¶teborg</ENAMEX>, and so on.
However, I recently read an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> account of
a neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> demonstration in a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nurnberg</ENAMEX>.
The problem here is that this is neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish nor fowl</ENAMEX>.  It
is not the correct <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> name for this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, which is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nuremberg</ENAMEX>, and it is not the correct <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> name, which
is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NÃ¼rnberg</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuernberg</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> strongly suspects that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> simply did not know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> name for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NÃ¼rnberg.</ENAMEX>  Yet more confirming evidence to the pessimists
amongst us who lament the deterioriation of standards
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and abusers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Tongue</ENAMEX>, especially
cis-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            
If there are any questions, comments, that arise from any
edition of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX>, please feel free to contact me (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>) atâ€”.  I'm also open to suggestive topics for next trimester's
edition.  [From a newsletter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Quality Management</ENAMEX>, published
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OAO Corporation</ENAMEX>, .  Submitted by
.]
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galling Gallicisms</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> English



            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Companion</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Language</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCEL</ENAMEX> ) is missing an s at the end of its title, for it
has headings for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than four hundred</NUMEX> varieties of our
multivaried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> tongueâ<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">€”Australian English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Vernacular English</ENAMEX>, etc.
Some of the varieties are unfamiliar, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babu English</ENAMEX>,
a mode of address and reference in several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indo</ENAMEX>-Aryan
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languages</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindi</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> working forrajahs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landlords</ENAMEX>, etc.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> tongue is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mutants</ENAMEX> listed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCEL</ENAMEX> , and I am constantly being reminded of the peculiarities
of my usage.  After giving an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> telephone
receptionist my phone number, I added, My local is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">222</NUMEX>.
Your what?  she retorted.  I quickly corrected myself:
My extension is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">222</NUMEX>.  I left a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newfoundland</ENAMEX> customer
perplexed when I told him that I would try to find an item
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our filials , instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> .  I am guilty of
speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Quebec English</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>, it is taken for granted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> affects
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> hears expressions like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">le</ENAMEX> snack bar, chequer
(instead of verifier ), and un towing a tow <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.  In the
business world one encounters a myriad of Anglicisms
like meeting, cash flow, down-size , and business itself.
The presence of these borrowings make some Quebecois
feel that their language is under threat.  More and more,
however, the flow is not unidirectional: most English-speaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monolingual Quebecer</ENAMEX> will use metro for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>,
dÃ©panneur for convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> , and caisse populaire
instead of cooperative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> .  The following demonstrates
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> influence on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Quebecois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>:



The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>) at the polyvalent (high
school) believed that scholarity (education) was being
affected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> consecrating (devoting) more
time to manifestations (demonstrations) about the
dress code than to their notes (grades).  During his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conferences</ENAMEX> (lectures), their inattention was hurting
their apprenticeship (learning of the subject matter).
He also felt he was getting collaboration (cooperation)
from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confreres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anglophone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francophone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>), and Allophone
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of neither <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>) in better
serving the collectivity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>).  He thus had
a rendezvous (meeting) with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Director-General</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monsieur Gendron</ENAMEX>, and stated that it
was a primordial (essential) consideration that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> be let go before they reached permanence
(tenure) under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>) agreement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monsieur Gendron</ENAMEX> wrote back saying that he had
requested a subvention (grant) in the annex (appendix)
to his planification (policy) budget to the confessional
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">denominational</NUMEX>) school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> in order that formation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modalities</ENAMEX> (training methods) could be created to
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> more dynamic animators (group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>).
            

            Although terms like collaboration, rendezvous , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">annex</ENAMEX> might be used in non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">contexts</ENAMEX>,
they read like inappropriate choices from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">synonym dictionary</ENAMEX>,
and cooperation, meeting , and appendix seem
more natural.

            The trend towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallicization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in
Quebec coincides with the introduction of pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
legislation around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>, and the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
has gained in prestige as a result, making it more likely for
Gallic loanwords to appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  Anglophones are
speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French</ENAMEX> to a greater extent at home and at work,
creating a situation in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> term becomes more
familiar than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  Thus, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglophone</ENAMEX> might use
the word demand when he means ask, reparations when
he means repairs, and remark when he means notice,
because he is constantly employing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demander</ENAMEX>, rÃ©parations ,
and remarquer when speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French</ENAMEX>.

            These faux amis (false <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>), as they are called,
are confused both by Anglophones speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French</ENAMEX> and
Francophones speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  They are also among
many of the words likely to have their meanings changed
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Quebec English</ENAMEX>.  For example, rÃ©sumer does not mean
to resume but, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> know from their adoption
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rÃ©sumÃ©</ENAMEX> for curriculum vitae, to summarize; and decevoir
means to disappoint, not to deceive.  Not many Anglophones
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> today use resume and deceive in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> sense, but over time I suspect that such usages
will increase.

            It is often hard to know where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> and French
begin and end.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franglais</ENAMEX> includes such classics as hot-dog
steamÃ© all dressed , and a rock music review which declared
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s appeal was to male white trash de vieille
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">souche</ENAMEX>.  Vieille souche is a term that refers to old stock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quebecers</ENAMEX>.

            To those who bemoan the loss of the chastity of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> language, all I can say is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> never was
a virgin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> is essentially mutated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> corrupted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaulish</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germanic</ENAMEX>, to name a few of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seducers</ENAMEX>.  Even the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> , owes its
name (as does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> ) to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>.  Language
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purity</ENAMEX> is a myth.  The reality is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> and French
have been borrowing from one another since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 1066</TIMEX>.
Ironically, some of the dreaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anglicisms</ENAMEX>, like rosbif
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> , were originally Gallicisms that had penetrated
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>.
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of Wordsmiths



            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX> remarked that language has bloomed
from the infinite fumblings of anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.  We
meddle constantly with our linguistic roots, grafing suffixes
and slang with equal abandon, and toss the resulting
hybrids about us with the carelessness of toddlers flinging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pablum</ENAMEX>.  Thus are new words born, whether as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>'s
lingo or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wino</ENAMEX>'s mutterings.  But new language blooms
also from the not-so-careless utterances of certain
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, particularly in the field of speculative
fiction.  At least since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Carroll</ENAMEX> intrigued his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jabberwocky</ENAMEX>, there have been writersâ€”Robert
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heinlein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seuss</ENAMEX>, to name twoâ€”who deliberately
minted new words.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Clockwork Orange Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burgess</ENAMEX> invented an entire dialect (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nadsat</ENAMEX>, a Russified
version of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>): I could sort of slooshy myself making
special sort of shoms and govoreeting slovos like Dear dead
idlewilds, rot not in variform guises and all that cal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Herbert</ENAMEX> was also no slouch at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">wordvention:</ENAMEX>
chaumurky, sietch , and heighliner are examples from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dune</ENAMEX> .  Much of it is fresh, serviceable language, not merely
humdrum technical derivatives or the names of gadgets
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, and has certifiable potential to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
language.  Grok , for example.

            But for sheer variety, quantity, and above all charm
of his neologisms, I submit that none compare with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX>, a.k.a.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Holbrook Vance</ENAMEX>.  As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Rawlins</ENAMEX> said,
...to make up words that carry just the right scent, that
strike the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> as new and familiar simultaneously, is
extremely challenging, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> at it.
It is not unusual for a single novel to have fifty or more newly
created words; in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Face</ENAMEX> there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a hundred</NUMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showboat World</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollon Zamp</ENAMEX> advertises for musicians
who ...play instruments of the following categories:
belp-horn, screedle, cadenciver, variboom, elf-pipe, tympany,
guitar, dulciole, heptagong, zinfonella .  In Galactic
Effectuator , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX> tosses off gangee, sprugge, cardenil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bush</ENAMEX>, raptap , and shatterbone in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> orgiastic paragraphs.

            Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX>'s neologisms are nouns, the majority
of them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>.  Others designate
musical instruments or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, denote magical spells,
crystallize cultural concepts or rituals, or express metaphors.
Some, like skak and merrihew , are footnoted with lengthy
explanations about the sociology of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">magical creatures</ENAMEX>.
Terms like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monomantic Syntoraxis</ENAMEX> and Tempofluxion
Dogma reflect his droll skepticism toward religion.  Some
are wonderfully playful, such as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">pinky-panky-poo</NUMEX>, or simply
wonderful, such as scurch and dreuwhy (the latter
alleged to have been drawn from the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX>).  The
adjectives are always vivid: the colors rawn and pallow
and smaudre (which also function as nouns), and squalmaceous
or halcositic.  He also gives us verbs (disturgle,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skirkling</ENAMEX>), a few articles and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal numbers</ENAMEX>, and even
a sprinkling of interjections and appellatives.

            The words may also be categorized according to
whether they are intended to be <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  Clearly most
of them are; we are expected to read them without recoiling,
though we may grope for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>.  Others are
implicitly or expressly taken from an imaginary tongue such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paonese</ENAMEX> or the idiom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirdir</ENAMEX>, or that of the
Water-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> (e.g., the shibbolethic brga skth gz).

            
But the most interesting method of analyzing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neologisms</ENAMEX> is by etymological speculation, which falls into
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly five</NUMEX> categories that shade into one another like
colors in the spectrum.  I list these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> in order of
decreasing distance from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>:

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.  Those that appear to have come into the world de
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">novo</ENAMEX>, from stem to suffix.  We can think of no corollary,
and feel little or no resonance with known wordsâ€”dyssac
(an herb liquor), thawn (a bearded cave-dweller),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bgrassik</ENAMEX> (translation uncertain).

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.  Those that tantalize us with faint echoes of known
words.  The morphemes are rather familiar, but overall
we cannot place them: harquisade (a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> with
glass foliage), marathaxus (a scale from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demon Sadlark</ENAMEX>).  Some of these are ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hauntingly</ENAMEX> familiar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">growths</ENAMEX>, like catafalque <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and hangman <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Dowling</ENAMEX> put it. 
Submulgery, ensqualm, bifaulgulateâ€”the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> runs to the dictionary and is surprised
to find them absent.  Some sound so real that they
flit past like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX> or called strikes, only to awaken
us in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> with the realization that
they cannot be: halcoid, subuculate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manciple</ENAMEX>.
Close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> of such words float unbidden into our consciousness.
We think of subterfuge and skulduggery
to explain submulgery; coaxed by ensqualm, we recall
ensnare, qualm, and squall; for bifaulgulate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ungulate</ENAMEX> and a host of words beginning with the prefix
bi- come to mind.  We are crowded with conjecture.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.  Portmanteau words, the most fascinating and treacherous.
Here the stems are reasonably certain, but they
ignite an extended metaphor.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thasdrubal</ENAMEX>'s Laganetic
Transfer was the spell used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iucounu</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">banish Cugel</ENAMEX> on his search for the euphoriant cusps in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes of the Overworld</ENAMEX>.  One might easily overlook the
hidden word lagan goods thrown into the sea with a buoy
attached.  This is certainly a reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firx</ENAMEX>, the painful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parasite</ENAMEX> installed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cugel</ENAMEX>'s liver to keep his mind on his
task.  Moreover, the phrase is a reminder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX>'s love
of sailing.  Another example is gleft, a kind of phantom,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of which stole part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guyal</ENAMEX>'s brain while his mother
was in labor.  Surely this word arose from glia, a class of
brain cells, and theft.

            
An especially intriguing case is pleurmalion, the tubeshaped
device used by the sorcerer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhialto</ENAMEX> to discern the
location of a precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">textual prism</ENAMEX>, even from great distances
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> and time.  We cannot avoid recognition of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> pleura side or rib.  And mustn't the -malion
fragment refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pygmalion</ENAMEX>, the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> who fell
in love with his sculpture of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and persuaded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aphrodite</ENAMEX> to bring it to life?  We are struck by the insight
that the pleurmalion relates to the lost prism as the biblical
rib to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, bringing it (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">her</NUMEX>) into view and thus to hand.
They must be reunited.

            
Any doubts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX> actually thinks along these
lines are dispelled by a revealing footnote to the word murst
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 16</ENAMEX> of the last book in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Demon Prince</ENAMEX>
series: The meaning of this word, like others in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dreams</ENAMEX> [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">villain</ENAMEX>'s childhood notebook can only be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conjectured</ENAMEX>.  (Must: urgency?  With verst: in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Russia</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>?  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farfetched</ENAMEX>, but who knows?)

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.  In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> are words that draw clearly from identifiable
roots and appendages and combine them according
to traditional rules: calligynics, malepsy, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gynodyne</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photochrometz</ENAMEX>.  These are mix-'n'-match suits of clothes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old English</ENAMEX> roots are readily discernible
(though I cannot explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-etz</ENAMEX> in the last case),
and generate few if any metaphorical overtones.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.  Compounds, straightforward <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alloys</ENAMEX> of real words,
sturdily welded or hyphenated: sagmaw, trapperfish, sadapple,
bumbuster, and the delightfully macabre ghostclutch.
He has even been known to do this in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French</ENAMEX>:
garde-nez nose-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX> is a logical amalgam of garder
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> and pince-nez: An extravagant garde-nez of
gold filigree clung to the ridge of his nose.

            
Such compounds can seduce us into spurious assumptions.
The term elving-platformâ€”a birthing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species hyrcan</ENAMEX> majorâ€”implies the existence of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">verb</ENAMEX> to elve, give birth to an elf! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX> can indeed be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the ridiculous.  (Meanwhile we should not overlook
that hyrcan major is also a fine portmanteau word,
with its references to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyrcania</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of the ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Persian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parthian</ENAMEX> empires, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ursa Major</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> constellation.)

            
Even some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX>'s proper nouns hint strongly at
the existence of daily words: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pancomium</ENAMEX>, the
name of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, suggests a more generalized category
of encomium; reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylas Extranuator</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a spaceship</NUMEX>)
compels us to ask what extranuate might
meanâ€”perhaps strain in wonder?  A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catademnon</ENAMEX> (pungent gust of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> syllables!)
is certainly not merely a confection, reminding us as it does
of condemn, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Agamenmon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parthenon</ENAMEX>, all of which
relate directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emphyrio</ENAMEX> and his tragic fate.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX> has achieved something extraordinary: the
invention of nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1700</TIMEX> interesting new words, a number
sufficient to justify his own dictionary. 
In contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs Dictionary</ENAMEX> 
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dune Encyclopedia</ENAMEX> include many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and places and are thus actually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concordances</ENAMEX> or encyclopedias rather than true dictionaries.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX> is still busily, incorrigibly at work.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neologisms</ENAMEX> remain in their literary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">greenhouses</ENAMEX>,
to be enjoyed only by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.  But some have
escaped and spread like <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> to become part of the language:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heinlein</ENAMEX>'s grok, for example.  How many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coinings</ENAMEX> will infiltrate our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> gab?  Will we send our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies skirkling</ENAMEX>, or drink skull-busters at the corner
bar?  Will our windows be made of translux?  In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Languages</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX> explored the notion of using created
languages as instruments of social engineering.  Let
us hope that his whimsical wordsâ€”Whimsicantâ€”are
already doing just that.
            Rawlins,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demon Prince</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dissonant Worlds of Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borgo Press</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2  Dowling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art of Xenography</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Vance</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Culture <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Novels, in Science Fiction: A Review of Speculative</ENAMEX>
Literature, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vol.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX>, no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>.
            Temianka, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Vance Lexicon</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Ahulph to</ENAMEX>
Zipangote, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underwood-Miller</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.
            McWhorter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George T.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs Dictionary</ENAMEX>: An alphabetical
list of proper names, words, phrases and concepts contained in the
published works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Rice Burroughs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Press</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lanham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>.
            McNelly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. E.</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dune Encyclopedia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. P. Putnam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>.
         
         
            
Child <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safety Prevention Program Offers Little Sisters</ENAMEX>
Sound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategies</ENAMEX>.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Reaching Out</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX> of the Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Greater Boston</ENAMEX>.  Submitted by 
.]
         
         
            
Built of sandstone bricks and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25ft</NUMEX> tall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuller</ENAMEX>'s remains
were placed beneath the floor of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> on his death
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1834</TIMEX>.  [From The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent, , Section</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>.  Submitted by .]
         
         
            
Has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> brought the lowering of voices and
search for common ground called for in the wake of the shootings
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardinal Bernard</ENAMEX> Law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX> and others?
[From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX>, , front-page article
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Aucoin</ENAMEX> (who ought to be made to stand in the corner).
Submitted by .]
         
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem</ENAMEX> of Names



            Recently a brisk, chummy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whom I had
just met asked me what my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name is.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>,
I told her.  Well, now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>...,she began.

            Nobody calls me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, I said gently.  I then explained
to her that it is not so much the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-naming itself that
some of us older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> do not like but the doing it in
a casual way by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we do not know.

            I told her that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know me call me Jock .
I have carried that label from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> of my
life.  I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winnipeg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX>.  My mother
was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> by birth; my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> an immigrant from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nurses</ENAMEX> in the hospital teased him about his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accent</ENAMEX> and began referring to me as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wee Jock</ENAMEX> .  My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> picked it up and I have lived with it ever since.
When I was in high school some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> took delight
in referring to me as an athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX>.  (I like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter De Vries</ENAMEX>' novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Forever Panting</ENAMEX> , who
spoke about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jock Rousseau</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne W. Dyer</ENAMEX>, one of the better-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gurus</ENAMEX>
in pop psychology <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, gave this advice in
his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulling Your Own Strings: Always</ENAMEX> deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name basis unless they make it clear
that they need to be addressed in some other way.  Why
did he use the word need with respect to those of us who
prefer not be called by our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do
not know us at all well?

            I read somewhere that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> was given the name
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camery</ENAMEX> because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> had served in the Queen's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Own Cameron Highlanders</ENAMEX>, a regiment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
army.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> pointed out how unfortunate that was,
as camery , he said, is a disease of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pimples</ENAMEX> appear on the palate.  I was skeptical of that.  So
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> dictionaries.  No mention.  That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>,
I knew, liked to do a little leg-pulling in his writings.
Then I went to the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>: camery is an obsolete
word and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> had simply quoted that dictionary's
definition.  Now I worry a little about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, a splendid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secondhand Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. L. Mencken</ENAMEX>, in one of his more crotchety moods,
said this: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotarian</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to call
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John the Baptist Jack</ENAMEX>.  On the other hand, an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> said this about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Milton</ENAMEX>: I would
venture to assert that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> ever called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">him Johnnie</ENAMEX>.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who appears in two roles in a
play is given as his name for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spelvin</ENAMEX> .  An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georgina</ENAMEX> .  I understand that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
he is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Plinge</ENAMEX> .  I do not know what name they
give to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. G. Wodehouse</ENAMEX> has delighted many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with
the names he gave to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in his wonderful humorous
novels: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeeves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertie Wooster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pongo Thistleton</ENAMEX> ,
and many others.  About the naming of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> he said
this: Odd how important story names are.  It always takes
me about as long toget them to my satisfaction as it does
to write the novel.

            Many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> I found in an abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX>
a copy of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Presbyterian</ENAMEX> , a periodical
published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> and devoted to spiritual uplift and
the sale of patent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> and trusses.  In it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commented</ENAMEX> briefly on a recently published pamphlet
written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Going to Church</ENAMEX> .  He gently
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">castigated Shaw</ENAMEX> for indulging in one of the modish
foibles of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> by calling himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>
rather than use, in the good old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> manner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> .  Then he suggested to his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> that
 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Melchizedec Smith</ENAMEX> looks more impressive than either
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M. Smith</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. M. Smith</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX> I read a brief report on some research
that had been done at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> by a team
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> in which they discovered that the way
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sign their names and use it for public purposes
tells something significant aboutthem.  They said that if
you use <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John J. Doe</ENAMEX> you probably are a very conventional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.  A simple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doe</ENAMEX> suggests that you are rather
outspoken, an assertive loner.  ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX> was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playwright</ENAMEX>'s usual byline.)  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John James Doe</ENAMEX> tends to be
rather proud, and he likes to stand in the limelight.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Doe</ENAMEX> ,
on the other hand, is likely to be excessively modest.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. J. Doe</ENAMEX> is generally a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who likes to remain in the
background, a shy oneâ€”like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. A. Davidson</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. James Doe</ENAMEX>
is a go-getter, and likes to think himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of considerable
importance.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Allen Smith</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">humorist</ENAMEX>, called this, and exemplified in his own usage,
parting one's name on the side.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years ago</TIMEX> I noticed a tendency among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
preachersâ€”a tendency I noticed also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canadaâ</ENAMEX>€”to adopt
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-name pattern.  This particular foible may have
been initiated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Waldo Emerson</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1803-82</TIMEX>), who
had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> before concentrating on being an
important literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Emerson Fosdick</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1878-1969</TIMEX>)â€”notice that middle name, although it may
not be significantâ€”was the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX>
of his time.  And, of course, we must not overlook <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Peale</ENAMEX> .  Would not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N. Vincent Peale</ENAMEX> have given
the eminent positive<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-thinker</ENAMEX> a bit more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>?  (I read
somewhere that a striptease artiste in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> adopted as her stage name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Vincent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peel</ENAMEX> .)
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Turning To Nod Goodbye</ENAMEX>



            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyberspeak</ENAMEX> is ubiquitous.  Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyberwords</ENAMEX>, for
example, download, laptop , and modern are
euphonious, enriching the language.  They are not
loanwords, but here in their own right.  Other terminologies,
especially that of metrication, are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cuckoos</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX>.  In
turfing out the venerable words, they deprive the language
of colour and warmth

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Bennett</ENAMEX> said that any change, albeit for the
better, is always accompanied by drawbacks and discomforts.
One regrets the inevitable parting with words that
have served us since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> times and were here
before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred</ENAMEX>.  Many arrived with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William the Conqueror</ENAMEX>.
Others were absorbed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s time, often
from the great literatures of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sailors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> brought home idioms from distant lands.

            Some words die and are forgotten, but many of those
which wrapped themselves about us like comfy old coats
are stolen off our backs.  So we don <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hectares</NUMEX>, litres, and
milligramsâ€”but not, I hope, without turning to nod goodbye
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">respectfully</ENAMEX> to the earliest form of English bequeathed
by our ancestors.



I like that ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saxon</ENAMEX> phrase, which calls
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX>-ground God's<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-Acre</NUMEX>!

[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longfellow</ENAMEX>: God's<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-Acre</NUMEX>]
            

            Only in phrases like God's<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-Acre</NUMEX> and broadacre does
acre still mean a field of sorts.  Correctly, an acre is a measure
of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4840 square yards</NUMEX> of land, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old English</ENAMEX>
aecer was the fieldâ€”a piece of land cleared for ploughing
or grazing.  An acre's precise definition varied according
to time and place.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acreman</ENAMEX> who paid
a firma , or fixed rent.

            Later an acre was a strip of open field, large enough
to be ploughed by a yoke of oxen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>.  To help the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ploughman</ENAMEX> measure his <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4840 square yards</NUMEX>, a chain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">yards</NUMEX> long was laid along the field's headland, showing
the width to be ploughed.  From here he would plough
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">furlongs</ENAMEX> (i.e., a furrow long), of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">220 yards</NUMEX>.
Come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the ploughman might mark out the village
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">cricket</ENAMEX> pitch, having borrowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22 yards</NUMEX> exactly.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Persons</ENAMEX> of a certain age learned by rote that eight
furlongs make <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX>, and since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9th century</TIMEX>, a furlong
has described <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighth</NUMEX> part of an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> mile, regardless
of its agricultural definition.

            From time immemorial we have used our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> for
measuringâ€”by foot , for example.  An ell , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon eln</ENAMEX> ,
was a rough reckoning, being the distance from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> to the end of the longest finger, the elbow being
where the bow or bend occurred.  Bow is from an old
verb, bugan to bend, and is at the root of rainbow, bow
(tie), and bow (and arrow).

            Using our fingers, we counted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens</NUMEX>.  Numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> emphasize this finger-reckoning.  After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> sheep
had passed him, the shepherd had used up all his fingers.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">etymologists</ENAMEX> believe that endleofon is the
Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> form for left after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>, one left over.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> in Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twa-lif</NUMEX> or twelf , when two
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than ten</NUMEX>) were left.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twa-lif</ENAMEX> represents the elements
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and leave.

            To tell meant to count (as in telling the beads of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rosary</ENAMEX> ); a tale was a reckoning.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'Allegro</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton</ENAMEX>
writes:



And every shepherd tells his tale
Under the hawthorn in the dale.
            

            In telling his tale, every shepherd counted his sheep
as they went past him.  We still tell the time.

            A hand-span is the stretch from thumb to little finger.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, span new was the term applied
to cloth immediately after taking it off the spannans , or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stretchers</ENAMEX>.

            A rod, pole, or perch was measured by a stick, the
Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> rodd being <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5Â½ yards</NUMEX>.  The area of an acre was
standardized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward I</ENAMEX> as being land <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> rods long by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> rods wide.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yard</ENAMEX> (OE gyrd, geard ) is of superior stock: the earth
itself was middangeard middleyard, being the place
between the abode of the gods and the abode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>.
As a suffix it survives in churchyard, dockyard , and
shipyard .

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 1150</TIMEX>, Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> time was reckoned
by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>, not by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> language
flourished in lands where <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> were long and the days
fleeting periods of light.  The light of learning, notes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simeon Potter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Our Language</ENAMEX> , shone more brightly
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northumbria</ENAMEX> than anywhere else in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.  Northumbria
was then on the periphery of the civilised world.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> rightly regard as archaic my
use of fortnight , this word being a survival of the old way
of reckoning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>, by using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX>-night.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
uses sevennights for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> weird
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sisters chant:</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Weary se'ennights</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> times <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
Shall he dwindle, peak and pine.

[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Macbeth i, 3, 20</ENAMEX>]
            

            Reckoning by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> is a relic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> custom
of starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sunset</ENAMEX>.  In the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Genesis too</ENAMEX>,
evening always precedes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>: The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> and the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX>....  The time between light
and dark, twilight , is of the same root as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, twain, twixt ,
and tween , from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old English twa</ENAMEX> .

            A certain drama is attached to words prefixed by
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night -</TIMEX>.  From Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> galen to sing comes nightingale ,
simply the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.  Deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nightshade</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">woody</ENAMEX> nightshade , the narcotic plants commonly known
as belladonna and bittersweet, have their origins in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">nihtscada</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">niht night</TIMEX> and scada shade.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">English mare</ENAMEX> in nightmare means demon or devil.  Tennyson
writes of the black bat, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> of the
foul womb of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.  Better sleep might have resulted from
taking a nightcap or grog (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX> preferred) before bedtime,
helped too by wearing a night cap .

            Small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> of timeâ€” <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> , and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hour â</NUMEX>€”are
borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> secundus, minuta , and hora.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month, week</TIMEX> , and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> are Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> gear, monao, wice ,
and daeg .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day</ENAMEX> has poetical overtones.  The daisy flower
closes its pink-tipped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">petals</TIMEX> (lashes), and goes to sleep when
the sun sets.  In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> the petals open to the light.
Anglo-Saxon for daisy was daeges <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eage day</TIMEX>'s eye.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> uses dayspring for the beginning of the
day; also for the commencement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah</ENAMEX>'s reign:




[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Luke i, 78</ENAMEX>]
            

            Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> springan (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> springen ) became
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">spring</ENAMEX> , but an older word for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that season</TIMEX> marks a period
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Church Year: Lent</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saxon</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> was lencten .
Lenten <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> being frugal and stinted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> has
lenten entertainment in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> , a lenten answer in
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Twelfth Night</ENAMEX> , and a lenten pye in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and Juliet</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Lent lily</ENAMEX> is the older name for the daffodil.



When daffodils begin to peer,
With heigh! the doxy, over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dale</ENAMEX>,
Why, then comes in the sweet o' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>,
For the red blood reigns in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>'s pale.

[A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Winter's Tale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ii, 1</ENAMEX>]
            

            Of unknown origin, doxy is variously the low term
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>, female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tramp</ENAMEX> or beggar, plaything
or paramour [toy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>?], even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>.  In the West
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> were called doxies.

            The oldest words, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, live, fight, love,
sleep , and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> , relate to home and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.  They also
include the counting of time and measuring of space, the
meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, the working of the soil and caring
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX>.  The language was not called Anglo-Saxon
by those who spoke it, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englisc</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engle Angles</ENAMEX>,
Anglo-Saxon being simply the earliest form of the language.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Burroughs</ENAMEX> said that words are an around-the-world,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>-cart way of doing things, awkward instruments,
eventually to be laid aside.  He was thinking of
the space age and no doubt would have included the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberworld</ENAMEX>.  But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Morrison</ENAMEX>, writing in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, says he knows a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who has taken to writing
his stories in longhand, revising them laboriously in
ink, and only then tapping them into the computer.  When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> asked why he did that, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> answered, So
that posterity can compare the various drafts.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
would surely have understood the need.
         
         
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANTIPODEAN ENGLISH</ENAMEX>
            
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dharuk Words In English</ENAMEX>



            When the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1788</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 250</NUMEX> separate languages
spoken by the indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>.  During the 200 years
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> occupation these have declined in use, to the
point where not more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty</TIMEX> are active, in the
sense that they are being learnt by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
cover aspects of the everyday life experienced by those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            These active languages tend to be those spoken in
the north and the west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, in those parts of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborigines</ENAMEX> have been most able to
retain their traditional way of life.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> languages that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> encountered, those once spoken on the east
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, survive only as they were recorded by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> and have been reconstructed in the light of
later acquired knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> languages
as a whole.  Paradoxically, it is these languages that
have contributed most to the lexicon of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
Not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than about 400</NUMEX> words have been borrowed
altogether, and yet of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 60</NUMEX> come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dharuk</ENAMEX>,
the language which was spoken on the site now occupied
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> and not much beyond it, which
existed in an inland and a coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dialect</ENAMEX>.

            Although there are still a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dharuk</ENAMEX> descendants
in the vicinity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>, and these may still use a handful
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharuk</ENAMEX> words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharuk</ENAMEX> effectively ceased to function
as a language by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19th century</TIMEX>.

            What then survives?  Names of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX>, names
of implements, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, a few miscellaneous
names of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwellings</ENAMEX>, ceremonies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> identified by sex
or activity, striking features of the environment, and a
handful of pidgin terms suggestive of an only rudimentary
communicative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX> are characterised by their distinctiveness.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great South Land</ENAMEX> was to prove extraordinarily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> in new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, some of which, like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kangaroo</ENAMEX>, had an irresistible novelty about them; at the
same time they were as numerous as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
and as useful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.  The wallaby and the wallaroo were,
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kangaroo</ENAMEX>, large marsupials which the Aborigines
hunted; the koala was also a marsupial but arboreal in habit
and sufficiently unique in appearance to have had the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> liken it to a bear, a sloth, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> in their naming
of it; the wombat was a heavy, thickset marsupial
sometimes known as a badger because of its burrowing
habit.  The only animal immediately recognisable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
eyes was the native <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> or dingo , and the distinction
was early made between the domesticated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, or
dingo , and the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, or warrigal .  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the small number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> identified were the boobook , an omnipresent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX>, and the currawong , a large, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crowlike bird</ENAMEX> whose
curiosity would have brought it to notice.  The name of a
good eating <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, the wollami or snapper, on which the early
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> were frequently dependent, was again an understandable
borrowing.

            When it came to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, the same sort of criteria
were observed: the waratah, a strikingly beautiful red
flower which has become the floral emblem of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, was soon identified, as were the burrawang , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palmlike</ENAMEX> plant very common in the coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX>, and the
kurrajong , a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that yields a useful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibre</ENAMEX>.

            The name of the dance ceremony corroboree , probably
the most immediately observable characteristic of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peoples</ENAMEX> regarded as savages, which had both a religious
and an informal social form, was readily adopted, as was
koradji a wise elder or, as he was often described, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch doctor</ENAMEX>.

            Weapons like the boomerang, the hielamon (a wooden
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">shield</ENAMEX>), the nulla nulla (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>), the waddy (ditto), and
the woomera (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a spear-thrower</NUMEX>), were identifiable to the
earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> as were also gin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, myall , which distinguished
a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Aborigine</ENAMEX> from his civilised or tame
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, gibber a stone, and gunyah a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling</ENAMEX>.  But the
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of words that characterise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early</TIMEX> period
are those that clearly formed part of a language used for
the limited communication that took place between the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>: cobra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, mundowie foot, bogie to bathe
or a bathing place, crammer to steal, nangry to sleep,
patter to eat, budgeree good, cabon big, cooler angry,
jerron afraid, narangy little, muny very, baal a negative,
and cooee a call or to call.

            Of the several word lists compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Fleet</ENAMEX>, as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> group of convict-laden <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> was
known, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lieut</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Dawes</ENAMEX> is the most ambitious,
attempting a grammar of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharuk</ENAMEX> as well as a vocabulary.
But such a resource is more an indication of what
was available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> than a record of what they
actually used.  For that we must turn to their accounts of
life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> and to the words which they adopted,
which they use more or less unselfconsciously as part of
their language as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX>.

            And here there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> observations to be made.
First, the words used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborigines</ENAMEX> were seldom as
attractive to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> as descriptive <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> names
that emphasised the perceived resemblance between the
new and the known and familiar, and so made for more
certain communication.  Thus, distinguishing epithets like
colonial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX>, wild, black, brown, green , and gray qualify
names of common Old World species like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX>, ash,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oak</ENAMEX> , and pine to build a considerable and understandable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocabulary</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, a positive effort needed to be made
to ascertain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> name, and experience showed
that the geographical range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharuk</ENAMEX> was extremely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>: the fact that a new set of names came into use
as one crossed the boundary of another <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> language
must have mitigated against borrowing.  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the
Aborigines were widely thought of as backward and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncivilised</ENAMEX> and, while this attitude persisted, their nomenclature
carried no great recommendation.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Thoughts on Collective</ENAMEX> Nouns




            Could the thoughts of the estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX> Couple
occasionally turn to an interesting series of collective
nouns that apply to their circumstances?  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s
musings, in her sea of troubles , could go back to her association
with a nayful of knaves , particularly one, one of
an execution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> who have betrayed her confidences.
She has encountered a threatening of courtiers
and an abandonment of confidantes .  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of a
beribboned bundle of love letters would entertain a company
of gossips and a knot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX> for ever, much
to the embarrassment of her eloquence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> .

            Outdoors she is harassed by cassettes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>
and a worship of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> , all of whom are employed by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cluster</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> .

            At school her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are surrounded by a rascal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and, on occasions, a flock of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> .  The young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> have to endure a kissing of aunts and suffer a slew
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>'s reflections are of a non-patience of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>
(both his own and others') and an incredibility of cuck-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">olds</TIMEX> .
He is one of a state of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princes</ENAMEX> who are shod by a
drunkship of cobblers and clothed by a disguising of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tailors</ENAMEX> .
During his sporting activities he is accompanied by
a stalk of foresters while shooting at a column of wildfowl
or riding with a blast of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">huntsmen</ENAMEX> who are escorted by a
kennel of hounds .  His estates are managed by a provision
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stewards</ENAMEX> .

            At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> he is surrounded by a farrago of toadies,
a draught of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butlers</ENAMEX> , and a temperance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>'s affairs are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of a caucus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>,
a noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX> , and a bench of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> , all of
whom are kept informed by a diligence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messengers</ENAMEX> .
Finally, he is devoted to his maternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX> of a dishworship of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> .

         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyberspace</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khyber Pass</ENAMEX>




            The language of the information superhighway is
Englishâ€”more accurately, a sub-species thereof with its
own grammar and semantics.  Since it has come into being
with a sudden and persistent rush, reflecting the burgeoning
and undisciplined information system it conveys,<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
it has not been amply recorded, much less described, in
standard reference works or lexicons.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Shorter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>) and reprinted with
corrections in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX>, does not even include internet .
To fill the gap, specialized glossaries have emerged,
the best naturally in computerized form (like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Jargon</ENAMEX>
File, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version 2.9.6</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 August 1991</TIMEX>), where entries
can be quickly and efficiently updated, a process which
in itself reflects the hasty transience of much of the vocabulary.

            Although a complete linguistic description will have
to wait until the dust settlesâ€”if it does at all, given the
volatility of the technology and the ever-increasing number
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>-certain features, destined to
remain, are already apparent.  As far as grammar is concerned,
the simplistic syntax and the exceptional preponderance
of nouns and verbs (with an accompanying
heavy reliance on conversion) are obvious and enduring.
The vocabulary, like the grammar, is determined to a large
extent by the medium of computers and the operation of
networking.  But their insistence on speed is not entirely
the message.  Nor would it be correct simply to draw comparisons
with newspeak or some other centrally decreed
and regulated system.  For although the vocabulary does
make important use of computer terminology, and although
it does share with newspeak a penchant for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blends</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acronyms</ENAMEX> and an avoidance of adjectives and adverbs, it
reflects a manner and an environment greater than both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">computerese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">newspeak</ENAMEX>.

            Within a strictly controlled computer system, in which
accuracy is absolute, the vocabulary as a whole is programmatically
casual.  Its salient characteristic is its playful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primitivism</ENAMEX>.  It is laid back: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> talks, chats, browses.
Stress (evident in terms like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prowler</ENAMEX>, skulker, lurker , as
well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worm</ENAMEX>, vulture, leech ) is soothed with
(or disguised by) a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linguistic palliatives</ENAMEX>: generous
helpings from pop culture ( cookie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kermit</ENAMEX> )
and science fiction ( cyberpunk, core wars, cosmic rays,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emoticon</ENAMEX> ); chummy diminutives ( archie, newbie, smiley );
and jingly rhymes ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX> mail ).  The iconic word is surfing:
a sociolinguistic cornucopia of connotations of sport,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vigor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, individuality, speed, independence, leisure,
health, and middle-to-upper-class education and affluence.
The vocabulary is jocular in its easy mixture of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">casual</ENAMEX> (in slang or coinages or abbreviations), the learned
(in avatar, baroque, catatonic, synchronous ), the visual (in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hieroglyphics</ENAMEX> or emoticons), and even the aural (in the
fondness for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>, like bang , common spoken name
for !) or onomatopoeia ( bletch, glitch, gonk ).  The vocabulary
is suffisant in its wordplay ( <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A* Infected Disk</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Syndrome</ENAMEX>, sex , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Software EXchange</ENAMEX>) as in the nonchalance
of its central and mixed metaphor: surfing the web ,
borrowed from scanning television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> for a watchable
program.

            The vocabulary is mischievous in the mixtureâ€”and
not just in the ways just mentioned.  One prominent phenomenon
is the flaunting use of homographs: words that
appear in conventional dictionaries are given a meaning
which is not to be derived logically or figuratively from
the customary <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.  Leaving aside <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blends</ENAMEX> and acronyms,
a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> examples (with definitions from various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>) should be sufficient:



advent the prototypical compute adventure game.

arc to create a compressed (archive) from a group of
files using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEA ARC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKWare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICARC</ENAMEX>, or a
compatible program.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biff</ENAMEX> to notify someone of incoming mail [named after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">implementor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> barked whenever the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailman</ENAMEX> came].

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bum</ENAMEX> to make highly efficient, either in time or space,
often at the expense of clarity.

chemist someone who wastes computer time on
number crunching when you'd far rather the
machine were doing something more productive.

flag a piece of information that is either TRUE or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALSE</ENAMEX>.

flame an ill-considered, insulting e-mail or Usenet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retort</ENAMEX>.

jughead an index of high-level gopher menus.

lynx an excellent, text-based, UNIX browser for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretzel</ENAMEX> command key.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strudel</ENAMEX> common (spoken) name for the circumflex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

tin a threaded newsreader for UNIX.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">troll</ENAMEX> to deliberately post egregiously false information
to a newsgroup in hopes of tricking dense know-it-alls
into correcting you.
            

            It may be argued that such personal semantics are
more than mischievous.  But it would be going too far to
assert that they are critical of existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>.  Jargon
or slang and standard have always coexisted and over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have grown more mutually tolerant.  What is clear,
in any case, is that a private and exclusive language is
evolving and engaging ever larger numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
in a linguistic process which is destined to become
more and more public as computer technology itself
becomes the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in communication and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> activities.  From the point of view of language, what
is interesting is the coincidence, be it mischievous or critical
or accidental, of the ideal and the real.  For the examples
of semantic noncomplianceâ€”along with features as
widely disparate as computerese or the variety of registersâ€”begin
to reflect a world-view, the crystallization of
a special sphere.  Real , as in realtime <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> the time it takes real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to communicate, as on a telephone' is set against
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">virtual: 1</ENAMEX>. common alternative to logical.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. simulated;
performing the function of something that isn't really
there.  For netizens , cyberspace is the shared imaginary
reality of the computer networks.  For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, shared
reality is the existence in space and time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khyber Pass</ENAMEX>.

         
         
            Atmosphere English



            As a guest in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> household I was drying my hands
on a towel when, glancing down, I noticed some
writing on it.  I think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> were a little disconcerted
to see me emerging from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> laughing roundly
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of minutes</TIMEX> later.  I hastily told them what it said
on the towel: THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUN WAS SHINING AND THE DUDE</ENAMEX>'S
FAMILY WENT ON <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A PICNIC</ENAMEX>.

            This is an example of what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> call atmosphere <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, particularly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-sounding names
and writing on products add prestige to goods marketed
there, and it is certainly true that atmosphere <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> has
reached its apogee.  This has resulted in such products as
a brand of jeans called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Trim Pecker</ENAMEX> , lawn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertilizer</ENAMEX> called
Green <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Piles, Cow Brand shampoo, Shot Vision</ENAMEX> TV sets,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carap</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocket Wetty</ENAMEX> pre-moistened
towelettes, and a nail-polish remover called Fingernail
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remover</ENAMEX> .  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverages</ENAMEX> are named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calpis</ENAMEX> and Pocari
Sweat , and a coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">creamer</ENAMEX> is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Creap</ENAMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slogans</ENAMEX>, too,
are sometimes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, like this one on a deodorant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">container</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet Medicaâ</ENAMEX>€”it frees you completely from the
smell of your underarm sweat .  Or this, on a bottle of nose
drops: Nazalâ€”for stuffed nose and snot .

            But let us return to for a moment <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sun Was Shining</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dude's Family Went on a Picnic</ENAMEX> .  It turned out
this towel had been made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>.  As is already well
established, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> are the undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of
putting largely meaningless <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> on their products.
Here, however, was an example of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> efforts in the
same direction and, as a long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> here, I am
pleased to note that it is grammatically irreproachable
and makes some sort of sense!  My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other
towel in the same series which they eagerly dug out; it
read: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Evening the Sheep Was Praying to the Twinkling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stars</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dark Sky</ENAMEX> .  I plucked disconsolately at
this towel.  Not at all contemporary, maybe it wasn't the
simple-minded nonsense it seemed, maybe a parody of
Wordsworth perpetrated by a disillusioned towel copy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">writer Ã  la J.K. Stephens</ENAMEX>' celebrated parody of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Voices</ENAMEX> are there: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> is of the deep/And one is of
an old <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-witted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>....  But in the end I decided it
was the simple-minded nonsense it seemed.

            I work with many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, often outside
office <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>.  So, intrigued by the
Dude towel, I furtively began to case their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' T-shirts
(all of which, it turned out, had been bought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>).
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX> I came across the following, starting with
the simplest:



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNOB HOUSE</ENAMEX>

YOUR OWN FEELING

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPP BABY</ENAMEX>

THE <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EMPLOYMENT OF GOOD SENSE IN CLOTHING</ENAMEX>

THE <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">HAPPINESS OF BEING FASIONALBEâ</ENAMEX>€”A POLICY
OF SELF-DETERMINATION
            

            Here, meaning and grammar cannot be faulted (except
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPP BABY</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAP BABY</ENAMEX> would be intelligible if oddâ€”
lactation, paps, pap pabulum), though, with regard to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clothing</ENAMEX>, few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> can be said to conform to the
extent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> does.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">salariman</ENAMEX>'s uniform is well known,
and all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolgirls</ENAMEX> must wear blouses modelled
on those of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese mariners</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of sail.  Some
have said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> even conform in rebellion: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakuza</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>) all dress alike though a little
sharper, e.g. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-colour ties, mean pairs of wraparounds,
tattoos, brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> cuts, and an attitude!

            Next up on the catwalk is a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> modelling
a truly classic T-shirt:



ALL KINDS OF INSECT WARMING

I AM MUCH PLEASED AT YOUR HONESTY

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAUGHTY KIDS BEBE CO.</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BEBE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KIDS FAVOURITE BEBE NAUGHTY CLUB</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLEASE</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> the spelling of favourite â€”the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> is incomprehensible
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British English</ENAMEX>.

            Rivalling haute insect-warming couture is the last
gem my research turned up, a T-shirt bearing the words:



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KIDS COMPANY</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KIDS DREAM</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLITHE MATE</ENAMEX>.

YOU OFFERED <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ME A GOOD PLAN</ENAMEX>, I MADE UP
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MY MIND THAT IT SHOULD BE DONE</ENAMEX>.  IT IS VERY/
THOUGHFUL OF YOU TO DO SO.  I GAIN A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOT OF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">KNOWLEDGE BY THIS</ENAMEX>.
            

            All these slogans are wrought in attractive designs and lettering
and are not intended to be read, so I would like to
express my thanks to those puzzled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who
allowed me to do so.  Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native English-speakers</ENAMEX> confronted
with this manner of stuff will have trouble not sniggering
in their sakÃ© andâ€”horror of horrorsâ€”be asked to
explain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wherein</ENAMEX> lies the humour.

            How do the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> manage to come up with such
copy?  Some have suggested the injudicious use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese/English</ENAMEX>
dictionaries combined with deplorable highschool
English teaching.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Bornoff</ENAMEX>, in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samurai</ENAMEX> , cites some perhaps edifying advertising copy
from a catalogue for bar and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> furniture:



I <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">QUENCH MY THIRST BY A HOT LIQUID OF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMBER</ENAMEX>-COLOURED

THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICE</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROCK-GLASS TICKED AWAY WITH</ENAMEX>
A CRASH

I GET <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRUNK</ENAMEX> ON <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MY FAVOURITE LIQOUR WITH MY</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONGENIAL FRIENDS</ENAMEX>

THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HOME WORLD ONLY FOR MEN</ENAMEX>
            

         
         

            More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Treasures</ENAMEX>




            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idioms</ENAMEX> in other languages can be misleading, for
there are many different and often colourful metaphoric
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> of expressing the same concept.  Here are a few
examples from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">avoir du</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monde au balcon</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. to have the world
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balcony</ENAMEX>] (of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>) to be well-endowed

avoir une peur bleue [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. to have a blue fear.] to
get the fright of one's life

avoir <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">des antennes</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. to have antennae] to have a
sixth sense

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bruit de couleur</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lit</ENAMEX>. a colourful noise] a rumour
