
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French Lessons</ENAMEX> in Lallans



            Once upon a time, as they say in all the best
fairy tales, one of the most unlikely treaties
ever envisaged was forged between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
who were poles apart in almost everything except
their mutual dislike of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that separated
them geographically.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auld Alliance</ENAMEX>, a treaty
of accord between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, was born.
Today, nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven hundred years later</TIMEX>, it remains
intact despite the vicissitudes of time and a language
barrier that only the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have ever made much
effort to surmount.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Luck of the Bodkins</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.G. Wodehouse</ENAMEX>
remarked on the ...look of furtive shame, the
shifty, hangdog look which announces that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>
is about to talk <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>....  The inimitable
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wodehouse</ENAMEX> was, as usual, spot-on with his
characterization.  We insatiable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> have seen
similar scenes enacted many times around the watering
holes of the world, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calais</ENAMEX> to the fleshpots of
Douala, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> to the silver strands of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">C√¥te d'Ivoire</ENAMEX>.  The average <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit</ENAMEX> is seldom at his most
confident when forced by circumstance to attempt
the language of another.

            Not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> suffer
from this malaise when finding themselves on foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">shores</ENAMEX>.  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Average Scot</ENAMEX> does not, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.  The intricacies
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallic</ENAMEX> subjunctive do not worry him at
all, and for the best reason in the world: he does not
even bother to try.

            There are those who will sneer that a race
which owes its very existence to the ingurgitation of
massive quantities of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porridge</ENAMEX> during its formative
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> is capable of speaking in no other way.  But
Scots have long been inured to such slurs.  As a
proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scot</ENAMEX> myself, I feel that a much more probable
reason for this apparent lack of linguistic ambition is
to be found in the regional dialect.  There are parts
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in which regional dialects can be as incomprehensible
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tocharian</ENAMEX> to the innocent abroad,
and the farther north one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
the more incomprehensible they seem to become.  It
gets worse in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>.  Strangers listening to any of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> dialects will soon realize that they are as
replete with gutturals as any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Teutonic dialect</ENAMEX>.
Tongues created by God for the pronunciation of
names like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auchtermuchty</ENAMEX> are quite unsuited to the
more delicate nasal nuances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French</ENAMEX> language.

            Each dialect is distinct and distinctive.  Aberdonians
have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doric</ENAMEX>, with its quines <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and
loons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glaswegians</ENAMEX> bombard you with The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patter</ENAMEX>, famous for its infamous glottal stop and raw,
street humor.  In the moors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galloway</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives converse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lallans</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lallans</ENAMEX> is the language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>, and it is a language
in which he wrote most beautifully.  It is, in
fact, not a separate language at all.  It is just one
more dialect of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, but one would have to be
listening pretty carefully to figure that out on first
exposure to it.

            For reasons that need not detain us here, some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> I happened to be visiting the translation
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> of a large publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in darkest
Hertfordshire, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, and I became involved in
conversation with one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, a charming
young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>.  The subject of regional dialects
in our respective <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> came up.  Being very
new to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and having, so far, only encountered
school <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, she found it difficult to believe
that dialectal variation could be so great in such
a tight little island as ours, and that so much of it
could be unintelligible to the uninitiated.  We were
interrupted by the arrival of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> clad in a boiler
suit of some antiquity.  I could not recall having seen
him before, but I would have recognized his type
anywhere.  He was a raw-boned, sallow little chap
with sunken eyes and lived-in features, the sort to be
found aplenty in bygone days walking out mean-look-ing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whippets</ENAMEX> in the thin gray mists of gloaming
around any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ayrshire</ENAMEX> mining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.  At that moment
I would have bet my very soul that he hailed
from The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land Of</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbie Burns</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> words
he uttered showed the intuition inherited from my
mystic forebears to be firing on all cylinders.

            Huv ye seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ma gaffer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>? he queried.

            I sneaked a sidelong look at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> and
a glow of the purest contentment spread slowly
through me.  She was about to get her first lesson,
and I could feel in my bones that it was going to be a
good one.

            I don't think I know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, I hedged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">craftily</ENAMEX>.  What does he look like?

            The little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> took off his cap.  He removed a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">squashed</ENAMEX> cigarette from somewhere inside it and lit
it carefully with the minute, barely smouldering
stump of the old one.  He drew with deep satisfation
on his reefer and exhaled an acrid cloud of blue
smoke around us.  He glanced at her, the world-weary
eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Scotia</ENAMEX> and the prelapsarian ingenuousness
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Picardie</ENAMEX>'s meeting in a fleeting
look that spanned the ages.  He coughed harshly and
spat copiously on the ground.  Then he let her have
it with both barrels.

            Och, he intoned with Bren-gun rapidity,
He's jeest a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nyatterin</ENAMEX>' wee nyaff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wi</ENAMEX>' a skelly cacke'e
an' a manky, broony-kinna gansey.

            When he had gone, my young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> friend
asked me in understandable bewilderment, What
sort of language was that?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, I replied innocently.

             <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>??!! 

            Well, yes, sort of...

            Oh my God! she exclaimed, appalled.  And I
am supposed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>! What on earth was
he saying?

            I thought carefully for a moment or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> before
committing myself:

            He intimated that, in his humble opinion, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overseer</ENAMEX> is a loquacious and diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> of a
somewhat devious and unpleasant bent, that he is
afflicted with a strabismus of the sinistral optical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, and that he is currently attired in a rather
noisome woolen torsal garment of an indeterminate
off-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate hue</ENAMEX>.

            She stood before me like a stricken stirk, her
eyes glazed and her mouth agape.  Then her teeth
clicked shut and she lanced me with a look of frosted
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>.  I theenk you are taking the meeckey
out of me, she ground out savagely.  And off she
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flounced</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auld Alliance</ENAMEX> must have been strong indeed
to put up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> centuries of this sort of
stuff.
         
         
            
Balloonist lands in hot water with ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">n.d. Submitted by</ENAMEX> .]

         
         
            
It would also ban public consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and
wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> in these areas.  [From an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Rochelle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> , .  Submitted by 
.]

         
         
            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX> for an Aye




            I cannot really lay claim to being a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Country</ENAMEX> as most of my ancestors
left the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Borders</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>,
and I was born farther south, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX>.  However,
I did live a large part of my life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seahouses</ENAMEX>, a
small fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> on the north Northumbrian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast</ENAMEX>.  Even though I consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northumberland</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Borders</ENAMEX> to be home, technically I am
still a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yorkshireman</ENAMEX>, and, having been raised in that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">county</ENAMEX> of virtually unshakable local accents, it was
natural that my tongue would give me away and that
I would be called a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yorkie</ENAMEX> when living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northumberland</ENAMEX>.
But on return trips to my birth place,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northumbrian</ENAMEX> influence would show and I
would be baited as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geordie</ENAMEX>.  (I have since gone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX>: I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pommie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and an
Aussie when back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>!)

            While in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northumberland</ENAMEX> I did serve my time
on a coble, a traditional fishing boat working out of
that tiny harbor not far from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> border,
and it was during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX> at sea that I learned
some of the more subtle intricacies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northumbrian</ENAMEX>,
in particular that most flexible of all words--
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX> .  To most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the English-speaking world,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX> means yes, as in that well-worn phrase, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aye</ENAMEX>,
aye, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skipper</ENAMEX>.  But the initiated know that there is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal more to this little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gem</ENAMEX> than meets the ear,
so to speak.

            I remember walking down to the harbor, early
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very misty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX>
who was coming out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> to watch us
haul the creaves (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster pots</ENAMEX>).  As we neared the
village we met an older fisherman heading in the
opposite direction.  He glanced up as we passed,
shook his head and uttered a terse greeting.

            Thick, eh?

            Aye, I replied.

            That was the sum total of the conversation.  After a
few <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of deep reflection, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX> friend
could contain himself no longer.

            What was that all about?  he asked.

            He said that it was very foggy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and he
thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> would probably not be going
out--he asked me if I was of the same opinion.  I
said that I agreed with him.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> lapsed back into thought, stunned by
the hidden complexity of such a brief exchange.  Unknown
to him, the conversation down at the harbor
would be even more perplexing.

            The smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> had no radio or radar, so it
was customary, during adverse weather conditions,
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> to congregate around whatever
spot at the harbor offered the maximum shelter from
the weather of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.  After an appropriate period
of time, some sort of taciturn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> decision would
be made on whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> would go out
that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.  Sometimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would stand for
several <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, all attention turned to the prevailing
conditions--and anything else that might happen
by.  As we joined the inevitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> gathered at
the end of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lime kilns</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> looked up.
The conversation went something like this:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX>?  (In a short rising tone as if to say,
Who's this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> with you?)

            Another fisherman turned his head.

            Aye, aye.  (These were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> level-sounding
words meaning So your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>'s going out with you,
is he?  It was more of a statement than a question.)

            Another voice added:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H'aye.</ENAMEX>  (With an expulsion of breath, and going
down at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>: He'll be lucky to go anywhere
today, with all this fog... it's far too thick.)

            And another...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX>' he.  (This had a long dip in the middle,
with a short ending: That's right, very lucky to get
out.  He'll be lucky to climb down onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>.)
Silence for a while.  Then a more resigned sound
came from within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.  It was almost a sigh:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX>.  (I think everything that you all just said
is correct, I don't think that the mist will clear, not
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX>.  (A short, sharp, high note, with a hint of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradiction</ENAMEX>: You never know, it could; we'll see
who's right.)

            Silence again.  An old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> of a car bounced past
with several rough-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> inside.

            Aye!  (Quite strong, starting low, rising to the
end, as if to say, Going far too fast!)

            Aye!  (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More</NUMEX> of a growl: Yes, a ridiculous
speed to be traveling; and what are they doing, driving
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about at this time of day</TIMEX> anyway?  Up to no good
if you ask me.)

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayes</ENAMEX>--all different, but all in agreement.
(A rare thing!)

            Silence.  A big lift (sea, wave) came in the harbor
and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> made a run on their rope ends.
It was studied thoughtfully, the implications for the
prospects of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> mulled over.

            Aye!  (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX> and strong, quite a dip in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middle</ENAMEX>: Not only is it misty, but the sea is making
too!)

            Aye!  (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short</ENAMEX>, resigned, exhaled as a sigh: I
can't see that we'll be out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, just you mark my
words.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX>.  (Fairly level, slight dip, then rise toward
the end: That's right, we'd have been far better off
staying in bed.)

            More silence.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> lazily drew his
knife out of his trouser pocket; he laboriously
opened it and began to sharpen the blade on the
corner of the sandstone wall.  There are providence-tempting
implications to be considered in an act like
this.

            Aye!  (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Throaty</ENAMEX>, short, rise at the end, hint of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgust</ENAMEX>: I don't know what you're sharpening that
thing for...)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H'aye</ENAMEX>!  (Strong, definite but falling: Put your
knife away, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, you'll only make things worse.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> looked up at the mist.  His face scanned
the bland emptiness of the full sky.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX>.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Descending</ENAMEX>, exhaled, slightly wavy, almost
a touch of ridicule: Well, you lot can do what
you like, I've been here long enough, I'm off back
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.)

            Aye!  (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short</ENAMEX>, sharp, level: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me too</ENAMEX>!  This was
followed by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ayes</ENAMEX> of agreement, but all different.)

            Aye, aye.  (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> level, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one descending:
We'll not do any good down here.  I think
we've made our decision.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> started to move off, each going his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>.  My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skipper</ENAMEX> turned to me.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX>.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short</ENAMEX>, to the point: That's it my bonnie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lad</ENAMEX>.)

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> looked inquiringly into my face.

            Does this mean we're not going out to sea?

            What could I say?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aye</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            Falls the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow</ENAMEX>




            There's many a glitch 'twixt script and speech.
For a start, the script might be mis-typed or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">semi-legible</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> ignorant.  On a state
occasion during the Queen's recent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Namibia</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of ceremonies introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Majesty as</ENAMEX>
Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> the eleventh.  And on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
radio requests program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX>
launched into a dedication to this effect:
And now, a special message for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Donachy</ENAMEX> of
Ballycloran, who is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX>-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>!  ...no
he's not, he's ill .

            And of course, even the clearest of scripts and
brightest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> will produce occasional misfires,
such as:


faulty accessing: a funfair of trumpets; a prawn in
the game; I know you like the back of my head.

mispronunciations: deteriate; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>-orkers; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>
as if written <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granada</ENAMEX>.

botched tongue-twisters: shallow and slipshod
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shatire</ENAMEX>; that disquieting condition called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwok</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quease</ENAMEX>; the fire at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tirestone</ENAMEX> fire tactory.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spoonerisms</ENAMEX> and similar transpositions: submersive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>; a cross-fannel
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cherry; Tonight</ENAMEX>'s orchestral concert comes to you
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath Room</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pump</ENAMEX>.

            

            As long ago as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1960s</TIMEX>, the phenomenon
was conspicuous enough to inspire the title of a comedy
series on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> radio, I'm Sorry I'll Read That
Again (whence the title of the current I'm Sorry I
Haven't a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clue</ENAMEX> )--the catchphrase adopted by radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presenters</ENAMEX> as part of their retrieval strategy.

            For all their humor and popularity, such types
of deviation are in reality neither very common nor
particularly revealing.  The interesting types of deviation
are the more common, yet less recognized
types (widely unrecognized, it seems, perhaps because
seldom funny).  They are mistakes at sentence
level rather than word level; prosodic rather than
lexical mistakes; mistakes of stress, intonation, and
syntactic segmenting: in effect, accentuating the
wrong word or syllable, modulating the pitch incorrectly
(a rising rather than falling tone, say, or a
questioning rather than affirming tone), and pausing
in the wrong place.  A well-known literary example
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quince</ENAMEX>'s mis-structuring of his prologue within A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midsummer Night's Dream:</ENAMEX>

               
Consider then we come but in despite.

We do not come as minding to content you [etc].

            

            And ponder these old parlor-game jokes:


What is THIS thing called<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, Love</ENAMEX>?  (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">inquisitively</NUMEX>)

Pick your OWN <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberries</ENAMEX>! (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">indignantly</NUMEX>)

There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> ¬¶ odd
teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>.  (tiny pause after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> rather
than after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">odd</TIMEX>)

It's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">now ten o'clock</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>.  Meantime, here
is the news.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenpeace</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> blew ¬¶ up an effluent
pipeline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Sea</ENAMEX>.  (tiny pause after
blew rather than after up)

            

            Underlying such jokes is a crucial linguistic law:
a written sentence carries a higher risk of ambiguity
than a spoken sentence.  The stage directions
within a written/printed sentence are rudimentary--being
almost always of just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following four</TIMEX>
kinds (in descending order of explicitness):


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">typeface</ENAMEX> (italics or boldface, say, to encourage
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to accentuate the word);

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">punctuation</ENAMEX> (a sentence ending with an exclamation
point, say, prompts a quite different reading
from one ending with ellipsis dots);

word order (position an element later in a sentence--in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, at any rate--and its chances
of taking the main stress are usually increased);

word choice (a word like disgusting, for example,
specifically invites being enunciated in a withering
tone, whereas the more ambiguous revolting
might not).

            

            Since these cues are so rudimentary, ambiguity
pervades written sentences--sentences in isolation,
that is--and the transition to a spoken version can
therefore be a hazardous procedure.  Can you read
out loud the following sentences, for instance, without
feeling torn between rival renderings?


Do you understand?  (inquiringly, or menacingly)

I spoke to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.  (accentuating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>)

She hasn't scooped me, has she?  (confidently, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anxiously</ENAMEX>)

When can I meet your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>?

She tried shooting herself.

Build thee more stately <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX>.

Do you think we should postpone or cancel the
meeting?

            

            Where the genuinely informative stage directions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reside</ENAMEX> is not within the written sentence itself,
but in the sweep of the preceding sentences--in the
context.  It is context that makes smoothly intelligible
reading possible.  Context, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Disambiguator</ENAMEX>.
Written sentences that in isolation appear ambiguous
will snap into focus when enmeshed in a larger discourse;
moreover, written language has the advantage
over spoken language in that it allows rereading
(and reading ahead) in order to ensure an accurate
interpretation of a given sentence.

            Consider how indeterminate the following sentence
is, out of context: on which word should the
main emphasis fall?


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has also criticized the Bosnian
Serbs for various violations of the ceasefire.

            

            But put the sentence in context, and it suddenly becomes
quite clear where the emphasis lies:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> have criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> for
moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> into a demilitarized
zone south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarajevo</ENAMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has also
criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX> for various violations
of the ceasefire.

[approximate transcript of a news report on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC World Service</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 May 1994</TIMEX>]

            

            Obviously it is on the word <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> that the main stress
should <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> (to point up the contrast, established in
the preceding sentence, with the word <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> ).
Unfortunately, the newsreader failed to render it
that way.  He placed the main stress on also , overlooking
the parallelism of the sentences and the contrast
that it was intended to foster.  In doing so, he
made nonsense of the report.

            What accounts for this tendency of theirs to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misread</ENAMEX>?  Sometimes it is a clear-cut matter of fatigue
or inattention, speaking trippingly, without attending
to meaning.  (In fairness, it does sometimes
happen that they have little or no time to acquaint
themselves with the script before reading it on air:
stop-press reports flash up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autocue</ENAMEX>; urgent
traffic bulletins or revised continuity announcements
have to be read unpreviewed from a last-minute
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">printout</ENAMEX>.)  And they neglect, through ignorance or
overconfidence, to take the elementary precautions
that would guard against such lapses: above all, to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mark</ENAMEX> up their scripts, the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> do--inserting
a vertical pause here, or a curving tonemarker
there, or an underlining to cue emphasis, or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dots to indicate a dying fall...

            Even pre-recorded broadcasts yield a good crop
of clangers.  (Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> examples quoted below, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
fall into that category.)  Perhaps cost-cutting (which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>, for example, seems to regard as one of
its main functions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>) has led to cornercutting--before,
during, and after the recording
session: less run-through time, less editorial monitoring,
less post-production checking and polishing.

            Here is a brief selection of examples (limited to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> programs) from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> I collected during
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 1994</TIMEX>.  They are broadly of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinds</ENAMEX>:
those in which the wrong word is accentuated and
those in which the pause is wrongly positioned (or
perhaps, in technical parlance, examples of faulty tonicity
and faulty tonality, respectively).

            Continuity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BBC2</ENAMEX> TV:


Cataclysmic events in the cosmos are taking place
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>.  At this moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jupiter</ENAMEX> should be on the
receiving end of the first gigantic comet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MASS.</ENAMEX>

(The main <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> should be on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or gigantic or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comet</ENAMEX> rather than on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass.</ENAMEX>)

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Norman</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BBC1</ENAMEX> TV:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúLadybird Ladybird‚</ENAMEX>Äù is not, however, a polemic
...Nor is it an attack on the social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">WORKERS</ENAMEX>,
although they do sometimes appear overzealous
...

(Shift the stress from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to social.)

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prof.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wistrich</ENAMEX>, in a lecture given on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Radio</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreyfus</ENAMEX> was pardoned in time ¬¶ for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>
Exhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1900..</NUMEX>. and his innocence
solemnly proclaimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years later</TIMEX>.

(The unwanted pause after time reveals a misreading
of his own sentence.)

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Serle</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Radio 4</ENAMEX>:


As he talked about his life ¬¶ and played his catholic
selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert Island</ENAMEX> discs, ¬¶¬¶ it became
clear that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DOER ¬¶</ENAMEX> and not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PONDERER ¬¶</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">life</ENAMEX>'s inequities.  (Get rid of that last pause, and
place the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of the emphases more on inequities
than on ponderer; the current rhythmic and intonational
pattern thoroughly misconstrues the
construction.)

            

            Continuity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BBC1</ENAMEX> TV:


It's downhill all the way, ¬¶ in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SECOND of</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s films ¬¶ starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ROBERT REDFORD</ENAMEX>.

(Considering that the previous film had been The
Sting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX> is missing the point when he
allows a pause after films and then accentuates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX>: surely the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> words really
constitute a restrictive rather than a nonrestrictive
phrase.)

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Porter</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Radio 4</ENAMEX>:


How then did it happen ¬¶ that a successful and
wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> ¬¶ declined to become one of the
poorest in the world?

(Shift the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> pause so that it follows rather
than precedes declined, and the sentence is
changed--utterly--from its intended sense.)

            

            Won't someone tell the big broadcasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
that accurate script-reading involves more
than accurate pronunciation?  Isn't it time, for instance,
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> and Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Affairs producers</ENAMEX>
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>, and the Talks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> as well, began
taking advice not just from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>'s excellent Pronunciation
Unit but from its wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drama Department</ENAMEX>?
         
         
            
Insectarium buzzes in heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of buggerly
love.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline</ENAMEX> in The (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ,
.  Submitted by 
.]

         
         
            
He could not shake the dread feeling that he and all
the others who had been involved in those projects were
sitting on a bomb that, sooner or later, would explode in
their faces.  [From The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Acting President</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Paul Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.P. Dutton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 273</ENAMEX>.  Submitted by
.]

         
         
            
[I]n our attempt to provide direction on how to control
and mitigate damages, it appears we neglected to empathize
with the fact that orchestrating such efforts may
have been difficult for you.  [Letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William C. Turnbull</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chubb Group of Insurance Companies, .</ENAMEX>  Submitted by .]

         
         
            Towards a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Literature</ENAMEX>




            This brief article describes and illustrates the
struggle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hieronymus Stoat</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947-</TIMEX>) to
produce a completely new literature.  In his own
words:


The concept of things happening is inherently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bourgeois</ENAMEX> and ultimately capitalist-imperialist.
We must, I believe, strive to rout out these corrupting
influences on literary art; to debourgeoisify
writing.

[letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>]

            

            This achievement could only be brought about by a
completely new style of writing in which nothing
happened.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoat</ENAMEX>'s first attempt, a novella (untitled, like all
his work) opened thus:


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">haddock</ENAMEX> looked at the wall for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.  The light was on.

            

            He was dissatisfied with this even before the ink was
dry.  Although little appeared to happen, a number
of events were implicit.  For instance, the moment
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> were up, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">haddock</ENAMEX> presumably
stopped looking at the wall--a momentous event in
the context.  And, more subtly, the light's being on
contains the event of its having been turned on.  But,
most tellingly, it was argued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> that the haddock
looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> constituted a happening,
even if it were rather drawn out and somewhat uninteresting.

            Absorbing these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stoat</ENAMEX> came to the realization
that the problem lay in verbs.  Wherever
you have a verb, things happen.  By definition.  He
thus tried to write in a completely verbless way.  His
revision of his untitled novella now began:


Pale <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">haddock</ENAMEX>.  Endlessly white wall.  Ambient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lucency</ENAMEX>.

            

            This was better.  To make up for the missing verbs
he attempted to add interest by scattering adjectives
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adverbs</ENAMEX> everywhere.  But after a time, he had to
recognize that even though the text did not actually
describe anything happening, the mind had an extraordinary
facility to make things happen, unbidden,
to the haddock and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> in the light.  And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjectives</ENAMEX> actually helped.  Quite interesting things
could happen, with a vivid imagination.

            Now this was as bad as describing happenings.
After all, the text had no meaning outside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>'s mind; so if that mind became full of imagined
events as a result of reading the text, then it
had failed in its quest for happeninglessness.  Slowly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoat</ENAMEX> came to the realization that substantives, too,
were the problem.  Write a noun and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> will
conjure up an image.  Moreover, the image will be
doing something--an event will be happening.
What if they too were expunged, then?  He tried it
and came up with:


Pale.  Endlessly white.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambient</ENAMEX>.

            

            With horror, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stoat</ENAMEX> realized that this was worse!  The
text provided a backcloth for all sorts of imaginings.
Amazing events were enacted in the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>,
conjured by these suggestive qualifiers: virgins
dreamt of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> on white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chargers</ENAMEX>; dirty
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> elaborated prurient extravagances.

            Reluctantly he was forced to discard nearly all
of these signifiers.  Even prepositions could convey
the impression of happenings.  The single word up ,
for instance, was so loaded with connotation that it
too had to be avoided.  Stoat flirted briefly with a
form of writing that used only the definite and indefinite
articles, but soon became disenchanted with
such lifeless passages as:


A <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the a the a a the.</TIMEX>

            

            He ruefully concluded that even this could stimulate
an over-heated imagination.

            Meaning: that was the problem.  Where words
had meaning, they would engender images in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' imaginations.  These images would start to
move and things would start to happen.  What was
needed was a meaningless language.  How about
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX>?  Granted some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still understood it, but
not the great generality of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.  He tried it.

            Video meliora proboque; deteriora sequor.

            A whole new set of problems emerged.  With a little
more imagination, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> could see all sorts of English
words hidden in the text.  With mounting despondency,
Stoat was forced to conclude that the
problem was words.  Any words, any words would
defeat his purpose.  To substitute pictures would be
to enter the world of graphic art and to desert literature.

            In a dream, the answer came to him: punctuation
!  How about a literature that was simply punctuation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX>?  He tried it, tentatively at first:


,<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">.;;..,,!,:</ENAMEX>

            


            Then with more authority:


?;,<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">,,.;;:!;;,..?;:...</ENAMEX>\?\\?\.,<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>

            

            Too many semicolons, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX>, while the
more pragmatic marveled at the piquancy of the single
(unopened or unclosed?) quotation marks.

            We shall reserve judgment until we see his first
work of major length.
         
         
            
But each dish is more elaborate than the next...
[From a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> review by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Irene Virbila</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">, p. 26</ENAMEX>.  Submitted by
.]

         
         
            
There'll be plenty to eat: hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> under twelve, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only a dollar</NUMEX>.  [<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Hillbilly</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WHRB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>'s radio station), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, .  Submitted by .]

         
         

            Notes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> English



            <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> shows much evidence of creolization.
Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> live in a linguistically complex
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, a mosaic of languages from around the
world in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>, dominated everywhere by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>
of standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joual</ENAMEX> (from cheval ),
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poitou</ENAMEX> dialect that is
the folk speech of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brigitte Harris</ENAMEX>, who is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>,
immediately observed many peculiarities of usage
when she arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> to earn an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.A.</ENAMEX> degree
in applied linguistics at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concordia University</ENAMEX>.
Our plan for her thesis was to count the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallicisms</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> reports of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Schoolboard</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Montreal</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970 and 1980</TIMEX> and to compare
them.  We carefully considered spelling, punctuation,
and vocabulary, reasoning that such texts must
have been prepared by several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and vetted
many times, so the texts must have seemed unexceptional
to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.  We found twice
as many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gallicisms</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> text as in that for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>.

            Textual rules of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> seem normal to native
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Quebec English</ENAMEX>.  For example, the spelling
of the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benedictine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St-Beno√Æt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">du Lac</ENAMEX> contains a hyphen instead of a period,
as well as a circumflex accent.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> names for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> are common: poulet frit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fried chicken Kentucky</ENAMEX>; moules mussels; frites
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fries</ENAMEX>; poutine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fries</ENAMEX> with curd
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX> (named after a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poutine</ENAMEX>
who was in charge of provisions at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siege of Quebec</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1749</TIMEX>; at the end, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> remaining
were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>, and chicken stock; local folk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etymology</ENAMEX> has it from putain, putanesca ); aubergine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eggplant</ENAMEX> (the usual word in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>); jarret de boeuf
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">caribou</ENAMEX> a fortified sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, etc.

            Some examples of peculiar usage: we pay at the
cash cashier's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in the wicket grated window;
we lose waste time ; we open turn on and close
turn off the light ; and we say il y a rien l√† there's
nothing to it, literally, there's nothing there.  We
watch out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.Q. Suret√</ENAMEX>© <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">du Qu√©bec</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">police</ENAMEX>)
on the autoroute <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interstate</ENAMEX>; if you are going to the
d√©panneur handy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> (a mom-and-pop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>),
stop at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.A.Q. Soci√</ENAMEX>©t√© <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">des Alcools du Qu√</ENAMEX>©bec
(liquor store).

            We receive subventions subsidies; we give conferences
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lectures</ENAMEX> and lectures readings; we have
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of scholarity schooling; belong to syndicates
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>; have fond souvenirs memories; attend
colloques colloquia; serve as animators <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>;
ride on the metro <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>; and we eat hot dogs
steam√© all dress steamed hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> with the works.

            Typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> pronunciation is found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, such as raising--actually incomplete
shifting--of the /<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">au</ENAMEX>/ phoneme, and the Briticisms
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">been /bin/, tourniquet /</ENAMEX> `t\?\rnike/, and again /\?\gen.
There is increasingly a syntactic change in the use of
the present perfect for the simple past, as in I have
noticed that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> .  The present perfect in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
has the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pass√© compos√©</ENAMEX> ,
but traditionally it has had a different meaning; this
usage may not be peculiar to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>: perhaps it is
spreading in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>.

            Recently, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Francophone</ENAMEX> taking calls on CBC
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> said, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> I make a precision
[clarify something] for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>]?
Those who speak neither the dialect nor
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> would be unable to understand that question.

         
         
            
The fates of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> massive proposals to ease conjection
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city centre</ENAMEX>... are still undecided.  [From New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statesman & Society</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">, p. 16</ENAMEX>.  Submitted by .]

         
         
            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoning Enforcement Officer Ron Discher</ENAMEX> reported
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> has stopped work on the paddock, an enclosed
area where <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> can graze and be mounted.
[From the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Redding Pilot,</ENAMEX> .  Submitted by
.]

         
         


            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson Cochrane</ENAMEX>'s enjoyable article, Me
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empathy</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>], says, Why is it... that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will not hesitate to proffer publicly their
guess-work on word origins and other language matters,
when they would not similarly dare to explain
the ordinary facts of botany and chemistry?  But
that is not so; for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>, for one, was interested
in language and in evolution (the life force
in Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methuselah</ENAMEX> ).  But the vitalists, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergson</ENAMEX>, weren't alone in trying to explain evolution;
there were also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamarckians</ENAMEX> (and later in
the then-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lysenkoism</ENAMEX>); the orthogenesis
true-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>; and, finally, the neoDarwinists,
whose view of random mutations is the currently accepted
explanation.  But even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, with the Ebola
virus, are there explanations that are not guesses?
And in cosmology, what is the Big Bang theory if
not a guess?

            Guess-work on word origins is not and probably
cannot be science, since the matter is not involved
with well-established general theories.  But hunches
and logic and experience surely play a crucial role
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX>).  Take, for instance, the slang word kiester
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">buttocks</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bryce</ENAMEX>, I have read, writes that it
comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>.  But in my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 70</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of speaking, reading and listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>, I
have never heard that word (or read it); also I've
never heard any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German-speaking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> use it and
say that it derives from Kies meaning small round
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> (gravel).  But in the largely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> neighborhood
where I was born and raised, I heard it often.
So, I guess that it's an adaptation of chiostra , referring
to a round thing, like a circle or a globe.  And I
must, or rather, want to say, that one of the prime
reasons for my enjoying Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochrane</ENAMEX>'s article is
that he demolished the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-empathy</ENAMEX> argument by
using logic and facts.





         
         


            In your review of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Dictionary</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">XXII, 1, 18</ENAMEX>],
you appear to believe a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> who asserted
that most of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ever lived are alive
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  [In an earlier discussion of join the majority .]
That has not been true even for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two centuries</TIMEX>.
Today, there are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 5.6 billion</NUMEX> living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
If you add the estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> from the
almanacs for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800, 1850, 1900</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, you get
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.0 billion</NUMEX>--and the real figure for the period was
certainly much higher.  A similar result is arrived at
by calculating in a different way: the almanac estimates
a world population of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; if
they had quietly reproduced themselves every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-five years</TIMEX>, with no increase in the rate of
population growth, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 16 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would
have lived and died since then.

            I suspect that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> was misled by
the word exponential in most statements of Malthusian
theory.  The statement would be true for a pure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exponential</ENAMEX> series (for example, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">series 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2, 4,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 16</TIMEX>, it is clear the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 > 1</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>), but humankind
does not increase by such a series.





         
         


            I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashok Mohapatra</ENAMEX>'s basic thesis in
Politicking with Words  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">XXII, 1, 1</ENAMEX>], but I think his
search for elegant formulations obscured his judgment
in the selection of examples he cites to make his
point regarding the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dictionary</ENAMEX>.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.2</ENAMEX>)
Stating that ...many words and usages exiled from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX> now found a place as free citizens
in the world of linguistic glasnost..., he cites only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republikflucht</ENAMEX> , which is a true <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX>
neologism, i.e., a new crime--leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--
which didn't exist before and has since been eliminated
from the penal code.  He is downright silly to
claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meinungsfreiheit</ENAMEX> (it should be one word
and capitalized, as all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nouns</ENAMEX> are), Weltreise
(obviously not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wettreise</ENAMEX>, which would mean a trip
to make a bet--only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phileas Fogg</ENAMEX> combined the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freizeit</ENAMEX> have now found a place in the
world of linguistic glasnost.

            Pomposity of expression is no substitute for clarity
of meaning.  Meinungsfreiheit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weltreise</ENAMEX> , and
Freizeit were descriptive nouns used in the German-speaking
world well before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX> regime
came into being, although it, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> before,
connected the latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> with state-run programs
capitalizing on the human desire to travel and have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for oneself.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meinungsfreiheit</ENAMEX> is a term both regimes
clearly shunned; I suppose in a sense it was
liberated.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stasi</ENAMEX> is simply an acronym for the infamous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gestapo</ENAMEX>,
a term well known on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX>.
It found its place into the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Duden</ENAMEX> ; OK, so what?
Where is the linguistic glasnost?

            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohapatra</ENAMEX> is on solid ground in buttressing
his argument with the two widely diverging definitions
of capitalism.  But I am astonished that in his
diligent search he did not come up with the most
glaringly telling example of all juxtaposing definitions:
those for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX> .  It would have been interesting
and enlightening to learn how the communist
state, which called itself a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Democratic Republic</ENAMEX>,
defined the form of government which its every action
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perverted</ENAMEX> and defiled.





         
         


            Intrigued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Horowitz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Discouraging</ENAMEX>
Word [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">OBITER DICTA, XXII, 1, 13</ENAMEX>], I set about tracking
the word balagan along its etymological course back
from the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> into which, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Horowitz quoting Herman Wouk</ENAMEX>, the word
was borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>.

            The entry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> word in the Tolkovyi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slovar' Russkogo Yazyka</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>), reads as
follows, as transliterated and translated:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balagan</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">balahana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balcony</ENAMEX>].  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A light
wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for shows at fairs.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. An amateur
theatrical production with primitive scenery; a theatrical
style based on imitation of this primitive stage-craft
(theatrical term).  Balagan art.  Balagan concepts
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Meyerhold</ENAMEX>'s productions.  II By extension: A balagan-like
show, i.e. a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, artistically tasteless, disordered,
frivolous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (derogatory).  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clowning</ENAMEX> turned the comedy into a balagan.  This is
no session, but a kind of balagan.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. A temporary
wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> at a fair.

            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russko-Angliiskii Slovar'</ENAMEX>, compiled under the
general direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.I. Smirnitsky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edition; E.P. Dutton & Co</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>), defines
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> word in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as follows:


Balagan, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.  (wooden structure) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX>; (for presentations)
show-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. show; (extended meaning)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">farce</ENAMEX>, tomfoolery, preposterous piece of buffoonery.

            

            Does not one come away from these definitions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> word with the impression that whoever infected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Horowitz</ENAMEX>'s software may have taken
the discouraging word directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> rather
than from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>?  According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wouk</ENAMEX>'s footnote, as
quoted by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horowitz</ENAMEX>, in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX> balagan
has come to mean mess, foul-up, snafu, fiasco.  But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> meaning of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, vulgar buffoonery
seems to fit better the trick title that appeared
on Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horowitz</ENAMEX>'s computer screen.  My
guess is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">joker</ENAMEX> who named the program Balagan
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX>, either to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, who may well have been aware of
the word's currency in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> but for
whom the meaning remained the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> one.

            Also interesting is the indication in the Tolkovyi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slovar</ENAMEX>' that the word is of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> origin and that in
Persian it means balcony.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balahana</ENAMEX> looks a lot like
our <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word balcony ; so I looked up balcony in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Dictionary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Language</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>), where I found the etymology given as:


balconye < It balcone < balc(o) scaffold (< OHG
balcho <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX>)

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third New International Dictionary</ENAMEX> gives a
similar etymology, stating that balcony is ultimately
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gmc</ENAMEX> origin.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolkovyi Slovar</ENAMEX>' states that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> word for balcony (balkon) is borrowed from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, which took it from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>, not the Germanic
languages.

            So which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are right, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dictionaries</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolkovyi Slovar</ENAMEX>'?  Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>
take their word balcone from some Germanic tongue
and pass it on into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>, and other languages;
or did <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> take the word from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>
balahana , as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> did balagan , at least according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolkovyi Slovar</ENAMEX>'?  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etymologies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Unabridged</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kluge</ENAMEX>'s Etymologisches
W√∂rterbuch der deutschen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprache</ENAMEX> have
cognates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">balagan</ENAMEX>/balcony popping up in Slovene
( <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">blazina</NUMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, and most significantly in Lithuanian
( <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bal«Ωienas</ENAMEX> ), purportedly the most conservative
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> languages.  I suggest that
these scattered avatars of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">balagan</ENAMEX>/balcony evidence
descent from a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Proto</ENAMEX>-Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> root,
most prolifically in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>.





         
         


            In response to the letter from Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maughan S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mason</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">XXI, 4, 17</ENAMEX>] regarding the odor emanating from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pozzuoli</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>), I did not know there was a refinery
there, but I do know that it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX> area (probably
a bath in ancient times), and it does smell to
high heaven.  I know: during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">WWII I</ENAMEX> was stationed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> and we would go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pozzuoli</ENAMEX>.





         
         


            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Stough</ENAMEX>'s delightful article, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insulting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nicknames Give Journalists Something to Be Proud</ENAMEX>
of [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">XXI,4</NUMEX>], he gives <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Grope and Flail</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of record, The (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> .  Another common nickname, bestowed
by a satirical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> , is The Glock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">und Spiel</ENAMEX> , probably a sly dig at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>'s conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leanings</ENAMEX>.

            I have heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
referred to as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> , and, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>,
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Women's Day</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotsman</ENAMEX> changed its masthead to The Scotswoman
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, there is a well-known summary of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s best-known papers.  Here is as much as
I can remember (possibly inaccurately as well as incompletely);
perhaps another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> can supply the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> version:


The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> is read by those who think they run
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>;

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is read by those who actually run the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>;

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> is read by those who think they
should run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>;

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> is read by those who think whoever runs
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s a bunch of bastards;

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX> is read by those who think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> run
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>;

And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> is read by those who don't care who
runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as long as she's got great tits.

            





         
         


            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Billingsgate in Kerala</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O. Abooty</ENAMEX>
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXII</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>], we read, ...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magnesia</ENAMEX> (a metal-bearing
region in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>)...  There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia Minor</ENAMEX> called Magnesia : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lydia</ENAMEX> on the river <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermos</ENAMEX> below <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Sipylon</ENAMEX>; the
other, usually called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magnesia</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maiander</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meander</ENAMEX>
river], was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ionia</ENAMEX>.  It is
probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lydian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> whose name provided the
word magnesium as well as related words, like magnet .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lydian Magnesia</ENAMEX> survives as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manisa</ENAMEX>,
in what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>.

            To expand on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Powers</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPISTOLA</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ibid</ENAMEX>.]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shrimp</ENAMEX> is not the only shr - word pronounced sr- in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>: shrink and shrapnel may be added to the
list.  Other southern pronunciations that strike the
northern ear as different are:


[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>]                  all        [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fŒôŒ∏</ENAMEX>]            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kst</ENAMEX>]                   asked      [har]                    hair
[`<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bŒôdnŒπs</ENAMEX>]      business   [`pou\?\l]               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
[`biy\?\n]             <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX>    [`w\?\d\?\nt]            wasn't

            





         
         


            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Boys Named Sue, But...</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">XXII, 1, 7</ENAMEX>].

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX>'s real name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Morrison</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Cary</ENAMEX> , not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.  The author notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX> had mainly masculine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>.  A major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
sportswriter for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> was (the male)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Povish</ENAMEX>, most noted for his article on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larson</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> perfect game in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>.  It
began, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hell</ENAMEX> froze over.





         
         


            There has recently been some opinion in VERBATIM
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">XXI, 3, 21</ENAMEX>] concerning the acronym <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AWOL</ENAMEX> .  I
suppose it doesn't matter all that much whether
someone is absent without leave or absent without
official leave--in either case, he or she is probably
in for a heapa trouble.  But, for my <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two cents</NUMEX>' worth,
when I was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1950s</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>,
Land of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Morning Calm</ENAMEX>, sometimes referred to as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frozen Chosen</ENAMEX>), I was in a battalion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> unit
and handled daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Reports</ENAMEX> from each battery.
This included manpower accounting.  We always
saw the term and heard it and used it as absent
without leave.  While we had few or no real
instances of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AWOL</ENAMEX>, it was reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>.  The use of
WO for without meant--to us, anyway--that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who was gone, missing, couldn't be found,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>, was absent and had been granted no leave--
official, unofficial, or what have you.  This was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AWOL</ENAMEX> .  There could be leaves of unofficial nature
(often called hip-pocket leave), but those were
not reported as any kind of leave: they compensated
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> some time off for a job well done or for a
long period in action and were not charged against
ordinary leave allowances.  But being AWOL was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">no-no</ENAMEX>, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> or unofficial.





         
         


            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s comments on ...prejudice
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX> in many Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>...
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">XXI, 3, 9</ENAMEX>] were apt but somewhat incomplete.  I saw
equally severe prejudice against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of darker
skin, often including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Negroes</ENAMEX>, by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whites</ENAMEX> in two
major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in which I worked (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968-70</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978-83</TIMEX>) and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen sub-Saharan</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
in which I worked (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972-74</TIMEX>).  Bigotry against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX>, sadly, is not confined to Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>.





         
         


            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.A. Livingston</ENAMEX>'s communication [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>] certainly
struck a responsive chord in me.  I have been
troubled by the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> and AfroAmerican
to describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in question, especially
since a dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine, who is solid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caucasian</ENAMEX>,
emigrated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> and is now a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and thus is aptly described as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>!

            Since I recently had the privilege of seeing the
revival of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showboat</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, I was particularly
interested in the lyrics of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Man River</ENAMEX>.
When I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1930</TIMEX>'s, the song was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sung</ENAMEX> with the words: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darkies</ENAMEX> all work, etc..
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> recorded it, he said Here we
all work, etc., fitting the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> but supposedly
more correct politically.  I never had any reason to
suspect that the original was other then Darkies
until I recently acquired a CD of songs from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
musical shows which were recorded in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
as performed there.

            Please look at the lyrics of the song in the enclosed
copy of the notes which accompanied the
CD.  I suspect strongly that this is the way it was
performed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.  What I now wonder is
whether anyone can authenticate these words as being
the actual words when the show was first performed
in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, I was
happy to see the corrigendum of the misattribution
of authorship of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poplollies</ENAMEX> and bellibones , since I was
the one who called it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>'s attention!)

            Let me just add how much I have enjoyed and
continue to enjoy your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.  I am probably one
of your longest-standing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> (a very awkward
locution but I am probably not one of your
oldest).





         
         
            The relevant verses are:


Niggers all work on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de Mississippi</ENAMEX>,
Niggers all work while de white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> play,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pullin</ENAMEX>' dem <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">de dawn</TIMEX> till sunset,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gittin</ENAMEX>' no rest till <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Judgement Day</ENAMEX>.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">(¬© 1927 T.B. Harms Company</ENAMEX>.  Copyright renewed.)
         
         
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBUM SAP</ENAMEX>
            
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha</ENAMEX>...ha...have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on me!




            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Act III</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scene 3, of Much Ado About Nothing</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constable Dogberry</ENAMEX> exclaims, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hah</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ah ha</NUMEX>! Well,
masters, goodnight... In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act II, Scene 1, of The</ENAMEX>
Tempest , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebastian</ENAMEX> blurts out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha, ha</NUMEX>!  And Act
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Scene 2, of Troilus and Cressida</ENAMEX> contains one
Ah ah! and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two Ha ha</NUMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s.  Which</ENAMEX> goes to show,
perhaps among other things, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX> was no
surer on his <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> when it comes to the peripatetic
letter h than the rest of us.

            Its now-you-see-it-now-you-don't habits have
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">haunted English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of virtually every generation
since The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venerable Bede</ENAMEX> was an altar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.  Although
dropping or adding an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un-Standard h</ENAMEX> became
a social stigma only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, the
habit itself is ancient.

            In his preface to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lay of Havelok the Dane</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">c. 1300</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Skeat</ENAMEX> cited several h -bombs, including
holde for old, hevere for ever , and Henglishe
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> .  In addition he found a handful of instances
where the title character was rendered as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avelok</ENAMEX> .  Indeed, the earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxons</ENAMEX> had little
more luck with the voodoo h ; in a brief article in an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1888</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queries</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prof.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skeat</ENAMEX> wrote:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only last week</TIMEX>, I found ors for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hors horse</ENAMEX> in an
unedited A-S manuscript.

            Of course, Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> provided more opportunities
for error.  The time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bede</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beowulf</ENAMEX> were
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hey-days</ENAMEX>--or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha</NUMEX>!  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-days</ENAMEX>--for the letter h .  Besides
providing early aspiration for many words, h did
yeoman service in front of the consonants l, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX>, r , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> .  A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> of our verb load for take on water
was haladan , which logically led to the words
hl√¶del ladle and hl√¶den pail.  It is possible to see
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s louse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>, or nit in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OE</ENAMEX> hnitu , but better by
far to illustrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hn</ENAMEX> start with the felicitous verb
hnappian doze or nap.  Hrog , it seems to this perhaps
perverted mind, is a better word than ours for
mucus of the nose, or snot.  But then, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a loaf</NUMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxons</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> , while a whole one
was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> .

            The hw beginning accounted for a slew of
words, many of which (such as which ) have survived,
but with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> initial letters transposed.  Here too,
the migrant, mystic h has served as a social shibboleth.
But those who make a big thing of correctly
pronouncing their wh words should know that it is
impossible.  What the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX> are doing is
fully sounding the old hw in that order.  And my
guess is that even the most fastidious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> drops
the h from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-person pronoun in the question,
What did he say?
            

            Mind you, the letter h was playing hide and seek
even before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> times.  Its use in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Classical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX> was more or less the same as it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--as a
weak aspiration, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Romans</ENAMEX> being no more desirous
of exerting themselves than we are.  Spelling and use
were already erratic.  Arena was used as often as the
more correct harena <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>, and we seem to have
preferred it as well, because that is the word we
adopted for the sandy site of gladiatorial combat,
sand being unbeatable at absorbing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and gore.
As another example, the word umidus has no historical
right to its initial h but sports it anyway.  In the
Romance languages spawned by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, h has all but
disappeared as a symbol of sound value.  It frequently
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persists</ENAMEX>, however, as an etymological relic
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> homme from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homo</ENAMEX> ) or with an imagined
etymological value (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> haut , actually from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> altus , but influenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old High German</ENAMEX> hoh
high).

            Following the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> were the
earliest to scrap h entirely.  The result is such Cockney-looking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constructions</ENAMEX> as orribile and istorico .
They were digging the grave in Old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">burial</ENAMEX> service was rudely interrupted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, who were importing French
words prodigiously, now have many examples from
both sides of the letter-shed-- ability and the suffix
- able , as well as such words as arbo(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">u</ENAMEX>)r , from the cut
stage.  We have others where the h has been reinstated
but is not pronounced ( <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX>, honest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> , for
example), and still others where the h has been replaced,
but on whose pronunciation we have not yet
made up our minds ( humo(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">u</ENAMEX>)r, humble, herb ).  When
I was young, we took family vacations near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Huron</ENAMEX>,
where pronunciation was subject to the same
lack of certainty, providing the potential for some
proverbial southwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX> jocularity.

            Perhaps the most notorious example of English
dithering in this matter is the word for which a Himalayan
snow monster is named.  Though no one has
met the snow monster, and therefore no one is in a
position to pass judgment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>'s disposition,
we seem to feel that abominable is an apt descriptor.
But from the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wycliffe</ENAMEX> until
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid 1600s</TIMEX>, we spelled it abhominable in the belief
that it sprang from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements ab</ENAMEX> away
from and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homo man</ENAMEX>.  We changed back again
when the abominable truth was discovered that the
word had its own legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> ancestor, abominosus
meaning away from the omens, or hateful and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">odious</ENAMEX>.  Something similar happened for a while to
preheminent , the suspicion being that the h was inserted
to avoid what the linguists call hiatus.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> solve this problem by illogically placing
a dieresis over the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> e .

            But h in the initial position has long been the
more nagging nuisance.  Abundance existed as an excrescent
habundance for most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX>
and for a good while after that, in the belief that the
word derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> habere to have.  And neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hermit</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> began life with an initial h .

            The letter's name, aitch, goes back to Old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> ache , from a late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> accha, ahha , or aha --
all or any of them descendants of an earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha</NUMEX> .
I am sure we will all be happy to know that we are in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> the same league as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> when it comes to knowing our ahs from
a 'ole the ground.
         
         
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANTIPODEAN ENGLISH</ENAMEX>
            
         
         
            Famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> Etymologies



            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>--in the sense of earliest
recorded and significant--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Australianism</ENAMEX> is generally
awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kangaroo</ENAMEX> , despite the fact that another,
much less striking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, the quoll , is noticed in the
same glossary of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> language, that compiled
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">navigator</ENAMEX> and explorer, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1770</TIMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years</TIMEX> elapsed before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> decided
to establish a penal settlement in the land which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>, when he took possession of it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1770</TIMEX>, primarily
to forestall the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New South Wales</ENAMEX>.
But, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1788</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Arthur Phillip</ENAMEX> landed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Botany</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX> (near the present <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>) with a mixed
party of convicts and their military custodians and
sought to use what little knowledge had been passed
on to him of the indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>, their language,
and the new land's <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX>.

            Somewhat to his surprise and that of others in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborigines</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Jackson</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
Harbour was named) did not recognize the word.
Instead, they appeared to think it was an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
word and borrowed it (as they did other words, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gammon</ENAMEX> and fellow ) with glee, using it of the cattle
which the invaders had brought with them and apparently
thinking it meant edible <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>.

            This was to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX> and others their first
intimation that there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> Aboriginal
language; but, so distinctive and so immediately
made a symbol of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> itself,
and the word rapidly took on in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and, indeed,
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.  And when, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1820</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip King</ENAMEX> landed
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Endeavour River</ENAMEX>, in the north of what is now
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queensland</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s glossary was obtained,
he found that the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborigines</ENAMEX> did not recognize
the word, using a name something like menuah instead.
It was to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a century</TIMEX> before the
explanation became clear, and, in the meantime,
several other possibilities were floated.  It was at first
thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Banks</ENAMEX>,
who was at his side, had erred, either in their understanding
or in their documentation, and it was later
suggested that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">informant</ENAMEX> had misunderstood
the question and replied I don't know or
something a little less polite.  It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">linguist John Haviland</ENAMEX> identified the word in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Queensland language Guugu Yimidhirr</ENAMEX>, where it denoted
a particular species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kangaroo</ENAMEX> and evidenced
the fineness of distinction that characterizes
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> languages.  By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, of course, the
number and complexity of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> languages was
well known, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Jackson</ENAMEX> language, or
Dharuk as it is now known, was long extinct.

            As a footnote, and in illustration of the sense of
Aboriginal humor which might have misled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>,
consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> word moomba ,
used since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> as the name of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> carnival
and freely translated let's get together and have
fun.  Later scholarship suggests that the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
were taken for a ride, the word apparently being
widespread in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Victorian</TIMEX> languages and meaning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">buttocks</ENAMEX>.

            Aboriginal etymologies are now mostly settled,
the historical and geographical evidence of a word's
early use being brought collectively to bear as in the
case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kangaroo</ENAMEX> .  But where there is no evidence of
borrowing and no feasible source language, some
other explanation has to be sought.  This is the case
with a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> term for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pom</ENAMEX> or pommy .  At first sight this might appear to be
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> regional dialect word, but there is no possible
etymon even remotely like it recorded in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright</ENAMEX>
or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> .  So, whereas for dinkum , for instance, a
sense history can be established that fits chronologically
with a verifiable regional antecedent, for
pommy there is no such answer.  The first task then is
to track the word back to its earliest recorded occurrence
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian English</ENAMEX> to see if the context yields
any clues as to origin.  And it does.  Both forms are
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> found in popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, notably the Bulletin ,
an aggressively <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX>, and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
Truth , also a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> and no less <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>, but
more scurrilous because more urban in outlook.  In
both papers the chase goes back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>, when there
was a sudden increase in assisted immigration and in
the consequent expression of attitudes to this immigration.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> displayed an editorial indulgence
in word play.  Both evidence <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> form,
pomegranate , with its tell-tale variant spelling pommy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grant</ENAMEX> .  The rhyme might not have been a very good
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, but the chant went up nonetheless--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immigrant</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy-grant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pommy</ENAMEX>-grant--originally expressing
a prejudice against assisted immigration of
any sort, but later, simply because of the numbers
involved, becoming focused on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, and later
still on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.  For some reason unknown to lexicographers
the word became popular, and it was but
a matter of time before it was shortened to pommy
and then pom , both of which were used adjectivally
as well.

            But this explanation, first advanced and documented
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian National Dictionary</ENAMEX> , has
yet to win full acceptance, there still being those
who prefer the unsubstantiated acronym POME
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prisoner Of Mother England</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> pomme
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de</ENAMEX> terre as a source.  There are even those who find
the comparison of the brightly colored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> with the
ruddy cheeks of the newly arrived <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX>
sufficient explanation in itself.  Folk etymologies
often have a life of their own.
         
         

            My jugular vein is caught in the bedding




            That statement, we were once asked to believe
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cleese</ENAMEX>, was an example of the irrelevancy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian English</ENAMEX> phrase books, along with the well-known,
My postillion has been struck by lightning.
But each age and each culture has its own phraseology.
Already after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> LPs, gramophones , and
wirelesses belong to history and a never-ending tide
of new transatlantic terminology swamps these shores
with the everyday expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.  Perhaps we need an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> to keep
our language pure.  But, whether through technological
or social change, language moves on.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> recent phrase books of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> languages
illustrate how <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
mealie-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> language is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swahili</ENAMEX>--as approved
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swahili Committee</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>; the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fanagalo</ENAMEX>-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lingua Franca of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Africa</ENAMEX>, printed only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> but
using language very alien to the urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brit</ENAMEX>.  The
phrases chosen aptly describe the sort of society and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these</TIMEX> languages serve.
