
   
      
         
            By Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes Ye Shall Know Them</ENAMEX>: A Look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onomatopoeic</ENAMEX> Ornithonymy



            According to the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linguist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX>
Jespersen, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> theories to account for
the origin of language: the bow-wow theory, in
which speech imitated animal calls; the pooh-pooh
theory, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> made instinctive sounds
through physical or emotional reactions; the dingdong
theory, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> reacted to the environment;
the yo-he-ho theory, in which people
spoke when working together; and the la-la theory,
in which speech arose from the romantic side of life.

            If bird names are anything to go by, the bowwow
theory (perhaps we should call it the tweet-tweet
theory) rules the roost, since many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> are
named for their songs or calls.  This even holds for the
generic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cock</ENAMEX>, hen, and chick .  The farmyard cock is so
called for its clucks, as illustrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaucer</ENAMEX> in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nun</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Priest's Tale</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanticleer</ENAMEX> cryde anon,
cok, cok.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cockerel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cock-a-doodle-doo</ENAMEX> is an
extension of this, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow</ENAMEX>.  The hen is so called
for her singing, with a name related to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> canere
to sing, and so to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> chant .  (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanticleer</ENAMEX>, though
male, has a name meaning one who sings clearly.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> has a name related to that of the cock ,
with its changed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vowel</ENAMEX> representing its less powerful
cry.  The chick , as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>, is named from it.

            Outside the farmyard, but still (usually) within
farmland territory, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow</ENAMEX> and rook are both named
for their harsh call or caw , and though less common,
the chough and the raven are similarly named.  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chough</ENAMEX>'s cry has been described 
as kyaw , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">raven</ENAMEX>'s as prruk (suggesting the name of the physically
related rook ).  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corncrake</ENAMEX>'s cry has been verbalized
as crex , which adequately represents the crake that is
the basic form of the name.

            Elsewhere afield, the curlew , with its cry of courli ,
is obviously named, as is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cuckoo</ENAMEX> , whose name is
similar in many languages (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> coucou , German
Kuckuck , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> kokkux , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> cuculus ).  The first
part of its name is in fact directly related to that of the
cock , as the initial cuck - of its call corresponds to the
farmyard <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>'s cluck.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jackdaw</ENAMEX> also belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow</ENAMEX> family
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corvidae</ENAMEX> ), and daw represents its chak .  (It does it
better in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, where the bird is a taccola ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from earlier</TIMEX> tacca .)  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of its name is

            the personal name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> .  The sparrow does not itself
have an imitative name, although it was formerly nicknamed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX> , for its rapid twittering and chirping
notes.  Hence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Skelton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 16th-century</TIMEX> poem
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllyp Sparowe</ENAMEX> , a lament by a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> for her pet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sparrow</ENAMEX> killed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, with the affecting lines:
Nothynge it auayled/To call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phylyp</ENAMEX> agayne,<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/Whom</ENAMEX>
Gyb our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat hath slayne</ENAMEX>.

            Another bird with an imitative name prefixed by
a personal name is the magpie .  Here pie is related to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> pipere to chirp.  There are other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pi -</ENAMEX> or its equivalent in their names similarly, such as
the peewit, pipit , and even the pigeon .  True, pigeons
coo , but the bird derives its name from the onomatopoeic
base pip - that imitates the chirp of a young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bird</ENAMEX> (and that also gave <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX> ).  Hence also the
more obvious name of the sandpiper , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> that pipes
(or peeps ) on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sands</ENAMEX>.

            We are now by the seaside, where the gull has a
name representing its repeated kyow, kyow .  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seagull</ENAMEX> is also known as the mew , likewise an imitative
name.  Another aquatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> , whose name
represents its distinctive honk.  The male of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, the gander , has a directly related name, as
does the gannet .  Its cry is described as a barking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arrah</ENAMEX> .  Still with the water <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, the heron is named
for its harsh cry rrank; the name itself is related to
that of the hen .  The bittern is a further wading <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>;
its cry is usually described as a boom, and the first
part of its name, from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> butio , represents this.
Yet another water dweller is the garganey , a kind of
duck.  Its name represents its distinctive quacking.

            On dry land, the finch is named for its prolonged
nasal tswe<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-e-e</ENAMEX> , mostly clearly heard in the greenfinch.
The siskin is in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and has a similar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nameâ€”and</ENAMEX> indeed a similar call.  A harsher note is
sounded by the shrike , whose name is related to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">screech</ENAMEX> and shriek .  The quail is so called not because
it is timid but because the call of the female is a double
note queep, queep .  The quail is a gamebird, as is
the partridge .  Its own name is equally imitative, not
of its voice but of the sharp whirring sound made by
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> when it suddenly flies up.  This sounds like
a fart , a related word.  (Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> perdix partridge.
and perdesthai to break wind.)  Quite a different
sound is made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX>, whose name represents
its familiar hoot, otherwise the final, longer
note of its conventional call <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tu-whit tu-whoo</NUMEX> .  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">howl</ENAMEX> is a related word.  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hibou</ENAMEX> also imitates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bird</ENAMEX>'s call, as does its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eule</ENAMEX> , a diminutive
form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uhu</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eagle owl</ENAMEX>.

            Even the little wren has an echoic name, as much
more obviously does the chiffchaff , although its chiffs
and chaffs are usually repeated in irregular order, such
as chiff, chiff, chiff, chaff, chiff, chaff .  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rarer bird</ENAMEX>, but
also with an obviously onomatopoeic name, is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hoopoe</ENAMEX> .  Its far-carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">poo-poo-poo</ENAMEX> is also represened
in its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> name, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upupa</ENAMEX> epops .  Its name
evokes the equally exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bobolink</ENAMEX>, bulbul and whippoorwill ,
with their clearly echoic names.  The last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bird</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nightjar</ENAMEX> , where jar is also an imitative
word, referring to its loud churring cry.  ( Churr
and jar are related words.)  The nightingale does not
have a directly imitative name, although the final- gale
is related to yell , which is undoubtedly echoic.

            It is tempting to relate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">yellowhammer</ENAMEX>'s name
to yammer (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> jammern ), referring to its fussy
call, a rapid chi-chi-chi-chi-chi... chweee , traditionally
rendered little<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-bit-</NUMEX>of-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>.  But the
origin of the name is disputed.  (The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of the
name indicates the colour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and underparts.)

            Finally in this bouquet of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> names, let us
savour the rail , whose repeated gep, gep, gep and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groaning</ENAMEX> and grunting notes suggest a death rattle , a
related word.  They order things more neatly in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> here, for rÃ¢le is both the name of the bird
and the word for this agonized and agonizing sound.
            Verbal renderings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>' calls and notes are those given
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Field Guide</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Birds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tory Peterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Mountfort</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.A.D. Hollom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3rd ed.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>.
         
         
            
Ex-woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to get a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125,000</NUMEX> settlement.
[From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Post Intelligencer , .</ENAMEX>  Submitted
by .]
         
         
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EX CATHEDRA</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Vale!
            

            The time has come, as it does to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, animate
and inanimate, to say goodby.  This issue,
Volume XXIII, Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter 1997</ENAMEX>], will be the
last published and edited under our aegis.

            It has, as they say, been a good run.  There have
been ups (like the time when we had a mailing service
that kept adding new and renewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>' names
and addresses without removing the old ones, leading
us not only into a state of euphoria contemplating our
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> but, at the same time, into
near bankruptcy paying the attendent increased printing
and postage costs without the expected revenues);
and, of course, there have been downs (like falling
behind so far in the publishing schedule that we
changed the dates of the issues from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autumn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spring</ENAMEX> (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Of Thee I Sing</ENAMEX>! ), and the dismay and disappointment
at the down-marketing of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , once a stalwartâ€”if expensiveâ€”source of new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>, nowâ€”still expensiveâ€”catering to the
pretentious philistine market).

            Present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> might be surprised to learn
that the initial rate for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s subscription was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.50</NUMEX>
and that copies were sent out via first-class mail.  It
must be said, though, that those <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issues ran to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> pages compared with the current <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-four</TIMEX>
(or, sometimes, more).  Being rather indolent in
money matters, we have never been aggressive in pursuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>; but the frequent return and regular
orders from some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> reflected some satisfaction
with the results sought.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of our proudest moments came when, upon
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> loading into our computer the CD-ROM of the
discovered that it contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX> quotations from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM</ENAMEX>.  We were pleased, too, when, several years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, we were able to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, a rare occurrence
in the loftier realms of noncommercial publishing.
Also, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> of lesser circulation, have reprinted articles
from VERBATIM.

            With the rarest exceptions, those who wrote to us
seeking information, offering comment or criticismâ€”
and there have been many, from everywhere in the
worldâ€”treated us with kindness and respect, even
when they caught us in the most embarrassing errors.
We have enjoyed chatting with those who have telephoned,
and we haveâ€”without fail, we thinkâ€”sent
written replies to all who have written (with the exception
of those who sent publishable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPISTOLAE</ENAMEX>).
Lately, we have been remiss only in writing discouraging
letters to job <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>, because virtually all
have written merely to a name and address found in
a list of book or periodical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>.

            Our book publishing activities have not shaken
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> beneath our or anyone else's feet: our bestseller
by far has been the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grammar</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Language</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George O. Curme</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> printings),
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lederer</ENAMEX>'s Colonial American
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> a close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> printings).  Other books,
which I still believe to be good ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Word for Word</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward C. Pinkerton</ENAMEX>), amusing ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wordsmanship</ENAMEX> , by
ClaurÃ¨ne duGran, a thinly disguised anagram of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Urdang</ENAMEX>), and useful ( <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Verbatim Volumes I-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX>
and the Index thereto, altogether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> books), have
not fared so well: indeed, a substantial portion of the
stock at our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> consists of
Word for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Word and the Verbatim volumes</ENAMEX>.  Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Disaster</ENAMEX> (though it will probably go unnoticed
on any television series of that name) has been our offering
of VERBATIM binders: one must assume that the
back issues have ended up, along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roebuck</ENAMEX> catalogue, hanging from a nail in the privy.

            We found the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who knewâ€”or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knowâ€”about VERBATIM</ENAMEX> to be astonishing: in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,
among ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>,
among linguists, among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> in general, most
knew of it; alas, they didn't subscribe.

            We, personally, shall miss the correspondence
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>;
and we shall miss the silent majority, those of you
who quietly continued to renew your subscriptions,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, occasionally dropping a line with a
complimentary remark.

            If we owned a green eyeshade, quill pen, and
cuff-protectors, we could tell you, with some sentiment,
that we are hanging them up.  We do not, and
you may be assured that if there is any reason to write
to us, we shall be about (either in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aylesbury</ENAMEX> or Old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyme</ENAMEX>), hence reasonably accessible to answer
your questions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">â€”The Editor</ENAMEX>
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muddled Meaning</ENAMEX>




            Confusion results not only from using the wrong
word, but also from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinful Syntax</ENAMEX>.  In the sentence,
She loves music better than me , the syntax gives
the meaning She loves music better than she loves
me; but a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, infected
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinful Syntax</ENAMEX>, will today understand the sentence
as She loves music better than I love it or ...better
than I do.  If that is really what was meant, then the
sentence should have been, She loves music better
than I .  Elementary!  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> would have said only a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>; but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinful Syntax</ENAMEX> is now pandemic
and contaminates even some of the most careful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>.  For example, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Senate</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, both of whom have said on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> occasion
between you and I, for you and I, like you and
I .  Other examples are:




The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> argue in the media
over whom is more obsessed with sex

[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subheading</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> Press <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> article.]

Who's more to blame?  Them?  Or us?

[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine NBC News</ENAMEX> anchor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Williams</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 May 1996</TIMEX>.)

He is that rarest of travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, one whom his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
feel is completely trustworthy.

[From a review by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John David Morley</ENAMEX> of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The World</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Literary Supplement</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 July 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.7</ENAMEX>.]
            

            Not even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> , our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of record,
is immune.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">caption</ENAMEX> beneath a photograph in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro Section</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1995</TIMEX>, was




<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivy Pearson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>, left, reflecting on the everyday
hardships that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX> like she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lakesha Perry</ENAMEX> face
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brownsville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>.
            

            Sometimes it is not the case that is wrong but the
pronoun itself: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> who; the people
which .  Even possessive pronouns present difficulty
for some.  My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I's constant fear was ... said
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> interviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine NBC News Health</ENAMEX>
Beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Atwood</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 December 1994</TIMEX>;
and, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plante</ENAMEX>'s novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Family</ENAMEX>, hers and
her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">husbands bedroom</ENAMEX> appeared several times.  So
many educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> misuse pronouns that others,
uncertain of what is correct, try to avoid one error by
committing another.  This, at any rate, would explain
the increasingly common for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and myself and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and myself are.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most basic rules of grammar, that decreeing
agreement in number of indefinite article or
demonstrative pronoun with the noun modified, is,
apparently, no longer seen as binding.  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
News <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thom Halleck</ENAMEX> said, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 May 1996</TIMEX>, ...a
potentially-fatal tumors; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angles NBC News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter David Bloom</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1996</TIMEX>, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> occasions,
has spoken of a balanced-budget amendments.
Far more common are errors like the following:



These sort of habitat...
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zoologist Dr. Merlin Tuttle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bat Conservation International</ENAMEX>,
speaking on NPR All Things
Considered, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1995</TIMEX>.]
            

            ...those kind of redeeming aspects...



[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Courts</ENAMEX>, a direct-mail fund-raiser
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacred Heart League</ENAMEX>, quoted
in an article about a film, The Spitfire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grill</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> Press <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 August 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.2</ENAMEX>.]
            

            Breaches of that other basic rule decreeing agreement
in number between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> and verb are at least
as common as the foregoing errors:



Everyone have assured that...

[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston NBC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tewa Che</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 December 1994</TIMEX>.]
            

            If there are such a thing...



[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Walsh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX>, speaking on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 December 1994</TIMEX>.]

The best device [for detecting bombs] are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>.

[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, speaking on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacNeil/Lehrer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Hour</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 December 1994</TIMEX>.]

More generally, there are a variety of pleasures...

[From a review by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stade</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Lehmann-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haupt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Crooked Man</ENAMEX>, in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 February 1995</TIMEX>.]
            

            If meaning is to emerge without ambiguity from
a language like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, largely uninflected and having
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homonyms</ENAMEX> and homophones, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must
be able to recognize not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Parts of Speech but</ENAMEX>
also those peripatetic words that wander from one
category to another.  All your work is undone .  Does
that mean no work was done or the work done was
destroyed?  In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine Sunday Telegram</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1992</TIMEX>, an article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hibernating</ENAMEX> bears
contained this sentence: I have seen some bears double
their size.  Is double verb or adjective?  Treating
adjectives as if they were nouns is a form of abuse
which has become common.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Painting for Posterity</ENAMEX>,
an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sutherland</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegram</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Section E</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1996</TIMEX>,
there was this: [in a portrait] Too broad of a smile
could look maniacal, or like a smirk.

            Even when syntax is not sinful, meaning may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">muddled</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gleick</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> biography, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Genius</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Feynman</ENAMEX> , quoted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> philosopher, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.V. Quine</ENAMEX>: I think that for scientific
purposes the best we can do is give up the notion
of knowledge as a bad job...  Did he mean
give up as a bad [useless, vain] job the notion of knowledge
[of the ability to know anything with precision] or
did he mean give up thinking that knowledge is a bad
[impossible] job?  In light of the context, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> interpretation
seemed more suitable to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>.

            On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1995</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Remains</ENAMEX>, wrote:
Because most of us fear suffering so intensely...
Did she mean fear so intensely [all] suffering or
fear such intense suffering?  In the comic strip
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Valiant</ENAMEX> , whose captions are consistently well
written (and no wonder: their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cullen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>), there was in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1996</TIMEX> sequence:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cormac</ENAMEX>'s arrival was watched... by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populous inhabitants</ENAMEX>.  Perhaps the original was most
of the populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> and was deformed
through some editorial glitchâ€”but even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>, it is said, sometimes nodded.

            Stress may alter meaning in ways unforeseen by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.  On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> August
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, there was this: I think it's what they used to call
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.  Was it something for calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s name?  On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> of the same issue is the ambiguous
He disliked boring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Advertisers</ENAMEX>
often exploit the possibility of a double meaning or of
a pun which shifting stress can provide: A growing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">problem; Drink</ENAMEX> in the sun!; The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you
keep.

            Other ambiguities occur when vernacular expressions
begin to invade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High English</ENAMEX>.  A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Rooks</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 January 1995</TIMEX>,
said, [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say they have no problem with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.  Because of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faddish</ENAMEX> (and odious) No problem!, such a sentence
will soon meanâ€”even now will be understood by
many to meanâ€”that school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> do not disapprove
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            And what of that little word, too?  I cannot
speak too highly of him.  It cannot be too long.
He's not too fond of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, is he?  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costello</ENAMEX> could have wrung a good many laughs
from such sentences, as well as from one in an accident
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>: There was no one to help.  At first, the
meaning seemed to be no one to give help; but,
as the report continued and we learned that the victim
had walked away, the meaning changed to no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to be helped.

            Meaning can be muddled in many ways.  Sense
is slippery.  It easily escapes the nets flung out by
words, even when they are straitened by rules of syntax
and by logic.  When the possibilities for misunderstanding
seem nearly as infinite as words
themselves, what a wondrous thing it is when words
and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' intentions coincide.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salty Sayings</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cornwall</ENAMEX>



            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> way with words tends to be as salty as
their native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilchards</ENAMEX>.  Many old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sayings</ENAMEX> are
concerned with cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down to size and
shrewd thrusts are meant to find their mark!

            The slow-witted are often described as, Like
Tregony <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bandâ€”three scats</ENAMEX> [beats] behind, or as
too slow to carry a cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dennar</ENAMEX> [dinner].  Stronger
still is the old gibe, Put in weth the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and took
out weth the cakes, often muttered behind the deficient
one's back.  Any sign of putting on airs or assertiveness
is frowned upon, and one still hears crude
jokes like, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quietness</ENAMEX> is the best noise as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> said when he knocked down his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, or
Dressed to death like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hatch</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mournful</ENAMEX> looks
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crisply</ENAMEX> dismissed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Cornwall</ENAMEX> as looking
like a dying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> in a thunderstorm.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greed</ENAMEX>, too,
was discouraged with a terse reminder, You don't
need that any more than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">toad</ENAMEX> needs side pockets.

            The famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> pasties provide the saying,
As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Bedella</ENAMEX>'s fiddle if a new young cook
makes a misshapen pasty.  For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> tend to be
rather a critical race owing to their struggle to make
ends meet in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> which has long known economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hardship</ENAMEX>.  A hard-pressed life naturally tends to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blunt</ENAMEX> speech.

            Of a bandy-legged individual you will hear, He
couldn't stop a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> in a passage! and of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lank hair</ENAMEX>,
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> of pump <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.  Even a contented person
is often heard to say, Ah'm happy on me own dung
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heap</ENAMEX>, with typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> self-mockery.  Ask an
older inhabitant for his or her age and you may well
get the familiar reply, As old as my little finger and a
bit older than my teeth.  In a strong-minded county
like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cornwall</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> may be admired as being
as tough as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX>'s motherâ€”an archetypal
dragon lady rooted in local history.

            Being a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish cleave</ENAMEX> naturally
to vivid descriptions.  Any sign of restlessness, for
instance, is summed up as, All of a motion like a
Mulfra <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">toad</ENAMEX> on a red hot shovel, and when shivering,
it is a case of cold as a quilkin [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">frog</ENAMEX>] or chilled to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marra</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX>].  Although pushiness is not a
quality naturally approved of in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cornwall</ENAMEX>, neither is
undue modesty: standing in his own light like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Market Jew</ENAMEX> (another apocryphal figure).
Pride is rebuked as, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fancies</ENAMEX> she was brought up in
Court, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> one end and she t'other!  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laziness</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tartly</ENAMEX> described as, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludlow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, leaning agen
the wall to bark.  As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of weak <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, more
strong words are forthcoming: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX> bewitched and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea begrudged</ENAMEX>.

            More encouraging are the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> sayings,
Turn the best side to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> Show off the best
side of anything and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cheer</ENAMEX> up you'll live till you
die!  More rough good humour comes out in the oft
heard, You'll do it bit by bit as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> said when she
swallowed the hatchet ...I'll manage but it's a tight
fit.

            Dark explanations may be given for misfortune in
Cornwall such as, He bin awverlooked [ill wished].
Still, bracing remarks in plenty urge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> to get on
with things.  After all, concentrate on the basics,
carry a knife, a piece of string and some money; then
you can cut, tie and buy.  Count your blessings, however
meagre, as, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">toad</ENAMEX> is a diamond in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>'s eye.

            The idea that someone has been in a situation
very like your own, long before you, is very prevalent
in these old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> sayings.  Often this has a warning
note, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Fan Todd</ENAMEX> dressed to death and killed
with fashion is one, so is the curious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tongues</ENAMEX> will cut your throat with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX> or hang
you with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX>.  Just as strange is the gluttony
warning, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Dumplens</ENAMEX> after guldize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supper</ENAMEX>, carry me home and don't bend me, for I'm
feeling rather possed up.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX> in young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> is
checked by, Nobody will stop their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> galloping to
look at you.

            Throughout all these sayings, a downright judgmental
tone can be heard, summed up in the old
Cornish last word, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tes</ENAMEX> [it is] an' caan't be no
tesser!  No arguing with that.
         
         
            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANTIPODEAN ENGLISH</ENAMEX>
            
         
         
            Settlement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX>




            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astride Port Jackson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sydney</ENAMEX> marks
the site of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">settlement</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>.
From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> a second convict settlement was established
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobart</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tasmania</ENAMEX>.  To the north, on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moreton Bay</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queensland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brisbane</ENAMEX> was founded;
to the south, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Port Phillip Bay</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>.
Westward round the southern coast,
Adelaide was first approached from the sea as was, at
the western extreme, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perth</ENAMEX>.  In time, overland routes
between these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobart</ENAMEX>, of course, excluded)
were found but, for much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, what
are now the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital cities</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian States</ENAMEX>
were most easily reached by sea.

            In each of these the linguistic situation obtaining
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> was replicated.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> quickly discovered
that knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharuk</ENAMEX> (the Aboriginal
language spoken in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>) was of no help to them in
communicating with the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aboriginesâ</ENAMEX>€”unless the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborigines</ENAMEX> had learned words from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> in the
belief that they were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, as indeed happened
with some pidgin terms and, in the west, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boomerang</ENAMEX> .  In each new settlement, therefore, borrowing
began anew.  So, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brisbane</ENAMEX>, dialects of
Yagara were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> encountered, and the source of
some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> loan words.  In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>, the Victorian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languages</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wuywurung</ENAMEX> (spoken in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dialects on
the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> and to the north and west) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wathawurung</ENAMEX> (spoken on the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">side</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bay</ENAMEX>) were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> source of borrowings,
though the surviving words number no more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>.
The language spoken on the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adelaide</ENAMEX>,
Gaurna, though unusually well recordedâ€”by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lutheran missionaries</ENAMEX> who were amongst the early
settlersâ€”again yielded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about ten</NUMEX> loans.  The extremes
are provided by the nameless <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Tasmanian</ENAMEX> languages,
which gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no more than three</NUMEX> words to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nyungar</ENAMEX>, the language spoken over quite
a large area in the southwest of Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> but
essentially the language of the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perth</ENAMEX>, which
has enriched English with more than fifty loanwords.
The ignorance surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Tasmanian</ENAMEX> languages
betrays the fact that the relationships between convicts
and later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tasmanian</ENAMEX> Aborigines
were of a hostility unreached elsewhere; the continuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fertility of Nyungar</ENAMEX> by contrast results from a
much happier and more accommodating relationship.

            One has to assume that the words which had a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>-based currency in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> were known to
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> because they had been encountered
either in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> or in accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>.  Nonetheless,
there is a sense in which each new settlement
meant a new start, and consequently a duplication in
the nomenclature of key items.  Gunyah , the Dharuk
word for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling</ENAMEX>, is matched by the Melburnian
quamby , a verb meaning lie down, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, and also a
noun meaning shelter, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brisbane humpy</ENAMEX> , the
Adelaide wurley , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perth</ENAMEX> mia mia .  Of these,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hump</ENAMEX> is now the most commonly used, in the general
sense of a hut or temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling</ENAMEX>, whether of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> provenance.  And mia mia
has been widely used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX> in this sense and, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>'s hide.  But the fact
remains that, despite this diversity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> word
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hut</ENAMEX> enjoyed a greater currency than any of the borrowings,
being the usual word for the accommodation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX>, the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labourer</ENAMEX>, and the
itinerant bushman.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pidgin</ENAMEX> acquired a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> negative,
borak , used as an alternative to baal or in a figurative
sense for humbug, nonsense, or rubbish, from
Wathawurung, whence came also an exclamation merrygig
well done and coolie , a derogatory term for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who partnered an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.  It is
ironic that lubra , a word for a black womanâ€”usually
a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> than is connoted by the Dharuk
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin â</ENAMEX>€”was one of the few survivals of the Tasmanian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languages</ENAMEX>, in which it has been suggested that it
meant penis.  From <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yagara</ENAMEX> come bung broken,
dead, yacka , both as a noun and a verb meaning
work, and yohi , an affirmative, all originally in pidgin.

            Other loanwords repeat the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> pattern, striking
or otherwise significant <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX>, and weapons
being named: so there is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tasmanian</ENAMEX> boobialla , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX>-bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acacia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melburnian</ENAMEX> bullan bullan , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beautiful bird</ENAMEX> with a lyre-shaped tail, the Brisbane
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yungan gong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adelaide</ENAMEX> pinkie , a bilby or bandicoot,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perth</ENAMEX> quokka , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of wallaby.  And
there are local names for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, like weet-weet , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> missile used both as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> and as a toy,
-wirra , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, and kylie , a West
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> boomerang.

            Each new settlement meant a new beginning but
so limited was the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> and
Aborigines that there was little progress beyond the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Port Jackson</ENAMEX> model.  Not until travel by land supplemented
and eventually replaced that by sea did incremental
borrowing became at least a possibility, just
as the passage of time meant that there was a likelihood
that a language would be more fully and more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">competently</ENAMEX> recorded.
         
         
            The Case of Nyungar





            Exploration and settlement overland followed
travel by sea.  In particular, once the mountain barrier
had been overcome, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> area
moved inland and to the north.  Thus the languages
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New South Wales</ENAMEX> inlandâ€”Wiradhuri and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamilaroi</ENAMEX> and its dialect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuwaalaraayâ</ENAMEX>€”formed part
of a borrowing continuum which began with Dharuk
and which incorporated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> pidgin which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Collins</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Fleet</ENAMEX>, had described
as a barbarous mixture of English with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Port Jackson</ENAMEX> dialect.  Words like gammon and piccaninny ,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> slang and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> pidgin respectively,
joined a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Jackson</ENAMEX> words to form a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pidgin</ENAMEX> in which limited communication was possible.
This was added to as it travelled north and west by
words like yabber talk, based on the root ya -, found
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wiradhuri</ENAMEX> and other languages), the Yagara
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brisbane</ENAMEX>) words bung dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">humpy dwelling</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yacka</ENAMEX> work (as noun and verb), and, particularly, by
names for <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX> the travellers now recognized
as being commonly found in the inland.  So
Wiradhuri words like corella and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang-gang</ENAMEX> , names
for cockatoos, kookaburra , a kingfisher, boggi , a lizard,
belah , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Casuarina</ENAMEX>, billabong anabranch, gilgai waterhole,
and bondi , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, became parts of everyday
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian English</ENAMEX>, as did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamilaroi</ENAMEX> words brolga ,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crane</ENAMEX>, budgerigar , a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX>, coolamon wooden
vessel or basin, gundy , yet another word for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hut</ENAMEX>, and
towri <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> of an Aboriginal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuwaalaraay</ENAMEX> words galah , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX>, and
gidgee , an acacia, and words common to Kamilaroi
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuwaalaraay</ENAMEX> like the names of other species of
acacia such as boree and mulga .  When a would-be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poet</ENAMEX> writes the lines,



Where the tangled boree blossoms,
Where the gidya thickets wave,
And the tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yapunyah</ENAMEX>'s shadow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rests</ENAMEX> upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stockman</ENAMEX>'s grave
            

            he has, in a sense, guaranteed the currency of the
words he uses.

            Much the same sort of continuum exists in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nyungar</ENAMEX>, which had a number of advantages
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dharuk</ENAMEX>, has provided for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 150</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> a source of loan words.  First, the settlement in
the west took place some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after that in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> had a better idea of what they
were handling.  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, though the language is no
longer spoken, it was more fully and more intelligently
recorded than those first encountered.  And,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, as a matter of governmental policy, Aboriginal
names for <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX> have been preferred.  So,
for instance, the names of the farmed freshwater crayfish,
koonac , and marron , have only short histories of
usage in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, coincident with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>, though
they were first recorded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>.  And
there are substantial lists of the names of treesâ€” jarrah,
karri, mallett, marri, tuart , and wandoo â€”and of
animalsâ€” chuditch, dalgite, dunnart, kumarl, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">nool-benger</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">numbat â€”that</ENAMEX> are familiar at least in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west</ENAMEX>.

            There are also words representative of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> life, such as boylya cleverman or
wise elder, gnamma waterhole, kylie boomerang,
miamia <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling</ENAMEX>, monaych , originally the name of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cockatoo</ENAMEX> and by transference a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, nyoongar
Aboriginal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, wagyl , the mythical rainbow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">serpent</ENAMEX>, wilgie , a red ochre used to paint the
body on ceremonial occasions, and wongi , a word for
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, originally used around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kalgoorlie</ENAMEX>.

            But, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyungar</ENAMEX> words supply a more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> life than do the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharuk</ENAMEX> or those from any single inland language, the
greater number of words used to denote key notions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> belief and life are special uses of English
words like cleverman, which has replaced words like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharuk</ENAMEX> koradji and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyoongar</ENAMEX> boylya , which
are effectively obsolete.  So the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> equivalent
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creation</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dreamtime</ENAMEX> , itself a translation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alcheringa</ENAMEX> (an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aranda</ENAMEX> word), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bark hut</ENAMEX> is preferred
to gunyah or humpy, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamilaroi</ENAMEX> towri ,
and walkabout to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyungar</ENAMEX> pink-eye .  And bark
paintings are known in the terms in which they are
characterized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX>, as dot or X-ray
paintings.  The language of the invaders is the language
of choice, except in the artificially maintained
case of the nomenclature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX>.

            In other words, although the opportunity was
there for borrowing on a larger scale and with a degree
of comprehensiveness that had not been
achieved hitherto, it has not been taken.  In the west,
as elsewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the lexicographical evidence
of a developing understanding of the indigenous peoples
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> is slight indeed.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proliferating Plurals</ENAMEX> (and Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singular Substitutions</ENAMEX>)



            It seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> have invented a new rule: Whenever possible,
use plurals.  Thus television, radio, and newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> tell us:



<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Aids</ENAMEX> and assistances were given by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>.

The conditions of the bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are unknown.

An oil spill has impacted [i.e., affected] many fishing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crafts</ENAMEX>.

Damages to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> from the collision were slight.

It was a meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> faithfuls.

The futures of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are in doubt.

Toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> in their drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> have caused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harms</ENAMEX>.

A passing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorist</ENAMEX> gave much-needed helps after the
accident.

The intelligences of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are the same.

I am writing in regards to...

A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> savings over the regular price...
[A retiring football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>] always worried about the
academic standings of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>.

Fog will lower visibilities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
            

            At the same time, perhaps from an unconscious discomfort
caused by so many perplexing plurals, there
has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>trend in the opposite direction.  One
form has been the de facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singularization</ENAMEX> of some
commonly used words of foreign origin: L <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX>,
datum, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, stratum ; It graffito ; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LL</ENAMEX> (fr <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gk</ENAMEX>) phenomenon ;
Gk criterion .  Though all are currently
being used almost exclusively in plural form, they are
treated as if they were singular, e.g., a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, etc.
The more usual form of singularizing appears when
we are told that someone is no longer in the good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX>  of someone else; the ground for divorce was...;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> or custodian (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>] of a school
building was also responsible for the upkeep of its
ground ; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, evidently mightily disturbed
by the prevalent pluralism, even tried to
make a singular noun still more so by lopping off its
final s : a specie of mammal (which one might think is
right on the money).  Though the singular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> is
far outstripped by the multiple mania, one can expect,
in this age of downsizing, to encounter more of
the less and less of the more.

         
         
            What's In a Name?
            This slightly enlarged version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Dickson</ENAMEX>'s
Names , published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delacorte Press</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, is a
light-hearted collection of names that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> considers
to be interesting for one reason or another.  We
are invited to share his delight in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embraceable Zoo</ENAMEX>
(for a store selling toys), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Onan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Parker</ENAMEX>'s pet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">canary</ENAMEX> who spilled his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robot Redford</ENAMEX> (a robot
which once gave a commencement address), and
many similar examples.  For most of us, these are typical
tit-bits that raise a passing smile when we come
across them as column-fillers in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.  To
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irrespressible</ENAMEX> name-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Dickson they</ENAMEX>
bring the thrill of a new find that anyone who has
ever collected anything will understand.  I have
known a few name-collectors in my time, and they
are an enthusiastic bunch.  I remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbard</ENAMEX> showing me the filing cabinets in his New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, crammed with lists of personal names
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mollie Panter-Downes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo Yench</ENAMEX> .  I also
recall with affection the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leaver</ENAMEX>, who cycled
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> countryside as a boy collecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pub-</ENAMEX>names.  He was still collecting them in his seventies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leaver</ENAMEX> is not mentioned in this book, which
is very thin on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>.  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickson</ENAMEX> says, for
instance, that he has long had a special passion for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apple</ENAMEX> names, and quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> of them,
but he ignores the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Apple Register</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uriel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.G. Smith</ENAMEX>, which catalogues
the names of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22,000</NUMEX> cultivars.  (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Smith</ENAMEX>
once amused herself by working <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">365</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX> names into
a story, which began:



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mrs Toogood</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little</ENAMEX>
Beauty, but rather a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coquette</ENAMEX>, despaired of ever seeing
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Golden/Ring on the Lady's Finger...</ENAMEX>)
            

            We need not cavil, of course, at the absence of such
obvious reference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>; in a work like this the author
has the right to favour serendipity over methodical
research.

            Whether he has the right to be needlessly careless
in his statements is perhaps another matter.  As a
typical example, we read that the word derrick , derived
from the surname of a famous hangman, was
in use for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> as a name for the gallows.  A
glance at the citations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> or at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partridge</ENAMEX>'s article
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Name Into Word</ENAMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickson</ENAMEX> cites in his
bibliography, would have made it clear that this usage
did not extend beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>.  It is also
news to me that I once wrote a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Names , mentioned on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX>.  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickson</ENAMEX>'s definition
of name is itself rather unsatisfactory.  Why are
we suddenly treated on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> to an incomplete list
of -ine words ( bovine, feline, lupine , etc.)?  What are
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nouns</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wettfahrt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahrtwind</ENAMEX> (printed
without their capital letters) doing here?  The latter
may interest those who make a special study of flatulence
(perdologists?), if such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> exist, but these
are not names.

            There is no need to include non-names in a book
of this kind when we are surrounded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
minor nomenclatures.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on which these
words are printed, for instance, as well as the typeface
and even the ink, have names.  Almost any generic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noun</ENAMEX> can be broken down into named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subdivisions</ENAMEX>.
To a knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pogonologist</ENAMEX>, a beard is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bodkin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral, Ducktail</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goatee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lavatory Brush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial</ENAMEX>,
Pique-devant, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spade, Stiletto</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vandyke</ENAMEX> , to name but
a few.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least two hundred</NUMEX> types of hat have more
specific names.  If Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickson</ENAMEX> wished to remain thoroughly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, he could still find interesting names
on his doorstep.  Let me recommend the names of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-pin bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, which often pun on strike, split ,
or pin .  (The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-fifties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for which I play is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irons</ENAMEX>: we strike while the iron's hot and also play
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Merriam-Webster</ENAMEX> say that this book forms part of
their lighter side of language series.  I hope that
they will at some stage do justice to the more scholarly
work that has been done, especially on place names
and personal names.  Names and naming rightly attract
the attention of philologists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>,
literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, and others.  Huge sums of
money are spent on finding suitable brand names.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Dickson</ENAMEX> has every right to approach names in a
light-hearted way, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet</ENAMEX>'s question, What's in a
name?  can be answered in many more intellectually
satisfying ways than this.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames Ditton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Surrey</ENAMEX>
            
         
         
            Chasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonathon Green</ENAMEX> has deservedly acquired the
mantle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Partridge</ENAMEX> as the foremost authority on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> slang.  His books are many; listed on the back
flap of the dustjacket of this book are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macmillan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dictionary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Slang</ENAMEX>, The Slang
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thesaurus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neologisms</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Words</ENAMEX> Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, Slang
Down the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ages</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Development of Slang</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dictionary of Jargon</ENAMEX> .

            The present work is a departure for him, for most
of his earlier works have been reference books.  I
have heard some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX>'s broadcasts and interviews,
and he comes off quite well, for he is smooth and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glib</ENAMEX>, just what is needed for radio.  That style translated
into book form, however, makes this book seem
greatly overwritten.  Its main fault lies in the reliance
on extensive quotations from the works described,
the sort of thing one expects to be paraphrased by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian</ENAMEX>, with the original matter buried in footnotes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercifully</ENAMEX>, there are few such notes, and they come at
the end of the book where they can be ignored.  The
problem with the quotations is that they are often
quite long and neither interesting nor revealing, often
serving to support a point made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, whom
I would be happy to believe on his own recognizance.
Still, there are a number of errors which ought to be
corrected for any subsequent edition or printing.
            

            Green's account of the early history of dictionary-making
is very useful and interesting, for it gathers
together information about the personal lives (and
qualificationsâ€”or lack thereof) of the famous lexicographers.
One might quarrel with an occasional
comment (like, [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Techne</ENAMEX> ] might be said to have
become the basis of every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> textbook that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolboys</ENAMEX>,
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and elsewhere, would face until the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 1000</TIMEX>, which must have encompassed a relatively
small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX>), but such are few and far between in
the earlier chapters of the book.  It is not till we arrive
at the final chapter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Modern World</ENAMEX>, that serious
inadequacies rear their ugly heads.

            Green writes:



[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Lexicographers</ENAMEX>] have retained their priestly role, especially
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and especially in the world of
what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> terms college and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> concise
dictionaries,...

[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p. 359</ENAMEX>]
            

            The simple facts are that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> college (or
desk) dictionaries today contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 170,000</NUMEX> entries
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> that number of headwords), up from
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Â±130,000</NUMEX> they had till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> concise
dictionaries contain far fewer than that: the Concise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> , the best-selling dictionary in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>, contains
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 120,000</NUMEX> entries (probably not more than about
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60,000 headwords</NUMEX>), which is equivalent to what are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classed</ENAMEX> as concise dictionaries in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.  As far as
I am aware, what are called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or desk dictionaries
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> have no special label in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>,
though <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several</TIMEX>, notably the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Collins Dictionary</ENAMEX> , are of
comparable extent.

            Green is correct in writing that the (unabridged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Funk & Wagnalls</ENAMEX>) Standard <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of the English</ENAMEX>
Language (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>) gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pronunciations for each
entry, but he is mistaken in reporting that one represents
the popular pronunciation, the other showing
the precise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p.364</ENAMEX>]: there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pronunciations
because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> employs a more popular, presumably
understandable pronunciation key (called, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">phonetics</ENAMEX> trade, a broad transcription) while the
other cleaves to a scholarly transcription (called a narrow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX>); if such a pattern were followed
today, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> would be the simplified system used
generally in most dictionaries and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> would
employ the symbols of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Phonetic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alphabet</ENAMEX> (which, for their more recondite transcriptions,
require a trained phonetician for their understanding).

            
In discussing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam-Webster</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New International Dictionary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MW-III</ENAMEX>),
Green describes one of its main advances as a general
move away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s traditional prescriptive
lexicography, towards a more descriptive, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
style. Such a move had, indeed, taken place many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Gove</ENAMEX>'s editorship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">MW-III</ENAMEX>
and is evidenced in such works as the Merriam-Webster
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collegiate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s New World, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College</ENAMEX> dictionaries, among others.  Some
of these dictionaries contain notes describing contentious
issues of usage (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infer</ENAMEX>/imply, reason is
because/that , etc.), but those are, essentially, reflective
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of the language, hence
can be set forth as descriptive.

            On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">366</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">MW-III</ENAMEX> as containing
450,000 headwords: it does not, of course; it
contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450,000</NUMEX> entries.  The notion of entry, as described
many times in these pages, includes (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-word,(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inflected</ENAMEX> forms (which, in the sole case of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">MW-III</ENAMEX> , includes regular inflections, which pumps
up the entry count considerably), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) changes in parts
of speech, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) embedded boldface entries (like idioms
and phrases), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) run-on forms (those that are added at
the ends of entries to illustrate headwords with suffixes
of transparent meaning added, e.g., national and nationally
run on to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and nationalization run on to
nationalize , (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) spelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">variants</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> honour,
nationalise, nationalisation , etc.).  Thus, a dictionary
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 80,000</NUMEX> headwords, the size of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictionaries</ENAMEX>, contains more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170,000</NUMEX> entries.  I do not know how many headwords
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">MW-III</ENAMEX> contains, but it is far, far fewer than
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450,000</NUMEX> entries claimed.  (Those who greet with
consternation what might seem to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s fiddling
with counts in dictionaries ought to know that the
system for such counting was worked out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>,
mainly between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam-Webster</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>, which was then in charge of all
government purchases, as a means for assessing the information
content of dictionaries being purchased for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, a responsibility later shifted to another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.)

            On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">379</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> writes:



There are, after all, a number of books of Americanisms
but none, although there have been plans to fill
this gap, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Briticisms</ENAMEX>.
            

            That is not quite accurate, for, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macmillan</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US; Johnson</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>) published
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman W. Schur</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Self-Taught</ENAMEX>; revised and
expanded, it was published as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English English</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VERBATIM BOOKS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>; revised and expanded further,
it was published as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British English</ENAMEX> A to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zed</ENAMEX> by
Facts On File in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 1990</TIMEX>. It is not entirely accurate
to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schur</ENAMEX>'s book as a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>, for, although
it is in alphabetical order (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briticism</ENAMEX>, with
the American equivalent in the Index), it combines
definitions with descriptions of cultural phenomena
(as in the entry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashes</ENAMEX> , which needs an explanation
rather than a mere definition).

            Green's treatment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern World</ENAMEX> of lexicography
is very thin on the ground.  Bare mention is
made of the most important and best-selling dictionaries
published in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX>, when the sales of
all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">dictionaries</ENAMEX> exploded throughout the
world.  It is probably true to say that an entire book
could be written about this recent period in dictionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, including not only the reflection of
sound linguistic philosophy but the effects of the introduction
of computers into the dictionary research,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compilation</ENAMEX>, composition, and accession (as through
personal computers to CD-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROMS</ENAMEX> and diskettes): certainly
there is more documented information about it than
the period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several hundered years</TIMEX> covered in the first
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> chapters of Chasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> .

            But one must be grateful to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonathon Green</ENAMEX> at
least for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, which gather in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place an enormous amount of interesting, useful
information about (deceased) lexicographers and the
dictionaries they prepared.  The title, which will make
the book difficult to find amongst others that deal
with dictionaries, is from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s Introduction to
his dictionary.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 239:</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guildford Connecticut</ENAMEX>, read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guilford</ENAMEX>.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 244</ENAMEX>: If asks is correct, then there should be a ? at
the end of the quoted matter.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 244: new-dangleâ€”ok</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 245:</ENAMEX> for accumen read acumen.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 276</ENAMEX>: (bottom) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Walker Read</ENAMEX> read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 298:</ENAMEX> for no less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> read no fewer...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 306</ENAMEX>: correct to join at the this period.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 307:</ENAMEX> for reconsituted read reconstituted.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 310:</ENAMEX> for enormity read immensity.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 311:</ENAMEX> for slacked read slackened.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 319:</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor</ENAMEX>, it turned, out... read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor</ENAMEX>, it
turned out,...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 329:</ENAMEX> for  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Beaux Strategem</ENAMEX>  read  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaux</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagem</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 333:</ENAMEX> for fulsome read flattering or effusive, etc.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 361:</ENAMEX> for pronounciation read pronunciation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 369</ENAMEX>: (in extract) for grey read gray (the way the
word was spelt by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDavid</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 370:</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encyclopedia Britannica</ENAMEX> read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encyclopaedia Britannica</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 378:</ENAMEX> for soldily read solidly.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 392</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.4</NUMEX>) what does  IEL  stand for?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.: (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.5</NUMEX>) Trench [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] is not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibliography</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. 418:</ENAMEX> for  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House College Dictionary</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>-4
read ..<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.35</NUMEX>-6.
         
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Terms</ENAMEX>
            We need not be bludgeoned with the information
that the world has become more bureaucracy-ridden
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few decades</TIMEX>, a trend that probably began
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> to be reinforced through <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
It is probably the language that has borne much of the
burden in that development: the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> citation for
acronym in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>, quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Notes
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queries</ENAMEX> , which refers to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, unidentified
usage of the term.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1940s</TIMEX> we were besieged
by repl <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">depots</ENAMEX> (pronounced REPil DEPOZe), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> ,
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of other acronyms and abbreviations
the meaning of which we learned through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> repetition
on news broadcasts.

            (I find it convenient to distinguish an abbreviation
as a shortening that is not or cannot be pronounced,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>, from an acronym as a shortening that is pronounced
as a word, like ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lib</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WREN</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMSAT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> , etc.  Those who specialize
in this area prefer to subsume them all under the general
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rubric</ENAMEX>, initialism , a term quoted by the OED
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the 1890s</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queries</ENAMEX>, but one that
did not become current, I believe, till <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gale Research</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX> published <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Acronyms and Initialisms Dictionary</ENAMEX> ,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>.  An enormous work, that book has
grown by the publication of periodic supplements.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care</ENAMEX> Terms contains a good deal besides
initialisms, but I focus on those because they are probably
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the jargon we are faced
with whenever we encounter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureaucracy</ENAMEX>: as if
the compounding of incomprehensible, undescriptive
jargon were not enough, those who concoct that obfuscating
gobbledygook are not content till they have
turned it into an abbreviation or an acronym.  The jargon
also becomes sprinkled with euphemisms, among
which I count health care professional , a definition for
whichâ€”too long to repeat hereâ€”appears in this book
under professional .  Part of it (excluding the awkward
pronoun of reference) is pertinent:



...[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ome individuals</ENAMEX> may call themselves professional
with little or no training.  For example, there
are no minimum requirements to be a nutritionist,
so anyone can call him or herself <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
            

            During a recent hospital stay (my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>), I learned that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who mops the floor is referred to as a
health professional, along with what I would have
called the medical orderly who has the responsibility
for taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood samples</ENAMEX>, the registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> in attendance,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> floor or ward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>, and the various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>.  Having been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosby's Medical</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nursing Dictionary</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">first edition</TIMEX>),
it occurred to me that I, too, might be termed
a health care professional; so too, perhaps, might
an inveterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypochondriac</ENAMEX>.

            This book can do nothing, of course, to relieve us
of the sort of vocabulary that makes a garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or
dustman into a waste removal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, but it is
enormously helpful in explaining, in a straightforward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> and (unfortunately) without rancor, what bureaucracy
has bequeathed us.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evidently</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GP</ENAMEX> no
longer exists, having been replaced by the family
practice practitioner, now considered a medical specialty.
Naturally, family practice is referred to as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPâ</ENAMEX>€”what else?  why not FamPrac?â€”for which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Terms</ENAMEX> offers the following definition:


The specialty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> which deals with providing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supervising</ENAMEX>, and coordinating the continuing
general medical care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> of all ages, primarily
in family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.  The care provided is primary care.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the medical specialties for which residency
programs have been approved by the Accreditation
See specialty.
            

            I suppose that means that as an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divorcÃ©</ENAMEX> who
lives alone, I am only marginally entitled to treatment,
for a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> can scarcely be considered a
family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.  This specialty reminds me of a time,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some decades ago</TIMEX>, when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> advised me, indignantly,
that he was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GP</ENAMEX>: gesturing to a
framed certificate hanging on the wall of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, he
told me in no uncertain terms that he was an internist,
to which I replied that I should thereafter
require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, an internist and a dermatologist.
He didn't see the humor of that remark.

            If one's field touches on the medical profession,
insurance, or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> concerned with the bureaucracy
(which I am always tempted to spell bureaucrazy),
this is an essential aid in unraveling and
clarifyingâ€”insofar as is possibleâ€”the verbiage that
assails <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from all sides.  Although the average victim
of the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> need not have this as a
vademecum, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, private, and, especially, hospital
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">librarians</ENAMEX> should note its great value as an adjunct to
the other reference books available, none of which
covers the same territory.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appendices</ENAMEX> round
out the usefulness of this work.

            It would be only fair to mention that the terminology
is that used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Urdang</ENAMEX>
         
         
            Ship to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shore</ENAMEX>

            My aim in this work is to illustrate what I believe is
the astonishing debt that our idiomatic speech owes
to the nautical language of the past.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is extraordinarily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> in metaphor, and it is the intention of
this book to show that many of the figures of speech
that we use from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to day derive from the language
and customs of the sea.

            â€”From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preface</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter D. Jeans</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> who writes a column
in The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Australian</ENAMEX> on the origin of words.
This is a substantial, useful, interesting work, but if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader/user</ENAMEX> is seeking an authoritative, documented
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archive</ENAMEX> of nautical expressions, he may be disappointed.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VERBATIM</ENAMEX> are aware, we give
short shrift to the trappings of academia in our pages:
we eschew footnotes (with rare exceptions) as well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bibliographies</ENAMEX>.  But in reviewing the works of others,
attention must be paid to such materials, and the
Bibliography of Selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> and Dictionaries
Consulted include only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-five</TIMEX> titles under the
former category (plus fifteen of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick O'Brian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aubrey</ENAMEX> novels) and only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> under the latter, some of
which are curious choices indeed: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hunter</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Dictionary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Language</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collier</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>, which I have never heard of; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partridge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Origins: A Short Etymological Dictionary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Modern English</ENAMEX> contains a great many errors and
ought to be avoided by serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>; the author
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evidently</ENAMEX> chose not to wade through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX>,
relying instead on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAdam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milne</ENAMEX>'s A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Selection</ENAMEX>.
            

            Still, it is unfair to judge a book by its peripherals.
Before getting to the content, let us look at the appendices,
of which there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>.  The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, Nautical
Prepositions, includes aback, abeam, about, abox,
a-cockbill, adrift, and other words that are adverbs,
not prepositions, along with ahoy and a few others
beginning with a -: evidently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> believes that
many nautical words beginning with a- are prepositions,
which is simply not the case.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Appendix 2</ENAMEX> contains
Changed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spellings and Corrupted Word Forms</ENAMEX>;
although the information given here is accurate as far
as I could tell, it is confusing to have some words
listed under their original spelling (studding sail,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treenail</ENAMEX>) and others in their corrupted form (gunnel,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bosun</ENAMEX>) â€”and what happened to trunnel?  I fear that
there is a great deal more to the question of spelling
and pronunciation than has been allowed for.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Appendix 3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nautical Terms Related to Human</ENAMEX>
Anatomy, shows nauticalisms that were borrowed
from anatomical terms, not the other way round.  The
coverage is a bit loose, but no one is likely to consider
earring an anatomical term, and forelock, a
small iron wedge of pin driven through a hole or slot
at the end of a sheave-pin to prevent it from working
out, contains a - lock from a door, not from a forehead,
which has a different etymological origin.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nautical Terms Derived</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land</ENAMEX>, Appendix
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, is divided into the sublistings Domestic
Environment and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Environment</ENAMEX>.  The suitability
for such treatment varies: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosun</ENAMEX>'s chair is listed
simply because it is a chair; cap is listed presumably
because it is thought to refer to an item of apparel.
But a chair is virtually anything for an individual to sit
on and cap, etymologically at least, originally meant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cape</ENAMEX> (with a hood) or so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> has it.  Without
dated citations for the earliest occurrences of these
words in a nautical context, how is one to know if they
were derived from the Land or merely coincidental
with them?

            Still, no serious harm.  Let us now turn to the
main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of the work.  Opening it at random we
find, appropriately enough,



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogwash Sailor</ENAMEX>'s slang for nonsense, rubbish, a tale
with no truth in it; and worthless stuff:
His claim that he is an experienced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motor</ENAMEX> mechanic is all hogwash.
            

            Aside from the unfortunate quotation, which hardly
seems nautical at all, hogwash is ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>,
which, it may be assumed, (English-speaking) sailors
used as a medium in which to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> their nauticalisms.
Thus, the direction would seem to have been
from everyday word to language of the sea, and not,
as advertised, vice versa.  The same must be said for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hitch</ENAMEX>, go without a hitch, get hitched, hoist, hold off,
hold on , and scores of other entries: these were everyday
words in the general language before they were
used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>.  The problemâ€”and it is a serious oneâ€”
is that there are, indeed, many words and phrases that
originated at sea and were brought ashore for ready
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embodiment</ENAMEX> in everyday speech, but to find the same
terms in both does not justify the assertion that the sea
term came first.

            It must be saidâ€”and I believe I shall be borne out
on thisâ€”that relying on citations appearing in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> or in works written long ago is a precarious business:
the only accurate, safe statement that can be
made about such information is that it provides evidence
for the existence of a word in a given context at
the time of publication of the work: it cannot and must
not be construed as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the word appeared
on the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, merely as the first written
evidence we have of its appearance.  Clearly, that is not
to say that most words appearing in quotations in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> and in any other (original) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> are being used
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX>: on the contrary, it is very likelyâ€”and
this might well apply to terms of art of a specialized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX> and, particularly, the speech of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>, who did
not enjoy an entirely savory reputationâ€”that the terms
were in oral use for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> before they were written
down.  Consider how long it took lexicographers to
include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-letter words in their dictionaries; yet we
know from long experience with spoken <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> that
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hundred years</TIMEX> hence would be wrong
to conclude that those terms were invented or even
came into general use at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 20th century</TIMEX>.
(And still not all are listed.)

            A problem arises when those who would swallow
dictionaries whole are left to conclude that their content
is sacrosanct.  Those who try to apply a scientific
approach to the assessment of data become rapidly
aware that what we are examining is not likely to be
completeâ€”which is certainly true when dealing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languageâ€”or</ENAMEX> even accurate, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alchemists</ENAMEX> and
other early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in science discovered.

            There is a certain charm seen in working the
alchemy of language, and we can well appreciate it in
the context of artistic license.  But it is quite another
thing when it is foisted on an unsuspecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> as
fact, when, indeed, it is either pure speculation or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">writer's</ENAMEX> interpretation of the best way to make data fit
into the procrustean bed of his theory.
