
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		let's see did i press one
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		did i okay i didn't know whether you could hear because i i have to take the phone away from my ear to do it
 	
 	
 		i guess that was one
 	
 	
 		did you hear it
 	
 	
 		i heard the beep
 	
 	
 		all right we're on uh hey <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> who's your favorite team
 	
 	
 		uh i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Durham Bulls</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay and uh uh  we're not to have much mutual interest there but i'm curious uh uh what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> are they class A
 	
 	
 		yeah they're i think a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">farm league</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but uh they're they're the closest by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah do you go
 		do you go see them very often
 	
 	
 		yeah actually uh we went a couple of times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i haven't gone they started i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		well i imagine they're just starting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you you know what's exciting about watching i never watched minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> until i came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> because i was raised one near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> and then i went to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> so i became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirate</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and i was never in a minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> until i came <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> we were a minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> when i came here in fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and i immediately bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> tickets uh to the class triple A uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and then the class uh double A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth Spurs</ENAMEX> we later uh they went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> league
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh i just really enjoy it i guess i enjoy watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> when they were very first starting out playing here and then seeing them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two later</TIMEX> as as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> in the majors
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i i think that's probably the fun of watching minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and the other thing is watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on the other end uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that i had seen play for both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh they get to the other end of their career and now they come up and talk to you between innings of games i i think that was exciting too uh have you seen any minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaguers</ENAMEX> come through uh any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> come through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> that are now in the big time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh not not yet i mean i
 	
 	
 		not yet okay well of course you're at the class A level you're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> away from that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh hang on a second <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> i got to see who that is
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you still there <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		yeah uh uh do you follow any major league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh which ones
 	
 	
 		uh i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay well how do you think they're going to do this year
 	
 	
 		um fair
 		i don't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX> are so uh unpredictable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> huh
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> will do well
 	
 	
 		well i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX> picked up some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX> market didn't they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> i guess what surprised me most about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> was letting uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valenzuela</ENAMEX> go
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know he's getting old i think they got their money their money's worth out of him though
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they probably did he probably i was reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that what may have happened to him is he pitched too many innings too young
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they say that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s pitching that that his arm is still developing until he's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> and if pitches a whole lot of innings before that it may take its toll later in life
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		of course i've been watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> and uh  it doesn't seem to bother him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh he he has to be an outstanding physical specimen to to do what he's done
 	
 	
 		yeah well have you heard anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Palmer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX> tried a comeback
 		and uh got sore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> early and they uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> are playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> this game that i'm watching and just the last inning they put the camera over on he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks Robinson</ENAMEX> they are the broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and apparently apparently his uh his come back just didn't make it and that he got he got hurt early in the uh in the uh uh in the spring training uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> have got an interesting thing they've got this uh rookie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> what's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Martinez</ENAMEX> his name
 		that uh that pitched a bunch of innings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> as a nineteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty year old year old</TIMEX> and they were using what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valenzuela</ENAMEX> as an example that they should be careful and not over work him this early of course i was really uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dodger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> when they won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World World Series</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hershiser</ENAMEX> won all those games in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> that was that was really a
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> they beat the As
 		yeah that was really dramatic they were
 	
 	
 		uh yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> they beat the As i was really and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i can still remember that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Gibson</ENAMEX> home run
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they were such under dogs
 	
 	
 		yeah they were because everybody thought the As were the greatest things in the world and uh we've got we're the only ones around here that got cable and that particular game was some reason or another was on a cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s in high school and all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		um
 	
 	
 		we're all sitting around we must have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> watching it gosh gosh everybody just erupted when that happened and uh that was uh uh strictly an outstanding game uh the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX> i'm not uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> we have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> here so i don't get that much into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> stuff here i see them on the game of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> occasionally and i haven't seen the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that much i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Smith</ENAMEX> retiring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> left a big hole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offensively</ENAMEX> who do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX> look to to drive in a lot of runs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't even know anymore i i follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX> but uh i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> i guess that's why
 	
 	
 		who do they
 		of course you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Marshall</ENAMEX> was the big guy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that uh
 		uh they won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Gibson</ENAMEX> Who who are are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> big RBI <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think i um
 		i don't know  i thought i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Ranger</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you you know they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> but i think they're going to be one and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of today</TIMEX> they're sitting here with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> with a uh fifteen to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> lead
 	
 	
 		uh i think that's pretty
 	
 	
 		that looks that was fairly comfortable yeah and it was why and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> pitched the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> innings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and he gave up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> runs in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> inning and i said oh my God here we go again you know you know with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outs walk walk home run b ang we're down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to nothing
 	
 	
 		pretty good guess
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their half of the first and then</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX> was invincible
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		he went out after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> and had he had only give up those uh that one hit in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> inning and another hit so he went out after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> inning with a uh it at the time he had a uh i think uh a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three ten</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> lead and uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh he had only given up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hits and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> walks and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> strike outs so he's he's back in the groove and a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> his age <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this this afternoon</TIMEX> here it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventy nine degrees</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a little bit humid clear blue sky and the sunshine
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> don't play <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">many afternoon</TIMEX> games because of the heat we have here in the summer
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh they try to play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April May</TIMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
 		and uh uh with the bright sky like this where you've got a real bright day when he's out there throwing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ninety four ninety five miles an hour</NUMEX> he's almost invincible
 	
 	
 		right
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh that's just a exciting uh is really exciting sitting here watching him on TV <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		um
 		wow often how often do you go out to the baseball park
 	
 	
 		uh well it different times different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> because
 		because
 		because my uh
 		uh my job takes me out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a lot and it always seems to be during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we got to go out maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a dozen</NUMEX> times which is the most we've ever gone out and we had about uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		won uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty three</NUMEX> games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> which was just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more than they lost but we had an exciting time and that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time in about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> period we went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> straight wins
 	
 	
 		um
 		wow
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we happen to go out there on win night and uh uh they and they got hot then and i'm not sure they put the prices up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> a ticket <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we may have to go less but
 	
 	
 		um
 		um
 	
 	
 		what we like to do the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> have got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tiers to them and we like to be in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> tier behind home plate about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> row
 	
 	
 		right
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> holds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about forty thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh i never go on a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> when they think there's going to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand</NUMEX> there's just too big crowds i i pick the games where they don't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		expect to have a high attendance and uh what what about your your ball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> uh the minor league ball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX> they're they're thinking about moving it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 		but it's it holds maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four thousand</NUMEX>  and it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dollars to get in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		oh that is great when i got here in the class triple A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> we used to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and if you bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX> ticket it was only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one dollar</NUMEX> a game
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh uh that is fine and not only that but you probably get some pretty good seats too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we're in the pretty much wherever you want to sit
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah what do they do they have times of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> where they have promotions and you get gigantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> like maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four thousand</NUMEX> where they actually sell the place out
 	
 	
 		yeah they they give out stuff and it's have you ever seen the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bull Durham</ENAMEX> i mean it's just like that exactly
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well a little more modern <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> but not much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i love that movie i absolutely love that and i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> uh you know the class A salaries are are really uh not anything a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can live on too much so i guess they've got to go out and find rooming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		things like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bull Durham</ENAMEX> did With fairly economical accommodations
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh uh the other thing is that that's really hard but of course you recognize the minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> exists for the purpose of the major league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and the problem we always had in triple A is you want to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> go good but then when they go good you know you're going to lose them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>
 		and i guess at at your level uh you lose them to the next level if if they decide to recall the the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> decide to call to recall a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from triple A then a double A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> goes up to replace him and a single A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> goes up to replace him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and and you've immediately uh now you got you you go out to the ball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> is not there anymore and you say you've got you've got to learn his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> but do you get any local uh do they broadcast games locally or televise them locally
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		no
 		there's actually there may be an AM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> that does it i'm not there may be an AM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> that does it but i'm not i'm not really sure
 	
 	
 		no so you've you've got to uh uh
 		yeah okay so
 		so you you've pretty much got to the ball park uh uh to figure out but
 	
 	
 		yeah but it's i mean you could you the game could be at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifteen</ENAMEX> and you could say hey let's go to the game and you'll get a seat
 	
 	
 		yeah but yeah yeah uh uh there's probably that's pretty neat because i don't imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>'s so big that you have big traffic jams going one way or the other
 	
 	
 		no i mean it's it's actually there's an interstate
 		
 		
 	