
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		unfortunately it's apparently the crime wave is not limited to cities you know it's spreading to you know our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> also and smaller
 	
 	
 		right um right my i'm from originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> over in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i'm originally from a little little rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh the crime in in you know in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is uh i i think it's just about as bad the burglaries and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and stuff seem to have moved out into that area
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 		that is
 		that's really scary it has it's done the same thing even in my little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and gosh it's only like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah but uh
 	
 	
 		there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy sheriff</ENAMEX> that tries to you know patrol the whole thing and he's you know he's just overwhelmed
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		right uh i guess uh it is really scary but the uh recognizing or i think recognizing that a lot of the crime in these smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> is really geared toward
 		the the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> anyway because i think that you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are involved in the drug scene out in the rural areas are really out there to provide for the little you know the center cities
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		sure it's probably a safer environment for them
 	
 	
 		but uh right but uh i guess the question is what do you do
 	
 	
 		boy i who knows i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh you know i think that uh from my own observation that that a lot of it probably stems around the school system i i don't want to blame the school system on everything because it's
 		it's not what they're doing it's not that they're doing so much wrong as that they can't not cannot do
 		a lot of the things that need to be done uh right well even even not just education but uh even discipline and and things like that
 	
 	
 		are you talking about educationwise yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are not allowed to do anymore that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> you know are just they have so much control over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> themselves that that everything seems to turn around that
 	
 	
 		that's right absolutely
 		um-hum yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know as you know you watch the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> news you know like i do and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you know that's not a day or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that goes by in this in this area at least as somebody at least somebody doesn't get killed or raped or robbed during this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		the jillion others we don't even hear about probably
 	
 	
 		i do uh i travel a little bit in my in my job with i've got some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> out there beat you know beat up on that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes that's been a hot topic yeah
 	
 	
 		traffic deal yeah it's a real yeah really was and of and of course everybody's reaction to that was you know anger and disgust and shock and all of that but then when you turn around and look at at what's going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from the criminal element that that probably that does not even compare you know to what goes on crimewise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's right
 		that's right you never hear about
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		and you know some some of the crimes are so crazy you know
 		just you know killing somebody for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollar</NUMEX> bill or some stupid thing like you know you just you just never know you know it's i sometimes get concerned about you know driving down the down the street you know if you look crosswise at somebody they're liable to blow your head off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really scary
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i i i really don't i don't know what the answer is but i think that if we don't find an answer
 	
 	
 		i don't know either
 	
 	
 		soon that it's we're really going to be in a lot worse trouble than we are now
 	
 	
 		yeah it's obviously not getting any better
 	
 	
 		i think uh perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has taken a couple of steps in the right direction recently uh i understand that they lightened up a little bit on some of the the restrictions on you know crime investigation and stuff so
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right um-hum and even down to the death penalty i think as far as you know appeal after appeal after appeal i think they've finally began to say you know enough's enough
 	
 	
 		and you know
 		right And say if you don't don't appeal
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		to start with then you don't have the right to appeal
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i think the
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> favor you know mandatory jail time with no no time you know no good time off you know i don't know i don't know if that's an answer or not i'm not too sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really scared of jail time anymore because they're in and out so quickly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure that's a real scary item for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it's
 		that's uh that's a fact you you can
 	
 	
 		you know it's
 	
 	
 		look forward to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a few days</TIMEX> in jail sometime for you know for what would seem to be a major crime in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with uh appeals and all that and getting time credit for spending time in jail and i think they even give credit sometimes for the the time they're out of jail between
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		between uh the time they're indicted and the time they're tried and stuff like that that still counts toward their sentence
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		right
 		you know this building <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> you know more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> the answer i'm not sure it is i don't know i honestly don't know i wish i did i'd be glad to share it with everybody if i knew
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah That uh i guess uh
 		the uh the number of of beds available in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> you know we've got to have it to increase because the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are increasing but we've we really need to work on the other side you know to to
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		before they get to jail
 	
 	
 		right but uh i don't know what
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree
 		i don't know maybe you know maybe maybe it needs to start at home you know with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> as much as they can do you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> can only do so much up to a point and they've lost it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think uh uh you know back to uh back to uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school</TIMEX> situation the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are the ones that that that demand all the rights for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 	
 	
 		they they want to put so much restrictions on and and and you know then they don't take on the responsibility themselves
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so it's it kind of perpetuates itself
 	
 	
 		i'll tell you the truth about both i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> both of are are you know young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> grown and gone away from home i'm honestly glad i'm not raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at this point and time
 	
 	
 		yeah well i've i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that are they're still at home but they they think they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> they're both out of you know out of high school one of them go to college
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i we really were nervous about our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> going to school and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are some of the best around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		and even at that it's you know it was a real touchy situation as to what you know as to
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's no guarantee
 	
 	
 		who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> were there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in every school system
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		that uh you don't want your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> associating with if you can help it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right if you can help it that's key you know
 	
 	
 		and uh you don't you know you don't have any control over it yourself
 	
 	
 		that's right yep up to a point you after that you've lost it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		sure have i'm just glad i'm not raising young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		so
 		um-hum yeah it's uh we said you know that we'd have been a lot better off our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would have been a lot a lot better off being raised in a smaller smaller area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> smaller school
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		or at least we thought perhaps at the time but you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i'm not so sure
 	
 	
 		not so sure anymore we did have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that moved uh out into well out in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Collin County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		thinking that that would have been a you know a better place for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and before their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got out of school the drug scene had moved in out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		and you know so they you know it's not not a whole lot different there than it is
 	
 	
 		no maybe just a smaller just a smaller scale maybe but then then you know the idea is still the same it's there
 	
 	
 		in you know in town
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		so
 	
 	
 		it really is
 	
 	
 		but well it's
 	
 	
 		i don't know uh like i say i'm just glad i'm not trying to have to raise small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm glad that they're not expecting us to come up with all the answers on these phone conversations right yeah yeah they you'd think that what
 	
 	
 		yeah me too  in the time allotted no i don't don't think so but i don't i don't know anyone that isn't concerned about it
 	
 	
 		well everybody's concerned but you know we give uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and we give the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> the you know all these powers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and everything and they they spend a lot of time on it and they can't come up with the answers so right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monies</ENAMEX> spent
 	
 	
 		so but uh it's
 	
 	
 		so i don't know wish i did
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe we maybe it's uh it's time for
 		there to be more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved i guess in in trying to find the answer but
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so
 	
 	
 		and since you know
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> i'm sure are just you know maxed out
 		there's only so much they can do
 	
 	
 		yeah well they can all they can do is enforce enforce the laws they can't uh pass the laws and they can't run the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> systems and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they do their do their job i don't i don't have a lot of complaints about the police myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no i don't either as a matter of fact i think they're doing you know probably for the most part the best job they can do with resources they have it's really must be discouraging though to know that you know you bust somebody for something they may be out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> before you finish your report you know
 	
 	
 		but they're doing
 		yeah yeah we
 		um-hum well
 	
 	
 		that's got to be discouraging especially if you've risked your life to do course you know if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> you expected to risk your life
 	
 	
 		that's uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> said she just couldn't do that couldn't be a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> because you're you know you never know
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		what uh you know you stop by somebody for traffic accident and you walk up and they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> pulled on you or you know something of that kind and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		as i understand it talking to a couple of my police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> what they fear most is a call to go try to settle a domestic quarrel you know apparently it's very dangerous you just never know
 	
 	
 		right yeah because
 		yeah you you've got a they get a a domestic uh violence or domestic domestic dispute and they get there and both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> turn on them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um that's right
 		apparently it's very very dangerous situation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't i don't think i could be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> i really don't
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		well
 		you think there's anything else to talk about on this subject  okay well it's been nice talking to you okay thanks bye
 	
 	
 		i guess that's  that's pretty well it
 		nice to talk to you uh-huh bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	