
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well um so um have do you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's looking for a college
 	
 	
 		uh been through it
 	
 	
 		ah i'm still in it
 	
 	
 		okay  no we've uh we've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children graduate</ENAMEX> so and i have worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it was a topic that uh seemed appropriate as far as discussion like this
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you had you're in the process of planning for or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are there
 	
 	
 		no i'm i'm i'm i'm still in college i'm still a student
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay all right
 	
 	
 		i'm graduating this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this May</TIMEX> well good where are you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh North Carolina State University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		very good uh uh the uh planning for college tuition and all the associated costs is a tough tough decision  at
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think it's it's when you're looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that you want to go i think you really should know exactly what you want to be so you can pick the best quality
 	
 	
 		how did you choose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i chose it basically that way uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> has a reputation for being uh good agricultural school
 	
 	
 		um-hum it's a land grant university right
 	
 	
 		in the area
 		exactly and um they have a good extension service for agriculture and uh i wanted to go into agriculture so i came here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and since since i was in you know in-state i pay resident i pay resident tuition so it was also a it was also good for me because you know being a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> plus in-state tuition saved me a lot of money
 	
 	
 		the
 		oh yes it certainly does and familiarity with the area there's sometimes advantages to moving way off and going to a unknown area but uh there's as many
 	
 	
 		right well for example yeah yeah i i think that's very true because for example uh i'm going to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> after i finish here and uh i'm going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to stay in the same area
 		yeah uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons for that i think if they even recommend in advanced degrees to
 		uh try a different set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> get a different perspective as far as the the advanced degrees they'd like for you to change rather than stay in the same institution
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean they would like for you to stay so that you know
 		they they could keep getting your money but one you know an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> likes to see different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum and i and i think a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> would uh tell you that it's best for you anyway to get a different uh
 		different set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> on it and a little different outlook and plus there are regional differences i think too <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> may have a different
 		type of emphasis now agriculture changes by region as far as it's emphasis is concerned middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would be wheat land here it's tobacco and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> it may be
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> and and uh other types of
 	
 	
 		right they have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> they have a lot of heavy metal problems also and a lot of salts because of the valleys very very salty
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's what i i was interested when i went over there i i uh talked to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the university
 		i think also you know um dialogue between university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> helps a lot in decisions because i think that's what really turned me
 		towards that you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school</TIMEX> that i'm going to is i went and talked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and they gave me information which i could not have gotten otherwise and that that really finalized my decision
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah what is your specialty
 	
 	
 		well i'm graduating with just a soil science degree here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> but i hopefully will go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to receive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> in uh
 		soil science with a specialization in environmental  environmental quality
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which will deal with uh eco-toxicology heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metals</ENAMEX> and soils and things like that so away from the production agriculture end of it and more into the soils and you know contaminants
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm kind of branching off into a pretty specific <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> which i think is going to be a hot topic in the future with you know all these lands and and things that are being spoiled
 	
 	
 		no question
 	
 	
 		and how to how to remediate them and all
 	
 	
 		no question you i'm sure you you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> have been following the uh
 		waste situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and the the absence or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> to handle
 	
 	
 		right especially in the sounds
 	
 	
 		right and it's it's a universal problem you know
 		if you look at uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you expect them to have problems <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> now with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cholera</ENAMEX> and and a bunch of other problems associated with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		waste management
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> you can expect more out of but we still have the same very deep problem of how to take care of our waste we create a bunch now now what do we do with it
 	
 	
 		yeah now that now that it's getting harder to get permits for landfills uh the the problem's pressing down harder than ever
 	
 	
 		yeah and then i think there's a a big mistrust public mistrust as there is with nuclear energy
 		uh they were talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX> again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this this week</TIMEX> because it's an anniversary but i think there's a big mistrust of uh
 		some of the waste management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in terms of how well they do take care of their product
 		and that's got to be solved i think there has to be public trust in it before you can
 	
 	
 		yes uh i agree with you
 	
 	
 		find a good sight
 		well i wish you luck in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh thanks a lot it was nice talking to you all right bye
 	
 	
 		okay
 		same here bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	