
 
     		
 	
 		uh so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> what type of music do you like
 	
 	
 		well i like uh classical and uh sort of uh popular rock type music um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i enjoy classical too i never really had listened to it till i i got married and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> um enjoys it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i had never listened to it before till then but now i listen to it well whenever she does
 		and every once in a while i'd put it on myself you know um  what
 	
 	
 		yep yep so i yeah i used to play the piano and i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh sort of the baroque music <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Handel</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivaldi</ENAMEX> and those kind of
 	
 	
 		oh yeah see those are those are really nice i like those though i i couldn't tell you anything about them other than what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> says this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yep yep
 		oh yeah yeah well i you know i don't i don't know all that much myself i just i just know when i hear it that i like it
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah that you what you like how about popular music
 	
 	
 		yeah uh whatever's on the radio is is usually okay with me but um
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		sometimes have a hard time understanding you know hearing the words clearly if i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and there's noise and stuff so it's mostly just the tune
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i'm pretty much the same way you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always say wow the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the meanings</TIMEX> of those words and i'm always meaning there's words well you know i just thought they just all sort of rhymed you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i know
 		yeah
 		i know i know about the only thing i can remember after the song is over is the refrain
 	
 	
 		right yeah that whenever they say it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm the same way  yeah it's funny um  depending on where you live i i i commute back and forth between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salisbury</ENAMEX> which is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half hours</TIMEX> away and the difference in the radio with popular music is totally different you know when yeah because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>'ll play more um what might be considered more little bit more progressive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and as soon as you go down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salisbury</ENAMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that's you know uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half hours</TIMEX> away in the suburbs or whatever uh in the real rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> they it turns into  basically classic rock
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they don't you know yeah mostly oldies but classic rock you know with if you know like when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Doors</ENAMEX> movie came out you know Doors was really on the radio there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oldies</ENAMEX> or what
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know where you know you'd hear what's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> of their more famous songs maybe top <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salisbury</ENAMEX> you would that's all you would hear was this is the Doors you know so was sort of a funny thing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 		yeah yeah there's a big variation among the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i mean if you go down south and country music and
 	
 	
 		you
 		you
 		yes that's i'm starting to realize that i never really thought about that much but there is
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i never
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i never i didn't i i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and i didn't i never really noticed the difference when i moved to this area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really didn't notice at all it just seemed the same but when i went more rural you know that it really changed so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> has a lot of good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> um yeah um fact they have a they have a continuous news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> which is nice if you're driving and you wanna hear
 	
 	
 		oh does it yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now you don't have to wait till the hour mark it's it's it's sort of constant you just turn there and um you get the latest news and everything it's uh it's sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> you know you turn on your TV it's on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that would really be beneficial because you never hear the you never hear the news basically on the radio i never get it
 	
 	
 		so yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and if you don't if you don't read the paper you sort of fall behind if you're in the car all the time
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yep
 		yep yep
 	
 	
 		yeah that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		so yeah i like to listen to tapes uh of music or or um stuff on a long trip and um now you can even get books on tape um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah in fact
 		my my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> does that a lot because she's blind or what she's losing her sight or whatever but yeah that of in i can imagine you know if you're driving cross country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know uh listening to a story  lot of the classics are really on tape yeah
 	
 	
 		right yep yep so that's a lot of fun but
 	
 	
 		yeah that that would be good
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		well we strayed a lot from music but i but i guess music comes into that whole aspect of listening so as long as you're listening so
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so well
 		right right right yep
 	
 	
 		but if you do if you do have to go something i guess we can just cut off
 	
 	
 		yep okay
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> it was nice to talk to you and and good luck and i hope you get some more calls and make some more calls  bye
 	
 	
 		yep nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
 		all right good thank you bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	