
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well have you ever been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of any particular any type of crime
 	
 	
 		uh that's interesting  because i've talked about this subject before and it it didn't come up to either one of us to act uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no no nothing that i would consider major probably the most that anything of mine has ever been violated is uh
 		you know like you know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> throw their change like into uh the glove box or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ash tray</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we had you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and anybody whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was open they kind of trashed that stuff out but they didn't do any vandalism and yeah it bugged me but you know when i think of crime and and things that could happen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i guess that was minor
 	
 	
 		sounds like you've been very fortunate i haven't had too many terrible things happen to me but my tee tops did get stolen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time off my car
 	
 	
 		i have
 		ah that's a very popular pass time up here do you have a Vette
 	
 	
 		out of
 		right
 		uh no it's a TransAm
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TransAm</ENAMEX> uh in fact there was a ring i know that you stop right up here and uh the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> would call <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> security when they knew they were in town basically and say
 		you know tell all your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vets</ENAMEX> and whatever else to be look on the lookout for them but that's expensive you know
 	
 	
 		it's very expensive and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> don't like it either
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't want to write you
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i did put an alarm on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> after that
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and uh i kept that for a while until the alarm malfunctioned and started going off in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> for no reason and
 	
 	
 		oh that's not good
 	
 	
 		it upset the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment complex</ENAMEX> so i disabled it
 	
 	
 		well okay
 		now i uh i mean i've had other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> touched um i have had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> of mine that was murdered
 		uh things like that uh for no apparent reason you know it's that was lost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> trying to find her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		stopped to use the phone and a teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had lots of money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh killed her so nothing was ever done to him
 		but so you know yeah i i'm not sure there's many lives that aren't affected by it somewhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know what the answers should be per se
 	
 	
 		yeah you stop and think about what you can do to uh to prevent or reduce crime
 		and in fact tonight uh alone i i got a phone call from one of the security uh
 		uh systems home security systems that uh install uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		monitor and uh
 		i guess detect uh it's that that type of break ins
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they uh
 		have a certain fee that they charge each month and an installation fee and they're real hot hot about uh trying to get uh trying to sell these systems to everybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i um i would like a home alarms that perimeter alarm system i've been very impressed with the one that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway Corporation</ENAMEX> uh
 		puts together because it's it's as extensive as you want it to be you can
 		you can kind of coordinate to your own home you know however many uh types of devices you need and it's a wireless system so it's not one they can disable
 	
 	
 		do you know what the
 		do you know the name brand is for that

 	
 	
 		the name Amguard
 	
 	
 		okay that's the their own personal alarm brand okay
 	
 	
 		yeah they make it uh-huh and
 	
 	
 		there are several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> like that there's one that uh
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> sale sold once upon a time called Schlage
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's also modular and wireless and you can add as many sensors as you need to
 	
 	
 		yeah about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he's like one of these like i want to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> kind of scare me
 		uh not so much for me you know i feel like i'm responsible i'd learn how to use it and yes i could shoot someone if you know they were trying to take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or take my life or
 		you know i'm basically a nonviolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but i could do that
 		but it scares me because of so many accidents that have occurred with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well there's some some
 	
 	
 		uh you know accidentally shoot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> or shoot a sister or shoot themselves and i'm not real sold on that yet
 	
 	
 		right but there's also a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are end up being victimized by their own weapons
 	
 	
 		by their own
 	
 	
 		a burglar comes in and uh finds a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and ends up using it against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well are you for uh capital punishment
 	
 	
 		oh certainly yeah depending on the crime i think i discussed that at at another time
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting that you say that because i am too my my sadness with it occurs that it doesn't seem to be consistent
 		you know i i have a hard time putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s death for the same crime that you send the other to jail for
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it does to me need to be consistent but
 		uh i i
 	
 	
 		well it's such a waste of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money too to put them in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life
 	
 	
 		for life
 	
 	
 		uh especially if there's no chance of parole
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		of course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s of the mind that you ought to take them all out in the back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> and shoot them
 		
 
 	
 	
 		sometimes that's the best solution i guess
 	
 	
 		i don't know i guess i have a little bit more compassion i do think they ought to have their day in court
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		only because there have been ones sent away that didn't do it but i know that's few and far between
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i uh i don't know the answer you know i have always thought that maybe the answer to the dope problem that you know generates so much of the crime is
 		you know always you know shoot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and somebody made the you know take away the supply but somebody made a comment to me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months ago</TIMEX> that's kind of had me thinking he said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he said somebody else will come up with the supply he said what you have to do is you know shoot or make it hard on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> because if the demand is gone they won't have anybody to supply to
 		well that makes a little bit of sense
 	
 	
 		well it makes some sense but uh
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> end up being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> and they uh they commit crimes for for a living to make the the cash to buy their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> with so
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they have no respect or for for any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		but where was it uh oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> and i want to say like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>
 		something with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M Madagascar</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX>  a small country
 		uh you know it's it's a crime punishable by by death to them to be carrying anything and i think some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> ci tizens had gone in like uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and they had some marijuana on them and they hung them
 	
 	
 		oh that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and they they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>
 		okay i knew it was something like that and i thought jeez that seemed so severe for marijuana but then i thought or is that just because um
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i have become accustom ed to other things in hearing other things you know if i knew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> got hung for carrying a little bit of marijuana it might make me think twice before i ever did it if i was of the mind to you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i don't know what the answers are but i
 		i do feel like
 		i do feel like when they're blatant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and they've got records that it seems like the system protects them more than it helps the others
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well we're not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that has a a drug problem
 	
 	
 		no we're not
 	
 	
 		a lot of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> do especially smaller <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> uh strictly enforce uh
 	
 	
 		death
 	
 	
 		policies against uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use and uh uh dealing and things like that so yeah the death penalty uh exists and it is put in force
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i don't know i know that you know i remember growing up and uh
 		you know we'd leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> open if we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> yeah if we went somewhere i grew up in a large i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if we went somewhere sure we'd lock the doors if it was just down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> we wouldn't or if we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we wouldn't
 		but now you know i come home i lock the door if we open the door i lock the screen door you know i want it locked when i'm in it every time i go somewhere and i i just almost hate that feeling
 	
 	
 		right
 		well you make a habit out of it and it's a tolerable situation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i also grew up in in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> and my a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> are on dairy farms
 		they would leave the house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unattended</ENAMEX> unlocked  just figuring that if anybody really wanted to break in
 		they would anyway and there wasn't much of value to take any way so
 	
 	
 		well that's one way to look at it isn't it where'd you grow up
 	
 	
 		uh up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		um excuse me
 	
 	
 		but i've been fortunate i guess in that the only things that have happened to me are the tee tops and hubcaps off <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> well
 	
 	
 		yeah that's pretty minor when i think that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give their lives  so
 	
 	
 		sure uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so i don't know the answers though i i i do wish we had a system that was a bit more fair
 	
 	
 		yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> is pretty good about it too they've got excellent uh police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> here
 		uh i haven't seen any any evidence of uh any uh
 		mischievous deeds going on in my neighborhood
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 	
 	
 		the suburbs it's not near as bad in the suburbs as it is in the city <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is pretty bad
 	
 	
 		right i'm sure that's true i'm sure that's true
 		i do know that our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> across the street our development is probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only eight years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe not that long we've lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX>
 		and uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> across the street you know she walked in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> on somebody and of course he left she was fortunate
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but things like that make it real to me and aware that it really is going on
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know that's it not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale world here
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have been victimized too a lot more seriously
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's not pleasant to think about that and uh you have to live with that forever so
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		well
 	
 	
 		yeah i enjoyed talking to you about the subject uh
 	
 	
 		and i appreciate you calling it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		thank you very much huh you too bye bye
 	
 	
 		okay have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> sure bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	