
 
     		
 	
 		dining out seems to be a uh uh something we do off and on
 		through our lives i guess as economics and as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come and go and uh situations change uh we used to do
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		quite a bit of dining out before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and then as they came along and uh additional expenses sitting came into every dinner out um
 		that that halted a lot of it as well as just the the uh oh i guess the lifestyle changes a little bit slows down a little bit and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		now even the atmosphere that that we would seek uh when we go out is often more quiet and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a little bit more uh subdued uh not smoke filled or or bar uh dance floor type yeah so
 	
 	
 		yeah funny how that happens after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		that uh those type of qualities have uh moved into the picture and then there's there's some economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> but usually it's if if it's going to be a night out it's going to be a a decent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal and</TIMEX>
 		and uh fortunately for us there's not a whole lot of places in the immediate area that's totally really expensive you have to go a ways to get to a really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		high dollar uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollar dinner type deal which they're forty to fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> away and they're they're all around but they're just a ways so we can do a good um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty twenty five</NUMEX> dollar night out and have a decent steak and it comes out okay
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh we look for i guess uh service uh you know i'm not i'm not in
 		eating at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> long enough the fastest the speed of it doesn't bother me you know i'm not looking for fast food at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> so the fact that it took them <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty thirty minutes</TIMEX> to get it there that's that's okay i'm
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or however long you know you're out for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> or it doesn't really matter that they not get it there right away but um
 	
 	
 		right that's right
 		right
 	
 	
 		have a little chime little hard time finding a place that'll cook the steak just right i have to remember how to ask for it for this given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> to get it just the way i like it without too much pink in there and uh get it cooked good
 	
 	
 		i imagine uh in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there would be uh a lot of steak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah there seem to be quite a few quite a few
 	
 	
 		yes
 		um-hum and now on this area of course here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> you're close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chesapeake</ENAMEX> there seems to there is some there are some steak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> but they lean more towards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		um-hum steak and lobster type
 	
 	
 		uh you probably have seafood a lot also
 	
 	
 		yeah they do oddly enough even being near near the gulf uh they tend to advertise the the main
 		the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> coast uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> for some reason it tends to be a draw i don't know particularly why i mean to me it tastes pretty much the same once you do to it whatever you're going to do to it you know like
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 		right well do you have crabs and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster</ENAMEX> in that area that's
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah crab and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster</ENAMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's
 		hum that's funny that they would
 	
 	
 		yeah they withdraw from that i guess you know you can ship stuff anywhere pretty much and uh
 	
 	
 		right right right and you probably have crawfish would you have crawfish
 	
 	
 		uh probably i'm not a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of that so i wouldn't wouldn't be paying much attention to it um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well a lot of what you said uh sounds similar to us i remember that uh before before we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we have
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that are like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and actually the oldest one is just starting to
 		learn to behave in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> so before we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we would
 		definitely dine out more frequently probably several times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and it didn't have to be
 		necessarily anything fancy but it was more uh a matter of before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> say we were both working we didn't feel like cooking we just went out
 		and now you know as you said once you've <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that's not always an option uh i worked off and on um you know because they were little and
 		and and also you know once you're home and you have them um
 		places that you went before spur of the moment that might be nice but casual um
 		sometimes it's not worth it to go through the trouble of digging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX> and everything just to go and so what i have found now that um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		when we do go out uh as you said you out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> now when we go out it's it's you want it to be more special
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't want to just uh necessarily run out for you know a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> and come back i noticed with us it's more when we do go out then we do try to make it something nice maybe a dinner theater or nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 		um sometimes lunches when we can do that that's okay too but
 		um it definitely you know it definitely changes is changed we maybe eat in somewhat nicer places now but that's because when we do go
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		there's so there's like a special quality to that because it is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um but not as often we don't do it as often
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and what i'm finding now is they're finally getting to the age where we're venturing into going again with them
 		and of course when you take them though you're going to go to something like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> level or maybe a little bit of a family style restaurant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but in this area there there are quite a few decent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that are not too expensive and uh
 		i i i tend to agree with you too we look for more um
 		uh quiet type more of a subdued atmosphere now and i think part of that is after you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you're you're not as interested in going to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> type places where you know you go in every place and there's a lot of uh noise
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">yelling</ENAMEX> and uh you know you look for different things and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> seems to change and you know you're not as much part of it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and you don't there are more decent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> moving out to the suburbs you know and that type of thing uh you don't necessarily have to go downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> to to find decent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and uh
 		there's a lot that are moderately priced also whether you're in the suburbs or go downtown so there's there's quite a selection in this area
 	
 	
 		there's a uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place that
 		really not sure if the marketing concept is is carried throughout it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> but in this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> um i live <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two suburbs</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> actually and in this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> we're <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two miles</NUMEX> from this uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this steak <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that has a
 		oh i don't know a motif to the entire uh shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> it's the anchor for this entire strip shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> i guess and they'll the entire place is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> has covered walkways all around to all the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> that are they're not
 		they're not even individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in some cases some cases are just kind of you they they put it all out in a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> shed out on to an area and then they put it all away at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> um then there are there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one two</NUMEX> whole rows actually of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of just what we would call a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stall</ENAMEX> of flat concrete place with little posts and they're all marked off with little lines and so if you want to rent this little spot though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> bring their stuff down and have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> market type
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		so we went to this steak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> once uh well several times but the most particular time that we were away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and had a a good length of time and it was on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and we knew the place would be really busy but we
 		we got there about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or six thirty</TIMEX> and put our names on the list of of the waiting list and then we walked around the uh the place that has
 		there were still some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> there at the time there was a lot of hand uh craft type stuff being sold uh there was a blacksmith and he's showing off his little traits and things that he could sell as well as uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's nice
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that were of of business the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX> were decorated with uh old pictures and history of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> as it were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we killed about a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or so doing that because it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour and a half</TIMEX> wait to get into the restaurant and uh then about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> worth of a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal or so thirty or forty five minutes</TIMEX> there and then
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> came back out and walked around a little bit more and went home so it it's quite an interesting uh deal they don't even take reservations because they're so booked like that that uh
 	
 	
 		wow jeez well if i'm here also there's been such a growth in in housing uh not in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> but before that it was just
 		i don't know if you've been in this area in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> but it's just been incredible and and has it's gone crazy i mean where we are was basically a farm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> and it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> are stacked and what has happened really is that
 		um some of the commercial um
 		uh places have not caught up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> here and so we do have a problem of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the half</TIMEX> decent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> when you go on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> you're looking for quite a long wait
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and um not all of them do take reservations either so so you sometimes have to allot yourself uh enough time
 		um you know to go out uh you can't figure on going out and being back in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> you know
 		um the other thing that's changing here is because of the um the age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">set</ENAMEX> here uh a lot mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in they're i'd say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late twenties</TIMEX> to early forties in these neighborhoods that
 		uh we haven't done it because i don't think it will work well with us having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> but um some of the more expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> now i understand are catering
 		um to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> price menus for them whereas before um they would be totally discouraged from bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in
 		and they're doing this basically because they're so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working parents</ENAMEX> in this area and that they were losing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> because once all these younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they weren't going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	