
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah matter of fact it's sort of interesting because they do have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testings</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i work at
 	
 	
 		they do all right
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know i was uh
 		for the most part the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that it's effected have not exactly been the most valuable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> so i personally think that you know it doesn't hurt the business center the work atmosphere
 	
 	
 		um-hum are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> subject subject uh subject to it or just a certain
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah it's basically new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are too but they for some reason they don't uh uh do anything about it you know they don't uh exercise it
 	
 	
 		yeah what about random testing
 	
 	
 		they supposedly have it but i've never heard of anybody getting randomly tested
 	
 	
 		what what type of industry is it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um electrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> yeah hold on just a second
 	
 	
 		electrical okay  sure
 	
 	
 		my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month old</TIMEX> just got hold of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three and a half inch</NUMEX> diskettes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think uh that won't last very long write protection just doesn't uh doesn't have any eat protection on it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		so
 		uh i've i've never been involved in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that had the drug testing but have been involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have discussed it one of them very very hazardous type of uh operation
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		drilling oil and gas wells
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and there's enough problem with injuries in that area anyway
 		uh without contributing to it through <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or alcohol
 		and you know it it was encouraged it's just a matter of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> today i don't believe know how to implement a drug program
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh how to really really have a good one whether it's preemployment or ongoing either one
 	
 	
 		yeah they they i think the way they figured out with us is basically just they can globally say if anybody comes for you know an application white black educated uneducated everyone has to take it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that way you know they're open um and i guess you know our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has a fairly good turnover so i guess they figure that they'll get the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that way
 	
 	
 		eventually have everyone yeah it at least run a spot check
 		and i think maybe the knowledge that they could have random testing uh may have an effect too
 	
 	
 		now i do know of um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that were fired because they they couldn't pass
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know exactly why they were picked out to do the drug testing because i know i wasn't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but um
 	
 	
 		i personally don't it's easy to see in some industries you know you don't want uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> to be under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and it's easy to see that type but
 	
 	
 		that's right interesting
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it can effect uh almost every every office
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah ours is for security reasons we're government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> and they don't want secrets like leaking out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		are if you're government contractor you probably fall under some
 		type of government supervision on it uh
 	
 	
 		right yeah there are requirements matter of fact i think  levied upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to have some sort of drug testing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		did uh was there much objection to it prior to implementation or
 	
 	
 		oh yeah there was a a big thing saying that it was you know invading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s rights and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		which is which
 	
 	
 		you know and but then again it's against the law so it's like how can they you know
 		how can they be invading your rights uh verifying that you've just been invading the law you know
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are confused uh i think too by what is a test you we all know about the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> and the testing there and how some of them can be wrong and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i i think they're afraid of
 		appropriate prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> showing up some of them are some of the innocent ones are and they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well they you know they said that um i don't know if it's ever been proven for sure but they were saying that some prescription drugs could show up as being <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		i think they can and uh i think a lot of it uh that's that's why the type of type of test is important
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		as long as they give you another shot
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we we tend not to know uh we tend to think theoretically
 		but lots of times getting down to the actual method and and results
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being evaluated properly is where we have a short fall
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		where are you located <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> okay uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		where are you calling from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but i've been in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about twenty years</TIMEX> so
 		just got kind of got back to this part of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		okay well up i'm um up near the capitol
 		up near D C
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah pretty pretty time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> up there now isn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cherry Blossom Festival</ENAMEX> apparently went all right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i missed it this year
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		but uh you know we've we've seen it a couple of times and it's really nice but didn't get to see it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> there are so many things you take for granted when you're in here you know year round <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes do you get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then we've been down there haven't uh taken the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> down yet though we uh took them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter Egg</ENAMEX> roll
 	
 	
 		but
 		oh good good but i think
 	
 	
 		and uh down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> for fireworks and things
 	
 	
 		that's one of the areas uh i've found  several areas in the government
 		that i really enjoy seeing money spent and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is one of them i think it's great to go through there and see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of all all sizes and ages going through those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		and my oldest is uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> so she's just getting to the age where you know she'd recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> and ever ything like that but
 	
 	
 		um-hum and it'll be a great memory for her later too i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well the uh
 		time limit i think is is about up but i enjoyed talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i did too  thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right thank you bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	