
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um i was just trying to think about how i how i dress for work you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is a very casual atmosphere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what i usually do on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> is is lay out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> outfits
 		and uh on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> i i wear the the worst looking one  because it doesn't seem like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really are you know are that alive on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> you know so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then progressively through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> i'll i'll wear nicer looking things and then on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> most everybody wears jeans jeans and sweatshirts
 		or you know jeans and blouses or something like that
 		uh but mostly what i wear are skirts and blouses or you know skirts and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> pullover sweaters or
 		uh
 		you know little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> piece dress suits suits like but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh you know that's a good way to approach it i've never thought about um i do plan my clothes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> in advance actually i plan them a month in advance i usually do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> at a time so i don't repeat an outfit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um i've never thought about wearing your worst outfit on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> because really no one's paying attention but anyway
 		um i really i don't work outside of school um i work in the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i can just wear whatever i have on for school and
 		and um
 		and really it's
 		i try to dress dress presentable but very comfortable
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		like um in the warm weather it's always shorts and a T-shirt or a button up or something like that and then in the winter time it's jeans or or pants i usually um you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is so casual you really don't want to dress up unless you
 		you uh have a job and you have to be there right after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		right like where i work it's it's pretty casual um
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		it's it's i guess it's more like a a college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> also i mean there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just just wear jeans and and uh sweats all the time
 		and they dress up like when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are coming in or uh when we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> meetings or something like that and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like those that work in the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> for their the real um higher ups like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those that work for the the higher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>
 		they uh they really dress up all the time so there's a good combination in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX> all the time you know
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well that's good that they're so casual i mean uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> works for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and he's a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> or computer engineer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um you know whenever he was going to school he was expecting to having to wear uh a tie or a dress shirt everyday but uh he goes to work in his blue jeans T-shirt and tennis shoes and he just loves it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and that's very acceptable at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i believe at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> they they make you wear a blue suit and uh some kind of colored shirt and a tie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's what i've heard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i would i would hate to be in that atmosphere
 	
 	
 		but uh i mean they they just moved into the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> he calls it the new building i don't know it's where all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		and so they were they were going to try to take their blue jean code with them and trying to get all the all the upper level to start wearing blue jeans but he just left for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and he'll be over there until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> first setting up some kind of computers for them
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		over in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> mean for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> but over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is everywhere
 	
 	
 		oh yeah he was so excited about going
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh he didn't carry any ties or anything because he he just went over there with the that attitude well if i don't take it then they won't make me wear it  because uh he just
 	
 	
 		that's true that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		he didn't you know he's not really into all that he would wear it if he had to for his job and all but you know if he had the preference i mean his his preference is um blue jeans and a T-shirt so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think that's great about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and also uh to get off the clothing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> you know how they have the the different designated areas for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> and stuff i think that's great
 	
 	
 		the no
 		right
 		yeah and if you happen to go into one of areas that is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke smoke</ENAMEX> area and you don't smoke you almost strangle
 	
 	
 		oh really do you smoke
 	
 	
 		because there is so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> in the air
 		yeah areas the smoking area you know it's closed in and if you don't if you don't smoke and you go in there that everybody that goes in there smokes so it's full of smoke when when you go in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think that's um
 	
 	
 		i used to smoke a long time ago i used to burn my clothes talking about getting back to clothes  i used to burn my clothes with cigarettes that's one of the reason that i stopped
 	
 	
 		well um you you mentioned your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> had graduated from college well when she was in high school did she always have to have all the new fashions and
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah she always had uh yeah she always had to have a lot of clothes
 	
 	
 		see that's how that's how i am but my mama was not raised like that and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no i i wasn't either she my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> um
 		she's real good at finding sales though you know she she she'll buy a lot of she yeah she'll buy a lot clothes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of seasons</TIMEX> you know and uh just have them for the next year
 	
 	
 		oh me to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i have to hunt hunt them down
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she you know she finds all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> and all the discount places
 		and uh buys clothes
 		um when you know when they were coming up i i didn't sew but now i've i've learned how to sew so i'm well i'm i'm still learning how but i'm getting and i'm getting much better at it and i
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		i'm going to be able to make my own clothes
 	
 	
 		i wanted to take a sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but i just haven't fit it into my schedule yet but that i mean that can really benefit
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um that's something that i'd be very interested in very interested in learning
 	
 	
 		right because clothes are some are really expensive you know uh uh a little simple shell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell blouse</ENAMEX> you know that you can make for about
 	
 	
 		uh they're outrageous
 	
 	
 		say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars at you know at at the most out of a decent fabric
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boy</ENAMEX> runs you like twenty something dollars in the store
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's marked up
 	
 	
 		just a little shell to go under a suit you know
 	
 	
 		it is it is really outrageous but uh i mean like whenever i i was growing up and all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> i never understood this then but i do now but she never would buy me like the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> jeans that had come out that were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> dollars or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um or she wouldn't buy me the fifty dollar tennis shoes and stuff like that and she always told me it was because i was still growing and she wasn't going to buy me something i was going to grow out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right especially to to pay that kind of money for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who um she had a she had a baby a little boy
 		and uh she she used to dress him out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neiman Marcus</ENAMEX> i mean she dressed him
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		oh fabulously
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then seems like every time she turned around he was outgrowing stuff and she finally learned that you just can not do this you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so now she
 		finds the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> sales and just like you know everybody else
 	
 	
 		that's the best way to shop i mean i always thought my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was being mean to me but i look back at it now and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is going to i mean i'm going to raise mine the same way
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know i just
 		ah they're just so outrageously priced it's just incredible i try to uh always catch the sales
 	
 	
 		yes and yourself
 		right
 	
 	
 		always
 	
 	
 		and yeah and you just have to keep buying them
 		you know if you if you if you're not buying the most expensive clothes out there the the quality is really not that great you know for the price that you pay
 	
 	
 		yeah it it depends on um
 		yeah there's there's always a reason why they're on sale
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so that that has a lot to do with it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		like i bought i bought the most
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		beautiful sweater uh sweater
 		from uh i believe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross Dress For Less</ENAMEX>
 		and it was it was really pretty it was just you know it was just plain a plain uh round you know round uh necked
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh sweater sweater
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it had
 		uh like it was embellished around the the top you know it had uh leather leather designs and
 		um
 		some other other little things on it and i just thought it was so pretty and i got i got it at a real good price i think maybe it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine ninety nine</NUMEX> or something and it was so pretty
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		and after i wore it a couple of times i realized why it was
 	
 	
 		huh oh
 	
 	
 		why it was it was so cheap
 		there was in the middle of the back of it there was
 		it's like there it had been slit and they had like just sewed it back together
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right in the middle of the</TIMEX> the back you know wasn't a seam or anything you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's why it was so cheap although it's not it's not really noticeable
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um from the outside but but still it's you know it's really not not not a good quality
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then i was told by somebody that works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX>'s that um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Ross</ENAMEX> is just one of those places that sells sells <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		the defect
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um
 		they don't really buy the first quality they buy the second
 		and uh places like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX>'s that they'll reject the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> they'll send them back every time but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		places like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross Dress For Less</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh TJ Max um uh</ENAMEX>-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TJ Max</ENAMEX> does that yeah we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TJ Max</ENAMEX> over here and um
 		
 		
 	