
 
     		
 	
 		well thanks for being home uh on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> i uh i'm actually working at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and uh
 		there very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are on the list for calls uh on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah well sometimes i'm home and sometimes i'm not but if i am it's always fun to talk
 	
 	
 		are are you part of the school system out there
 	
 	
 		i am as a matter of fact i'm at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the reason i said that because i've had about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> calls and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> had one too from different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> i guess they pass the names amongst your computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i was the one who did that actually
 	
 	
 		oh is that right great great
 	
 	
 		yeah i had a uh i teach a course in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice I O Systems</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is that right that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		so i know uh you know i know about this project so i got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to sign up and uh apparently a number of them have been participating
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i talked to one we're not on the subject of course i talked to one i think he had a whole bunch of calls he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> that had calls and everything he had way more twice as many calls as as i've made uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i'm of course we at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> just hoping it works out that the new products that they come out will uh sell like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> books busters busters really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay you first on the subject what what do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh let's see the subject is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know whether i have any real profound thoughts about that i actually was was planning a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and i got warned off by
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> can't be traveled to and the crime rate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> makes it not a pleasant place to go and so on and so forth
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> had a place i'm not to sure i don't think they do anymore down i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campinas</ENAMEX> i'm not sure and uh i guess we were selling parts to the automotive industry or whatever and they had quite a few
 		locations not quite a few several uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> is closed and i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> is closed but i
 		i don't know why that is a problem down there and i guess the crime rate is terrible up here too and uh
 		and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but i don't i don't have an answer to the crime rate it's sad that is a sad situation i i'd like to go down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> you know and i keep hearing that you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and and the crime rates pretty high too that that is sad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh not that we can uh sell any great program we have with crime but uh i think uh i'm kind of like you i don't have any strong opinions on it i guess maybe that's our biggest problem we have with our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> down there is that we don't have any we have more
 		i guess ties we in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> have more ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and everything and we don't really aren't that close to everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> i don't really know why though
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't understand it either although i i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Americans</ENAMEX>
 		regard the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as as bullying and uh that's certainly from a historical point of view
 		would be true i mean certainly we took far more from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> ever dreamed of taking in in his wildest dreams from his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right yeah i know that i saw in a book i was reading a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> book uh not that i read <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> you know i just you know reading some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> words and there was a comment in there about
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> don't really want us to say we're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> they would like to say that we're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX> because they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> too you know and i guess that's true we don't think of
 		any one else but ourselves i guess we're kind of uh the smart asses in the world i suppose uh or of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> anyway we think of ourselves as the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> when they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think they're going to have that's a tough row for them to to hoe because i think most of the world is going to regard
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> and they can stand on their heads if they want too but i don't think that they're going they're going to change that and
 	
 	
 		as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> yes that that
 		
 
 		no no i know
 	
 	
 		and and really i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX> i think are when you say that even i think i mean i tend to think of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> i just don't think of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> as being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX> although i guess strictly speaking they are
 	
 	
 		yeah no i mean they were saying that of us that we're the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX> and they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> they they we always say we're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and they they want us to say we're the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX> we're not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> we're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX> and they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Americans</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		whatever i i don't want to make i read it somewhere though it's not my point i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's it's so interesting i just i just don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s problems are going to be cured by semantics
 	
 	
 		no no they they were lucky enough to have some oil what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> an and they they blew all that and borrowed enough more money than they can pay back now and uh
 		uh so they're not exactly business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> i do think we should deal more with them i don't i do have a lot of sympathy in that we're here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh for the language you know is very foolish
 		i'm relative relatively familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> school system and we should teach <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> at least in uh grammar school you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> grades of it so that we can speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> i think that helps
 		when you certainly can speak their language uh and there are problems with you know the wet back problem you know for everyone knows what we're talking about when say wet back problem and then we should somehow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are working on that to try to have some uh businesses uh at the borders of both sides so that you can you don't have this problem of them trying to come up here and to to get the jobs you know there there may be some organized way to do this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i do feel for them uh they are very envious of us or they wouldn't be coming up here you know risking a lot not that they're risking their lives of course but risking a lot uh getting thrown back i guess is all that uh happens
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you probably don't see that where we see it you know once a month i'm sure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> they see it more often than that
 	
 	
 		well i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well you see it saw it out there then too
 	
 	
 		and uh in fact i drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> when i was a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> so i i knew uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> pretty well
 		and certainly you know knew that problem knew you know knew about apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in them sleeping in the same bed in shifts and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was
 		it was pretty wild
 	
 	
 		i think a a common factor to a lot of problems both whether it be crime if if you want to jump on that is mostly uh poverty uh and i think a lot of their problems is poverty if we could
 		uh uh the problems we have you know in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is is a lot of it's poverty whether it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't trying hard enough to get out of poverty i that's another story but uh uh it is sad there there's so much down in all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>
 		uh so much potential you know we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> of course is is really pushing world markets in their products and they're they're mostly in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and in in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orient Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> now just announced
 		building a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> uh they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and they're they haven't had what that much luck in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and there's got to be a lot of potential for business down there for the products certainly that we make and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there's got to be trade i guess that's some of the answer i guess is business uh uh and i try to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX> and say well that that's one way is to help any problem whether it be crime or certainly poverty obviously is to is to get some business going between each other
 		and we need we need to do more of that uh somehow and encourage more business between us
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they've got to have a lot of resources i would think an enormous amount of of well potential that way a lot of it of course is hot and jungle and all that but uh there's got to be a lot of potential down there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what are what are you taking in school i didn't ask you that
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 		well i am actually
 	
 	
 		what are you taking in school
 		oh you you're an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> yeah you're an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> yeah you said
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm the
 		i'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i give
 		as it were
 	
 	
 		that's great are you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teaching Computer Science</ENAMEX> what you said what were you saying you were teaching there
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Science</ENAMEX>
 		and uh very interested in voice systems and in speech recognition but of course this project is really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to collect a data base of
 	
 	
 		great great
 	
 	
 		of uh of casual speech uh in an attempt to get some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">kin</ENAMEX> d of a model of what speech is like
 	
 	
 		right
 		i of course i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i'm a little puzzled as to why when they get my voice one time why that isn't enough i mean i'm i'm i'm getting a kick out of the whole program but uh
 		there's going to be i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> i don't know how many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of these recordings and i wonder how they're going to analyze them whether it would be
 		listening to them or analyzing i guess they've got to be analyzing with a a voice recorder some how
 	
 	
 		yeah well they record these and then somebody transcribes them so that they they have uh they have a speech signal and what and what is said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have a they're able to average it over a number of different occasions because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> voices change a lot even from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning to evening</TIMEX> and that's uh a big problem in speech recognition
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh yes i know they change with age i know mine changes uh has changed uh although you you never found your your voice echoes in your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> which is makes it different than what it really sounds to other people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know that and you always hear your own voice in recordings and say my God that's that's not obviously that's not me you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i know your voice in your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> resonates a different way
 		uh go ahead you you comment on it yeah i'm glad that you're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s gotten it with their Speak and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spell</ENAMEX> and everything i've told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that one of the reasons they're doing it is because eventually you'll be able to talk to your computer you wouldn't have to have a keyboard
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you'll be able to just give it commands and i'm sure they have some of that now and not not in computers but a lot of potential of course for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX> people
 		
 		
 	