
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay  he did where'd he decide to go
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh sure i'm familiar with it
 	
 	
 		and that he was he was uh trying to decide between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and it was a very difficult choice and uh
 	
 	
 		and he well he must know is he interested in law or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> he must have a definite profession in mind
 	
 	
 		no but that's one of the reasons why he chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> that it has solid liberal arts
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		medium size aren't they
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		is he excited
 	
 	
 		very excited yes uh i have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who's at their chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amherst College</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow i can i
 		uh-huh while they're east coast i mean i don't know anything about their football but there you go
 	
 	
 		well they're they're they're really very strong academic rather than you know big sports
 	
 	
 		yeah that's where where you at
 	
 	
 		we're outside of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> how about you
 	
 	
 		oh okay i'm in uh suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		no i don't i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>  we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> yet
 		about all i can say is i guess about picking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> um i guess uh if you don't know what you're going to do liberal arts program is a good idea
 	
 	
 		okay um
 		well i i one of the the advises we've given our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is that you can always learn a job
 	
 	
 		this is true
 	
 	
 		uh but what you can't learn uh on a job is
 		a good solid well rounded well rounded education
 	
 	
 		right the humanities the history yeah
 	
 	
 		that's right you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and uh and if you get that you can and if you do well you can you can learn a job
 	
 	
 		right right no no no
 		yeah but they you know if they learn the job and they can go into graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> usually a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it will if it's worth it's weight will subsidize and
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right
 		that's right so the advice we gave to them was number one visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> that you're thinking about describe <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		this this is true
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the size school that you might be interested in
 	
 	
 		and if you want to go away right
 	
 	
 		do you want to go away how far from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> do you want to be
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what do you want in a college now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a national level competitive swimmer
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		so he wanted to swim in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but he did not want to be in a swim factory
 	
 	
 		okay so he wouldn't have gone to something like where we're at they'd in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> or something like that so he didn't even consider those
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Aquatics</ENAMEX> yeah okay well that's i think the other thing is too um i know i went to a uh city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> weren't as fortunate as say my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i were and economics was the choice um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sounds like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has academically the standing to get into that type of school
 	
 	
 		he is very very strong academically yeah so we've just but you know he had to look to see what kind of environment he liked and yet he he did wind up having to make a choice he did apply to a large you know large group
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Penn</ENAMEX> i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Pennsylvania University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's got <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about nine thousand</NUMEX> undergraduate
 	
 	
 		yeah that's strong i mean that's you know and it's it's well it's a little bit i don't want to use the word wilder that's not the word i want um more diverse
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 		uh yes and it but it does have the under you know that's total undergraduate with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> school so that the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> of arts and sciences is you know i guess <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> how large is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> is an undergraduate school only um and it's a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that's not bad
 	
 	
 		yeah so he knew the feeling because my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amherst</ENAMEX> which is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen hundred</NUMEX> and he had visited his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amherst</ENAMEX> and knew that he liked the environment but he did go on college visits and he liked
 	
 	
 		which is a lot
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's the thing to do i mean i not having any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and uh that has something like either the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> like fifty thousand combined community
 	
 	
 		yes yes it's large and they both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> had decided no that they did not want that
 	
 	
 		yeah that is too much and i mean i um i can only say it's strange your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> picked those kinds of college because i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bennington</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> um and that was this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> showing my age
 	
 	
 		oh it's so you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and did you ever eat at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Bin</ENAMEX> Diner
 	
 	
 		yes oh my God where are you from well let's not talk about that
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no but we've been there when i'm up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> we've gone up there
 	
 	
 		it's um in that area i mean i just can't say enough about it
 	
 	
 		oh it's it whatever we went and he was you know impressed by the clean air and he he met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and he liked them
 	
 	
 		well you know um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and a strong liberal a strong liberal arts background with uh a graduate degree in a technical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> will get him much further than say like a a strong um business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> degree than with another MBA on top of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's okay that's it the thing is if if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> really knows very early on that they want to go in a technical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> than you're not then it's probably good to go to you know to apply to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with a strong technical program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and they usually
 		yeah but they usually don't
 	
 	
 		but uh for if you're going into if you know engineering is the thing if then you've got to at least take engineering
 	
 	
 		right but they no but who does i mean i think i think all i think the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't know no he looked at criteria such as location size of school yeah
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		uh-huh no he didn't apply to any school further the furthest away was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowdoin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> which is about twelve hours
 	
 	
 		that's still pretty far though i mean a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just don't even want to go
 	
 	
 		yeah that was the furthest and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> which was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six and a half hours</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's not too bad
 	
 	
 		yeah so well i mean he so it wasn't he you know then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> is like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> from here by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bucknell</ENAMEX> in mid state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he will enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> i think and  is a good academic
 	
 	
 		yeah and he knew and if it came down i mean as he came he's been talking to them and and he came down and one of the things that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he said is he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> and he had an absolutely marvelous time he had a great time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then he said you know it was such a good time that i almost got the feeling that their emphasis is on having fun
 	
 	
 		that could very well be i mean
 	
 	
 		and he said it almost backfired i think it backfired
 	
 	
 		so he's developing his his uh internal instincts right now that's good because i mean i'm sure what he said was true that uh you well actually that's one of the reasons i went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyon</ENAMEX> he went he made a good choice i went i
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i well swear w e're not supposed to but i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my freshman year</TIMEX> it was just too far away it was too different uh the level of income of lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and their attitudes was just um beyond my
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		um in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs et cetera</ENAMEX> which i thought was shocking
 	
 	
 		of course that period too was probably difficult to for you but i did uh my advice to him and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s was that
 	
 	
 		right yeah you're right but then i went
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he had to really decide what he wanted out of college he had to look at himself uh in a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> he had to realize that if he was going to screw around it he could probably slip
 		and it wouldn't be caught up until it was too late where in a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where especially in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyon</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> where you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> all the time you skip class in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and they see you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and you're going to get a little bit more input  than discipline yeah
 	
 	
 		that's yeah yeah and a swim <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> is going to be right on top of you uh so that and he will know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> in a small
 	
 	
 		well i don't know how to put this either in this way and then it doesn't sound like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> would need this but i just think the other thing is with the way a lot of the youth is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i think the refinement that they get i don't mean specifically etiquette or culture but just what you're saying just a solid background
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		because i just don't think at that age i just don't think that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know what they want to do
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right and um and it's just the personal contact where if you need help
 	
 	
 		you know and um
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		he has i told him to look to yourself are you the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that will go into a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> says i've got office <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> but you really don't feel that you know him because you're in a class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> that you're really going to look him up but if it's a class of fifteen
 	
 	
 		right right lecture yeah
 		this is very very
 	
 	
 		and you need help you know that it's much easier to do it and especially in the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> they have lectures
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and even though they may break it up into smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> is known for having
 	
 	
 		they have video lectures yeah video lectures
 	
 	
 		graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> teaching they have graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> to teach the smaller groups
 	
 	
 		this is true and i mean that is very ironic too that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> just made the did he just make the decision today
 	
 	
 		just a he made the decision uh i'd say about uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		how funny
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean that's so funny i mean and and in fact he had just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> before that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh recent graduates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyon</ENAMEX> spent close to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> talking with him
 	
 	
 		well he'll
 		that's funny
 	
 	
 		and uh i mean and he they were really nice and but he said is that they didn't tell him anything that he didn't know but they helped confirm his decision that a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was better
 	
 	
 		it was easy for him to rule out he knew what he didn't want that's exactly yeah now is your other i mean we're talking about what you think but obviously you're experiencing it uh did your other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		right now yeah
 		my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is just as happy as a bed bug he the moment he knew he he decided early on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amherst</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> he's a classical guitarist
 	
 	
 		a clam
 		oh wonderful
 	
 	
 		and he decided he also got into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> school of music as an undergraduate for classical guitar but he decided he was going to go to the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the smaller and the
 	
 	
 		the smaller now and then graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> later
 	
 	
 		and they'll do fine in their studies and i'm sure they'll go on to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well he's really my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s real happy and he's minoring in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 		and he had thought about economics and he took a couple of courses in economics and decided that wasn't
 	
 	
 		and now he's a senior he's a senior or is this early admissions
 	
 	
 		he'll be he's finishing his sophomore year so he's double majoring
 	
 	
 		so he's
 		so he's yeah well sounds like you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you know see the advice we give is to not limit yourself especially this you know go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where you're not forced to make too many irrevocable decisions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your first year</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		i think and a lot of people talk about and it's not the economics i'm solely zeroed in on but i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think about the tuition level and what exactly are you getting in return
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shy away from the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges colleges</ENAMEX> because of that and i think it's rather sad
 	
 	
 		well one of the things we said is that they should pick the college this was our advice too irrespective of the cost that somehow we would manage
 	
 	
 		you are wonderful parents
 	
 	
 		well we place a real high priority on education in our family
 	
 	
 		no and i agree i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i in fact i'm taking my LSATs um i'm thirty something and taking my LSATs on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> tenth
 	
 	
 		oh good that's wonderful
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		um the point being and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> will learn this from you i'm sure that uh no matter what age you are you can learn
 	
 	
 		that's right that's exactly
 	
 	
 		and it sounds like they're going to you know they're just
 		
 		
 	