
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so what are the benefits working for a large organization
 	
 	
 		gosh i wouldn't know i've never worked for a large organization
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh that will make it interesting
 	
 	
 		well i will take that back i i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> i guess that qualifies as a large organization
 	
 	
 		yeah i i would qualify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		large if not too large
 	
 	
 		sort of large yeah just
 		a little bit little bit bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		okay i never really counted that as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> because it's uh
 	
 	
 		the benefits are funny
 	
 	
 		yeah the benefits are strange they change <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and uh
 		you don't really have a lot of choice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> do you want this or do you want this or do you want this
 	
 	
 		well we don't have that kind of choice either
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh i mean you certain
 	
 	
 		yeah out here in the real world it's all the same
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		no matter who your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		no i mean you have the choice of taking this health insurance or
 		or some other or something like that
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		uh yeah here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springs</ENAMEX> we have a choice of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> either an HMO or a company health insurance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so there are two
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		of course i can't say we didn't have a choice if you always wanted to you could uh go out and buy your health insurance
 	
 	
 		out of your own jeans yes
 	
 	
 		yeah out of your own jeans and stay a way from the base hospital which is generally what i did
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		kind of scary
 	
 	
 		it was that bad huh
 	
 	
 		uh i i never fully trusted them the only time i ever went there was when i had to for a flight physical or something
 		uh which has to be their doctor but they're not doing anything to me other than testing me so i let them do that
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well there are other benefits with the military
 	
 	
 		well i don't i
 	
 	
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> don't get
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i don't
 		i don't bad mouth the military too much i had a i had a good time
 	
 	
 		well i just meant from a benefit standpoint
 	
 	
 		well from benefit well that's one of the reasons i made a decision to get out
 		uh i what i perceived as the benefits were just eroding
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well the
 		their pension plan is really good
 	
 	
 		yeah you know that part is good except for the except for the little thing that you're paying into social security for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> and when you start
 	
 	
 		and then you can't draw it
 	
 	
 		that's right and then and then you start drawing your retirement pay and if you start drawing the social security they offset your retirement dollar for dollar
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i always thought that that that was a big rip off
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well on the other side of the fence
 	
 	
 		but still
 	
 	
 		the way it works is that uh
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
 		although they have a qualified pension plan they don't have a
 		viable pension plan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we won't mention any names
 	
 	
 		
 
 		don't worry they're recording every word
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i didn't say it was them
 	
 	
 		oh okay you're right you're right
 	
 	
 		but i didn't but
 		but i didn't say it wasn't either
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we will let them draw their own conclusions
 	
 	
 		that's right draw your own inference
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but but but what you are saying about the military times is is true i mean fifty percent uh of your base pay is pretty good
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh
 		medical for the rest of your life
 	
 	
 		yeah that you know that sounds great on paper but it's not it's not something that i would look would look forward to
 	
 	
 		well we have
 		we have had some medical i mean some military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> work up here for us
 		or a bunch really and
 		they did use the heck out of the medical
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		military medical
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now the military dental was poor
 	
 	
 		no now
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at best
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but the medical seemed somewhat adequate
 		somewhat adequate
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean don't get me wrong for something something that was major
 		i i wouldn't have any problems with them it's the daily uh go in with the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> or something like that
 		and and the the treatment is terrible i mean first you wait for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours and hours and hours</TIMEX> and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> says you have a temperature well i knew that
 		we're going to give you Sudafed you know i've been taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sudafed</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> it doesn't do any good
 		that's all i can do that's all i can do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah uh i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of an HMO
 		and uh from all indications it's quite similar to the military
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well that that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s are designed that way i mean they are going to they're gonna they're gonna get the most bang for their buck
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly and
 	
 	
 		and uh you know they're they're in the big profit making business
 	
 	
 		and
 		so
 		and so the single benefits that i consider among the most important are medical insurance
 	
 	
 		yeah absolutely
 	
 	
 		because without it you can be
 		broke for the rest of your life
 	
 	
 		that's it forever and ever
 		all all you have to do is you don't have it let something bad happen
 		and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> will slap a lien on you so fast
 		because they do it routinely
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 		yes and the funny thing is that uh
 		private medical insurance grossly expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i know i know
 	
 	
 		if you are not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a group
 	
 	
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roomie</ENAMEX>'s got the ins urance through the school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it runs fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> i think fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> bucks a month something like that
 		an that's not bad but you don't get anything
 	
 	
 		that's not bad
 	
 	
 		i mean to tell you
 	
 	
 		well you get what you pay for don't you
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right i mean it's nothing
 		um
 		uh it doesn't cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> or anything else it's crazy
 	
 	
 		doesn't cover doctors
 	
 	
 		no i mean you can go it will cover something major
 		but forget about things like eyes or your teeth or anything else
 		
 
 		what it is it's medical insurance on paper
 	
 	
 		are you covered yes are you covered really no
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right read between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> are you covered no
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		but you know i mean the whole health care thing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> is so screwed up that uh
 	
 	
 		yes it
 	
 	
 		uh it's totally ridiculous
 	
 	
 		it it's a shame it's
 	
 	
 		it is i mean
 		i'm one of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> running around with no health insurance at the moment
 	
 	
 		in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> currently when in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> whenever you fill out uh your state income tax
 		they ask you if you have medical insurance if you do
 		you have to pay for those that don't have medical insurance
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> a person i don't remember something along those lines but it
 		still the idea irks me so that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina North Carolina</ENAMEX> has an interesting thing on their income tax uh they create
 		money
 		tax you with or to tax you on
 		there's a neat little formula on the back that you have to complete
 		and assuming you're you're you're at poverty line where you're uh deduction or you take the standard deduction of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two fifty</TIMEX> uh that will work out to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional three hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		tacked on to your taxable income
 		yeah and of course it goes higher and higher the more money you make
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		but the very least that anybody filing income tax form will have to pay on is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX> and they create money out of thin air
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i attached a little note to my my return when i sent it in saying gee i didn't know i had this extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX> i wonder where it went
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Colorado</ENAMEX> is a nifty thing if you
 		or they did until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 		in times past if you got a federal tax
 		refund
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you paid state income tax the next year
 	
 	
 		on the refund yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> did that too
 		and i always thought well this is pretty nifty you taxed me when i made the money the feds
 	
 	
 		and now you're taxing me again on it
 	
 	
 		yeah the feds took it out and now they're giving it back to me and now you're going to tax it again i seem i seem to recall recall something about revolutions and wars about double and triple taxation and stuff
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		course uh course it it's the by word now i mean let let's tax everything <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		and there are tax revolutions going on currently
 	
 	
 		there should be
 	
 	
 		but the problem is it's not an armed insurrection
 	
 	
 		no
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not a violent overthrow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no because because quite honestly the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so apathetic about everything <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> can do what they want to do
 	
 	
 		and they are trying to take away our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that too
 		i'm a lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the NRA
 		i'm not as militant as i was when i was younger but i still firmly believe in the right to own and bear arms
 	
 	
 		and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that say that
 		all that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> was guaranteeing is that we will have a militia
 	
 	
 		yeah that's garbage
 	
 	
 		i think they are  sorely mistaken
 	
 	
 		they're they're wrong the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> was the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of militia the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX> made up the everyday common man
 	
 	
 		he pulled his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">squirrel rifle</ENAMEX> off his wall as he walked out in the yard
 	
 	
 		that's right and and if they said hey we need a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX> then all the able bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were supposed to show up
 		
 		
 	