
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i uh i have not like i was saying i haven't i have not had to make the decision for uh
 		regarding uh care for anyone of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> members however i've had quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have had to make that decision
 	
 	
 		well see i don't have a relative that's made it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty one</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s side have them up into the nineties
 	
 	
 		man yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		
 
 		the only time we came close and we started looking into it was when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> became senile she start senile at fifty
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and at that time the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that we were looking for when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i can remember them arguing they couldn't find one that it was either clean enough or they took enough care or
 		there was one thing or another that continuously arguing about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they ended up keeping her from relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> and of course she died when she was fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> so it wasn't that long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's a
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the few i've been in they have varied tremendous
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i think there's there's so many that are uh that are you know retirement homes
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		that are geared toward the ambulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you know the ambulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that is still
 		extremely active and just wishes not to have to live alone you know
 		separate any longer and then there are the uh the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> which actually provide you know nursing care i guess it goes there's a wide range
 	
 	
 		oh well we were talking about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> at work has got that problem right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she keeps saying she's never going to put her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i says hey look go around look at them they're totally different than your concept concept of what it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i says i don't know what condition your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s in which i didn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you do have the choice now and i says what is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> going to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long while you're out here at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i says think about what she would like to have because a lot of them hey they might be bedridden but at least they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> their own age to talk to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to keep them home what do you've got
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		they're sitting there like they're they vegetate
 		is what happens
 	
 	
 		that's true that's that's what i would be afraid of i would rather personally i would rather be in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
 		a greater chance of having similar interest with them
 		rather than being stuck in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where i mean if you if you couldn't drive i guess i mean if you're no longer have the the freedom of driving
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then it it changes it so drastically because you can't go someplace to do something when you want to you have you are totally dependent on someone else to provide all your entertainment for you and that would
 		i don't think i would like that i think i would rather
 		if i where in that situation i think i would rather live in a in a nursing home situation
 	
 	
 		see you're not aware of the the horror stories and things like that that i've grown up with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i mean i'm talking about horror stories and they're still out there i mean it's it's not something that's eliminated eliminated been eliminated
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		there are lots of homes out there that just literally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drop them off forget about them and they change hands i mean i'm not saying they don't investigate they investigate it's great when they're there but unless they keep current with it
 		and they changes hands it goes either direction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		they're relying on a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that hey they're like any other business if you lose a lot of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> they get into a financial bind
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well you know they're a nursing home but the hey it doesn't work that way they're a business
 	
 	
 		that's true and and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> that they hire are
 		frequently not um the most qualified in their field
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> she runs down here to this nursing home down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she just point blank's tired the pressure and responsibility of working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she admits it she's tired of it so she works down here she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> she's qualified
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but she's fifty oh she's in her fifties early fifties somewhere and working down here at the nursing home keeps her hand in there she gets good money for it and she enjoys the old people
 		you know it's it's just that simple for her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh she says it's hard they get cranky they get obstinate
 		but she feels the same way i do i would rather depending on the situation i would rather be able to put myself or anybody else in a nursing home if i was able to get close enough to them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so they don't feel lost
 	
 	
 		right i think
 	
 	
 		now see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> she wouldn't go in a nursing home besides being scared and everybody else didn't want her she was terrified of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> literally and positively terrified
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because she remembers the old stuff
 	
 	
 		uh-huh my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was and she was she was terrified that some day someone might try to put her in a nursing home she even wrote a song about it she used to sing but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean she she died when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety six</NUMEX> and uh
 		from a fall i mean she didn't die of natural causes she died from a fall she uh you know had she been younger it would not she would not have died from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> but
 		she uh you know and she was still
 		she was still  household independent she was independent in the household you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and she couldn't drive but heck but she'd never learned to drive to begin with so i mean it wasn't um
 		her age that had prevented her but she was she was very afraid that someone would try to put her in a nursing home and she lived with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> until she died and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> still at seventy
 		uh she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy nine this year</TIMEX> uh is living independently
 		and she drives  just to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and back and to and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> you know all there right in just a block or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but she's still real independent so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh she drives yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that for so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh the nursing home represent obviously different uh different things and depending on the level of function
 		whereas my you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> doesn't need need any extra uh camaraderie or anything like that because she gets it from her church or from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that come by but uh
 		i've seen a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't live near their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or don't have you know significant roots in this in their little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> they've been uprooted for some reason or another
 		and they i i think that it would be good for them to be into a situation that
 		would offer them uh oh activities to maintain an active mind
 		because like you say if you just put them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and keep them there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long and they they become they vegetate  and that's
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they've got nothing or they get on the telephone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i mean this is one area where i'd like to see social security or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> step in an d take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over a certain age or with handicaps or something and take their social security away from them
 		i mean give them you know money at a certain point and putting them in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> to where they can get something fed back to them in other words people talk to and become still human beings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down in south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and every where else sitting in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they don't know anybody they're scared to death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbers</ENAMEX> they're scared to death of everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they hardly have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to even eat on
 		i meant they're not living
 	
 	
 		and that's not living right right exactly
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean hey i'm putting all this money out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> why can't they put it out there rather than in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 		but you know you see pictures on TV i mean i wish i had enough money to go down there and do something but
 		you know i don't know they if they can have day care why can't they put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> care and put them in a home to where it's regulated
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it's it's a shame that we have this to where it's we don't think of our older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we really don't
 	
 	
 		oh no i mean look at the uh Orientals  they protect respect uh they conserve their elderly
 		for for what they are they're a true natural resource and they cherish them and uh yet i mean we as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are such a throw away society
 		that we've basically done that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have so called outlived their usefulness
 		you know i i think that's uh an atrocity and i'm fortunate enough that i've had uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> have lived very long full lives and uh
 		or most of them have and as a result i have uh i've been you know
 		
 		
 	