
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> public service for everybody
 		is that that was it right
 	
 	
 		right uh
 		who wants to start this one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't know i've been i've been sitting here thinking here because it was you know took a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> tries before i found somebody well you know i'm like i'm not really sure what i think about this um
 		uh i mean the first thing is the oh if it's going to be mandatory it's got to be mandatory i mean everybody not just like you know poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and all that you know but
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and all that stuff too i mean everybody's got to do it um
 		i don't know it'd probably be it'd probably be good i just don't know if you know i was eighteen or whatever i'd want to be stuck doing it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure i want an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen year old</TIMEX> to make that kind of decision uh i mean uh that that doesn't sound right
 		um i guess i see overall beneficial if if we're going from that point of view
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i you know in the past i don't know i don't know how old you are but when i was uh in high school was uh beginning of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and so forth and many of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> were being drafted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i could see that many of them had conscientious objections to war or whatever
 		but i i felt strongly then that even if they didn't feel like they could kill someone or go into a military situation that they could help the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in other ways
 		be it cleaning out uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> in in their neighborhood or whatever kind of community or public service might be available
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i guess i see that as as not so much a a demand but but a privilege it's it's kind of uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah is um
 	
 	
 		it's something it's it's since we live here and we all benefit rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> or in between uh there are benefits even for those who have it the hardest i just see that as maybe a good idea i wouldn't mind doing it at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i find ways to to turn some of that back to to others uh and i i guess i i can't see that as being something to really object to
 	
 	
 		well i guess it's gonna depend on how i mean if if you're talking about any  if you're talking about something that's like a full time
 		you know one year full time you know this is what you do you know you're going to go and and fill pot holes and you know and you know all that stuff i mean
 		i you know i don't know
 	
 	
 		i could see a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a full</TIMEX> a run a gamut of different kinds of opportunities things that need to be done that would that could be done in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh a day or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half of a day</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> or something like that in addition to what one does
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh besides that i i can't imagine what kind of uh
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX> we'd get into and expense having it be full time oh you're going to go to this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and you're going to you know like um
 		back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> the CCC the the construction corps that went out and did things that was great it was needed it gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> some jobs and we got some great public works out of it but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i don't see that as being necessary now i can see it being done uh on a regular schedule
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh everybody has to put in so many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of uh public service in a given time perhaps
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i i guess i see all of us benefiting and i i don't see it just relegated to the young
 		but i see i i see so much going on that that's bad and this would give them a chance to have some positive self esteem something that they turn back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well and and also you know you you you feel more like you know you're actually part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> if you've done something in it
 	
 	
 		that's right you take pride in that and and get some some positive feedback from those who benefit besides yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i see it being most beneficial if it's in the neighborhood where or or at least the area where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> lives it may not be the same neighborhood but the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or county
 	
 	
 		uh definitely
 	
 	
 		because then you're you're coming in contact with it it's not as meaningful for me to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and do something up there that i'll never be able to see again unless i happen to go on vacation up there
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's so it almost needs to be something that has more
 		impact for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> on going
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but as far as putting that into work i don't want to  i don't want to deal with the with the heartache of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all getting it started and figuring out how to do the logistics
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh uh that would be a nightmare
 		and just i mean just getting getting it going
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i see a lot of things like uh scouting uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys Clubs Girls Clubs</ENAMEX> things like that that kind of get into that citizenship uh the uh looking after the environment sort of thing and and i guess i don't see
 		uh this being that different
 		but even more beneficial because it would be something that everybody participated in and would take a turn in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you have kids
 	
 	
 		no uh no
 		not yet
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months</TIMEX> we will
 	
 	
 		oh well good good you have a little time think about that i guess i i have uh when i was teaching school i saw many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that were at loose ends
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that didn't really have a purpose and i can see you know some some really significant things coming out of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know you've got to get past that that grudge attitude that many have but that's uh
 		that that would be a part of selling it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> ahead of them that probably would never serve and and to each succeeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> there'd definitely have to be a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> campaign in each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> each county
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> parish or however the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was divided up
 		hum i may well i don't know around here we have a number of community projects that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> just volunteer for
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boy Scout troops</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church groups</ENAMEX> or civic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> will uh police a uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of miles</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and keep and i i've seen it in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> too i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah they have that here um they've got um in most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> around here i think uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> there was a big controversy for a while because the uh the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX> wanted to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um to participate in it and uh there was a
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and there were those that said no you can't do that i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh it was it was interesting because that's an interesting question you know should these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be allowed to or not i think they finally decided not to because they figured that stretch of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> was going to get trashed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh and i hadn't even thought about that uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other the other end of that</TIMEX> that that's an interesting uh situation i hadn't thought of that
 		we had visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> not too long ago and i thought i had seen when we were traveling around the state some similar signs up that indicated that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were being policed and cleaned up and
 	
 	
 		yeah i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s got it and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> does and we just we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> and back and um i'm pretty sure i saw yeah stuff in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana Indiana</ENAMEX> about it and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 		i don't remember for sure now
 	
 	
 		and i don't know about your part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but uh down here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> oh year plus i it was last beginning with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth Day</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's just been more of a turn toward uh environmental concerns and even i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and they they've started some recycling campaigns that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year before</TIMEX> that had been turned down because they said well it's not feasible it's not a good idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and but then they lost too much business
 	
 	
 		and i see that as being
 		i i see that as being a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a change um it for the positive kind of along the same line as as as the mandatory thing it's just thing
 		a part of everyone's consciousness
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well the thing about that is though it's got a i mean because it was i mean it was big you remember like in the early seventies and all that and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and then it kind of just went out of vogue and i i'm worried that it it might you know it'll it the same thing will happen it's like you know environmentalism was really big for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like well
 		you know i'd ruther rather spend you know fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> less on uh on on such and such you know and even if it's not environmentally safe who cares you know
 	
 	
 		i'm sure the pendulum will swing the other way uh there have been too many other things that it's done that for just in my life
 		and if you look at history at all you see that you know uh we go from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side to the other on just about any subject that you one might care to bring up but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it is comforting to me to see uh more concern about some of these things that that cost us money especially when we have dwindling uh resources such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> that's
 		burning out of control in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> and and so forth just just every little bit does
 		it makes me feel better it it makes me feel like well there may be something left for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my nieces and nephews and so forth
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah uh well uh wouldn't
 		it's just probably a good thing that the oil's burning and may may make some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize that hey you know this stuff runs out
 	
 	
 		that's that's right because
 	
 	
 		of course that's probably blasphemy for you to say uh coming from where you are  in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no  no because if
 		
 
 		we what was it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy four</TIMEX> when we had the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last last</TIMEX> oil crisis and and uh we started getting smart and and we were looking all these alternative sources of energy and so forth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and as soon as the oil prices came back down we the pendulum swung the other way and we need those reminders
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or we'll suddenly be in the dark and say oh my goodness now we don't have the ability to go on to some new technology
 	
 	
 		right well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s in the in the solar energy business
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		so um you know we're acutely aware of a lot of this but you know on the other hand he voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> so um  you know i i wonder sometimes if he knows what he's doing
 	
 	
 		i'm sure you are
 		
 
 		well i this you know just about anybody you could name whether i voted for them or not uh makes um uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		decisions that i just can't go along with but uh that's why they're there and not me i don't want the i don't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> and the strain
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well the the thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	