
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well i've been sort of out of it for a little while so i don't know really what's going on
 	
 	
 		well there there's been some interesting stuff going on locally but i suppose nationally the big thing is probably uh the
 		reaction to the war in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> trying to show that yeah oh oh gosh we really did support it i mean  just because we wanted to impeach him doesn't mean anything
 	
 	
 		trying to cover themselves
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah there's been uh same thing locally here a couple of uh we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> who uh
 		went on national TV and said that you know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> tried to do anything over there without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> approval they should impeach him and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true there there's a lot of talk over there that i don't think anyone imagined that it could possibly be as as successful and and painless as it had been
 	
 	
 		then
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so they figured a little bit of opposition was safe but it didn't turn out that way
 	
 	
 		sure
 		no uh i don't know i i i usually don't talk politics with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> because it's a good way to get into an argument but
 	
 	
 		well that's why that's why being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> is safe we can
 	
 	
 		it's it's probably safer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least now</TIMEX> can't get hit this way you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh i i don't know i'm i've been <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> for as long as i can remember and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are just so disorganized and they have been
 	
 	
 		that's true i i've been <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> for since i've been voting which isn't that long but i'll agree with you there that there's not much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> going on
 	
 	
 		yeah they uh
 		yeah i i don't know it
 		right around the turn of uh oh gosh  i should say the eighties now now
 		it's already the nineties i forgot i forget that too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they just haven't seemed to been able to hit anything
 		uh on the head
 		every every time they go one way the wind is always blowing the other which is
 	
 	
 		well that's true but i suppose it's hard to judge from the eighties because um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was just so overwhelming to them i think they're seeing some of that unraveling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah no i don't i don't know how they're going uh i i you know i'm looking i'm looking at the upcoming elections and i'm trying to think who are they going to put up
 	
 	
 		well they've already got uh oh jeez
 		there's there's there's already <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> that i know of on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">end</ENAMEX> and i keep thinking there's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh Tsongas
 	
 	
 		yeah uh out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		yeah i wouldn't mind him too much he's a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> he's been around and he's he keeps a low profile and doesn't go after the the headlines and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i've i've i've heard the name but that that's the extent of my my information about him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i i would be interested to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Nunn</ENAMEX> decides to go this time i i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		try to get the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for once
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean if out out of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that i could think to run i would he is one that i would i would definitely like to see
 	
 	
 		that that would be interesting i i must admit i haven't been really enthusiastic about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX>
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last couple of</TIMEX> run throughs
 	
 	
 		well i'll tell you if they if they do it like they did uh
 		the last time around it's not going to be very exciting
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know um i mean let's face <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bentsen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bentsen</ENAMEX>
 		good grief surely they could have done better than that course they they had a they had themselves between a rock and a hard place they had on the one hand they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> with all that support
 		and on the other they knew very
 	
 	
 		but completely unelectable and
 	
 	
 		oh sure and and they could not give him the nomination
 	
 	
 		true it's it's probably their their their troubles probably stem from the fact that they're such a diverse party
 	
 	
 		uh i
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the nominating rules these days are so um pseudo democratic i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> deciding well who could we really get elected instead there's so much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i mean i mean they were really stuck because here they were everybody was expecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jesse</ENAMEX> to get at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> nomination
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh certainly not presidential but but quite possibly VP
 		and here they are they they know very well they can't do it because if they do it's going to split the party
 		and if they do it they're going to alienate a whole bunch of others
 		so i mean they were stuck one way or the other yeah it was an interesting thing i was laughing through the whole thing uh
 	
 	
 		true i suppose being on the other side of the aisle it probably made good comic theater
 	
 	
 		yeah i it it it was it was it was comical i i sat there and watched the just watched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and just giggle <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> you know uh oh this is great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> is in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has turned out to be a lot better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gave him credit for
 	
 	
 		i i must admit i'm i'm still i i still find him a little uninspiring he he seems like a reasonably competent
 	
 	
 		yeah he is he
 		yeah he he is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to sort of
 		do do some caretaking to um
 	
 	
 		yeah and and i i wonder the you know if if that's i mean that that really that really should be all we need in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> someone who is capable of managing
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		and that's all a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is anyway just a manager
 	
 	
 		sort of set the agenda and and let let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do the work it's it's unfortunate how how little domestic agenda he
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and set the agenda and
 		yeah well you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans Republicans</ENAMEX> have always been weak on on the domestic side they're they're very big on international stuff but domestically they they just say well it'll take care of itself
 	
 	
 		he he worries about
 		true but uh so many of his compi campaign promises were on the the domestic promises
 	
 	
 		but it's
 		yeah
 		well you know same old you know take it with a grain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> stuff you know he he
 	
 	
 		true
 		that that's that's what just amazes me though is that that so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do uh take the campaign promises seriously
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and they still do  he
 	
 	
 		well the the one thing that just amazed me in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> here there were a series of um ads
 		saying don't vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> he's going to take away your right to own a gun he's going to close down defense <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> he's going to do this he's going to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		half of which is coming true
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just here's my chance to giggle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> it's a good thing we didn't elect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> because i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know the interesting thing about i don't know if you've been watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> lately um
 	
 	
 		i know i know that the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> miracle has has gone bust
 	
 	
 		oh it's a disaster it's a disaster and the thing was it was all quick fixes finger in the dike sort of thing to make him look good for the upcoming race
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i i guess i didn't hear that i didn't go over it really
 	
 	
 		well i mean that that's what you can infer from it because it it's amazing that it started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> before the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> run
 	
 	
 		true true i suppose
 	
 	
 		and then you know it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> to crap out but i mean it was dying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i lived up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i mean it was terrible it was absolutely terrible
 		up prices are just unbelievable up there
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are getting terrible everything's going down the tubes
 		said he was going to clean up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Harbor</ENAMEX> and it's dirtier than it ever was
 	
 	
 		yeah that really is disappointing it's it's sort of
 	
 	
 		never
 		yeah and then on the other hand too while he was out busy running for the presidential thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> was having their own way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it was just it was a pure disaster because the way it was set up
 		he's the one that that put it together and he's the only one who knew how it worked or supposedly worked
 		and he wasn't there to run it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so here's a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> with their own agenda uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> with their own agenda
 		and of course the thing just fell apart fell to pieces and he couldn't do anything with it
 		it was amazing they had a poll <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> about i guess it was around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 		uh
 		they showed the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> only twenty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> could recognize him as governor
 	
 	
 		that's incredible oh oh there's there's one thing i've got to ask you about the the dump <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> movement i find that interesting
 	
 	
 		it it was
 		
 
 		i wish they would
 	
 	
 		i i find him such an embarrassment and uh i mean the the the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collin Powell</ENAMEX> well he's so powerful or he's so popular now
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i don't know if he's the the right <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to replace him he'd probably be a perfectly competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		boy i tell you
 		he i'll tell you what you know when i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> i met i met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collin Powell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah i was i had a pretty neat job i got to meet all the big wigs used to fly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and all that stuff
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Collin Powell</ENAMEX> is one capable guy
 	
 	
 		i get i i i would probably find him an order of magnitude more capable than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he
 		oh yes absolutely i i mean the
 	
 	
 		it's it's interesting to hear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		instead instead instead instead of just making bland uh pronouncements about having no plans to change the ticket has just really emphatically come out and said no way
 	
 	
 		i know i and i i'll tell you you know it
 		i i my my degree was in political science because i enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i had a good time during that during that election but it floored me when he came up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>
 		because there are so many other capable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well from from some of the things i've heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> he he he didn't want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> that was any competition for him
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		yeah and i mean certainly he wasn't going to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> on and not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> would even take the position i mean he'd be giving up more than he'd gain
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there are several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are who are just super capable
 		but to get this nobody with the kind of baggage that he's carrying
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh it just astounded me i mean he must have been so sure of winning that it didn't make any difference
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it uh uh i'm i guess i'm the i'm cloudy on the timing but there there was quite a while when his certain victory wasn't certain at all
 	
 	
 		yeah i well
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm not sure how that timing related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> announcement but he was trailing at at times
 		or or just just neck and neck i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah i yeah about that time i think it was neck and neck and i the only the only reason at the time that i could think of was that he was young and and sort of charismatic in uh in uh handsome sort of way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and hoping to bring in maybe a little bit of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> charisma or something
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is so uncharismatic
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> talks about he doesn't like broccoli well that's how how i think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> as broccoli you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh that brings up another subject it's the  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know the
 		
 		
 	