
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay the topic was uh should the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> adopt the metric system and if so should uh oh
 	
 	
 		how should they do it why didn't it work last time
 	
 	
 		and why didn't it work last time  well yeah well i'm
 	
 	
 		well
 		i'm all for it
 	
 	
 		i i am too i wish uh it had started a long time ago is the the problem because we're so wound up in the in the system that we've got that you know trying to convert over
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i guess  what'd they try they tried what'd the call it soft conversion and hard conversion one of them is where you just take whatever's already standard and you give it some sort of a weird
 	
 	
 		yeah they tried to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">metric</ENAMEX> number like uh  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eight seven</NUMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six millimeter</NUMEX> something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah direct conversion
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh
 		i i don't know uh
 	
 	
 		i think they just ought to you know start uh just go all all the way you know new products introduced or whatever you know start your packaging go to liters instead of quarts and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if they have to are going to learn to think that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well don't most of them doesn't just about everything now have uh both
 	
 	
 		but if you start
 	
 	
 		uh metric and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they do but things are generally packaged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> sized packages you know you buy a quart of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and sure it has has the metric equivalent written on there but it still a quart so if they started putting it in liters liter of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know liters of gasoline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to learn to think in metric as long as you can still buy a product in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that's how you're going to think of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i kind of remember back when gas prices started up uh you know pretty dramatically when they started getting toward a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> a gallon range somebody had uh i believe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		figures
 	
 	
 		we we were living in uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> at the time they started marketing it in in liters and it was only like  you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty nine</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thirty cents</NUMEX> a liter so they could put this sign out front that said you know
 		thirty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine cents</NUMEX> a liter and nobody had any idea what a liter was so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's the problem
 	
 	
 		when you finally figured out that liters what about a quart there's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about four liters</NUMEX> in a gallon you know so you can figure out what you're actually paying for it
 	
 	
 		right it's kind of hard for me to believe that this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age i don't know when i was growing up we were taught the metric system in school i mean not not at first but by the time i was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh i've never
 	
 	
 		it's i would expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with any kind of
 		buying power over the age of or you know under the age of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty or so</TIMEX> to have some idea what it is anyway a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">liter</ENAMEX>'s about a quart
 	
 	
 		yeah i yeah
 		the uh i think maybe there's where the the problem came in you know we uh tried to instead of learning it's kind of like learning a language you know when you learn one from the other
 		yeah you always end up in this conversion thing all the time so it's you it's almost like uh course this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> but you know it's like somebody said okay as of such and such a date
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know anybody caught talking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> metric you know in the will be shot or something like that you know but uh  uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well thing is it's a global
 		global market place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and you know we're one of like what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> backwards clo <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world as far as
 	
 	
 		yeah i read that what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		something i don't remember what the other one is but
 	
 	
 		uh
 		there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> others that just
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's it's just time i think for for us to go over because all you end up doing is if you're in business or you're in any kind of international
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't you know i don't know i uh i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> we're all around the world you have to perform this conversion anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i
 		yeah i i do too and uh one of the things that we've run run into a a problem of course you're familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> drawing well with any drawing system you end up with uh you end up with things in inches
 	
 	
 		and
 		right mils and microns
 		right
 	
 	
 		in parts of inches you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fourth half fourth</TIMEX> you know this sort of thing and then you end up with a decimal
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		where you start getting into mils and that sort of thing and then some of them are are done in uh you know purely metric
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i remember how big stink came around in the design area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX> when it was all overseas designs were in microns and ours were in mils
 	
 	
 		and it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it got to you know somewhere down the line they went standardized they went microns but uh
 		you just you know you end up with all kinds of problems with converting your designs
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i can imagine
 	
 	
 		and
 		so
 	
 	
 		the uh the one that uh
 		uh have you ever lived in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where they use metric
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		or
 		i was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and uh i had to get used to you know purely metric system down there
 		and because they they didn't understand anything else you know if you start talking about miles they'd look at you like what you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		uh i had a little bit of experience with it and also i noticed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> they uh you drop a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> fifty cents whatever in a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> machine up there and you get this funny looking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> you know it's in a can that's uh
 		that's taller but not as big around you know i guess that's some
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a half a liter</NUMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		it's not it's not a liter it's like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a liter</NUMEX> or something like that it's a strange looking can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter-in-law</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> and she has  they have uh
 		had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> down there for so long you know that they're they're kind of into both systems but uh she gets real confused on distances and temperature is the big thing is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Centigrade</ENAMEX> for which she says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celsius</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i would have more problem with
 		more problem with the temperature except that you know working in engineering
 		we do everything in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Centigrade</ENAMEX> or Celsius
 	
 	
 		well i had kind of gotten used to uh centigrade temperature you know if it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between zero</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> it's cold and if it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between ten</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> it's not too bad if it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between twenty</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> it's pretty warm and if it's more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> it's just hotter than all get out so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		getting warm right
 	
 	
 		but uh the big problem is not having the uh uh
 		the resolution between temperature you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between a hundred</NUMEX> and if you're talking about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred degrees</NUMEX> or what thirty zero you know thirty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four degrees</NUMEX> whatever that is you know you you don't get all the little
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's about
 	
 	
 		the differences you know the differences between seventy and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seventy two or seventy five degrees</NUMEX> isn't much but the difference between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty five degrees</NUMEX> is is quite a bit yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's about twice as much yeah what it works out to
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>  well i
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> times as many
 	
 	
 		yeah something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		points yeah so
 		i don't know i think as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a choice they're going to stick with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way
 	
 	
 		i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and until we have to have to learn to think that way we we won't
 	
 	
 		yeah i know we keep calling it the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> system but i'm i'm not sure what they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> now they're they're on metric aren't they
 	
 	
 		yeah for the most part i think so
 	
 	
 		yeah except they've got a now okay there we ran into some problems once i remember uh they've got a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a nut</NUMEX> and bolts system called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wentworth</ENAMEX>
 		and uh this thing was was even different than you know SAE standards and stuff so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh uh
 		this this came okay my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> bought uh one of these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash Metropolitans</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX> you know quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>
 		and the thing had uh uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin Heeley</ENAMEX> type uh engine you know it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin</ENAMEX> motors engine and running gear
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> or who you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> it wasn't that was even before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Motors</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> essentially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> somewhere
 		and that thing had the darndest combination of metric and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wentworth</ENAMEX> and uh SAE he ended up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> sets of tools  in order to work on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> thing because uh
 	
 	
 		he just get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more
 	
 	
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wentworth</ENAMEX> and the SAE bolt sizes were the same but the threads were different
 		and uh it was it was it was a it was a total mess
 	
 	
 		oh that would be a mess
 	
 	
 		and i know on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years old</TIMEX> uh part of it's built in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
 		matter of fact the thing is i always say it's built off shore you know because it was assembled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> the only thing that was in it was built in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> was the uh differential and it was built in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo New York</ENAMEX>
 		but it's got the darndest combination of uh of metric and
 		most of the body parts seem to be metric and most of the engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parts</ENAMEX> seem to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAE</ENAMEX> so it's
 	
 	
 		well i guess it just gets bad down to you got to you got to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and not mix them up because you're never going to get to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> system if you still still got a got a mix
 	
 	
 		it's just crazy
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course here that that would involve changing road signs all across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles per hour to kilometers per hour</NUMEX> and the whole whole <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine yards</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's kind of hard to do gradually
 	
 	
 		i thought maybe they would convert to uh metric back when they went to the fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five mile an hour</NUMEX> speed limit because what is it fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> or fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh uh</ENAMEX>  or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hundred kilometers</NUMEX> and uh you know a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred a hundred</NUMEX> yeah you'd have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> on the sign looks lot better than fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> but you'd have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going you're right a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred miles an hour</NUMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh hell you'd have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred miles an hour</NUMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so i don't know i'd kind of and the other thing too is you know between here and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>'s what <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hundred miles</NUMEX> but it's it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">almost eight hundred kilometers</NUMEX> you know that'd sure seems like a long way
 	
 	
 		yeah but they'd need they'd seem to be ticking off faster too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i guess that's it
 	
 	
 		every road sign you come to is like well i didn't know i went that far
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well they converted all the road signs to fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles an hour</NUMEX> you know they could of converted it to metric just about as easy
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they you got the problem with all your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are still
 		yeah you still got <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that don't have both
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		at that time anyway the
 		that was still when things were the metric system was still not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		not all that common
 	
 	
 		yeah you know now <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> they have both
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sooner or later they'll start putting the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> on the inside and the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometers</NUMEX> in big numbers so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start thinking that way
 	
 	
 		i was
 		yeah
 		i know the only other place that i was ever at where they really had it mixed was was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> where's a lot of the road signs and everything are in uh
 		in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles per hour</NUMEX>
 		and some are in uh
 		in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometers</NUMEX> and you you got to know where you are because anything that was the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal zone</ENAMEX> is going to be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles per hour</NUMEX> but any
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	