
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well um i'm uh pretty pro gun control over all i um
 		have had a lot of arguments with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about the issue of gun control and uh
 		i must say that there are a couple of arguments against uh strong gun control which i find very compelling although most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who argue gun control with me i find um
 		use sort of canned arguments you know sort of the NRA slogan arguments and um
 		uh so i've been very frustrated when i do debate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about it
 		um i guess on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a scale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i'm probably around a two
 		in terms of fair restricting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and i have to admit most of that is uh strong personal distaste i don't like the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being able to kill me with very very little effort
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are very symbolic of them having that power over me
 	
 	
 		well me being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i hope you're ready for this
 	
 	
 		um i'll i'll give it a try i've got my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> stereotypes in place
 	
 	
 		well i'm not your stereotypical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> i was raised around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> hunting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't have a fear of fire arms in any respect i respect i respect them and what their capabilities are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and on top that spending a good portion of my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX> in the military as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Beret i</ENAMEX> definitely respect the power of weaponry
 	
 	
 		um-hum it's pretty powerful isn't it
 	
 	
 		and here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> as well as just about any big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> anywhere across this country
 		and here here here you go here you this will be border line NRA which i am not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
 	
 	
 		okay okay
 	
 	
 		i mean you i know you've heard this this slogan um if you outlaw <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> then only out laws will have guns
 	
 	
 		um-hum that applies to anything as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 		a gun
 	
 	
 		well you've you've got well any of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> you've got the different rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> and they're having their little turf wars over their little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kingdoms</ENAMEX> and such
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they get out their little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX>'s they get out there little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uzis</ENAMEX> and they're going to fight with them and it doesn't matter what restrictions you put on that type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> or a class <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> firearm
 		if they want it they'll get it
 		i don't care if if they've got to go
 		down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> to get it they'll get it and they'll get across the border
 		now my position
 		although i have absolutely no use for fully automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		since i am a law-abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and i have never had a felony
 		if i wanted to buy one i don't think there should be that big of a restriction on it if they want to run a background check on me fine if they want to put a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> waiting period fine again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they want to have want me to present a letter from my county <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> saying that i've got his permission to have an automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> that's fine too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what i don't gets dangerous in terms of civil liberties because pretty soon it's  it wouldn't
 		you don't want to have someone making a personal choice in that way i would hope i mean because that means someone the personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> doesn't like doesn't get to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and someone the personal sheriff
 	
 	
 		well the only well the criteria the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> would have to follow has is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> uh is he a habitual trouble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> are we picking him up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for a drunk and disorderly and if he had an automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> could he really be raising some problems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know just proving that you're a basically a good citizen
 	
 	
 		but if you're not a very if you're not a basically good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> you just told me that you're going to get one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		if if they want the firepower they can get it
 	
 	
 		so why have
 	
 	
 		it doesn't it doesn't matter how restrictive
 		you're border control points are they'll get it across the border one way or the other
 	
 	
 		so why have any restrictions at all
 	
 	
 		uh
 		okay now go back to that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> scale where one being total gun control <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> being none i said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an eight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we could be
 	
 	
 		i said the restrictions i would like to see on for anybody whether it being for handgun a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> i would like to see them go through either
 		i'd like to see a law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> not NRA
 		but whether it be the your state police or your county police
 		for you to be able to purchase a handgun
 		you got to go through their course and get certified that you know how to properly
 		handle the weapon how to safely handle the weapon how to properly maintain it the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> basics
 	
 	
 		well that makes a lot of since to me i mean i certainly feel that if if we may disagree on when someone should own a fire arm but uh
 		i certainly agree that if someone owns a fire arm they have as much responsibility to know how to do use it safely as someone learns how to drive if not more so
 	
 	
 		well the hands in the hands of the wrong person the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> can be just as deadly as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> as a as a pistol
 	
 	
 		yeah  well i'm a bicycler and that scares me too to tell you the truth  because i've been run off the road and all sorts of things
 		well i'm still i'm still puzzled though what is the argument how does the argument work if uh if the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> anyway
 		what's the point of putting a restriction basically the restrictions are just to penalize the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> because the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are going to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> anyway they're not going to take those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> is it uh is it a way of raising the prices of illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there's
 	
 	
 		if it's not going to cut the supply of illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> it must going to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least</NUMEX> raise the prices is that uh main advantage
 	
 	
 		uh not necessarily a price thing what is
 		happening at least in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and i expect to see it in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> very soon legislation's been introduced as
 		that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the state being myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		has not committed a felony and has completed a certified weapons course i can carry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> on me at all times concealed or unconcealed unconcealed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay you you're  you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		um-hum uh no <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area San Francisco Bay area</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay you've been to the city
 		all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		someone attempts to mug me i would just i would
 		as it stands now if he pulls a blade on me we're equally matched because i can meet him blade for blade
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now if this legislation comes through he pulls i'm out with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we've gone shopping we're fixing to get in the car this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> comes out pulls a blade on me i'm going to pull a gun on him now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when you're looking and when you're looking down the barrel of a hand cannon things change real quick
 	
 	
 		what if you're looking down the barrel of a hand cannon
 	
 	
 		then it's still equally matched
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		having spent having spent time in combat i feel i feel it before they'll get the gun on me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i'm i'm sure i'm sure given given all your training i'm sure that
 	
 	
 		if i'm  we'll draw at the same time
 	
 	
 		you know you'd  if i walk into a bad neighborhood i'm sure i'd want to walk through with you because i'm sure you have good
 		you know u h far far above the average instinct for how to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and how to use them effectively and everything
 		um i'm quite concerned that if you let everyone who hasn't yet used a gun in a felony uh haven't hasn't yet committed a felony
 		if you let them all walk around carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in this sort of wild west scenario you're going to get an awful lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> pretty quickly just given human nature you're going to start getting a lot of gunfire
 		it's it's hard for me to imagine that a a situation of you know take it to it's logical extreme if everyone walking around carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> you're not going to have an increase in gunfire
 	
 	
 		i actually it's not it's more of a police action in itself the fact that everybody's packing a piece is a deterrent is a deterrence to someone saying well i'm going to mug this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> right here but hey he
 		carrying just as much firepower as i can and if there's if you got to go through a certification course to get to where to where you can carry it in public
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> also knows this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s pretty good with it
 		now whether this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is made the moral decision whether he can take another human life or not that's another trip but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in defense of myself defense of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or defense of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i can blow somebody a way in a heart beat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even even more so when it comes to my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and son
 		anybody tries anybody tries to hurt them i won't even blink
 	
 	
 		yeah don't it
 		no i i understand that what if uh what if you think someone's trying to hurt them and you make a mistake
 	
 	
 		this this is where the question of gun control comes in what i consider gun control is being able to hit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target</ENAMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shot
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh that was the topic
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		say a person uh starts uh uh get all of a sudden my combat antenna goes up and say i've got the vibes this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s fixing to do something i go ahead and pull my piece
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i make sure this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> sees it so he's got no doubt that i will use it on him and i will use it right then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if he doesn't back up that point he deserves what he gets
 		because i have sent the clearest signal you mess with me you mess with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i'm going to dust you
 		as it stands now i've got to do that with a blade
 		and the only reason i feel confident comfortable comfortable doing that is because of the training i've had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well as as someone who would would possibly be in the role of an independent bystander i feel more comfortable with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having blades because uh
 		you're not going to get  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> flying around and killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> instantly and uh
 	
 	
 		well if i'm the one doing the shooting i don't miss that's the kind of training i've had i mean it's
 		
 		
 	