
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what do you think about it
 	
 	
 		well uh the roles have definitely changed in the last generation or so um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i i think a lot of it has to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i do too i think it's going to in like in the future i think all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are going to work i mean they may let you off for a day or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to have your baby
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that will be it or either they'll have a computer at home and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where you can just you know just continue right on with your work i mean it it really is coming to that because most women
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now days</TIMEX> cannot afford the time that they could take off unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> pays them they can't even afford to take off you know to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it seems like
 	
 	
 		right right
 		and it and it seems if you're going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh that you are
 		you know  society has decided for you how many you can really have and make it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh because if you have you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> if you go to work you're just working to pay for day care <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> you know um
 	
 	
 		right
 		now i was real lucky because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had a good enough job where when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were you know when i had them and when they were small
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		until they got in junior high school my youngest one got in junior high i didn't have to work i mean i didn't work i i needed to but i didn't
 	
 	
 		oh that is good
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> she just had her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> one in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> and she doesn't have to work either i don't know how they do it
 		i don't i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it with one you know um obviously
 	
 	
 		let me tell you you go without a lot of things that you would you know
 	
 	
 		yeah obviously we don't have any and and i don't i think that's part of the role reversal is it's okay to get married
 		and not have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i think for society for such a long time said well you know you're married now you need to set have have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i don't think it's been until recently that that they had decided that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> was a family
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		right right well it's getting where you can't hardly afford if you're going to give your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> any kind of education and stuff you can't hardly afford to have over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i mean it's hard with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> now we uh my youngest one i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and my youngest one is going to be graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> soon but if i had a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just don't know where it would come from
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i work now i work full time and uh you know it when you put them through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> it just takes just about everything you got
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they get loans and grants and scholarships and stuff like that that helps out but still it cost a lot
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i mean just the you know the cost of living and loans don't pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		stuff
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and all their books and the books are outrageous
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know
 	
 	
 		i mean absolutely outrageous and they're getting worse
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> brought home a book <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>
 		that she was going to have to have for her one of her next classes and it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety six</NUMEX> dollars and this book is a little bitty skinny book i said my goodness what is it lined in gold you know uh but it is it's getting worse and
 	
 	
 		jeez
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if i'd of probably had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i don't see how we could have made it you know without me working
 	
 	
 		but that's that's probably because you know if you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> you you know would say if i'd of had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> i guess it's always not not being able to picture <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more but in essence you probably would have worked out fine
 	
 	
 		right but i think i would have had to work if i'd of had that many i'd of had to work in order for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to you know even though he brings in a real good living and everything in order for me to keep up i would have had to work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think it's getting more and more like when you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> now that's it you know then you go to work and you work because
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> by the  way the inflation's going i think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s always going to have to work and it's just going to be an accepted thing there isn't going to be any of this you know very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will ever stay home
 	
 	
 		yeah and and that's all right with me because i don't want to stay home you know i think i'm just part of that the new stuff that is just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i think i would just go nuts sitting at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long
 	
 	
 		well you know i can't imagine how i did because now i work all the time and um well i work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> and um i can't imagine how i stayed home you know i think to myself what did i do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think it just it revolutionized an where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> thinks that a way you know just like now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 		there's no way that she can imagine herself married at the age that she's at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>  to her everything is you've got to go through college you've got to get a job you know and then when everything's set up then you look for
 		somebody that you want to spend the rest of your life with but i mean it is so far down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when i graduated high school the thing uh-huh and then you got married and then you had a family
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's you did that's what you did
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i mean that's just the way it was you know and uh that's like when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> i know when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s age it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		always the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and  everything had to come first and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> stayed home and took care of them an
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i uh i i like the way it is it's uh being see we're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and so it's not so hard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know you've been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or so years</TIMEX> and you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> well it's okay not nobody does but you come to a place like Belton
 		and there a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> here get married out of high school it's real small town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> we're the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday School</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> who are in their forties and they can't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they can't imagine why we would want to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i'm going well you know
 		there's more to life you know there's life in there that's you know not everybody has to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i'd rather spend the time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> than you know spending time here it's your turn you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah but you know that now even whenever i was coming up and everything and
 		we got married right out of high school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after i got out of high school and uh i didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a half years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that was because i wanted to work and i wasn't ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and everybody thought oh my gosh what is the matter with her you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's what it is i'm not either
 		they're probably going oh i bet she can't get pregnant
 	
 	
 		right i mean they thought that it was terrible you know and then when i'd tell them you know well i'm just not ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yet oh but that you know you better you better just get ready now well you don't just get ready
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i was kind of odd because as a general rule the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that married during my time they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and i just was not ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i wanted to get out and work a little bit and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wanted to travel and stuff like that which we did and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> didn't fit in right then but it's getting more and more like that where there's more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> and really
 		if you don't w <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> then it's not the time to have it i don't care what anybody tells you and i think that more and more the attitude's getting that a way
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		because that's like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> now she says that you know maybe when she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> she might want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh even though i'd like to hav e <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> i can see her point
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> finally uh
 		finally said you know said that that God will take care of us when it's our time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		she finally admitted you know she finally told me it's okay if you don't but it took every nerve in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to say that because she's from a very very old fashioned family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she stayed home and raised her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and she expected all of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to do that too and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and to be the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> and have dinner ready by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and and you know be there at every beck and call and
 		i was raised totally opposite  how we got together i don't know but because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> girls
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and you know she worked too and i guess i just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i saw how life was when she stayed home and it was rough it was hard  you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and it really is i know it  just like now you know there's
 		there's so much more now all my income goes for things like luxuries i mean it really does except for what we give to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to you know put her through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and stuff but the rest of it we just buy things like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boats</ENAMEX> or we go on trips or you know just
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the more or less like entertainment stuff but
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you've you've earned that though
 	
 	
 		yeah i feel like i have you know because well we're to the age now i'm not old but i'm older
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i got to stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> which i really wanted to do but now i could not go back and do it i really couldn't i don't think i could stay home all the time and do nothing and i mean i did stuff but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		to me it  feels like i must have done nothing and i think it's just the new way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are thinking
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so i think it would be neat if if they could incorporate into small and large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> both
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		a built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> cares where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> but not necessarily right there with you
 	
 	
 		well you know more and more of them are i don't know if it is up there where you are but where i am the just like all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> they're getting day care but the reason they had to do this was because so many people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are they
 	
 	
 		you know so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> could not afford like you said if you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or even if you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you would be paying
 		all your salary to pay for those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to go so uh more and more of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> especially over here are getting them and then some of the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> but it's mainly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i don't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> does or not i know i know nobody around here does it we're it's too small around here yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't
 		oh really um
 		
 		
 	