
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what i was doing at at home in fact i work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> here so that's another long story we'll talk about
 		it's funny that i got you though
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to hand me the other phone because i was just i was busy and uh i had just gotten a call and i couldn't answer it and i said well i'll punch it on this one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's a walk around phone but it's not a uh it's not the other kind you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it didn't work
 	
 	
 		now i've got a portable cordless is that what you're using
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no i'm using a regular phone now uh
 	
 	
 		okay i got a i i'm using a cordless
 	
 	
 		if if it's a what kind of phone do they talk it's not a dial but if it's a touchtone it's okay
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		i realized that once i used i should have i was going to go in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and and punch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the touchtone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i realized that i had screwed it up so it was my fault
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that's funny that we had gotten it
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		uh  i guess they want us to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs but dogs</ENAMEX> or cats
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 		that your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat your Rex</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll switch over to birds you know we we don't really have birds as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> but we sure because we have cats
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we always wind up with i haven't yet uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> will catch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and usually we'll catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to kill the bird right away
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we wound up with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> we drop ours off at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> if they're still alive and you keep it alive which is hard to do for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you take it to an agency they'll send it back in the wild somehow and so we we wound up because of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> with with many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> uh again they're not pets exactly but uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at work that i work with uh raises birds uh he has a
 		a macaw macaw macaw
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parakeets</ENAMEX> and something else he one of those macaw parrots
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> next door across from across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from us just lost
 		is it a cockatoo what's that one that's white
 	
 	
 		yeah a cockatoo i think it's a cockatoo
 	
 	
 		it got loose and i've forgotten what how she did it and she had it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> of some sort
 	
 	
 		did it really
 	
 	
 		and what they were doing i don't know but it flew away you know and they called it and everything and rode drove around the neighborhood looking for it but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		those are expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah it's free yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm surprised that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> uh i guess they can find their way back but i wonder exactly where a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tame bird</ENAMEX> would go
 	
 	
 		did she ever get it back
 	
 	
 		no no she never got it back i've heard stories like this before with parrots and all this uh because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> let them out out in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know and fly around
 	
 	
 		oh that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> had one i wouldn't have one flying around my house
 	
 	
 		and
 		no i know uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh i've forgotten she had it outside somehow and somehow they they mixed signals or something and uh it got loose of course again again the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are so much faster than we are in one way or the other
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's a shame
 	
 	
 		uh you know i was telling you the story about fencing i do like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> i i would i've always had dogs my whole life as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		don't you miss them now i mean
 	
 	
 		well yeah i do i
 	
 	
 		because they're they have such personalities
 	
 	
 		yeah i do i think that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> have personality i'm not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> when we were little
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we always seem to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> together which again when you bring them up i do notice that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they get along
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> and when when we started out as a young young married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> we just had an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> so you it's kind of easier to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and then she just never wanted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and then we got here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh she's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> again and uh
 		she she had this thing with the fence and i i guess i have so many
 		interests i don't really quite have the time with with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and all the activities to personally train a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> but i would i would i guess i'll have to wait until both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are out of college before i get another dog again i guess i'm
 	
 	
 		yeah right right
 	
 	
 		i i i certainly saw your point with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greyhound</ENAMEX> that there's there is a limit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh to a pet um
 	
 	
 		yeah you know you think you're you think that's what you want and i really gave it a good try
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i had her spoiled i mean she was spoiled rotten but she was so
 		and i have a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i and
 		to walk in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i'd have especially uh especially on a rainy day i'd have to take a bucket of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> out there and wash <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> of her feet
 		this is a fifty pound dog i'm going to pick up a leg at a time and wash and set it down on something clean while i got the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> you know and and then i'd let her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house well</ENAMEX> still even putting her feet in the bucket of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and wash them real good
 		she still would come in so fast and so heavy that she'd dig her paws deep down into my carpet you know and just take out running to and she would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh she was ruining my carpet and i thought gosh i i love my new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> more than i love her i think you know i just really have a big investment and i don't i just
 		it was just more work than it was really really i wasn't enjoying her that's what it was maybe if i'd a had a run for a dog run but i think that's cruel to put a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in a run
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah no i think so too uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> just she keeps convincing me because my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are dead now but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> always had dogs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when we would visit them she said you can smell dog over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i said well you're really right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so i never she always had a good argument why not to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and we haven't since we've been married
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but now see i have always felt that i could always smell <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> to me always i i i used to have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that i couldn't stand to go in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i could smell their their litter box i thought oh my God i couldn't stand it and i don't know how they stood it i guess they didn't smell it
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah yeah
 		uh no yeah i think you're right uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are surprisingly are allergic to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> too we do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on and off that will
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 	
 	
 		i guess it's the hair the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> the short fur on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> is uh one of the allergic reaction things like uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cedar trees</ENAMEX> and all of the other stuff i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> has a real fine not the that the real short hair dandruff or whatever they have that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do get allergic to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in their eyes you know they just walk in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> even though we lock up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and they're crying
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and so some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> unfortunately of course i wouldn't have an animal if i was allergic to it either
 	
 	
 		well i wouldn't either
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time said she was allergic to them uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was going to say a story
 	
 	
 		well i know is there're supposed to be is it Chihuahuas they're supposed to be good for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> they say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuahua</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are supposed to be good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> i always heard
 	
 	
 		well i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>'s good for you just because uh it gets you out and everything i uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and don't i think they're using you know they're using <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and make and some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> because it's supposed to make people
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		brings your blood pressure down you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are always so happy to see you come home you know they always are just wagging i don't care how grumpy you are or what <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are glad to see you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are kind of independent like  get in they're they let you live with them you know  so independent
 	
 	
 		right
 		i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> uh uh that have horses you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> were a little younger you know i thought well maybe that's a good maybe i'll get them uh you know this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i'll get them a horse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we went over and we rode their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and everything but and and just listened to the stories and the money
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> was sick all the time
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you i don't know if you if you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> but they get all kinds of eating disorders if they don't if they don't eat the right <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> or if you
 	
 	
 		oh
 		see i was thinking about buying a horse maybe i don't want
 	
 	
 		if you give him an orange or something you nearly kill it i mean it the the stories he would tell it must have cost him a couple <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		just to feed
 	
 	
 		of course he had several <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX> and different things i thought my God and i just saw something interesting Consumer Reports they talked they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and they compared
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know whether you should have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> and and the pricing and it had a comment around a horse something to the effect of
 		you don't even want to know what it cost to keep a horse you know  and i
 	
 	
 		cost  yeah
 		i think i'll just go rent a horse if i want to ride one
 	
 	
 		right i think the best thing in the world is to rent them i think that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i do too
 	
 	
 		that that and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> are probably the same way i'd love to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> too but i think uh i'm not too sure i i would get that much use out of it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i mean well i do enjoy my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> uh she's such a
 		oh she's my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and when when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> she uh got paralyzed from her waist down and uh waist
 	
 	
 		my goodness from what
 	
 	
 		and i thought it was uh
 		uh we almost had to put her to sleep and i just cried for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> but i think what i i i ironically what happened was she got had fleas
 		and i think it was the stuff i was having putting on her that that paralyzed her but
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fleas</ENAMEX> i think's what brought her back is she had to scratch so bad that she started using her paralyzed the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was just amazed at a that she came back because
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he really was going to was going to do surgery for fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> or put her to sleep and i was going to have to opt to have to put her to sleep even as much much as i loved her i wasn't going to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifteen hundred dollars</NUMEX> on an experiment
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah plus i'm not too sure yeah i think they are experiments too and they don't know that much uh
 	
 	
 		no but it was just uh that spot that they put on the back of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> uh they used to use it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> and uh so i started using it on her and i'd take to her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> once a month and get that spot put on her
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> spent a lot of go ahead
 	
 	
 		and she wouldn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fleas</ENAMEX> never had any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fleas</ENAMEX> hadn't never any then all of a sudden uh i took her
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> and i put i put her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> for while i came home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for a while and i took and when i picked her up she had fleas again
 		and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> came down and visited me me from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and and while she was there the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> got paralyzed
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and so i took her back up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and
 		anyway he he said it wasn't that but
 		another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> told me that there had been uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the pet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> had been getting permanently paralyzed from petting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> that had that spot on them
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		so i thought well and so i can't find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> that'll do that for me anymore put the spot on her anymore and i don't want it anymore anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i do fight fleas oh gosh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they're they're a problem the the different rainy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> here i don't how long you been here in in the area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh i moved back in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh course you were here before
 	
 	
 		yeah i lived here before i'd worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventeen years</TIMEX> and then i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marietta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and let let me talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fleas</ENAMEX> we have nothing compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fleas</ENAMEX> down they have down there
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and they have them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round at least they die out kind of in the wintertime here in the yard down there they don't they're are just and they are big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> i mean big
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and they are just almost impossible to get rid of it costs a fortune if you have a pet you're going to have fleas down there
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just had my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> treated and treated and treated and treated and did i did all the things you're supposed to and i couldn't get rid of
 		
 		
 	