
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi hi uh can you hear me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hi my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanette Miller</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley California</ENAMEX> who am i talking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well hello <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX> how are you
 	
 	
 		good how are you doing
 	
 	
 		i'm doing fine so you want to talk football eh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what they gave us
 	
 	
 		well i guess you better push one
 	
 	
 		yeah okay
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so tell me do you like football
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what
 		yeah
 		yeah i love <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football football</ENAMEX> professional
 	
 	
 		how could you be from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and not like football right
 	
 	
 		right well i'm not really from originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but uh professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is my favorite thing to watch really
 	
 	
 		yeah so well then in in that case you're probably a devout <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niners</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah exactly i do like uh what's his name
 	
 	
 		
 
 		like what's his name
 	
 	
 		what's who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Montana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i do like him
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well i don't know if you know this but do you know that that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Craig</ENAMEX> and uh
 		oh what is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebacker</ENAMEX>'s name
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Lotte</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're not coming back
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah they've signed with another team
 	
 	
 		so they're not going to be as good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		well i don't know those are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> heavy duty players
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Craig</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Lotte</ENAMEX> i can't imagine you know so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just amazing you know you i i i i hope that living there in uh in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you you of course don't let anyone know that you like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Niners</ENAMEX> do you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		not at all not at all i'm i'm really a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a bandwagon fan i think i like whoever is good that year
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah well that's all right too
 	
 	
 		yeah i you know
 		yeah so i so i liked the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niners</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 		
 
 		but uh i like watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colts</ENAMEX> play because i'm from originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh oh wait a minute wait a minute wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX> if  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Colts the Colts the Colts</ENAMEX> i still have trouble adjusting to that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> Colts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the Colts
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes i guess i guess that sort of dates me but uh uh i i still think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colts</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff George</ENAMEX> so it's fun to watch him play being a rookie and all last year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah for sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i imagine speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have the what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> what what whatever happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they did the wrong thing by uh releasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i yeah i thought they were going to lynch those people
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i i liked  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> you know i have no respect for the for the new coaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> since they ousted him
 	
 	
 		well you know how do you get rid of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> like that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and and</ENAMEX> and justify it i mean
 	
 	
 		oh not i know not at all
 	
 	
 		that really was kind of sad i got sort of a raw deal on that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		So uh
 	
 	
 		you you you said something you know
 		uh in in college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have some some have you got  anything promising <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> as far as college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> like like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> A and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 	
 	
 		or you keech up keep up with collegiate
 	
 	
 		well i have to admit i don't keep up with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i keep up with uh i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		and
 		and so i keep up with what's going on up there they're going to have a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they it looks looks to be promising for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> so we're looking forward to seeing their program turn around
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>'s been kind of out of it for a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i didn't know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue i</ENAMEX> didn't even know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> still had a football
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  you don't hear about them much in fact you don't even hear about their <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> much any more but you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's how it how it goes i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah well it will be interesting to see well especially you know um uh here here in the in the bay area you know this this used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> also of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">of the of</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here still feel that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> are are are are you know in are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> but uh
 		i it's it's going to be real interesting to see what happens because uh there there're a lot of changes are happening here in the bay area as far as that they're talking about maybe getting a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> and with those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> leaving i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feagin</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Lotte</ENAMEX> i i i can't imagine a more devastating blow to a team you know the the uh the the top running back and the top defensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> uh leaving is
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 	
 	
 		what are they going to do about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Bo</ENAMEX> well i don't know what they're going to do about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bo Bo</ENAMEX> is is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is pretty much out of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo</ENAMEX> is you're talking about speaking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo Jackson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		uh uh uh it just doesn't sound like that with what's wrong with him that you know we're going to find out what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo</ENAMEX>'s made out of
 	
 	
 		oh yeah some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they're predicting that he'll make a big comeback
 	
 	
 		well uh i'm sure he wants to but i would be i'd frankly
 		extremely surprised
 	
 	
 		yeah i would be too
 	
 	
 		i really would that kind of you know that that kind of injury is not not something that
 		well i i hope he does you know more power to him i think that'd be just absolutely wonderful so do you i i guess uh uh i i've talked with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> from from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh on this thing and so it's it's it's  i guess all you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> just kind of got into this thing huh but
 	
 	
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI uh</ENAMEX> somehow got us on it
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's great i mean it's kind of fun i've met some great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> i really have and had some great conversations
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i bet they love to talk about uh pro football don't they
 	
 	
 		oh yeah indeed definitely
 	
 	
 		
 
 		or any football
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i i i must admit i as growing up <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> was really a great part of my life i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX> and and uh played uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> was just you know
 	
 	
 		you played <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i played football played played in college a little bit but certainly didn't go in the go into pro never never
 	
 	
 		where where'd you go to college
 	
 	
 		i i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well great what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> was that then
 	
 	
 		well it was uh long ago it was it
 	
 	
 		long ago huh
 	
 	
 		uh yes i got out of there undergraduate in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seventy three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		should have left in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy two</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i was having too much fun
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		those were those were <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and you just didn't want to get out too early
 	
 	
 		oh yeah definitely i understand that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you hung in there as long as you could
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		anyway well listen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX> it's been a pleasure talking
 	
 	
 		yeah you too and i hope the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Niners</ENAMEX> do well this year
 	
 	
 		thank you and i hope <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> does too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		thanks
 	
 	
 		you hang in there
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		see you later
 	
 	
 		you okay okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	