
 
     		
 	
 		huh okay
 	
 	
 		i don't know how much i know about this subject
 	
 	
 		well i don't know if i know anything or not but i've i've got some opinions on it see those type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that have the most opinions ones at don't know anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay go ahead
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well uh i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and i now have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and i don't know that it might do them a little bit of good to see the world from a different perspective
 		uh i think this me generation has gone far too far and the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are overly impressed
 		and i think it wouldn't hurt them to step back from themselves just slightly and see things from a more far more disadvantaged viewpoint
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i personally know nothing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		um me either i
 		i went to college and then started working and then got married and
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but they have i read somewhere
 		and i'm i'm out on a limb here some type of college uh
 		volunteer work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that they are straight out of college and they do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> of volunteer work teaching in the uh
 		lower income brackets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> have you ever heard about that one
 	
 	
 		no i haven't i know that uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> i have a twin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and when she graduated she went to teach in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> down in south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i know that like if you have college notes if you teach in
 		a lower income bracket where they don't pay as much and they cancel part of your you know your college note or whatever
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		if it's like you know really a you know a lower paying job you know where in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> you don't obviously you don't need <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as much as far as</NUMEX> to you know to live
 	
 	
 		and this is money that she's borrowed to for her college education
 	
 	
 		yeah she only taught there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> but i
 	
 	
 		but she got credits for it
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's very interesting
 	
 	
 		and um i think it would be i know that also one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> who uh he is in like the therapy type thing and and he was um
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> paid part of his college income but then he was required to go back and work for a certain number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> at uh
 		uh i mean it's a nursing home or something like that so you know if if i think that that's a good way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to you know maybe get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come back to these small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> to work by helping
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that normally might not be able to go to college and get the type of degree they want
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that is an excellent program i really do i like that and it's it's beneficial to the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> too because they really really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have have a disadvantage that we don't understand because we're in the Metroplex
 	
 	
 		as far as getting yeah getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and all that kind of stuff yeah
 	
 	
 		right you know if if we had some really major health problem that required a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> we could find one it wouldn't be convenient
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but we could find one we wouldn't have to drive and spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> someplace or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i i can see the advantage to that one
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> itself is really uh uh dying out isn't it
 	
 	
 		i really don't know that much about it you know i i i think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> you know more like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and that kind of stuff when but yeah and don't they go into other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		it's still in existence
 		i want to believe they go into other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and teach them how to do things like farm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh dig their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> set up their schools
 	
 	
 		things that make them yeah make them more self-supporting yeah
 	
 	
 		yes they it's not
 		a program to teach them to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> money it's a program to teach them to be more self-reliant
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and yes you're right i think it's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> program i think it was one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s hot points that he that was his big deal
 	
 	
 		but it definitely would give
 		a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now that have everything given to them that they want to see
 		what it's like if you don't have all the money and can't have what you want when you want it
 	
 	
 		right right um
 		i think i i i i've
 		singled out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and but actually they're they're pretty good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		along those lines as compared to what i have seen from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> mine aren't really that bad but at the same time i think it would do them a world of good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but there's a
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know that you could require everyone to to do that for yeah to do it for a whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year or two years</TIMEX> or something like that i don't know that that would work if if somebody's
 	
 	
 		mandatory just like like the draft no
 		every time you have
 	
 	
 		was didn't really want to be there and
 		didn't have yeah i mean there'd be loopholes just like there is in anything else
 	
 	
 		they could buy their way out
 		right you know they they'd figure a way around that one in a heartbeat but
 		i'm wondering if there's another issue here and maybe this is why this has died out
 		can you go into and this wasn't the question but it's it may be the more of the issue versus should young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 		can they go in there and can anyone
 		go into
 		well out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is a little bit of extreme at this time but say i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangladesh</ENAMEX> would have been a good example
 		or some some really desperate situation and teach them to farm and teach them and doesn't do any good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know that it does
 		i i i don't know that um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you step back from the current issue and look at it
 		more intellectually
 		there are forever over as long as we know there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are dropping out
 		you know we're losing certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that are obsolete point and fact just just like endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of animals so there are quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> of people
 		that are endangered or obsolete
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm just wondering if you're fighting a natural process there of being winnowed out there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> word for it that's elegant but i never can remember what it was uh
 		but but they're they're being winnowed because they're where they are they're not adapted to their environment
 		essentially
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and
 		uh one of the quick examples is the aborigines
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh when we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
 		uh sad little things
 		uh i felt sorry for them
 		because their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> isn't there anymore and their belief system and all all their structured of theirs all the structures of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society</ENAMEX> are gone
 		essentially
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they're just kind of
 		more like a side show than anything else and that's sad but i don't think there's any way you could go uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> could go in and rescue those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i that don't think you could have done it fifty or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years ago</TIMEX> either
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i i'm wondering if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> is really an effective tool
 	
 	
 		well
 		and here with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> we're talking about all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that aren't even in our own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> when there's enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here that i think probably need help and could be helped
 	
 	
 		good point we've got enough without leave without a passport there's plenty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes i think we ought to worry about our own species
 	
 	
 		and maybe rather than just require somebody to join like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> for a year maybe like um during college you know maybe have some kind of course where they'd be required to do some kind of community service type work and
 		help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that area or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wonder now in and i've been out of school too long to answer this but i wonder if there aren't some sociology courses
 	
 	
 		there probably are you know for but i'm sure that's probably like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do that are social are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are going to go into social work and stuff but i think that it wouldn't really be
 		half bad for everybody not to do something you know and realize that it's everybody's responsibility
 		to um help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know and not i'm not saying just give them money but i mean because they have to be taught to be yeah  i mean i know that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> was talking about you know when you give these people
 	
 	
 		that's the last thing you want to do
 	
 	
 		money or
 		what was it they were bringing up points asking as far as whether they need to give um
 		more money to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean and that's not really the answer i mean because if they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX> they'll just go out and spend it on you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> or something like that but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's exactly it
 		they're not going to take that money you give them and go try to figure out a way to dry out with it now come on let's be realistic that's just not realistic
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		or you know to find a job where they can learn how to support themselves i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i guess we're getting kind of off the subject here but yeah i mean it's
 	
 	
 		no we're not i don't think i think that's more realistic than going making them go in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		true yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that's a lot more realistic
 		uh
 		i i think that we should be spending more time and and again i don't think the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> is is as successful now simply because
 		it's not
 		it doesn't fit the circumstance anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh we've got plenty
 		in fact we've got far too many
 		you're in uh what  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flower Mound</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower Mound</ENAMEX> yeah
 		so we're a little
 		farther you know farther removed from like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and some of the areas where they probably have more of the homeless and that type of thing
 	
 	
 		i was that's exactly what i was going to ask you have you ever have have you been downtown recently
 		
 		
 	