
 
     		
 	
 		okay um what type of music do you like
 	
 	
 		well pretty much uh the thing i'm into mostly is new age uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yanni</ENAMEX> um oh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Barden</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gosh there's just so many of them i can't even can't even name them all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enya i</ENAMEX> just got a catalog just now as a matter of fact uh actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> got it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Slipper Catalog</ENAMEX> and it's it has music from a lot of women
 		and it's got uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enya</ENAMEX> in it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Nessin</ENAMEX> have you ever heard of her
 	
 	
 		no i have not what what is the the message what is the underlying theme of new if heard of new age music but i don't i wouldn't know how to identify it
 	
 	
 		well actually most of the music that i listen to there's no theme it's instrumental
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i tend to like instrumental better because there isn't that underlying theme there's no message to be get gotten there um it's just enjoying the melody
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		that's what i like about music
 	
 	
 		okay what separates that from something such as jazz music or you know
 	
 	
 		well um i guess you could tend to categorize some of the stuff like i like in into jazz uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Luc Ponty</ENAMEX>
 		is he's kinds of a he's he's jazz but he's kind of more of a contemporary type jazz he's got the um the electric violin
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> just said  before i switched to this other phone he said so you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie Dregs</ENAMEX> and that's is another one of my favorite groups
 		but it's they're kind of in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> by themselves really
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		they're more they're more like progressive
 	
 	
 		okay they're progressive in that it's just the same up beat tempo type or instruments they use
 	
 	
 		um no progressive music is more like they have real complex um uh rhythms and key uh key changes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		it's it's a more complex it's it's not your your typical top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX> type that has um it'll it'll be in a particular key or whatever and it it doesn't change
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um progressive has a lot of different um
 		i don't know it's it's a lot more complex
 	
 	
 		okay what does this type of music have to do like when i go to the book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and i see new age books does this have anything to do with that
 	
 	
 		no no that's really
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> don't like to be called new age because it's kind of a a label that it it kind of kind of connotates the out of body experience like the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Shirley MacLaine</ENAMEX> type thing and that's not it at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it's it's just
 		a different type of music and i guess
 		um i guess you would really call it contemporary jazz
 	
 	
 		okay
 		that's that's good and is this becoming more widely available
 	
 	
 		i think so um do you ever listen to one oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		um
 		um they play some of the stuff that i like although they've gotten them they've gotten to a lot more into the saxophone stuff and i don't really care a whole lot for saxophone like um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny G</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's okay but um i like more of a variety and it seems like they are playing all of this saxophone type music that enough is enough you can only handle so much of it
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		so you could label <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny G</ENAMEX> as a new age
 	
 	
 		well yeah he's kind of a new age
 	
 	
 		okay i was wondering
 	
 	
 		kind of a jazz new age
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	

 		it kind of kind of depends on how you look at it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i i've listened to one of his disks probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month ago</TIMEX> and and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what did you think of it
 	
 	
 		i thought it was talented i thought you know he's a
 		you know has definitely a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and i i wouldn't buy it for myself but i was glad to listen to it you know i'd
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i saw him in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> and he is puts on a really good show
 	
 	
 		seems like he does
 	
 	
 		he really is incredibly talented
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's cool
 	
 	
 		what what what kind of music do you like to listen to mostly
 	
 	
 		um
 		i'm very um open i listen to a little bit of anything i've got
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i listened to rock and roll a lot when i was growing up so a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that have been well established for a long time such as you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Petty</ENAMEX> or you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know most of their stuff and i continue to purchase their latest releases as long as you know they don't sell out and still stick within their you know their certain style
 	
 	
 		yeah i i like top <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Petty</ENAMEX> until he got to be kind of top fortyish
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> albums were really good they're real real you know nitty gritty down to the i mean real roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> and roll and i really liked that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when he got to doing his um um didn't he do a he did an album with who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Stevie Nicks</ENAMEX> i think
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they sang a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her albums
 	
 	
 		and that was okay but i liked his early stuff a lot better
 	
 	
 		yeah i was really i'm really impressed with his latest
 		the what was the name of the latest album i have it it's um
 		i like it you know it's you've got some top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX> hits and i'm sure you know he's geared to that but there are some songs that are pretty cool on that and you know with the videos and stuff now coming out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he may be softening up little bit but you know i still like his voice and you know he's not you know it's not that bad um i also like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like um
 		i like um i like orchestra i like symphonies classical music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because
 	
 	
 		i like some classical except that i have a really hard time going to buy it because
 		some of it is just really awful
 		and some of it is really good and i don't know the good from the bad
 	
 	
 		right you don't know until you listen to it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		yeah unless you have someone that can loan it to you or you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and listen to it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's kind of hard just to
 	
 	
 		yeah the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one one</NUMEX> classical piece that i really do like is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivaldi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i really like that and i like i like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		and that's really
 		all that i've really sampled that i
 		why i should say i i have listened to some others that i like that i can't remember their names offhand my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> makes all these tapes of all different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and i never know what i'm listening to
 		i just know that i like it
 	
 	
 		so
 		so if you walk into your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> then you stick something in you're you're not sure what what would you stick in if you come home and just could you turn on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> or stick in an album or disc
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'd i'd probably put a CD on and i would i would probably probably most likely go to something new age i would probably  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Nessin</ENAMEX> or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um or Yanni</ENAMEX> or somebody like that um once in a while i'll put on some classical
 		um
 		
 
 		sometimes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has a whole variety of music so i really have pretty much anything to choose from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well
 	
 	
 		um i do like a lot of the older stuff too but we don't really have a lot of the older stuff on CD
 		um
 		and that's pretty much all i listen to
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		i i hardly ever listen to the radio anymore
 	
 	
 		did you say one oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		has the new age <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> now are where do you live
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i live in Carrolton
 	
 	
 		okay we live i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> so i'm not sure if i'll i can receive that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> or not but i will try and i'll you know listen for a while
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and see what it sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie</ENAMEX> was it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well uh thank you very much for talking and uh maybe we'll get hooked up again sometime
 	
 	
 		okay great thank you
 	
 	
 		all right talk to you later
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	