
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think you got it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		uh my first thoughts on capital punishment is i the first thing i want to say is is no
 		just simply because we as human beings don't have the right to take another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>'s life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		we are punishing someone for taking someone's life
 		or in some cases we are punishing someone someone a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for taking someone's life and so in effect we're committing that same crime
 	
 	
 		well it sounds like you have really strong views on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i can see that point but i also have this you know i
 		i question i guess i can look at it both ways and just to play devil's advocate
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it never seems right to me that uh we take in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		low income or even middle income that are struggling to provide for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our taxes are paying to feed and shelter those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and it just
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		that that i find very difficult to swallow sometimes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		one thing i don't understand is the the whole concept of death row
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are supposedly i guess waiting to die
 		right okay and there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> upon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on death row and i'm not saying that
 	
 	
 		i agree with you there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i guess i am kind of saying what what are we doing i mean i guess that's the same thing you were saying
 		what what are we doing with these people
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		they're they're there we should either take some kind of action
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or
 		take enough or or go a different route but they're just
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		and then when you think of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> that get burned in court costs
 	
 	
 		oh exactly
 	
 	
 		you know we could be paying feeding poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and helping you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		helping the environment i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> is such a waste of
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> it doesn't do anyone any good yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be punished and i do agree with your statement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that to take a human life is wrong
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um but you know locking someone up and not getting
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		you know any benefit from that for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or for society to me is wrong too
 	
 	
 		and i guess i see both sides in that at the at the same time that i'm saying that you know we're committing the same crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i also agree that i mean if there's somebody out there that's crazy and cruel enough
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to kill somebody or in some cases kill several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time uh there was a case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> well i'm sure they haven't gone to court yet but
 	
 	
 		oh exactly well
 	
 	
 		uh apparently two teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> held up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX> they put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a freezer and shot them all
 		now to me that is inhumane
 		and
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be out in the world like that i don't i don't want them in my world
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		you understand what i'm saying i i'm
 		i mean i'm not for killing anyone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't want these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around at the same time
 	
 	
 		we want a safe environment for ourselves and we want to remove them
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		but but i think that the whole crux of the problem is no one has come up with a solution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		that is acceptable that does you know
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		basically you know i i think you know that the whole idea of
 		uh a a death penalty was invented for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons it removes removes them from society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> it's it's kind of uh it's the punishment it's the ultimate punishment
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because you know they've harmed someone and and
 		you know you want to
 		appease the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have suffered
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it
 		it really doesn't take their pain away
 	
 	
 		um-hum and at and at the same time like you said it drains society
 	
 	
 		um-hum but it's a
 	
 	
 		we i think we should be
 		we the same money that we're using to build more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and make more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison space</ENAMEX> and put keep these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in prison
 		that same money or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of that money could be used towards
 		uh rehabilitation programs of some sort something to get to to put these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> back in society but prepare them first
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		exactly but that the pob the problem is so incredibly complex i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who works on the pardon and patr parole paroles and she interviews
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> all the time that are coming up for parole and she says it is just really frightening
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how easy it is to you know have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> release <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because they're overcrowded
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have not
 		benefited from the stay there she says
 		just their emotional state and their way of thinking is so incredibly wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's not anything she can do to keep them in you know if they meet certain guidelines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and those guidelines keep getting lessened and lessened because they have to do it to make the system work
 	
 	
 		um-hum and you you want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of prison you want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get jobs and and live happy lives
 	
 	
 		so it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they can't just walk out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and do that they can't just walk out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and say okay i'm going to go a different route
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		there has to be some sort of
 		buffer in there some sort of program or and i know this costs money but it couldn't cost anymore money than we're already spending
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know i know i i would like to see
 		the money that's been budgeted budgeted for new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>
 		being put into the research of of an alternate solutions to the problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how are we going to fix that Tanya
 		how are we going to make that happen
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		really how what can we do
 	
 	
 		what power do we have
 	
 	
 		oh goodness i mean you know everyone's trying to make it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know in their own little world you know i'm trying to make it with my job and make you know myself okay and make my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and it's so hard to you know try and
 		be one of the movers and shakers i guess you would call them
 	
 	
 		hum oh i know i know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it it it sounds like you are uh you know interested in what's going on around you and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know when you have a a voice you do
 		contribute and i guess that's you know what what we're meant to do and maybe an opportunity will come by that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		we will have a chance to make a real change
 	
 	
 		and i i'm a broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and so i feel like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> i probably will
 		write a book or or something you know and some of these views will be able to come out i work at channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh where where do you work
 		oh you do
 	
 	
 		here i'm a i'm a news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and so i  i guess i'm i'm pretty emotional about crime things like that now
 		i've only been in it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but i get to see pretty much uh close up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know a lot of things that happen that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't see
 		uh i got to see get to see a lot of crimes and i get to see you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		uh pain and things and so when we talk about
 	
 	
 		right most of us are so sheltered you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the news that bring it to us and make us see what's out there
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that you're you're really performing a a benefit to society in doing that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		a service
 		yeah
 		but still you know we can't shut we can't
 		i don't i
 		i guess i would like to probably editorialize more
 		we have to just report what's happening we can't say well this is what i think about you know the situation sometimes
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you really want to say that you really want to say what you think or what you think should be done or how you think this court case should have gone or you know
 		that's a
 	
 	
 		i i'm just i'm just agreeing with you when i think of it how difficult it must be to
 		just to give the facts because usually on an issue that you really care about
 		uh you want you want to you know persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to your viewpoint
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you're right that has got to be a challenge sometimes
 	
 	
 		especially when you are dealing with a a subject like
 		uh capital punishment or something or abortion
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or something where there's an an no or yes side and you have your side and you have to report both sides
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but you really don't want to because you have your side
 	
 	
 		and you have to walk right down the middle with it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so sometimes that's hard but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's that sounds interesting and i'll read your book some day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay good
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right well it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		i enjoyed it thanks for calling bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	