
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well i personally don't have any problem with uh drug testing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> or potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> do you
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i mean basically
 	
 	
 		basically no um
 		um
 	
 	
 		okay i don't i really can't disagree with it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i uh uh the policy that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has i think is uh uh very fair
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i
 		they first had a policy where they uh would test new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and then since i've been with them the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> uh there's been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year year</TIMEX> and a half um they're doing random testing of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think that's really the only fair way to do it
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i really think it ought to be some you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junkins</ENAMEX> all the way down
 	
 	
 		and it is it and from from what i understand it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Junkins</ENAMEX> all the way down
 	
 	
 		right as a matter of fact i want to think they took the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> first isn't that a fact
 		i've been retired from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> but the program you know was still fairly new i guess it had been going on maybe almost a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		before i retired so i was not uh ever called upon to do a drug test i certainly wouldn't object to it and i think random is probably you know the only really fair way to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah um i like it because um you know i i i grew up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> i mean i graduated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty eight</TIMEX> and
 		and uh you know i i saw you know i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who were you know druggies and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who weren't and and uh you know it's i think it's a real problem
 	
 	
 		oh i absolutely
 	
 	
 		and i think it and i think it's causing us a lot of trouble and and a lot of problems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i'm hoping that uh a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will will follow the same path
 	
 	
 		i don't think they'll have much choice do you
 	
 	
 		um probably not
 	
 	
 		especially if they have anything do with you know government contracts or anything as matter of fact i want to believe that the uh
 		defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> more or less mandated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know who work on defense contracts you know some do some sort of you know drug testing i think that's really what maybe prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> to do it i was in the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Electronic Division</ENAMEX> when i retired i know it was a you know it was a real hot hot item there i think i want to think maybe they you know really got some nudging from you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D O D</ENAMEX> to do this sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to be in DSEG myself
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um A P</ENAMEX> D as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		yeah so you knew you know the atmosphere then
 	
 	
 		yep
 		very aware of it but i i'd i'd i really like the idea uh in fact i would like to see uh a lot more uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh adopt it uh like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing
 		i mean i'd like i'd like to know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s being taught by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who's not on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		or uh who might be at a point where they're trying to sell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> drugs
 	
 	
 		that's right absolutely yeah i don't i just can't disagree with you with you know the basic premise
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's to much as far as i know it's you know seems to be a fairly accurate program as far as uh you know the testing goes
 	
 	
 		and i like the idea that they have a uh system where they allow you to uh be retested if for some reason there may have been a problem or something did show up
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 		and offer you you know help if you need help
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too
 	
 	
 		yeah rather than just uh
 	
 	
 		put you out on the street
 	
 	
 		put you out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and let you fend for yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		that's not going to help anybody get over the problem i believe it is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a medical problem
 	
 	
 		no absolute
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		um of course i also think smoking is the most addictive thing in the world too
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely not to mention alcohol
 	
 	
 		yeah so i mean there's a lot of things out there and
 		things that uh
 		i'm just glad that they uh decided not to uh tax drugs otherwise they'd be legal and they'd be getting tax money off it the same way they are the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and tobacco
 	
 	
 		that's right  that's right  oh gosh well it's it's a real problem i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that work in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that are just now adopting the policy and and stuff and i uh uh i moved to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> that um had never had uh random drug sampling before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they were outside of the military sector it was uh an industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> purchased and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here a lot of them are real opposed to it
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh they were really opposed to it and you know there was a few of them that obviously were doing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and that's why they were opposed to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh it resulted in in a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leaving
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know because they just flat out weren't going to put up with the policy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they had a lifestyle and they weren't going to change it
 	
 	
 		yep right yeah i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
 	
 	
 		and it's
 	
 	
 		when it first began or at least began was in the talking stage you know everybody knew it was coming it just a matter of time everybody was screaming you know invasion of privacy and all this stuff
 		but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think after they thought about it for awhile and you know weighed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons decided you know it's really not a bad idea unless you're doing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> of course
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean uh you should have no objection to it it's like uh going down to get your license and checking your eyes i mean you know why do i need my eyes checked well we want to make sure you can see
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right yep yep
 	
 	
 		why are we doing this well so you don't kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the road
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right or yourself or
 	
 	
 		uh it's a basic  i mean it's the basic premise with you know drug testing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		especially some of the jobs um
 		luckily i've always been in the engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> and it's very little that anyone could do in the engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> as far as uh you know hurting someone i mean it's hard to imagine somebody misusing a computer and somebody dying from it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh in the manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> and over in semiconductor and down in some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah assembly people
 	
 	
 		yeah i darn if i'd want somebody down there that i'm working with side by side you know that could kill me
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		by doing something incorrectly because they were
 		not exactly all there because they were on drugs
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		so there's a there's a lot of sectors where i think that would would help out and i think in the long run we all benefit
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh absolutely yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean if you have uh
 		you know if you're not working with someone on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> well then you're going to have less accidents and you have less accidents and you spend less money on medical and you spend less money on medical then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s more profitable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah sure
 	
 	
 		well then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s more profitable then maybe they can pay you more if they can pay you more you can buy more and then and it and it goes around you know to everywhere
 	
 	
 		sure
 		trickles trickles up and down
 	
 	
 		yep all over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah affects a lot of people
 	
 	
 		it certainly does and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i just hope that uh more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> uh get on the ball and and start it up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think they probably will you know if they i'm sure it's a very expensive program to administer
 		i'm not sure every small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could do it
 	
 	
 		well a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are are coming down in price and i think that the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are starting to give uh benefits
 		you know reduction reduction in in medical costs if you know they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah it's got to help them too
 	
 	
 		yeah so i think everybody will will benefit from the program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i do too that's right
 	
 	
 		and i think if if a lot more insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> get on the bandwagon and say well if you impose uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		mandatory drug testing we'll reduce your insurance costs by you know twenty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">per cent</NUMEX> and of course you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s not going to reduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>'s cost of insurance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cent</NUMEX> they're going to reduce their own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no no but it it'll save in some areas yeah right
 	
 	
 		yeah and that'll cover it and maybe some insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> might start offering it as a uh
 		as part of the package
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that certainly could happen that's a very very very very competitive business
 	
 	
 		yeah so it i i think
 		i think all around it it's going to help out a lot course
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too
 		i just really can't disagree with you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay well it's nice to talk to you
 	
 	
 		it was great talking with you
 	
 	
 		and you take care
 	
 	
 		you do the same
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	