
 
     		
 	
 		do you have a recipe that you would like to share
 		
 
 	
 	
 		why don't you start <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and i'll think about it
 	
 	
 		okay uh  we i find that the nicest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for dinner uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh they set at my dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> table easily
 		and it just seems like you can decorate a table and and you can serve easily with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh particularly if you're wanting to do the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> to nuts thing which uh with my
 		dishes i have a really pretty soup tureen so i like to start out with you know some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> that nobody's had lately like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauerkraut soup</ENAMEX> or minestrone depending upon what the menu theme is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that i like to do um
 		of course i always want to make it easy on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of the country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> gave me a really good recipe for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham loaf</ENAMEX> that it's something you can make up ahead and then stick in the oven you know
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		after after your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> are here and you've started cocktails really
 		uh usually course you have to have some kind of entertainment too and and we do play bridge my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> plays when i make him  and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well usually our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are the bridge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are there because it's an excuse to get together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do find that in in order to have your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> last beyond
 		the dinner table there have there does have to be something to go on to or you just kind of sit around and everybody goes to sleep and gets bored you know there's got to be a a silly game or a
 		something fun to do afterwards
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		i would say <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our</TIMEX> dinners are probably more casual than that with um having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff it may be inviting you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> over for dinner or something like that but not really we haven't really tried a dinner party i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you have more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> than we do though
 	
 	
 		yeah or a barbecue or something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah we can do that well starting the end of this well starting now we can do that through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
 		but that's about it for us and then we're basically inside you know even if it's really warm during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> it's going to cool off and by the time you would get ready to eat you're going to want to be in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		so our climate is not as conducive to the outdoor entertaining as yours are although it's certainly a lot more casual and a lot more fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> busy too  gives the grown-ups a chance to well like you said play a game or just talk or something like that
 	
 	
 		right  i
 		yeah and i think outside you can just kind of kick back and and visit after dinner but is seems like when you're inside the first thing you know someone has turned on a TV and that kind of is the end of your party i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you do uh for a barbecue when you cook out what's your favorite thing
 	
 	
 		well i guess we i we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> for awhile and it was kind of fun to do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food up there because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hadn't had it before and i know um we were going to make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um fajitas</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and  the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> knew when i asked for the beef skirt that you use to make it they said are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>  so it's  fun
 	
 	
 		oh i see you're you're even labeled by your food how do you do fajitas
 	
 	
 		yeah  well it you can either use we've always used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um beef</ENAMEX> skirt steak but you can also use flank steak and you marinate it
 		the recipe i've used is you marinate it in a can of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and a bottle of Italian dressing and then you can either grill uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> ounce
 	
 	
 		and then you can either grill it or you can um
 		broil it we usually grill it outside and then you cut it into real small real thin pieces and serve it on flour tortillas with like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grated cheese</ENAMEX> and sour <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> and guacamole and that type of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i've i've i love <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and i'm always doing the hot things and i make my own salsa and all that and it's really spicy but i just haven't had the nerve to try fajitas how large a steak would you need to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think i was reading looking at this recipe we're going to have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">in a couple of weeks</TIMEX> and they said recommend a pound for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		so i'd need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pounds wouldn't i one pound <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> people
 		and then is that a fairly thick steak or
 	
 	
 		it it's kind of a thin steak
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so it doesn't take very long to to grill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so when you when you get it you don't have your meat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> cut it to a certain width you just take whatever you find okay flank or skirt
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay  okay i'm i've been wanting to try that and i just haven't got the nerve up i do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tacos</ENAMEX> and enchiladas and all that stuff but
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		okay a can a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> ounce can of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and then you mix <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight ounces</NUMEX> of Italian dressing with it do you let the beer get flat or
 	
 	
 		well you just um well i usually just put it like in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pyrex</ENAMEX> pan you know i have an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> by or a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> by thirteen pan i put it in there and i pour it over the top and then you just you know turn it leave it in there for overnight or something and turn it every once in awhile
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe i usually cover it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saran wrap</ENAMEX> or something and then  or start it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and it's ready in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> to cook
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you know something i do when i marinate steak that you might think is interesting i have a tupperware uh sealed or any plastic sealed and then i just turn it over every once in awhile
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and it saves you know it's just easy just to turn the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> over the whole container over
 	
 	
 		the whole yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay yeah so you do grated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and guacamole
 	
 	
 		that would make it nice and easy
 		and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like sour <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> and then you like warm your um flour tortillas up in the oven
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh okay</ENAMEX>
 		where did i write the part about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tortillas</ENAMEX> warm the tortillas
 	
 	
 		i usually just wrap them up in foil or something like that and stick them in the oven for awhile
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		in fact as a wedding gift we got a tortilla warmer but i don't think very many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have those and it doesn't hold very many tortillas so we don't use that often
 	
 	
 		i see
 		uh-huh i'm sure you'd probably i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would eat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would eat one isn't that usually how that goes
 	
 	
 		probably yeah
 		because once you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> in there it gets pretty filling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah what about salsa you can or you can't or you just don't usually put salsa on it  you know
 	
 	
 		oh you can yeah i i'm not into the hot hot food my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is but  i'm not so
 	
 	
 		i see
 		well we have our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> live here and our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> between them who range from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight to three</NUMEX> and
 		every time they and they always come here for every holiday it seems and birthdays and and every time we always have to start up with something really hot and spicy as an hors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d'oeuvres</ENAMEX> and it gets to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		both our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> sons-in-law are good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> and enjoy cooking and it kind of gets to be a contest to see who can come up with the
 	
 	
 		the hottest  yeah
 	
 	
 		right  the hottest almost not eatable hors <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d'oeuvres</ENAMEX> to start us out so well it's fun take talking to you i'm going to try fajitas
 	
 	
 		oh well good well it's nice talking to you where do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> that live up um near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Terre Haute</ENAMEX> oh okay
 	
 	
 		well we're way up the other end of the state we're uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> on i <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five so</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terre Haute</ENAMEX> is you know it's like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> south
 	
 	
 		yeah well i know when we flew up there we flew into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and then had to drive down there so yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah this is a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five thousand just</NUMEX> a perfect little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for us retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and for raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you can go away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and you come home and say what happened and they say oh nothing  so it's a pretty good spot well have a nice day bye bye
 	
 	
 		well thank you you too bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	