
 
     		
 	
 		i just pressed my uh
 	
 	
 		we're supposed to talk about recent political developments
 	
 	
 		i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that's interesting not too controversial not too controversial i you know not doesn't matter whether you're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> i i do get somewhat of a kick out of
 		because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> or the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> who i admire how everyone wants to make get them in politics i think that's kind of an interesting recent thing that that i could think of recently that uh i was wondering what you thought about that making the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		getting a general into politics
 	
 	
 		they want him because he's popular not because he can do the job
 	
 	
 		right although i've i've been thinking about it and i uh i kind of get a kick out of they always want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> those we're looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> was saying that in essence the the general's staff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		was comparing to corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and they said that in general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> are more familiar with training that they believe in training more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they are much more educated than the average corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and so the really were very positive on a general's staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> having a a very much better education than the average uh corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> so i thought well maybe
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i think they probably have a better education than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that too that too and uh you know they talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and because of the war and why did we win and all that and they talked about how the training was so important and that's so important in industry so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they're liable to be right that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals generals</ENAMEX> in the service and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> uh you know might make a good uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> whether it be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> or whatever you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		he he you know we know he's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> we know he's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> the question is you know can he be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's ultimately responsible you know like what he said is
 		you know a lot of times in his interviews he was talking about you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> asking why are you doing this why are you doing that he says i'm following the orders of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> i'm not the one who writes the orders i'm just the one who follows them
 	
 	
 		yeah it's interesting how they say that when they're usually the top dogs you know everyone has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of course
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> was ordered to get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so he went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and said okay here's how i want to do it but uh he wasn't the one that decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> needed to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you you you pick one i i i just thought of that one when when they brought up about politics that was uh pretty easy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you don't have to pick <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> you can pick anything you want go ahead
 	
 	
 		well the the thing that i'm wondering about is how we get a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> how do we get some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that have been in there for so long how do we get them
 		to not get reelected over and over again
 	
 	
 		well i have an easy answer for that oh i wish they would do it is that limit it you know to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or ten years</TIMEX> max you know whether that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two five year</TIMEX> terms or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think
 		yeah
 		that may be our only answer but i don't really like it
 		i don't like the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> is limited in the number of terms he can serve
 	
 	
 		oh you know you're not
 	
 	
 		because i think if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> be him <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> i think if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> can prove
 		that he's popular you know that he can do the job then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be allowed to elect him as often as they want i think the reason why we've got these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> is because of the fund-raising rules i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how many of these big campaign contributions that they're running on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> did they get after they were elected just you know just after they were elected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		basically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as soon as they get elected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dump all kinds of money on them and say yeah yeah you're my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> you're my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX> he remembers that so what they've done is bought this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i don't know i do like the the limitation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and uh i think there is a needed change i
 		i i think the same thing should happen for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> uh i'd like you know that would be my answer of an easy way to get these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> out of there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> my God it's ridiculous you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's that's the easy way i think the harder way out would be to make the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are in there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who are trying to get in there run on more level ground
 	
 	
 		we had
 	
 	
 		and that's that's what the financing rules and the uh the mailing rules and the size of the office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and all that stuff
 	
 	
 		i think voting is a problem i think i had one of the subject about voting and uh voting apathy or something like that and i think that uh the voting rules need to be changed where you have a little more time i i can't believe that a country our big
 		votes for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock in the morning till seven o'clock at night</TIMEX> you know of course they have absentee which is getting to be more a lot easier and i i vote as often on absentee as i can because it's so easy now but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> you could make it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days</TIMEX> uh it's just uh if you really want the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to vote then give them a couple of days
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could vote if
 		they were somehow persuaded that it's something worth caring about
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know like you know the the recent uh election about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas City Council</ENAMEX> should be made up that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election last December</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm in yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> limit
 	
 	
 		boy i i am in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> i am so happy not to be part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> when i see those those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		it's an ugly mess
 	
 	
 		i mean uh i don't know if you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> but i think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> the city council the what is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s name whose uh not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> but the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		the manager
 	
 	
 		yeah the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> all of them need to be thrown out i mean they're just awful they're awful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't yeah well what get's me you know this thing it went down to defeat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX> by how many votes by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a few hundred</NUMEX> votes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if if it had passed if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had gotten out the vote it would have passed and there'd be no more argument but they're still fighting about it because of the way that election went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know
 		it's so awful that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> always spent consulting money that we put them in office and then they go out and spend a couple <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> and then they don't even do that recommendation you know i mean it's amazing the money that they spend once they get in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah
 		but but this was for supposedly to benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> had to do was go out and get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple more hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to vote and they would have had their way
 	
 	
 		well you're right there
 		you're right there uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are uh uh politics uh the voting is still not as much as you think in all kinds of issues really
 	
 	
 		yeah it's pretty sad
 	
 	
 		yeah it is uh uh hopefully <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will get more involved uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh my my position is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't vote don't have any right to complain about the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s going
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but but those are the ones that are complaining i i think a lot i see it here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that don't take any interest in and and constantly on the negative of everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		and and you ask them why they don't vote they say well they don't want their name on the uh jury duty list
 	
 	
 		is that right ooh
 	
 	
 		that that's where they get the jury duty list is from the voter registration list
 	
 	
 		right you're right you're right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think they could do more about uh voting
 	
 	
 		i think they could
 	
 	
 		what are the issues i i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> i want to just say that i'm so sad that there isn't a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> i don't even know i could i could go out and
 		and debate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> better than i see any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> doing it you know i mean at least i'd like to see competition because i like competition you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think rolling over and put your belly up and play dead i'm so disgusted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> party i can not believe it you know
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential</ENAMEX> races that's about what they've done but they've got a pretty good lock on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and a lot of local things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i still think in the last uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> you know of course that's not a recent event that's only my opinion i guess that way i shouldn't talk about that but uh
 		i don't know whether they're recent events i guess they were on this uh speech thing they want us to use a variety of words you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">wight</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how many times have you called by the way i
 	
 	
 		actually i haven't made any calls but i received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a dozen</NUMEX> i i think yeah i have to make these but i get distracted and get to do something else and all of a sudden my phone rings and go oh what the heck we'll talk for a while
 	
 	
 		oh really i i
 		yeah i i've already got uh twelve cards you get any cards in the mail you know
 	
 	
 		yeah we got a whole bunch i can't remember how many
 	
 	
 		i don't know i'm amazed by of course we're not talking about politics but i am amazed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say they got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> i wonder why you need
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thirty</ENAMEX> renditions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> voice but i'm not in voice uh synthesis but i'd sure like to see a summary of it we'll get to politics i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		you might be well i think we've used up as much time as we're supposed to anyway we're supposed to do <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> and that was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> ago hey well thanks for the call yeah bye
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		yeah
 		yeah bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	