
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 		what can we do about crime i don't know the one thing that keeps coming to mind to me is that they're they don't have enough space in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they keep letting out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have you know these horrible records
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so maybe we need to have more
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prisons</ENAMEX> or use the old army <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> and make them into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> or something that's one thing i guess i could think of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's definitely a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> it's you know all are even we live in a little small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and there's just rapes and murders and burglaries and everything all the time and you just can't get away from it no matter where you live
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's pretty scary
 	
 	
 		well i i'm i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler</ENAMEX> and i can't say that there's too much of that there um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have problems with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i really don't know what we can do about it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's rough because
 	
 	
 		unless they start enforcing the um
 		
 
 		uh start giving more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> death sentences that's the only thing i could think of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well even some of the sentences just seem ridiculous i mean you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times have committed burglaries and they're still you know only serving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> in prison
 		so that's definitely something they could have a more automatic sentence instead of having the judge having the choice of like you know from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that would be one thing that you know i think could help is having the laws be changed so that they were more stiff penalties and more automatic penalties you know for certain crimes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i don't i don't know what they're going to do with the problem because it just keeps getting worse and worse
 	
 	
 		yeah and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> things that they're saying now are you going are you a student or are you in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		um i'm a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarion University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay because one of the things that i've heard so much about lately um lately is the situations on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> where crime has gone up so much and apparently many of the
 		especially like in date rape many of the um you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> seem to be getting off because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> kind of cover up and they don't really
 	
 	
 		well not only that a lot of them's not even turned in
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know what i mean a lot of times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> don't even report it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		um i've heard of a few cases up here but i can't say that i've heard of uh you know any significant amount uh but then again like you don't know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are reporting them or not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they say like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> are reported i believe it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's it's awful so one thing they could do is probably support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more reporting it i know some police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> try to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can report to and this kind of thing but
 		i'm sure it's still terribly traumatizing you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to report it so that's probably something else they could do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know it seems like something else in terms of crime is certainly involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you know and that's like as long as it it almost makes me feel in a way like making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> legalized just to get all the money out of it and not have you know because these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are saying why should i go
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you want to sit down
 	
 	
 		to high school and so i can go out and work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX> you know for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> an hour or whatever when i can make uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> a day selling drugs
 		so that's certainly a big problem i don't know what the solution to that is having more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> available jeez i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh
 		see see now i would say that that's a bigger problem up here than even the date rape or anything i know a lot of people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that partake in that and i'm not saying they're bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but i i i would say that's a bigger problem
 	
 	
 		yeah because it ends up even if it's just kind of like this social <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use you're still ending up supporting these big drug pin you know
 		huge amounts thousand and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> are getting spent you know on higher and higher up on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and it's definitely
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		got to do with crime you know you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> selling their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> you know to get some crack i mean just oh gosh horrible stuff like that one of the things they're doing is is they're prosecuting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are having these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are addicted to crack
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they said um some of the statistics statistics show like one out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> being born in these public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are addicted to crack and their moms are crack users
 		so that's you know another way of looking at it as as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is being a criminal you know for doing that to her child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't know who's the victim there i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are the victim it seems like a lot of times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> because they're addicted and
 		it's a very complicated problem i don't envy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> trying to cope with it gosh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i don't either
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i guess that's about all i have to say is there anything else you would want to
 	
 	
 		uh no i can't say that i i just know that it's really bad in some areas and something's going to have to be done sooner but
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know what they can do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's frustrating
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it was nice talking to you uh you too bye
 	
 	
 		okay well thanks for talking have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	