
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so i think i think what we should talk about is the the war um the war that just went on see i don't agree with it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all i don't believe in war
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has this attitude by saying you know thank you for
 		keeping us our freedom and stuff like that and i think it's all independent because it's it has nothing to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> you didn't gain anything from it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it wasn't our freedom that you were saving it was just
 		the thing the thing that that uh that i saw was okay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> wants to raise oil prices <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> wants to take <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> out of the whole system by leaving them independent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> you know saw this they said let's take over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which is a good idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> says okay our our oil prices are going to go up and like for example see okay like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lithuania Lithuania</ENAMEX> right they declared themselves uh an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> goes in there well the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> goes in there and they kick everybody's ass
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> doesn't go in there and say listen they were uh you know named an independent you know state with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and everything but we're not going to go into your country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> here which you know are you know like in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> have you ever read that book
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		okay nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> there are like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> big continents and uh there's just this area like around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> and stuff that everybody's fighting over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> the problem is is that nobody's going to invade anybody else's boundaries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right like their immediate boundaries like you're not going to go you know it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s not going to go straight into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> because there you're you're invading their border right but all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you can fight about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so the thing is is that you're wasting so much money to send you know it's like how much money did the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> spend when they could have paid so much money for each barrel of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> that was being
 	
 	
 		we'll probably never know how much it actually cost
 	
 	
 		and you know it's it was uh basically all based on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> because nobody actually like for example if uh let's say if uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> took over you know Surinam i don't think anybody would care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 	
 	
 		you know and uh
 		that's something that that has been you know very because see the thing is is like every time that i see a war i see myself on the front line
 		and on the other side i see myself again and i got to shoot myself you know  i got to shoot somebody that's that's got the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that i do you know the same relationships that i do and just because i was born here i've got to shoot them down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh it's never a pleasant thing that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh but at least it was it was over quick and there weren't that many deaths  now the only problem is is the aftermath that you're having so many deaths in the border with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's amazing
 		yes
 		yes that's really unfortunate it really is i don't know if we stopped too soon i don't i don't i really don't know what we need to do about that
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		well
 		there's there's something that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> did right which is say say you know okay let's kick him out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
 		which was our basic goal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh now indirectly let's try to overthrow him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and they're not going to do that directly
 		but the thing is is that they they didn't go into into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and say you know because they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to go in there and say get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know you can seek  seek asylum here and you can go there but no way are you going to rule ever again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i've been hearing some talk too of trying to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> up on you know criminal charges i don't know if that will ever happen or not
 	
 	
 		well the thing is is that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all they got to they got they have to get him
 	
 	
 		uh-huh which is very difficult to do
 	
 	
 		and and there's no way that you can get him unless it's by force
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and then you can put him on trial
 	
 	
 		obviously he's not going to turn himself in
 	
 	
 		no no i think i think he'd rather commit suicide than turn himself in because there's i mean there's like it's like there's no hope you know like what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> did you know like if you were going to put on trial you get to live the rest of your life but where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		true
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and so um the thing is is that  once you've done something wrong which is nationally you know internationally recognized
 		then you're going to try to get out of it and the there's no way you know and especially since he's got inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for using you know chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know like he sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> over to to shoot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down that were on the border with uh that  that were on their way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he had a couple of them bombarded
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah obviously human life means nothing to him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but uh
 		you know he's got uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of dollars like
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		fifty i think it was like i don't know if it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty billion</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty million</NUMEX> which is really doesn't make any difference
 	
 	
 		that's true past a point it doesn't make any difference
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's really really unfortunate it really is
 	
 	
 		and
 		but it's just it's just that uh you know it you know like the we just put our goals in different you know levels is like saying you know it's like yeah sure we need oil you know and we need it desperately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 	
 	
 		but the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that you know that have oil but not as big you know like they say you know like when the prices went up and then they went down when they took that big dip it was because they discovered another big oil well somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		seems like the prices never go down to where they were originally though before the before the increase started
 	
 	
 		well the it it's an advantage you know it's like you're saying okay i can bring my prices up to a dollar fifty a gallon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm not going to bring them back down to you know ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine cents</NUMEX> why because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are willing to pay a dollar fifty a gallon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so if i <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> leave it at a dollar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are still going to pay
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		you know i went down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty cents</NUMEX> but i went up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> cents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		about the lowest i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area is uh i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ninety two</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		ninety eight
 	
 	
 		ninety two
 	
 	
 		oh God
 		here it's like it's like a dollar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		well there's still a lot of dollar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> places around here but you can find some that's under a dollar but not not a whole lot that's the lowest i've seen
 	
 	
 		but still the i mean have you ever checked like uh the most money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> in uh in nin eteen uh ninety
 		uh you can see that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amaco</ENAMEX> and uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> oh God i forgot their names but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> was the number one money maker and that was just because of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">of the last quarter</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>'s doing very well too well i assume i assume all the major major brands are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh that was i mean and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> uh went up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> and some percent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's practically impossible to do now a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to to shoot up in that way and uh
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just that you know people
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take advantage take advantage of that you know like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were saying we're trying not to raise our prices but when you know when we get a barrel coming in at more than what we're selling it for we've got to raise our prices
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know but still if you realize that uh one barrel has like how much was it like uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gallons</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah something like yeah
 	
 	
 		something it's got <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty gallons</NUMEX> and they're selling you know
 		you you know you you got to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> at least and you know for uh for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one gallon</NUMEX> and it's it was selling like at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you're making uh you know fifteen dollars profit easily
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yep sure
 	
 	
 		and uh everything i mean and and the expenses you know of the war you know it's like uh you know it's like who's gaining on this okay because uh i uh does does the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> government own any gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like like you know like gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i because see like for example
 		i don't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> owns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shell</ENAMEX> i'm not sure about that
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure either
 	
 	
 		but the thing is like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> got nothing out of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because well you know it's like other the other independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> you know and they did
 		and uh then the taxes go up and then everybody else loses
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um you know they're just
 		they're just some things that might not be worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you know and and uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all how many how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had to had to die before the war  you know it's like transporting stuff and
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		things like that before you know it's like yeah sure you know like to to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that died there their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> don't feel it was necessary to do that yeah yeah you you could never you could never bring them back so oh well
 	
 	
 		sure dead's dead
 		that's true
 		well i don't guess we resolved anything but it's interesting it's
 	
 	
 		yeah so okay nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		to you too take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	