
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so tell me about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX> is it great
 	
 	
 		i liked it i really did actually i saw it twice my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> and i were
 		real into psychological things we we think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with mind problems are really interesting so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean you know real psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so we were dying to see it so we went and saw it and i had to see it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time to get it all because i kept my eyes closed through so much of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part
 	
 	
 		right
 		is it really that scary
 	
 	
 		well it's it's not that it's that scary it's that it's so graphic
 		because uh how well are you going to see it i don't want to tell you how it ends
 	
 	
 		i i i uh i plan on probably renting it at some point in my life
 	
 	
 		okay  so some time later much later huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i've got small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i don't get out to many movies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well it's uh what is so weird about it is that it it's a real it's based on real people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i read the story in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> about where they got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in the movie and they're a combination of a lot of different serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> in real life
 		and so a lot of things that happen in the movie the only thing really scary about it is that it could happen to you
 		it really does happen in real life you know normally normally in movies you can look at it and say well it's a movie
 	
 	
 		and that doesn't really happen it's only pretend
 	
 	
 		right
 		right but in this you're going i i would have done that i can see where that would happen
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it's it gets really scary but it's it's a real interesting movie very thought provoking there are so many things to discuss when the movie's over
 		if you're one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that likes to discuss things and and think about why it happened
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i still talk about it with  we'll call each other every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> and go remember when in the movie this happened well i was just reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and and things just keep relating back to it i thought it was fascinating
 	
 	
 		wow
 		maybe i should go see it in a theatre and plan to go out to dinner afterwards so we could sit and talk about it
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you want to go to dinner
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		maybe just go out for a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't think you want to eat
 		it it is real good though it's it's uh i liked it i liked Dances with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolves</ENAMEX> too though that was a real good movie
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah that's one of the best films i've seen in a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i didn't think i'd like it i don't normally like the uh the old West type movies things like that the
 		they don't normally interest me but that one i really really liked because it it i didn't know so much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> and all that
 		that happened in that part of the war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i had never heard anything really about that before and this was a whole new idea to me anyway i thought it was real good
 	
 	
 		what
 		what's your heritage
 	
 	
 		um
 		i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a quarter</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side is a little bit of everything
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> little bit of this little bit of that
 		and that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've got quite a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in me so
 	
 	
 		what
 		do you
 	
 	
 		some of it was um things that i had heard well both of i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> that were full blood
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and but they were on opposite sides
 	
 	
 		which
 		which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> were they <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sioux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> or what were they
 	
 	
 		no one was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackfoot</ENAMEX> and one was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherokee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		and um so i knew
 		a lot about just um
 		oh the kind of respect they had for the earth
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that it was real it wasn't something i'd just read in books it was something i was taught
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um
 		and so you know like the the scene with the buffalo
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i cried that was horrible
 	
 	
 		that was awesome
 		oh i did too i did too
 	
 	
 		i i just i mean it you know it that because i know it happened over and over and over again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean it's just like we're raping our land now but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know it was i i just thought that was one of the movies best movies i've seen in so long because it made me laugh i mean i was you know parts of it i was just almost in the aisles laughing over it and
 	
 	
 		it makes you realize how really ignorant some white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have no ethnic background no heritage anything other than just typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> a little bit of everything and they don't really know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't know anything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they don't know anything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> that came over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it it really made it seem like we are so in the dark on so many things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think that it yeah
 		tried to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize that um we can't close our mind to another culture simply because it's not ours
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		and uh and it was so there was so much the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> did teach us and there was so much more they could have taught us had we only listened
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and i still really other than just basic ignorance of prejudice i don't understand why we didn't
 		why them why did we not listen to them
 		i've never
 	
 	
 		they had something we wanted  we wanted
 	
 	
 		yeah well yeah but isn't isn't it sad to think that that much that greed can do that much to you or to a person
 		i mean they we wanted the land and we didn't want them to have it so just screw everything they're going to think and teach us and tell us and and we could just like wipe out an entire
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's that's sad
 	
 	
 		well i i think of the uh you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> wars and the racial wars that we have now in so many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and in our high schools
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that are basically the same thing acted out by a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know they're fighting over things that
 		are to them are important enough to possibly die for
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and yet they just don't matter
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you know i mean it comes down to that the land or the the territory or the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> or whatever is there for everyone
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it can be enjoyed by all if shared
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean but but that's what we did to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> we said
 		you know we're afraid of you you don't you don't look like we do you don't talk like we do so we're going to move you out
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and we offered reservations
 		as
 		you know consolation prize and they were a joke
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		right that is that's a good way to look at it a consolation prize that's about all it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they
 	
 	
 		that's really sad that things like that can still happen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> after all this time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you would think we'd a learned something by now
 	
 	
 		yeah but he who has the biggest stick is still going to win
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		he with the most toys
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hey all that counts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monopoly</ENAMEX> is who has <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boardwalk and Pork Park Place</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right who's got more hotel
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i really did like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the Lambs though that was really an interesting movie i
 		i liked Dances with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wolves</ENAMEX> but it was a more an emotional like you get real involved and you cried and you feel real sorry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know and all this but in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX> it was kind of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX> did you see that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was kind of that feeling through the whole thing on the edge of your seat wanting to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what to do next
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know you're like no don't go in there don't give him your name  you you just you start acting it out for them
 	
 	
 		yeah i definitely ought to get in on a rental then because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would look at me in the theatre going what is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> doing
 	
 	
 		no believe it or not the whole theatre got involved i mean yes in fact i'm trying to i can't remember which scene it was but at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point everyone in the theatre clapped
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 	
 	
 		they were so happy it was it was and i thought i was just there and i heard other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> crying when i was crying
 	
 	
 		man
 	
 	
 		there were certain parts in there that were real sad and you hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are doing things that you know are about to reap some bad thing and
 		everyone in the theatre will go  and you know everybody does it it's like the whole theatre you get this big  sound and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it was i i think everybody felt that way through it it was very real involved
 		and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were crying when they walked out and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were just kind of staring straight ahead like that didn't bother me and you know it did
 	
 	
 		goodness
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		yeah this is going to roll right off my side
 	
 	
 		right i remember the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i saw it was with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>
 		and he was joking with me about how i wasn't going to watch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of it i was going to close my eyes
 		and there were quite a few scenes where i did but this one scene i knew something bad was coming i could tell so i ducked my head
 		and about that time i heard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> go  and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> jumped
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he literally jumped and he swears he didn't do it and i felt him jump
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		and
 		it really was to this day i tell him he was scared and he says no no you you just didn't watch it you should have watched it it wasn't that bad
 	
 	

 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm like yeah right that's why you jumped
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm going to have a hard time waiting for it to come out on video now
 	
 	
 		yeah really it is a great movie you got to see it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's so fascinating to think that there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are so
 		so smart they're such geniuses that they've cross that line and they're they're psychotic and it's amazing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		it's very scary
 	
 	
 		it really is i mean to think that it could be anybody we know i mean you could be
 		walking right next to one of them and not even know it because they look perfectly normal i mean this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was a doctor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in fact they were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he killed you know and you think right now your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> could be wacko
 		he could be some psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> and no one would ever know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just strange but that that was what was that was what made the movie because it's so real
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i like movies that are based on on things that are real
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i do too oh yeah
 		oh what was it um
 		the ones about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Von Bulows</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh what was that
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh the something about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	