
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		what are your favorite programs
 	
 	
 		uh it's kind of hard to put my finger on a on a favorite TV program however uh one that i've been watching for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh how funny
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh it's going to be going off the air uh let's see a week from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> a week from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>
 		it's going to be its last show
 		so i've i've kind of enjoyed watching over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> i've been disappointed in it and also pleased in it
 		and uh i was uh greatly disappointed uh when i did move down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> to uh
 		find out that the uh the uh great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fork Ranch</ENAMEX> was really only a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom house</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've seen the sign that goes to there i've well i think i've seen it in the distance
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i have not even seen it and i have not seen the program
 	
 	
 		oh well that's a shame
 	
 	
 		so
 		and and uh i know when we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> it was really funny uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX> by the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> and by that program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and that's that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things they associate with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX> so i and i they asked me several several times they ask me why are there <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i didn't know what they were talking about it took me a long time they're talking about the viaducts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that that is right isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because they ask me why are there <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> going into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		darned if i know  i was blank looking you know i felt really dumb
 	
 	
 		well it it's uh when you look at the uh you know route seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> coming down there i i mean it's actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> but it's a bridge over top of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadway</ENAMEX> there's no water there i mean uh
 	
 	
 		well there's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity</ENAMEX> i thought it was to going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Cliff</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well there's there um
 		well they i think when they open the show up they give you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different views of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> one from the east and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from the west
 	
 	
 		oh do they
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and that's why
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		uh it kind of confuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but uh uh
 		i enjoy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a lot of different comedies um
 		i think it's mainly for an escape
 		um you know you uh my job is not the most thrilling in the world and uh i enjoy laughing and uh some of the shows that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are on the air some are just purely you know brain drainers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then there's other ones that uh deal with uh in a funny manner uh socially relevant things and uh one show that comes to mind is like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Designing Women</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that is just a hoot that's one of those few that i do watch and the television is on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes to watch TV it's on
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i usually read and watch TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and usually i can handle both at the same time you know because i am pretty sure where the TV plot's going
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that's one of the few that i just actually watch because it's funny
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i really enjoy that one
 	
 	
 		yes it uh it has been very entertaining and and also uh the the issues they deal with uh really tends to open
 		open your eyes as well as your mind to some of the problems and uh i've i've really enjoyed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> since it came on
 		um don't like the politics surrounding the program though but i mean other than that you know there seems to be a little fighting in fighting going on between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and one of the actresses but uh
 		and then uh i've kind of gotten hooked on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> stuff uh public uh TV
 		uh i like things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nova</ENAMEX> and uh some of the the special programs they come up with on nature and stuff i just enjoy watching that stuff
 	
 	
 		now we watch a lot of those uh and the ones that sometimes will hook me
 		to put down my book will be the one there was one uh recently about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> Address
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they wrapped a fictional story around it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i thought that was well done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and it it caught my attention i wound up watching the whole thing
 		um
 		i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">awards</ENAMEX> ceremonies and there seems to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of them per year
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		maybe i've spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> watching to see what they have on and if they make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> of themselves or not
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh they could take that whole collection and it would disappear and i'd never miss it for a minute
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		particularly the beauty pageants i i particularly take issue with those i i really dislike those
 	
 	
 		well i'm one of those rare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who i i rarely ever sit down and watch a whole sporting event
 		um if ever watch one uh there's just not that much i'm i'm interested in um
 		for a while i i i watched some football but i've just got too many more important things in my life now than to sit around and and watch a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> used to just be riveted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> and now
 		we're out running around and if they're if they're playing he'll turn it on while we're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to see what the score is and he'll listen
 		but even i've said hey look you're fascinated with this you sit and listen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> let me run in here and i'll do some things and i'll come back and you don't have to miss he'll say nah nah nah
 		and he doesn't he doesn't watch it he listen like i say if it's convenient he'll listen to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he just doesn't watch them on TV like he used to
 	
 	
 		well i think it was great when they were you know like world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">champs</ENAMEX> and they were doing real well
 		i uh i personally i i came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area and so i was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> Redskins fan
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh when i came down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it was uh you know i found myself rooting for the home team
 		i uh in fact i have a uh a baseball hat that was signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Dorsett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershel Walker</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh how neat
 	
 	
 		the only year they played together on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i actually got to go see them win in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> when they went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and i i i made the trip and did the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> before the game and the game and everything and uh that was
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		that was a lot of fun but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i haven't been as i'll tell you what i love to watch and this is not this is rarely on television but what is a lot of fun to go attend is this arena football
 		yeah i like it's so much better than straight football
 	
 	
 		hm
 		no i haven't seen that
 	
 	
 		it it doesn't it has a lot of different rules the field is half the size
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's no
 		they can't call time and things like that it moves a lot faster
 	
 	
 		uh
 		gee i'll have to try to catch that sometime if
 	
 	
 		uh again i think it may be on cable more than anything else we don't have cable
 	
 	
 		yeah that's proba bly true
 		yeah we don't either i uh
 		i couldn't rationalize paying you know it's like if i pay for a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> then i have to watch what movies they want me to watch when they want me to watch them
 		and if i
 		you know if i didn't use cable for anything else other than the basic well i can get that for free
 		and well i don't really don't need <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> i see enough bad news all the time i don't need to see more of it so i i've kind of uh
 		rationalized that it's it's probably a lot more economical for us to just go rent the movies we want to see
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and of course when we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it was real convenient with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Thumb</ENAMEX> you know having movies uh back then it was ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine cents</NUMEX> i mean go
 	
 	
 		oh
 		they're everywhere they're on every corner everything you've ever wanted to see
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and you can see them a lot sooner than you can see them on any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinemax</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well and i like to rent tapes because you can put the thing on hold if you get a telephone call or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or it becomes snack time for various reasons you can put you know the only thing this <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance with Wolves i</ENAMEX> want to see it in a theater
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yes i do too
 	
 	
 		because i understand that that your you'll lose fifty percent of it if you don't
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i've been trying to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to go with me to go see it she
 		she doesn't like going to movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> because usually they're dirty
 		
 
 		and uh you know she just doesn't like them and um she doesn't think that she could sit still for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> and watch the movie and i've told her you know everybody i know that has seen it has said that the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> go really quick
 	
 	
 		that's what i hear too
 	
 	
 		and uh so i'm i'm hoping i can get her talked into it soon
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> smokes he's one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> that still smokes and you can't smoke in movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and that has really slowed down the forward progress of going to movies
 		but i haven't really cared up until this point but i we are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> going to go see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance with Wolves</ENAMEX> it's that's it we will do it
 	
 	
 		um that's great
 	
 	
 		so yeah finally
 	
 	
 		yeah but as as far as uh regular TV shows i mean i've got some
 		some shows that i that that i would be afraid to admit to you that i've actually sat down and watched
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and then there's there's others that uh uh i i wish i had time to see it's like i enjoy watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> it's very funny some of the things in it are mindless but i i just don't have time to watch it
 		um i think about the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only night</TIMEX> that i really sit in front of the TV set <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> long probably is on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and because
 		um i work so hard over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> doing other things with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and stuff and going to work on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i'm just worn out
 		so i kind of use it as the time to catch up on correspondence and and look over things and i can sit in front of the TV set and look at you know
 		do go through my mail and and watch TV at the same time
 	
 	
 		well i tend my job tends to be very demanding
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and to sit down and to mindlessly either read or just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mindlessly</ENAMEX> stare in absolute comfort isn't as bad as it used to
 		
 		
 	