
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		okay do i still can't still can feel that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> as such is still a threat to the civilized western world absolutely
 		and my reasons are based upon not only from what i read in the newspapers what i see on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> but up against some of the
 		fun and exciting things i ran into during my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth Special Forces Group</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		okay
 		i guess i don't see them as much of a threat as they used to be but i think just the instability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> right now uh-huh
 	
 	
 		well that's what makes it a powder keg
 	
 	
 		so scary
 	
 	
 		the um
 		i'll go back in time a little bit to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eighty one</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real involvement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> started
 		um
 		naturally we were at the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> was considered to be the big military power and the big threat so we got lots quite a bit of
 		information as well as indoctrination on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> tactics and weapons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty three</NUMEX> before the marines ever got there with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN Peace Keeping Force</ENAMEX>
 		and with the training i received prior to going there with captured weapons we kept running up against
 		these weren't these weren't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> made copies these were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> made top of the line fresh out of the box AK-47s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as well as a lot of the explosives we were running into
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granada</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October twenty fifth eighty three</TIMEX> we invaded the place
 		sure there were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> there but there was also a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> that were damn good shots
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i was with we jumped in on the western tip of of the island down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Point Salinas</ENAMEX>
 		and for every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> there was at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and they were all shooting state of the art <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> weapons
 		in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX>
 		i was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Honduran</ENAMEX> army
 		again we were running up against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> quite a bit plus <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>
 		and the equipment we were capturing and taking from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicaraguans</ENAMEX> was brand new out of the crate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> made material
 		do i consider them a threat absolutely
 		they have a university in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrice de Lamumba University</ENAMEX>
 		about like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> or UT where they're teachings <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> like that they're teaching terrorism
 		some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we went up against in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> were graduates from that place and let me tell you they are nothing nice to go up against
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i'm surprised during this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> crisis we didn't have more
 		incidents than they did
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are top of the line
 		when they when they graduate from there
 		they can pull terrorist actions anywhere in the free world
 		and they are very very good at what they do
 		so until i see the entire
 		quote old guard
 		of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> military of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> government
 		completely roll over and disappear preferably buried
 		i still consider them a threat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is different from ours to where there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist generals generals</ENAMEX> that actually control <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens and thousands</NUMEX>
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
 		that irregardless of what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> policy is they're going to do what the general tells them
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess that's what concerns me the most is they're they're so unstable that somebody like that could make uh decisions that would
 		jeopardize a lot of people
 	
 	
 		well it's interesting interesting watching the different <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania Lithuania</ENAMEX>
 		doing their little revolts down there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those sectors has got a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> that are there
 		so far they hadn't run into the real psychos yet
 		there's probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> which would be an equivalent of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">joint chiefs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> that are in positions over some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> states
 		if uprisings happen happen in their sectors
 		it is it's going to be a total blood bath
 	
 	
 		yeah it looks like it's come close to that as it is
 	
 	
 		actually they're showing remarkable restraint
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they get real nasty the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hyundee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> come out and they
 		would level entire areas
 		okay you're from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay you know basically the size of uh the area around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> Hyundee <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> in the air they can level the entire area and there won't be anything left alive
 		and they can do that in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about four minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and they've got entire squadrons of those just standing by
 		they used them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> did remarkably remarkably well considering the terrain they were flying in
 		but on a highly populated area like some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> would be
 		with the weaponry that's attached on those things there is no place to hide
 		if the bombs don't get you if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> don't get you then the then the nerve gas definitely will get you
 		the only drawback on that little piece of machinery is they only got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> of air time
 		they drink that much fuel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		were you have you i take it you haven't spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any time</TIMEX> in the military
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> that's never been attached to any form of the military
 		i know a lot of this stuff that i was involved in never did make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		during that same time frame didn't you get some feeling that i mean they're getting all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and stuff
 		didn't it
 		it bug you a little bit why they kept coming up with all this stuff
 	
 	
 		you mean in the in the most recent conflict
 	
 	
 		in any of them since eighty one
 	
 	
 		oh yeah definitely i i'm i'm a little bit shocked to what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> has done in terms of selling to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
 		in the past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to fifteen years
 		yeah i think we we kind of shoot ourselves in the foot that way too it's bad enough that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> do it
 	
 	
 		it all boils down to whether it's our side their side it's a matter of money to a certain extent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the deal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi's</ENAMEX> have with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> was for oil
 	
 	
 		yeah it's scary to know that they're supplying that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with weapons
 		especially when it's to the south of us
 	
 	
 		uh the ones to the south are more regional conflict
 		they're not really that worried about
 		invading north
 		they're more interested in they've got a screwed up situation i'll give them that
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> all the way down into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> the situation down there is weird and it's very screwed up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		inflation is out of this world and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> which
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has technically supported for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> are corrupt as all get out
 		and generally the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting screwed and they're tired of it and they're willing to try anything to get out from under it even if that means going to communism
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is getting to the point where they're they're about to do something to get out of communism i guess i'd would like to see somebody like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
 		to get more power i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> has about had his day
 	
 	
 		unfortunately <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s got too many connections with the old guard
 		that's the only drawback that i see with the entire thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> has m ade his attempt and he's had his problems with some of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> himself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s in tight wi th the old guard
 		so it may be trying to choose between the lesser of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evils</ENAMEX> at this point
 	
 	
 		uh-huh true
 		i don't know i sure wouldn't turn my back on them
 	
 	
 		you mean i understand when they pulled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> out of uh
 		or they reduced the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX> went down i thought that was great
 		but by no means do i
 		endorse or approve pulling everybody out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it may be
 		a much reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> than what we used to have over there
 		but you still better have the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in place if something does go down even if it's a regional conflict
 		if
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> is going to flex its muscle and be the super <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX> that it is
 		not only does it it can talk the talk but it's got to be able to walk the walk it's got to have the stuff to back it back up what it's saying
 		if you've only got a token <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> there you can't hold your ground
 	
 	
 		at least they're learning a little bit from history i mean uh
 		
 
 		
 		
 	