
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> the subject is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> trials and should the jury recommend
 		uh sentencing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		now my personal opinion uh i don't know uh uh here lately it seems
 		well up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> i guess there there was uh there just too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> about and permitting too many
 		oh they just broaden the the human rights in to to cover just about everybody everybody and i don't think uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those guilty of committing capital crimes should be uh permitted to go spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> in jail and be turned loose on parole it's just not right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think i agree with that very much i do you
 	
 	
 		and therefore i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> should be able to recommend sentencing
 	
 	
 		i do you think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they are listening to a trial put themselves
 		in a position like that and say i would never do something like that and it's hard for them to believe that somebody else could do the things that have been done
 	
 	
 		uh yes very possibly so many of us have led led sheltered lives that uh when we go into a sit in on a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i've never done it myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i never have either
 	
 	
 		unfortunately i wish i could have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is there a reason why you have never
 	
 	
 		i've just never been called up
 	
 	
 		uh-huh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> so i always assumed that that was why i was never called uh-huh
 	
 	
 		well now that's possible
 		but uh i was called up as an an alternate once but i never made it to the jury
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh uh do they have such a thing now as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> jury
 	
 	
 		not that i know of
 	
 	
 		somebody told me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that there is what what they call a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six man</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and i had never heard of such thing and i wondered if it was true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh i've never heard of it
 	
 	
 		i never had either but i just wondered uh another question was uh should a criminal case uh should the jury be unanimous on their decision
 		and that i wasn't sure on either whether it should be unanimous or not
 	
 	
 		uh well there again uh
 		i suppose it should be
 	
 	
 		that would mean they all would have to decide
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> way or the other
 	
 	
 		is it guilt or innocence but then again so many times uh you get one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holdouts</ENAMEX> and and it permits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> to get a retrial
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and now that that's not too bad in this sense because you might get someone in their that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of circumstances i mean that's happened
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh giving them another another another trial might give them additional time to uh prove their innocence
 	
 	
 		bring some of these things out um-hum
 	
 	
 		yes uh we can't overlook the fact that there are innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do get involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jury</ENAMEX> trials
 	
 	
 		uh apparently there are i i i since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> worked as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> i can't believe there are very many
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that come to trial that have are not guilty of something some part of whatever they're accused of i have i still have a little bit of a problem with that
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i would suppose there are circumstances you're in the wrong place at the right time or know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> wrong person at the right time
 	
 	
 		oh that's it and you just might resemble somebody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we had a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a a</NUMEX>
 		great miscarriage of justice here it was finally after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> it was finally uh
 		uh uh taken care of we had a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was accused simply because he resembled uh someone who stuck who who held up a uh a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 7-Eleven</TIMEX> i think it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		ah um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and even though he had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> that said that uh he was at work and he had all sorts of of a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character witnesses</ENAMEX> and whatnot
 	
 	
 		they still found him guilty
 	
 	
 		they
 		they found him guilty
 	
 	
 		when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said he was at work
 	
 	
 		well they said it was that this happened during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch time</TIMEX> and he could have disappeared uh gotten away at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch time</TIMEX> and uh committed the robbery
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> well as a matter of fact they made a TV show about it after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> they finally uh came up with evidence and proved to prove that he was innocent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh for heaven's sake so there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s life gone um-hum
 	
 	
 		exactly now that just was not fair
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh yeah i guess that's where a lot of the problem lies we're we try bend over backwards protecting the guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the one's that are on trial
 	
 	
 		so
 		yes unfortunately that's what happens
 	
 	
 		and yeah
 		and we often forget about the one that the injustice has been done to
 		because i bet they still say our system is the best in the world
 	
 	
 		well it's not the uh uh it's it's it's not the best system but it's the best <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the world
 	
 	
 		yeah it's the best one that exists i guess so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and unfortunately we just have to put up with a lot of things and they they trying to solve them and everything and but uh oh i don't know i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm i'm still rankled about their decision to permit burning of the flag
 	
 	
 		oh i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are i think they've lost sight of some things that are very important to our country
 	
 	
 		well it the the uh the first amendment definitely says freedom of speech not freedom of action
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh uh oh that just rankles me no i swear if i ever saw somebody that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh burning burning a flag i'd i'd try to kill them i would
 	
 	
 		that bad huh  i wouldn't like it but i don't know if i'd go that far
 	
 	
 		well i happen to be a flag freak i served i was in the service i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		well i saw what the red in the flag represents
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think pride in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and our flag is is so important it's important in so many facets of our life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i i i feel like if they don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't like what our flag stands for they're welcome to go some place else exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah see what they
 	
 	
 		there's nobody holding them here
 	
 	
 		see what how they like it under another flag
 	
 	
 		right they'd soon be back i'm sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> we seem to be of of uh uh
 		the same uh uh opinions here i hope they get something out of this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i don't know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> making the decision if that's do you think that's good you know like if a jury
 	
 	
 		oh passing sentence well uh uh yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes but i i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> should be able to recommend
 	
 	
 		make a recommendation do they sometimes make a recommendation that's what i was thinking they they sometimes do
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh yes yes
 		uh i don't know if that's a regular procedure or what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i know i'm always hearing that uh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> came in with a guilty guilty verdict and they recommended uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		and they recommend some yeah and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has the final decision on what does really happen
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of course uh now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> may not be completely aware of all the ramifications of a sentence uh they may not know that if you give him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> he can get out in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think that's where a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> they're getting put away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but actually their chance course when a lot of times when they come up for a parole they're denied it depends on you know what they're what they'd been guilty of and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a lot of different things i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah but too many times they they are permitted permitted to go out on parole and
 	
 	
 		um-hum a lot slip through the the protective whatever they have to do and and there are bad ones that do slip back out and
 		end up hurting somebody again
 	
 	
 		yes they just go out and repeat their crimes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there well they say after after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> offenses why it's automatically life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> but i think they ought to make it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> offenses
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i always thought there was there was wrong it seems sometimes that like somebody who is stealing a loaf of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> to feed his family
 		got more jail sentence than somebody maybe that killed somebody it seemed like there sometimes there's not a good the balance isn't right it doesn't make sense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh yeah very true well here again now there is where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> seems to rear its ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> so so frequently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh race or nationality even
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		so
 	
 	
 		but uh like you said it's uh it's it's it's not the best system but it's the best one we've got
 	
 	
 		yeah right so let's put up with it i guess improve it if we can if we ever get a chance so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure enough
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> it's been awful nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		well it's been nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and uh i hope you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a real good day</TIMEX> and week
 	
 	
 		well let's hope neither one of us ever have to run into this this uh with subject we've been discussing take care now bye
 	
 	
 		i hope not  you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	