
 
     		
 	
 		uh i don't go to movies a whole lot but uh i went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks ago</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and saw Dances with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wolves</ENAMEX> which turned out to be an extremely extremely good movie
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen that yet i i i hear we
 		a whole bunch of us were going to go see it the
 		it's it's playing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> actually in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks</TIMEX> i guess so we're going to go see that but you enjoyed that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's something that uh my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lives over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> and i was telling him about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> and he said well i'll wait until it comes out on uh tape and and rent the the video and i said no this is not one that you want to do that with
 	
 	
 		that's what i heard  yeah
 	
 	
 		it's uh the the scenery and the the landscape and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that they're in needs a big screen it's just beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in in the hills and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and the buffalo and the whole thing it's just
 		uh just an amazing amazing picture
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard it it it's not one for the videos
 	
 	
 		no it's it's one i think well you know every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and then you find one that you say yeah this is my favorite movie well this this is the one for me this time
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah what have you been to lately
 	
 	
 		um let's see well  um this is almost sort of funny i was just at um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> and i went to see Out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> which is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Seagal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because uh we're both big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">karate fans</ENAMEX> so we wanted to see what this is like and uh wasn't very impressed with actually
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		is that right that was
 	
 	
 		yeah i wasn't i mean i've i've seen his other movies and he i i just think he's pretty good but uh this movie it's just i'm convinced now he can't act so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh how's his karate
 	
 	
 		oh his his his his karate's been pretty good i think in this one it wasn't so good i generally um movies like that scare me though i'd i'd be just fine without them because you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come running out wanting to beat each other up and you
 	
 	
 		well they they do they get i remember when we used to go to uh see well i remember when <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grand Prix</ENAMEX> came out when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and and some others movies like that we wanted to jump in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and and race
 	
 	
 		fighting
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i suspect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> what they see is bound to be what they want to do when they get out of it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well that that was number one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> actually too so
 		so it was a little bit uh i was thinking wow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> must be
 		
 
 		into crime movies again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but but in the middle of that conversation we sort of picked an um an an interesting point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s number one movie for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> was Ghost
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you saw Ghost or not
 	
 	
 		i did see Ghost yeah
 	
 	
 		except yeah and and and that was that that helped us sort of feel good about you know about ourselves and about that everyone around us in that
 		in that um at least at least if everyone's if if if everyone's running around seeing karate movies and stuff like that at least they're still going to see the real good movies you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ghost</ENAMEX> was one of those that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't think was going to be any good and it turned out to be an excellent movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it was it was i was absolutely enthralled by it
 	
 	
 		i i
 		i've forgotten the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name who was in it who had the lead role yeah and i especially like him uh
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Swayze</ENAMEX>
 		yeah he's he's very good
 	
 	
 		he's a really a really good guy
 		other than that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dances with Wolves</ENAMEX> seems like to be the the only thing i've seen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several months</TIMEX> to have any uh
 	
 	
 		really i'm trying to think what else i've seen recently  what else have we seen recently  oh you know what's pretty cute actually
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Defending Your Life</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right i've i've seen the ads for it but i'm not really sure what it's about
 	
 	
 		have you have you heard of this
 		yeah um i actually hadn't heard anything about it and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> called up and said do you want to go see this movie
 		and and they said it starred um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they told me and i thought what a strange combination <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that is a strange combination
 	
 	
 		well actually it starred out that it that it's actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so  so it's lot better um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> you you probably know is uh you know so it it was a strange combination but it turned out to be a very cute movie i mean the whole premise is that they go out and they they die
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and and they have to
 	
 	
 		both of them
 	
 	
 		right both of them are dead and they happen to meet in this this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> um this this sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where you're set up such that you know they go and they decide if you can move up to the next level
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you've ever read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Livingston Seagull</ENAMEX> but it's something like that it's something like that they sort of move up to levels and and they have to decide whether or not they're good enough and as it turns out you know it's uh they meet there and fall in love and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so you can guess the rest of the plot it actually it's it's really funny because they run through you know they do it they have them do is sit down and see scenes of their lives
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and then defend it well i guess that's where the title comes from then
 	
 	
 		and that's pretty good actually
 		yeah and it oh that's that's what you do you actually have to go up there and you have a they have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a defense and a prosecution and they have the
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s job is to make sure you don't move up a level and the defense's job is to make sure that you you do you know and it's uh it's a neat little story actually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it is it's
 	
 	
 		i was i was i was i i went i went in thinking it'll be okay not great and then i actually came away thinking it was really pretty good so
 	
 	
 		yeah it's funny we've got a couple of movies out recently <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghost and Defending Your Life</ENAMEX> that have to do with
 		uh after life i guess and it kind of makes you wonder i'm a also besides working at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at here <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Texas</ENAMEX> and working on a master's in communication
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's the behavioral science part of communercation and i i i think about these things and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to define their own world view
 		and uh what what exactly do we you know do we see about this world or why are we so fascinated with the other world is it just supposed to be better
 	
 	
 		hm
 		the other world yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes i think we we think it is and we like those things that way
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm i'm sure because it seems like it certainly would would would explain the preoccupation with it lately i mean but i suspect there's always been a preoccupation with that sort of thing in movies
 	
 	
 		well it has all all the way through history there's uh i guess if you want to call it mysticism or the occult or whatever it's always fascinating i guess because we don't know and there's no real way of finding out well there's only one way of finding out
 	
 	
 		right well
 		well did you ever see um Flatliners
 	
 	
 		no i did uh did not the a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> next to me saw it and she really liked it
 	
 	
 		that
 		that that's probably one of those ones that you know
 		it's it's on video now i think and it's probably probably worth seeing on video um actually we really enjoyed it but it was it was it was also right along the same lines i mean they they would go ahead and kill themselves for a few <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to see what happens and
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		yeah
 		yeah they say uh she said that this was uh almost believable that could really happen you know you get the medical profession doing these kinds of things and it you know you never know
 	
 	
 		almost yeah i i it's it's it's a little far fetched to find a bunch of medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> doing it but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it was um it was it was odd enough you know and the and they didn't just sort of make it silly it was you know it was done fairly well i think so act ually i actually enjoyed that as well
 	
 	
 		i
 		yeah i like it when they will will do something and not get too silly i've been disappointed in some movies that
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um they don't know how to end it it seems like so then they get crazy and and it doesn't end like the story has been going
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		the story just sort of keeps going and going yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i guess that covers our topic uh the
 	
 	
 		yeah great well it was nice nice talking to you alrighty bye-bye
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	