
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so how do you keep up with the news
 	
 	
 		most of it is TV
 	
 	
 		um do you read the newspaper
 	
 	
 		yes i do we get a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> and then i get uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		um what daily
 	
 	
 		it's the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlotte Observer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte Observer</ENAMEX> um
 		is that there in your city
 	
 	
 		yes right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> gives financial news and other information i'm interested in
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		do you think you get anything from your local newspaper
 	
 	
 		yes but it's usually after the fact uh as far as the major topics because most of the other has been on TV don't you agree
 	
 	
 		um yeah i don't i'm not exactly sure how good the national news is though how accurate exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh i think uh during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East Crisis</ENAMEX> there was a problem in terms of too quick to try to get a scoop and not checking facts out and i think that's probably a a good relevant uh
 		uh fear of all of it yeah i didn't see a movie a long time ago but it was about the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that um
 	
 	
 		fear
 	
 	
 		tried to influence the world and i i have a feeling that they're much more into themselves sometimes than they are into what the world um is ready to hear they create news
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like they're not really trying to report the news they are trying to report how the news affects them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think so too
 	
 	
 		or where they're at with the news or something along those lines
 		uh
 	
 	
 		radio is sort of a catch up in fact i was um listening to the radio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and that they were reporting on the condition of an of an accident victim
 		and i had already seen on the news about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> before that that accident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> had died but the radio news report was that he was still in intensive care so it's one of those um
 		it the most immediate is TV The others are catch up and fill in
 	
 	
 		yeah a little bit of color or something for
 		the lack of total information that was given on the TV lack they give immediate for the lack of total
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		how do you feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> treats local interest news
 	
 	
 		well
 		rather biasedly i think i believe huh very pro city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> but uh
 		it seems almost as though they don't
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		care about how the national news affects the local area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh i think about other topics too i i'd like to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and sort of look at the front page and find out what is going on in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but it's always the national information that you have to flip through to find out
 		anything special about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and i think that's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and then they give give you just the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> bits and that's it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		and well hell you don't know know those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that died or or what from
 	
 	
 		no the older you get the more you know though
 	
 	
 		well what i mean is do you if your in a strange city you certainly don't know them
 	
 	
 		oh right right yeah that's true what type of work are you in
 	
 	
 		i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay uh that uh is a news worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in itself so you're you would be interested in any news related to it yeah
 	
 	
 		uh yes and yourself
 	
 	
 		oh i'm i'm consulting right now i'm in between jobs so it makes uh it makes a difference i'm i'm interested in many more industries than i used to be just in terms of looking around so it
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand
 	
 	
 		i've been in the oil and gas business and then higher education and um done a few other things including international uh accounting so
 	
 	
 		huh that's interesting i've always considered myself uh
 		how is this best put
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bollfield</ENAMEX> trash
 	
 	
 		oh okay  uh uh
 	
 	
 		grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Texas</ENAMEX> thank you
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i understand that i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> so i i know the area very well
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		um so do you think our local do you think our national news tells us anything important
 	
 	
 		oh yes they'll they'll tell you a lot that's important but the trouble is the value do you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> and some of those other
 	
 	
 		um yeah i i i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i
 		i wonder sometimes where they get those topics you know some of the topics are very very good and others are like uh who who who dreamed this subject up you know
 	
 	
 		almost religiously
 		well and
 	
 	
 		and far as affecting a national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> i wonder sometimes
 	
 	
 		and more importantly than that i wonder how
 		the other side of the story is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and of course they're not going to tell the other side of the story and they're not going to tell it accurately
 	
 	
 		no
 		but i do enjoy we are here temporarily i enjoyed having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> so that i could tune in the news any time i wanted to and not wait for network broadcasting
 	
 	
 		uh we don't we don't have cable
 	
 	
 		okay it's it's a good addition because i think they're
 		they have a lot of news obviously all the time and there's not the pressure then
 	
 	
 		yeah we've watched little bits here and there during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf Crisis</ENAMEX> and we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		the
 	
 	
 		i didn't exactly i wasn't exactly sure how accurate it was either
 	
 	
 		oh i think it it too is under pressure
 	
 	
 		and it seemed as though during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf Crisis</ENAMEX> it might have been under pressure from
 		the incorrect side
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh yes it was there are games played
 	
 	
 		i i'm not sure how to phrase that
 		uh delicately
 	
 	
 		psychological warfare is a big factor all the way around um
 		it's been it's been a big factor for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years</TIMEX> but this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first uh first</NUMEX> time we have seen it so quickly and so close up
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		i i didn't feel comfy you know i you know you always hear about the warm fuzzy feeling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i kept watching that
 		be it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> in a bar or or or or local news at home or federal news at home or or see uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we don't subscribe to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> paper we subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> paper okay
 	
 	
 		and uh but on occasion more than occasionally we'll buy the local paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		that warm fuzzy that we're talking about i never could get that warm fuzzy feeling in the pit of my stomach about
 		are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really telling me the truth or more importantly all the truth
 	
 	
 		yeah i think all the truth is is the big issue they obviously had to be telling a lot of truth because they were there reporting firsthand but in terms of
 	
 	
 		well i'd suspect that to be true but you couldn't prove it to me
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and and
 		most importantly i
 		couldn't believe any of those people
 		they didn't
 		seem believable
 	
 	
 		did you just switch back and forth between programs
 	
 	
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> um well we have the independent here and we've got the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> majors and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and we watched
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> of those and on more than occasionally i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> that had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> running around the clock
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		still i got this feeling as though
 		from these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or eight</NUMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> i had that something was missing
 	
 	
 		uh i think they they withhold when it's advantageous both sides both sides and i think when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> announced afterwards on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> Show
 	
 	
 		and
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Storming Norman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes that um he knew you know what to expect out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
 		that he was playing games you know and and they both were i think that's all part of warfare is to play games
 	
 	
 		oh of course and you've got to expect that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i had the feeling
 		that no matter who i listened to it wasn't that they weren't telling me the truth i felt that someone was lying to me
 		and
 		there's nothing there still at this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that i can put my finger on and say oh here's where they lied to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just a feeling
 	
 	
 		yeah well let's hope we don't have to go through that again
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes wouldn't it be wonderful if there were no more wars
 	
 	
 		oh that would be nice i hope we never never get to but i'm afraid um human nature is such that somewhere there'll be a fanatic that will start something
 	
 	
 		and more importantly
 		wouldn't it be nice in this land of the free and home of the brave
 		if there were never again be any misinformation
 	
 	
 		oh yes oh yes
 		
 		
 	