
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right i i think our experience of camping is i i am the the passive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> i get things ready and then i enjoy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a good camper and so they he manages the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and they do the work and i have fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well uh uh your you said your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was grown uh all grown up now how about when they were younger did you go camping take them camping
 	
 	
 		that's when we camped the most when i thinks it's a marvelous activity for younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because uh i it seems like i would go through a period of time where i just uh was really overworked you know and and getting out into nature and relaxing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> do a good share of the work you know and the part that i did was more fun than uh than labor because they did the the running and toting chores and i just helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and kind of organize you know
 	
 	
 		yeah but even
 		even cooking over an open fire is a little more fun isn't it
 	
 	
 		it is isn't it it isn't have what kinds of things have you tried
 		have you done uh uh uh the big pot cooking
 	
 	
 		oh oh uh well
 		it was really my ex who did the the uh uh the cooking back when we first started
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we found that the you know what was one one great handy things was this uh uh uh hamburger helper
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		because all you needed was a big frying pan you dumped everything in together
 	
 	
 		big frying pan
 	
 	
 		and it was enough for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> of us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of us
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting you know interesting enough uh the food part was kind of uh important thing in our camping uh when my oldest son
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of us
 	
 	
 		uh always at the beginning i did all the shopping and everything but the the neat breakthrough was when my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> took his uh
 		uh cooking merit badge in and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> was the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camper</ENAMEX> who ate beef <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Stroganoff</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i mean you know he did it up really good  and so uh after he took that merit badge he did all the shopping and preparing getting ready for it
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		it was it was a marvelous experience because after that then all i had to do was uh follow the instructions you know and do and we did a lot of interesting kinds of things like i would take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn bread</ENAMEX> and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cook</ENAMEX> a pan inside of a pan over a over a camp uh stove and it works real good it's like an oven
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well
 	
 	
 		just put uh put a thing on it
 	
 	
 		cooking was our secondary interest i mean
 	
 	
 		what did you like to do most
 	
 	
 		well really just commune with nature
 	
 	
 		that's neat isn't it
 	
 	
 		we started out uh well we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> at the time
 		and we early in life we discovered that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all going on vacation gets to be very very expensive
 	
 	
 		right i agree
 	
 	
 		so my ex decided we're going to try camping and she went out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> on the spur of the moment and bought a tent
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that's how we got started we did it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 		well now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> is there is there times are there times of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> when it's very comfortable to camp
 		or is it always kind of hot
 	
 	
 		well yes uh yes and no i mean um yes in the winter time yes it's it gets kind of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">chilly</TIMEX> or it can get chilly but uh there's really no time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that you can't go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh is that true now now we're we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> now and you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because
 		yes i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay uh we have not camped a great deal here because uh a good share of the time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> time it's too hot really to be very comfortable camping
 	
 	
 		well it just depends on where you go for instance if you went down to the sea shore it would be wonderful a nice breeze blowing in from the water
 	
 	
 		i guess
 		yeah yeah we have done that
 		but but we camped mostly when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were little we were in we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh where abouts
 	
 	
 		and we uh in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allendale</ENAMEX> and uh and uh Waldwick it's just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twelve miles</NUMEX> south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> border
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we'd go up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adirondacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and it was so you know pick your own uh blueberries and make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blueberry pancakes</ENAMEX> for breakfast  uh also go ahead
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes yes i come i come from up in that area i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> myself
 	
 	
 		oh are you where did you live
 	
 	
 		a little town called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuckaho</ENAMEX> over by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">White Plains</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah i know that i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> who lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">White Plains</ENAMEX> that's a that's a neat area but it's a that is a particularly neat area for camping
 	
 	
 		well that i wouldn't know i left there when i was quite young
 	
 	
 		because
 		yeah it is neat though because there are lots of lakes fairly near by you don't have to go very far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and there's uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> and lot of uh hiking sort of things and and we had uh collapsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> which we uh clipper little clipper sail boat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we would sail and and uh did a lot of camping that way
 	
 	
 		well uh me i outgrew uh sleeping bags and uh tents
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i now have a motor home
 	
 	
 		oh do you we've gotten out a time or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> on a rented basis and it's fun too i think
 	
 	
 		well i live in mine yes
 	
 	
 		do you that's neat so you kind of uh uh an everyday camper
 	
 	
 		uh well yes i consider myself what they call a full-timer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		a full time camper well now are you living alone now or
 	
 	
 		yeah the
 		yes well just me and my dog
 	
 	
 		you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog huh  hey</ENAMEX> that sounds great well we don't we don't camp quite as much as we used to but uh i still think it's a great way to spend a time with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yes definitely
 	
 	
 		and enjoy nature and uh kind of wipe out the stress of everyday life i'd always
 	
 	
 		nothing like the fresh outdoors
 	
 	
 		right i'd always come home just relaxed and uh comfortable and ready to go at it again so it was a neat activity
 		good to talk to you tell me your name again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> uh-huh are you uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> all right
 		yes yes we've been here we're we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> but we've been here about uh eighteen years
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well that's where we that's where i am Plano
 	
 	
 		are you are you how about that well we're all lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> up this way
 	
 	
 		it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right good to talk to you all right all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	