
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> hi
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 		hi i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Crow</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nice to meet you
 	
 	
 		and i uh made a mistake i went ahead and punched one so we're on
 	
 	
 		oh okay all righty
 	
 	
 		okay the trial by jury
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh my thinking on the uh uh
 		unanimous decision
 		i think they should only i think they ought to change that to only in death penalties
 		that it be a unanimous unanimous i think in the others they ought to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not a majority but say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fourths or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because too many times they get hung up
 	
 	
 		yes and then there's a mistrial right
 	
 	
 		and there's a mistrial
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i agree with that i really do i you know there're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kind sides to everything and and i
 		you know i was i've never been on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i've been interviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple of</NUMEX> times but never got picked and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just really have mixed feelings about it because you know i i'm not sure that i'm for the death penalty and yet when i think if something happened to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> if somebody you know killed them or
 		brutally beat them or whatever i uh and killed them i i don't know that i would could be able to say that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know it's i have mixed feelings so if if i were to ever serve on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i would have to be honest about that i'm not sure that i could give somebody the death penalty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and so i'm not you know i agree with you i think that uh that um
 		a majority for uh you know a less severe case would be okay but i think for a death penalty it would be have to be everybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh i'm not so sure that well
 		a it would cost a lot more but i'm not so sure that
 		life in life without parole is not the stiffer penalty penalty than the death penalty
 	
 	
 		i agree
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		i've always said that i you know i i think that would be the stiffer penalty but we have such a problem with over crowding right now that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah plus it uh it would cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> quite a bit more money
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		exactly and and yet on the other hand you i feel so badly when i see people
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		when i read about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that have gotten out when they've raped somebody or beat somebody or aggravated assault or whatever and they're out in you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that's criminal because most most chances are they'll do it again but they have to let them out in order to make room for other people
 	
 	
 		make room for others
 	
 	
 		and if you they also mentioned about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> you know doing the verdict well
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i had an experience with that because my i have a brother-in-law that was um did made a mistake and he uh
 		was working as a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner planner</ENAMEX> and they the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> he was working for did a few things that was against the law and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX> found you know found out and prosecuted them and he ended up going to jail
 		and he's a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and the bottom line was that he was greedy he money and all that stuff but
 		when when he went to jail i saw the the side that i had never seen before because we would go and visit him
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> was the one that was  not lenient with him he really throw threw the book at him even though he was he had so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character witnesses</ENAMEX> and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that came forth for him and
 		he was tough and so sometimes probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> might be a little bit more severe severe than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i that's the problem i have with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> giving sentence
 	
 	
 		because don't
 	
 	
 		is that there's not consistency
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it varies even from state to state and even within state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i remember i was watching uh i think it was either <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Copy</ENAMEX>
 		or Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX> one of those programs <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and this poor uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> had bought some land
 		and had cleared the land there was uh uh uh fill there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had use thrown old tires and junk and everything else in the land
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they prosecuted this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and fined him like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> or something like that for disturbing water lands
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		and he cleaned it up it was even cleaner than when he bought it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		isn't that awful
 	
 	
 		and it's just you know ridiculous
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and you know i also feel like if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has has the last say
 		i i don't care what job you're in you know what social service type job i'm a teacher
 		after a while unless you really watch it you begin become hardened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s problems and they don't quite mean as much to you you detached yourself from them and i think that might happen with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that they they wouldn't be too lenient with certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because they're they're so hardened to the fact that you know there's a reason why all this happened and they don't want to hear the story anymore they just want them to you know go to jail or be punished
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i agree with you i'm not too sure i would like to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> be the sole
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegate</ENAMEX> of uh of a a sentence
 	
 	
 		right
 		i just uh like you say i just i just hear too many cases of
 		of somebody committing a small or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a minor crime and getting a much stiffer penalty penalty than someone else that commits a major crime and gets off lightly
 	
 	
 		yeah and especially and i hate to say this but especially if he's a minority or she's a minority
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a tendency to automatically sentence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> or any kind of an immigrant before they've even heard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's sad that
 		oh sad commentary on our times but it happens
 	
 	
 		and uh also they didn't say anything to talk about it but uh
 		the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can hire the the uh
 		top notch lawyers
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the poor folk
 		is more or less at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s mercy
 	
 	
 		exactly and and the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get off the hook
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's really is sad
 		but have you ever served on a trial on a jury
 	
 	
 		but i guess i
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">madam ma'am</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you ever served on a jury
 	
 	
 		i've got uh i got a summons before but i never got selected i was like you i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> down at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> sitting there
 	
 	
 		yeah but didn't get selected
 	
 	
 		and didn't get selected
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i always thought that it would be real interesting but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of the ones that i was came down for was had to do with um
 		drunken driving and um
 		you know i don't think i could be partial in a case like that i just i just uh feel like that that you just shouldn't drink and drive and and i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i could not be lenient at all and they asked me a couple of questions and i think
 		you know they came to the conclusion i couldn't you know i would i'd probably throw the book at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that that harmed somebody drinking and driving so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah the only one i i got uh not selected but as a as a uh perspective jury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> was uh a uh rear end collision
 	
 	
 		row uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and of course i guess there was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there and they called them down
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they asked if anybody had been ever rear ended to hold their hand up and i had
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh i think they
 	
 	
 		right away they
 	
 	
 		right away they said well this guy
 		won't
 		give a uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		won't will be partial
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure that's true i'm sure that's true
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well and it's the law is is very tricky and and we all come from different backgrounds and we come from different experiences and so we bring to that jury
 		different perspectives which in a way is good because if we all thought the same way a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that was uh
 		possibly innocent or possibly not as guilty as you know as
 		as uh you might think would you know get the book thrown at them or whatever because we're all we all feel the same way but
 		i know that i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have been on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> that have been deadlocked and it's no fun i mean because
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i wouldn't want to be sequestered sequestered for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and be locked up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> or a motel or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		no
 		that's right and especially hard on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are not along going along with the majority because the the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> get so angry because they want to go on with their life they want to get out of there
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and if you don't truly believe what you think and stick to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> it can be awful uncomfortable
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		and uh i guess uh i'm fortunately in working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> should you get hung on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> you do get get your normal pay yeah
 	
 	
 		oh is that right oh that's good
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		yes same with i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>  and and we do too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so which is great is great
 	
 	
 		it would be hard on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that uh
 		if he did not get  that pay  to get  locked up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> on a hung <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and be out
 		the time on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> plus missing his pay check
 	
 	
 		oh wouldn't that be awful yeah that would be terrible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i guess i guess it's like like a lot of other things in in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> uh
 		it's not perfect but it's better than anything else is
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah
 	
 	
 		that's out there
 	
 	
 		you're right you're right and we just kind of have to
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		to go along with it and do the best job we can if we're called it is a duty a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know try to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty when they're  you know and i would never do that because i feel like hey we live in a country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		where we have this you know privilege and i would never that's my duty to be as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and if i got called i'd do it but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't feel that way
 	
 	
 		right
 		
  
 		yeah
 		
  
 		yeah all you got to do is read in the paper every once in a while and see where somebody went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and had a car accident and got thrown in jail and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> there
 	
 	
 		oh gosh isn't that awful that'd be awful um yeah we're lucky to live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> there's no doubt about it
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		
  
 		yeah
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		but let's see i really don't have anything else to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i i believe i'm about uh
 		exhausted my
 	
 	
 		okay well it was good to talk to you all right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay you too and you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	