
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> or work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> or both both are you a TIer
 	
 	
 		both
 		yes
 	
 	
 		are you at work right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so am i in building which <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> are you
 	
 	
 		well are you Summit or are you uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm Spring i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh this is fun what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> are you in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm building uh one
 	
 	
 		oh i'm building <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> at least we found something  different  that's i've never had a call
 	
 	
 		who've
 		that like that neither have i
 	
 	
 		no isn't that funny i usually get some place i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> the last time i called i think
 	
 	
 		right that's funny
 	
 	
 		that is funny so the weather
 	
 	
 		so how's the building how's the weather in building two
 	
 	
 		the weather in building <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is cold  it's been cold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>'s not bad not bad typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI Spring</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> listen i got me doing it typical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas Spring</ENAMEX> are you a native to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ugh
 		oh yeah
 		no no i'm i'm a transplant from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from
 		so what do you think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> weather
 	
 	
 		not as nice as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how long have you been here
 	
 	
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> now i've been here long enough pretty long so
 	
 	
 		oh okay you
 		you you you know about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> then
 	
 	
 		yes oh i've been through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of those
 	
 	
 		okay there's no surprises left
 	
 	
 		right right a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> try to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> for you know if they're going to go out of state for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX> that's the time to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		good idea real good idea
 	
 	
 		yeah we went up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> this last uh Summer during that time and it was like you know eighty degrees up there it was beautiful it was nice to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's that's the even even farther away
 	
 	
 		that is really nice it is so cool you wear a jacket you know or or
 	
 	
 		even in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> time huh
 	
 	
 		yeah or keep one handy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it's it rains a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		uh it they call it their liquid gold
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		um
 	
 	
 		but it you know you get sunshine and it's lovely and then it rains just enough to keep everything nice and moist and very green and blooming oh my goodness it's pretty well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> isn't bad
 	
 	
 		green
 		um
 		right
 		no no
 	
 	
 		not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right i i i have to think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> to try to remember what it was what's it supposed to like this time of year
 	
 	
 		Spring is nice
 	
 	
 		yeah because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> we usually get a lot of rain
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> you you know it'll seem the the news the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Taft</ENAMEX>
 		you know on the local news he's says oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> we typically get a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and we've had this many inches and you know we're right on target you know and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and just seem like we were getting a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> but i you have to it's hard to remember twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX> what it was like but i guess yeah i wish i just wish it wouldn't come all at once  and it and
 	
 	
 		oh we always
 		we we always do though
 		uh it
 		that's right and then we get all that heat
 	
 	
 		right well it's just that you know when it rains it rains you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> you get these nice lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> you know nothing really downpours you know like downpours like you have here you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> we had some hail the biggest hail i've ever seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> yeah when i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh you got into that bad stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah we got hail the size of marbles
 		i mean just just so noisy hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the glass on the windows it didn't break anything but
 		we went out there afterwards and there's ice balls the size of marbles all over our lawn
 	
 	
 		isn't that strange
 	
 	
 		i know i just you pick them up you know and they're they're perfectly round you know and i go gee how did they form you know and have so perfect like that
 	
 	
 		isn't i
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i think that's one of the strange strange things and you very seldom see it though
 	
 	
 		right right you i've i've seen hail you know but they're usually the size you know of a
 		tiny tiny pebbles you know really small
 		you know but this was uh really large
 	
 	
 		so it had come it's a drop of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that had come through quite a few rain clouds apparently is that correct
 	
 	
 		uh uh i don't know how hail's formed tell you the truth you don't think it's cold enough you know to
 	
 	
 		i think i think that's
 	
 	
 		to
 	
 	
 		it's not on the ground but in in the clouds it is
 	
 	
 		right must be
 		i guess and it doesn't i think you know all that falling would warm it up and melt it but it maybe that's what rounds it i don't know but tumbling
 	
 	
 		i was dumb i was in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> for a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on business and uh i had called back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and i called back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX> was babysitting my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and dogs
 		said something to the effect of now we've made the national news don't get upset and don't worry it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> where all the bad weather is i said okay
 		you know and i watched the news and i thought <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha ha</NUMEX> that's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> that's not Plano i don't have anything to worry about i was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> heading back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> before it dawned on me stupid you own property in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		felt so dumb finally i got home found out my property was okay there was no problem with it but i guess you just tend to think of of where your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is you know and nothing else
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		right
 		right and close to that what's it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Duck Creek</ENAMEX> that runs through part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> that's the part that always seems to to get hardest hit when there's there's the hard rain the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">the creek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">overflows</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		a lot of houses a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> around that creek seem to to get flooded the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and stuff around that area get a lot of flooding
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that i bought is close to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Firewheel</ENAMEX> Firewheel
 		Firewheel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it's just going to be blocks off of that new highway <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one ninety</NUMEX> that's going through
 	
 	
 		right that's where i live close to that
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah uh uh not quite uh i don't live in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firewheel</ENAMEX> division
 		but i live close by there in north far north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> yeah they're supposed to it it's getting built up you know with more new new shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and and things you know it's a fairly new area
 	
 	
 		is that a nice area
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh
 		and they're supposed to be building a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> somewhere close by by the next by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety three or ninety four</NUMEX> or something a brand new mall
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		not too far away from that area so it should be nice
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that i bought was really really nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Firewheel Estates</ENAMEX> there whatever uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yes yes really really nice home very pretty uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but you're not living there right now
 	
 	
 		no i'm going to lease it it's it's investment property
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		i see
 	
 	
 		but it is really it's a very nice place uh i i would cheerfully live there at you know of course it's not my home and
 		and i've lived in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and you know i've got everything just exactly like i want it but if i were to live some place else it certainly meets my standards it's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i like it
 	
 	
 		right
 		it should
 		yeah that's a nice area is it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no it's not it's off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and i'll be honest with you i have i'm going to have to get a map to figure out exactly where is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> versus where my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		it's but it's in the estates that adjoin it
 	
 	
 		yeah right right well that's a nice area
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		that really is a nice area when they get that highway finished finished you can hop on that and get anywhere you need to go fairly quick
 	
 	
 		yeah that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one ninety</NUMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one ninety</NUMEX> is just going to be the most outermost outermost loop around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right another belt line just uh farther out go
 	
 	
 		right just continue to do that
 	
 	
 		right right right
 	
 	
 		where are you from in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern California</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> younger and
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> area and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anaheim</ENAMEX> right now
 		lived up in in north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand Oaks</ENAMEX>
 		area where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> have their training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> or used to anyways
 	
 	
 		i've been through all of that uh there is an area beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand Oaks</ENAMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> that's really an eerie strange looking area with boulders uh i wonder they're not really hills they're more like just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		was it
 	
 	
 		huge boulders with very little vegetation
 	
 	
 		huh i'm not familiar with what is it along the coast or
 		or more inland
 	
 	
 		uh very
 		well you know it may be a little bit more inland that is one of the strangest areas i have ever seen
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh i had to go up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> on business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		out there huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we went up that coastline and i was just amazed how unusual that looks
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		here hang on just a second i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> map let me just quick
 	
 	
 		yeah they have some pretty nice weather out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simi Valley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simi Valley</ENAMEX> okay i know where that is
 	
 	
 		yes
 		beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand Oaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Simi Valley</ENAMEX> is i've been out there before sure
 	
 	
 		you don't think that's strange looking
 	
 	
 		i didn't notice anything strange i guess
 	
 	
 		oh okay maybe i'm maybe i'm used to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		about it
 		maybe Texas the way
 	
 	
 		the elevation is extremely high
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's got curving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> on it but but the it's just a strange landscape there's very little vegetation
 	
 	
 		huh i didn't i don't remember seeing that part of it i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Simi Valley</ENAMEX> yeah it's just a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> and they've built some new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> out to that area and things lately
 	
 	
 		right it's a far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can get in and out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> faster easier
 	
 	
 		maybe it's a place i went to it was uh far extreme thought we'd never find the place
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it was interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that sounds interesting
 	
 	
 		because we went out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand Oaks</ENAMEX> and on up through that way
 	
 	
 		right right right i i know exactly i i i lived that area it's a nice area out there i love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand Oaks</ENAMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i don't know things things you just have a less a variety i guess it's
 		i think i don't think it's quite as green you know it it's green with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and things out here but it's just
 	
 	
 		oh it's green sometime
 	
 	
 		yeah but it's just you know i don't know
 	
 	
 		well it doesn't stay green you know the really and and in all honesty i i know this sounds like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> story all honesty you haven't seen the hottest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> if you've only been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> we haven't had a really bad one
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i i
 		i missed that one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty or eighty two or eighty one</NUMEX> that had the heat wave
 	
 	
 		uh it was maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> because we bought our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty one</NUMEX> and we built a pool in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 		
 	