
 
     		
 	
 		uh i guess i've had to return something but i'm can't can't decide mostly it's been because i didn't like the color
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or um i'm not sure whether i've had to return that many things uh
 	
 	
 		well i'm having a problem right now with a computer that we've just returned so for me it's actually a pretty good topic
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 		okay good so we'll talk about that some
 	
 	
 		yeah well we could talk about that and then we could talk a bit about um just quality of products in general if you they're better or worse like if they last longer or something like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		okay i'm going to let you kind of lead the pack because you sound like you're i let let me tell you just a little bit about myself i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i did all that shopping and what not but for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> i've had eye problem and i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cornea transplants
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shopping</ENAMEX> is no fun anymore  i can't
 	
 	
 		i can imagine well actually i don't
 	
 	
 		see good enough you know and uh it's hard to tell what i'm doing and it's just aggravating oh i just thought of something we have to return  all right it'll it'll come to us okay  are you ready
 	
 	
 		you can't read labels and you can't
 		good
 		there you go
 		okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie</ENAMEX> all right
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right uh tell me about your computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie</ENAMEX> i think that sounds fascinating
 	
 	
 		well we bought a computer because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> needed to use it to do some
 		work for a consulting project and we called up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and asked them details on it we bought it sort of your not a name brand because the clones are so much cheaper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we called up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that somebody else we knew had dealt with and they were very happy with the system and they felt they've gotten a good price and we went in we explained what we needed and yes we had to go across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington Bridge</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>  to get
 		to meet these people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we went there we told them about the stuff and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said
 		uh that the computer would fit our needs and we  these things won't make any sense to you probably but he told us there were we need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user positions</ENAMEX> to put our own equipment in the computer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and it's called a user <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> or slots is what it's called
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he told us there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two sixteen</TIMEX> bit slots and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eight</NUMEX> bit sorry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two sixteen sixteen four sixteen</TIMEX> bit slots and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eight</NUMEX> bit slots available for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> and we can put full size cards in there and so we said great you know we'll buy it and we put in our order
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week later</TIMEX> we went back and picked up the computer and then we got it home and tried to put our own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> in it and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> slot we could put it in
 	
 	
 		oh lovely
 	
 	
 		and at this point we only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> board so it wasn't so bad so we used it a bit but we tried to figure out whether we could put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in because we really need to be able to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> now now the computer was supposed to have two
 	
 	
 		and
 		well it has them but the problem is that you can't put the type of card that we need to put in it in it
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and even though they told us in advance that you could they told us there'd be no problem because you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> just doesn't really know
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		in some ways it has more to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who sold it they probably didn't know what they were talking about
 	
 	
 		right that's completely it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> didn't know so we went back in and we struck an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they'd change
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	

 		the casing it comes in so that we could put in extra boards
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		okay so they did that and we said are you sure that this will work we don't want you to go through the work and then find out that this doesn't really work anyway and etcetera and they're and they were doing it at their own costs and so we said fine
 		and we went back and we talked to the technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time and things like that and then we come
 		we get the computer home my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> goes to pick it up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and we couldn't go get it sooner because i just had the baby and  you know life's just a little bit complicated and uh he goes and gets it brings it home <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all they're missing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		components of it like cables so you can't really test it out and then <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thing we still can't put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> in because they have other things blocking where we need to do it
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and see now we're dealing with having to bring it back again and they say they can you know do something different and change some connectors and we hope so but it's a hassle you know you know it's just this problem with sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just not knowing
 	
 	
 		yeah it really is
 	
 	
 		what goes on
 	
 	
 		right and time and so much time goes past before you finally get any kind of satisfaction i think that's the worst part uh i
 	
 	
 		right
 		so well actually some things are pretty good with that because i put it on a gold credit card and i just called the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and explained to them the situation and they said well you don't have to pay for it yet
 	
 	
 		now that's an advantage isn't it it really is i think uh uh there's a lot not to be said for credit but that's one thing to be said for credit it how it gets you some muscle where you need it
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		yeah
 		right and so you know
 	
 	
 		and i think that's really really important
 	
 	
 		well because these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> if they um give us a hard time we're going to say you look you know if you if you can't fix this to our satisfaction we're just returning the computer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		and if we do that i just tell the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> don't pay the charge even though they've already paid it but they'll just you know undo the credit that they did to them
 	
 	
 		that's right no
 		yeah they will
 		that's right they will they will put the kind of clout on them that you can't really do yeah we <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hal</ENAMEX> bought me uh uh small uh well uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		and
 	
 	
 		little jam box kind of thing so i'd my i have my ninety <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> living with us and so i uh she doesn't remember anything but to keep her entertained music and some of these things do help and i thought well if i had uh a nice a nice little uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tape recorder you know so that i could put some good music on in there for her every once in a while and then also so that i can uh uh copy uh
 		parts off i i do some musicals and things like this and if i can copy sections off that i can use someplace so i figured well this'll be good well the first uh uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i turned it on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i was recording and the next thing i knew the tape was chewed up in the thing
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		okay so after that then you couldn't get a  you couldn't get a tape to play at the right speed in that side
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then on the other side when i when i uh i loaned loaned it to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> to take it over to a to a videotaping they were doing and uh she says it's wrong too because the little thing pokes out too far and so you can't
 		you you can't get it to run the right the right way either so uh yeah so i i wish i could tell you i really don't know which brand it is uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what brand is it do you know
 		but i was wondering like you know in our case we we knew we were buying a copy we weren't buying an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PC and i was wondering if you
 	
 	
 		yeah no i think this is a i think this is maybe a name brand and i suspect that it's probably just a fluke you know i have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and everything and we're going to get just take it back but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you buy it at some major store
 	
 	
 		yeah i think just uh just uh one of the major major i think it was a you know i don't i think it was uh
 		you know like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlands</ENAMEX> or something like this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlands</ENAMEX> because it's obviously a chain down there that i don't know up here nope
 	
 	
 		do they have Highlands up there
 		don't they well this is it was a regular uh electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> store you know so i don't think i don't think there'll be too much problem but i i guess i'm not sure whether i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things are not made as well i think they deliberately sometimes
 		um
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of things are not made as well
 	
 	
 		don't you what what for instance what are you
 	
 	
 		um oh well
 		gosh it's hard to think of an exact example but i think that um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they just get they're getting a kind of a attitude of not
 	
 	
 		i just yeah i just have well i like electronic stuff you know for one thing i know their work you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i think are not made as well as they could be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well cars
 		yeah yeah i think that's right the fact that
 	
 	
 		um because i they want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to replace it after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right the fact that they that they have have competition with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and whatnot sometimes uh dwells on a fact that
 		you know uh i've had i've known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyotas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that have had almost no repair work to do on them well they may cost a little more but they don't have to take them to the shop every other day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> and i loved it my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> did really well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it does the they do a good job so part of it is that we need to develop more of a of a pride in
 		in uh the kinds of things we do so we make them better
 	
 	
 		good
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it kind of has to start from the top and and go clear or from the bottom maybe and go clear up people
 	
 	
 		well i i think part of the problem comes in sort of shoddy workmanship the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't care about what they're doing you know the whole nobody cares nobody's nobody's really paying
 	
 	
 		no no
 		yeah
 		attitude is is just get me my dollar so i can go do what i want to do and  on what i'm doing right i think that's too bad and it's a shame too because um
 	
 	
 		right give me my paycheck so i can go home
 	
 	
 		when you get right down to it most things there isn't any if you do a good job nobody can pay you enough  there isn't any way to get paid enough
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but if if you do a good job you feel enough satisfaction so whatever you're paid is enough
 	
 	
 		yeah and also i think well i do research and so i'm used to sort of being underpaid for whatever whatever work
 		gets done but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you get satisfaction out of it and
 	
 	
 		that's right i think they underestimate how much how much value the satisfaction is
 	
 	
 		but i think a lot of it you know i think things come both from the
 		uh individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">side</ENAMEX> and also from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company side</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that let
 		give the attitude that well you know you're the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hired so you'll be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one fired and we just want you to do your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> work and we don't really care about you as an individual when you've got that type of attitude on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't care about their work and so
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah it probably it probably basically goes right back into the home home though unfortunately starts with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that
 		you know and so you need to really work hard at helping your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to understand that
 		there is value just in work for itself
 		without any pay you know
 	
 	
 		little value just in whatever you do
 	
 	
 		yeah the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> that the value is in doing it well and
 	
 	
 		doing a good job of it
 		
 		
 	