
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so do you do a lot of cooking in your family
 	
 	
 		um i do some every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then i i work and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> so she usually ends up doing most of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		when i was single we used to always cook around the house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do do you like to cook
 	
 	
 		huh yeah i really like it um there's a few dishes like i i grew up with the um you know having <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> she likes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and stuff so we we definitely have different tastes so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah yeah but that's neat though because you get to have different stuff  yeah i'm not i'm a pretty bad cook  i'm pretty bad my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is really good he put himself through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and uh he's a much better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> than i am so when i was home i still cooked a lot and i was into a lot of vegetarian stuff
 		and now that i went back to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half ago</TIMEX> so one of the things that he took over was the cooking and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are thrilled they're really happy that i don't cook anymore
 	
 	
 		they're like uh preferring it now right
 	
 	
 		yeah they say oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad cook mom</ENAMEX>  let him do it but um
 		so so do you all do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you obviously have one okay you have two
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> um-hum
 		yeah one is uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> and the other is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> oh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the hard part is cooking with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> around because uh
 	
 	
 		i was just going to say makes a difference in what you eat doesn't it or are you not at that stage yet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it does
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we try our hardest to to get them to eat what we eat you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> uh she's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the fast order grill you know she can make uh  she makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> but we like to have one thing you know one likes chicken nuggets the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> like hot dogs
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh my gosh
 		oh my gosh i couldn't yeah
 	
 	
 		and then she makes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">noodles</ENAMEX> with uh with soy uh soy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> or whatever so all things but um yeah our favorite let me think i was thinking of the one recipe that uh
 	
 	
 		boy i couldn't do that i
 	
 	
 		that we made i guess the thing that always turned out the best for us was something we thought looked really fancy but was real easy and that was um
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> scallops uh scallop um
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		it has a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> name it basically means that it has a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese cream sauce</ENAMEX> with it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah what's what is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Jack</ENAMEX> or something scallops saint something or yeah  yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and you pour it over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> yeah uh
 		yeah i can't even remember what the recipe's name is anymore but uh it it basically just ground up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and then uh standard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream sauce</ENAMEX> base and then uh
 	
 	
 		really
 		with scallops
 	
 	
 		the scallops and it sounds sort of funny but it tastes really good
 	
 	
 		no no i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> so we we had um a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> before we moved down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh that sounds delicious to me that sounds great i think we're just thinking of having a uh dinner party we went to this dinner party <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but uh
 	
 	
 		was kind of like a game they had uh a murder mystery and you came dressed as one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and you had to solve the mystery during the dinner
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was really fun and so we we were thinking we wanted to do you know we were going to try doing it ourselves but we're trying to decide what can we serve because at this one the hostess was pretty busy running around
 		trying to get stuff ready for the table and that kind of interrupted the game so
 	
 	
 		right
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		so i was thinking there's this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> bourguignonne recipe that i've tried before that's pretty good and then you can make that ahead and you can just leave it in the pot on a stove until you're ready
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's another thing i have a problem with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she uh she likes to um she doesn't like the beef dishes she likes the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and fish
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 	
 	
 		and like i said we always ate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and uh pork
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know a lot so
 	
 	
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> did too  his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> and they uh always made sure they had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> at the table
 	
 	
 		oh yeah red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> plenty of good red meat
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> could eat a a meal with out any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>'s you know they had you know meatless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> you know  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> wouldn't know what to do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		oh gosh so do you
 	
 	
 		course she grew up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> so you know they they sort of come with the there's a certain amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meatless meals</ENAMEX> you have to have
 	
 	
 		oh they did the
 		that you do right right that's just part of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we didn't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> didn't but when i got into the vegetarian cooking we got kind of used to that but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> always did it kind of grudgingly he never there was dishes that he really enjoyed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		eating there there were several things that he liked but it never was really something that he would have chosen it's just that i cooked so he had to put up with it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so but there was one thing that he couldn't stand and that was soybeans i tried it like once or twice and he just could not eat it so i never i had i was limited i had to make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetarian meals</ENAMEX> without using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soybeans</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's hard to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> content up then
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		huh yeah i like i like them every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> for a change yes it's nice
 	
 	
 		yeah some of the stuff is good but it just it was a tremendous amount of cooking  because you do have to make sure you have the right combinations of different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> to make sure they're complete
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we had little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at the time you know when i was home with them and it it was just so much cooking i couldn't i don't like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and i'm not really that great at it so it just turned out to be too much of a too much  too much cooking
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so well i guess i'll let you get back to feeding your little one there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no uh he's all done  yeah yeah i set him down
 	
 	
 		he's set oh okay okay
 		do you like to bake at all or do you do you get into that's that's
 	
 	
 		yeah we used to do that um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> used to go crazy every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> until my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> like blew up you know  after after he gained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eighty</NUMEX> pounds after coming back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> she stopped doing it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um she used to have you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> sticky buns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> rolls you know every week
 	
 	
 		really no kidding
 	
 	
 		and um the sticky buns of course would last you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four days</TIMEX> and that would be it
 	
 	
 		yeah then be gone i know that's the thing about baking i used to i i don't mind baking at all and i i can do a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> we have this pie crust recipe in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> gave my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taught me how to make it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um so i can make a pretty mean pie but
 		um i don't do it anymore because it's just too fattening we had the same kind of problem if you make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">homemade bread</ENAMEX> i mean forget it's supposed to save you money but you eat like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> that you usually eat  it tastes so good
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh we always we had that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> that was uh um you ever seen the the starter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> i can't remember what it's called they call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um Amish bread</ENAMEX> here but uh it's made with you just leave leave it out
 	
 	
 		oh uh yeah
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		you know and you let it spoil sort of yeah you know
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh i've heard of that i've heard of it but i've never done it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that sounds pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah it tasted pretty good really
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but um it's the sort of thing where you let a portion of it go bad and then you add all these other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX> to it but
 	
 	
 		yeah and then you save you make the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> but you pinch off a portion or save a portion of it for the next time or something
 	
 	
 		yeah right yeah you take some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batter</ENAMEX> out and give it to someone else and that's how they continue the thing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 		i know it sounds it always sounded i don't know how safe that was sounded pretty bad
 	
 	
 		yeah i know it sounded strange to me too i figure well you're baking it so you know yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's that's got to got to kill anything i guess but
 	
 	
 		um-hum okay well i'll talk to you later where are you calling from by the way Texas
 	
 	
 		all right well yeah thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano yeah Plano</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where
 		Plano okay
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls Church Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no kidding gosh it sounds so close
 	
 	
 		yeah i know we've got a good connection must be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh TI</ENAMEX> connection yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought for sure
 		yeah i thought for sure you were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah i i talked to so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that's where practically everybody i talked to is from i think that's why they call me because they want to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> outside the state you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yes yeah they're do they're trying to get all different amount of people well jeez my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX> and i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UVA</ENAMEX> that's where we met yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh really
 		yeah i went to school at uh well i went to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh you did yeah
 	
 	
 		but i grew up right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls Church</ENAMEX> right outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we'd like to get back over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> i'll tell you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's nice over there
 	
 	
 		yeah it's sort of funny i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that want to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah one of my one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> here he was just talking how he's thinking on leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> saying how
 	
 	
 		oh yeah no kidding well its things are doing pretty good down here we we were we tried to move over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and there just was there was so little
 		such little going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> you know you couldn't get a job to save yourself over there so we decided we'll try in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> but but business is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we were saying we could sell our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> here and buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> down there cash you know
 	
 	
 		yeah you probably could
 	
 	
 		well Northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you probably could okay well it's good talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay
 		nice talking to you too bye bye
 	
 	
 		take care
 		bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	