
 
     		
 	
 		well i don't know i mean i don't know what you think about this subject i  the
 		i had never really thought of what they said before about allowing the the sentencing to uh to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and allowing him to do that i've been kind of sitting here thinking about that a little bit while we was waiting for them to find somebody and  i don't know that that's not a good idea
 	
 	
 		that's not a bad idea i um
 		uh that you know they probably need to change it somehow uh the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> needs changing we've just got too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there and uh
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">docket</ENAMEX> and are putting too many
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> that probably don't need to be there and it's another form of sentencing but on that one thing i i still think it should be a unanimous decision uh i think we're getting to the point now where they're gonna eventually let it be um majority vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah i agree yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's not gonna be good no
 	
 	
 		i don't like that no i don't like that at all i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> served on a on a jury
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denton</ENAMEX> that uh was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> it was it was a drug conviction and i don't remember he had some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and it it was accused of selling it and i don't remember exactly how much he had but uh actually not selling it there's a difference couriering
 		couriering it is what and and there's supposedly a difference from selling then being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX> if he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX>  and um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they he he sat on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and they found him guilty and they went through the sentencing phase and everything
 		and uh you know they were told that you know during the trial that this is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> and he's got this clean record and and they ended up the jury you know decided hey it's time to crackdown here you know and it's time to to do this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> thing and let's crackdown and let's really and they sentenced
 		him to fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you know which they thought first offense okay this is they thought that that was that was a good thing  and they sentencing him to fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and um after it was all over uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> they sit down with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and with the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		let me come over in just a second okay
 		and sat down with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and with the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and they were told that uh he would probably serve three
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of the fifteen  and that he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> previous convictions
 		however they could not tell the judge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that during the trial because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of them were in appeal
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> didn't know about it so here they based their sentencing
 		thinking that this was this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> and so you know we'll give him fifteen which'll teach him a lesson but it's not just
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know horrible since it was first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> and he'd been convicted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times before you know and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was very upset and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> came home at home very upset i mean he felt like that that they had been tricked you know and so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		right
 		that
 	
 	
 		something i wonder if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> didn't have control of that if some of that would change you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> might know or at least it it wouldn't hurt to switch over there and see if it worked any better if it didn't we can come back for something else or or or what we've got so well we definitely need a change in the system and uh
 	
 	
 		that's true that's very true yeah
 		yeah obviously what we're doing is not working you know no
 	
 	
 		it's not working too
 		it's just piling up on us
 	
 	
 		yeah and there's you know there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> that are not being rehabilitated in any way shape or form and either they're in there forever or when they get out they're you know it's a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> and they're gonna be right back for the same thing so the system
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah we're just not willing to as a society not willing to spend the time or the money to
 		do what it takes yeah
 	
 	
 		that's very true yeah i was talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine about this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and i said you know i understand that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that rely on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to and and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> rely on our money to survive
 		but i really believe that we need to take care of ourselves i mean we and and it would i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say oh it would be cruel to you know pull our aid from these other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and and maybe so so tell them you've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		to work out a plan to make it on your own
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we will continue funding you for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two years</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> we're cut it down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy to seventy five</TIMEX> you know seventy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX>  and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> we'll cut it fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">in five years</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it should by then you should all should have a plan worked where you can make it on your own without our help
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and then we'll have all we'll have we will have the money if we would do that
 		to to work on our own system because we've got some serious problems here and we're trying to heal the world you know it's just not
 	
 	
 		very true yeah
 		oh yeah you're very accurate
 	
 	
 		it's just not working
 		i look at the i look at what you know this what the aid we're sending to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> and i i feel sorry for them and i know they're suffering and i know they're dying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> but we've got
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that are dying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> too you know and being
 	
 	
 		sure
 		oh
 	
 	
 		abused and neglected and you know i don't know i just have this problem with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		trying to heal the world when you're so sick yourself you know so
 	
 	
 		right well we seem to agree on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> thing and uh but uh we'll need an unanimous verdict and maybe let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> have a opportunity to make the sentence yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think we should try it like you say if it doesn't work we can always come back but i think it would be a good idea to try it
 	
 	
 		i do too
 	
 	
 		so anyway  well we all agree  you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		well good good to hear from you
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	