
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well do you think uh i mean i wonder the assumption is that it is a problem uh and i've never actually had too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> explain to me why it's a problem though i have the same instinctual feeling that it's a problem
 		and uh but it's not clear to me that it is
 	
 	
 		uh but
 	
 	
 		um it's a problem if those voting don't represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> demographically or in terms of their opinions but if those who don't vote if you made them vote and it those who don't vote would have voted exactly the same way
 		you know in other words if forty percent had voted for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">sixty percent</NUMEX> for the other just like everyone who did vote it's not clear to me that it is really a problem
 	
 	
 		um
 		that's that's interesting because i had thought i have feel that it's a problem also but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see your point on that
 	
 	
 		i mean i i assume that those who don't vote i mean if you look at the break down of those who don't vote they tend to be you know poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> for example vote very little and things like that and i assume that they would vote differently
 		if they were voting than your average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> but i don't know if that's the case in fact i've heard of studies that suggest that that isn't
 	
 	
 		uh
 		apparently they don't think it's a problem
 	
 	
 		uh i guess not i'm i i vote religiously i really do um i guess i guess i'm a fan of democracy and uh
 	
 	
 		that's right um
 	
 	
 		but it's funny because here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> things are getting uh increasingly democratically oriented in in the sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being able to vote for things i mean we have these initiatives state initiatives now
 		the first really popular you know wide spread one was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition Thirteen</ENAMEX> which was a uh tax revolt against property taxes uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it's funny because here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> things are getting uh increasingly and you know now we're and that was whatever <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> and now we're up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hundred</ENAMEX> and fifty or something like that i mean we've just
 		there were apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who just threw up their hands after the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> pamphlet because they were asked being asked to make decisions
 		on topics that would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different competing
 		proposals and you had to vote for you know yes or no on each of them and no one could make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> or tails out of some of them and it was incredibly complicated and difficult
 		and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> revolted against that they said we don't want to have to decide all these things that's why we hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who uh you know to to make these decisions for us
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i i kind of feel the opposite though i wish we were given an opportunity to vote on more things i think our elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say they are speaking for us but they're not speaking for me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i do too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh yeah i wouldn't mind having oh more votes than i get to have frankly  anyone who doesn't vote it's fine with me as long as i can have their vote
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that would make me happy though maybe not in a in a deep philosophical sense but in a selfish sense it probably would
 		i don't know it's interesting uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> voting is obligatory uh it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> for example yeah
 	
 	
 		well
 		is that true i didn't know that i was thinking that is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> solution to it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't know how i feel about that
 	
 	
 		but i don't that's not really democratic not what i'd consider truly democratic as
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> considers itself every bit as much a democracy as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and it's not for me to say that they're not um they they feel i mean here you have the right to vote and they simply define it as a duty there
 	
 	
 		is uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we have just as we have a right a duty to pay taxes
 		you know is that democratic i mean we don't have the right to pay taxes in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we have the duty to pay taxes and in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it's a duty to pay taxes and it's a duty to vote on how those taxes are spent
 	
 	
 		it's a duty right
 	
 	
 		and it's not clear to me that that's so much less democratic
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know but part of me <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> against that but then i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it that's
 		it's complex question when you start thinking about it isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't vote i mean there is like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> don't vote and i think they're eligible eligible for a fine i don't know if they actually are fined or or what happens
 		but you're eligible for some sort of fine if you don't vote
 	
 	
 		that's interesting i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here that i know that have never registered to vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think
 		i think they feel they can criticize if they don't
 		i told them if they don't vote they don't have the right to criticize
 	
 	
 		yeah i sort of see uh
 		well i that's how i feel i mean if you if you vote and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> looses well you least you least tried and you can say something but if you don't vote i sort of feel like
 		part of me and it's kind of a nasty part of me feels like well if you didn't vote you get what's coming to you you know and certainly that's true in the overall i mean no one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> that's true for but for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> as a whole i sort of feel that way
 	
 	
 		that's right i feel it
 	
 	
 		when they especially when someone they  they don't vote for someone because
 		they don't like any of them and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> gets in and they don't like him and he turns out to have been worse than her that they might have voted for or something like that and you know i say well
 		you know voting for the lesser of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">evils</ENAMEX> is still important
 	
 	
 		i think it is too sometimes it is a difficult choice you don't feel as though you have much of a choice but
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah yeah i mean you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean it's it's funny because technically you do i mean you have the right to do a write in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> but of course that's that's not really a vote
 	
 	
 		it doesn't really gain anything
 	
 	
 		um
 		yes it really really doesn't and
 		so it's it's a complicated situation but i would like to see i don't know i
 		i i'm i'm thinking of actually moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and and perhaps perhaps i'll call you back and let you know what how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> system works i mean not because of the vote i mean i'm not thinking of moving there because of the voting but just because of a job opportunity and uh i
 	
 	
 		is that girl
 		
 
 		now because
 		oh i see
 		i'm interested are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> employee i'm interested not okay i just wondered
 	
 	
 		i
 		no i'm not
 		and uh so i'm i'm really quite quite curious how that would work to have both i mean you know and i believe in the in a certain uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> block <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you are are obliged to vote too in fact it was even pretty much spelled out who you did vote for up until fairly recently
 		and
 		that's what i think of when i think of you're obliged to vote but when you actually really are given as much choice as you are in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> party system um
 		i don't know i kind of part of me is wary and part of me likes the idea of having it be more of a duty
 	
 	
 		well uh maybe they should
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		perhaps that would be a solution if they were required to vote at least for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first three or four years</TIMEX> after they become of voting age required to register and vote for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and perhaps
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they would be indoctrinated that this is their duty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh well that's a thought
 		or certain privileges come from voting which aren't that important but are nice to have i don't know the right to write your
 	
 	
 		maybe it should go with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> license
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that's see that's an example of a right not a not a actually that's considered a privilege not a right
 	
 	
 		that is a privilege right
 	
 	
 		yeah but technically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> technically it's a privilege but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of it as a right i mean in other words if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> denies you
 		driving denies you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> license <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get very upset but actually it's a privilege which is allowed to be revoked
 	
 	
 		it is
 		that's correct
 	
 	
 		and fortunately voting isn't that
 	
 	
 		maybe it should maybe it should be
 	
 	
 		except well except if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> it is taken away from you i mean they will take away your right to vote under certain circumstances
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		so gosh so we don't have a great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> yet do we
 	
 	
 		that's
 		don't have a great i  i think i checked that as a question i'd be willing to discuss too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i i also i also i don't know if you've uh read any of the um oh what do they call those the uh the early republican
 		uh republic documents uh when they were arguing through constitutional law written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> and all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> who wrote number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or something where he was arguing for a republican
 	
 	
 		no no i haven't
 	
 	
 		not in the sense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> now versus a democratic uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and arguing successfully why the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should be a republic not a democracy
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		which indeed it really is a republic not a democracy
 		where he defines <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy democracy</ENAMEX> as everyone votes for the issues and a republic is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote for someone who then in turn votes for the issues so as you vote for representatives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the whole idea was um
 		presumably those who get voted in would be wiser than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> and able to make more informed decisions and can protect against the tyranny of democracy
 		because just as you can have a tyranny of a single um you know bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> or something you can have a tyranny of the majority
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he makes a very uh passionate good argument for why you don't want some things decided by democratic process because anytime you have a majority
 		um they can change the law in a democratic a fully democratic process and there are cases when you don't want that to be the case um
 		oh you know a candidate if there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't like because of you know racial hatred or something like that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> can just simply vote again vote against them and cases like that he argues need to be constrained and and actually i agree
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		except that i don't trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are appointed to vote
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		sometimes i think we have that right now with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i mean i feel that
 	
 	
 		i think they're looking after their own
 	
 	
 		my you know
 	
 	
 		self preservation more than they're actually looking after the good of the country
 	
 	
 		yeah well their job is to be reelected by in large and so they work on that job
 		and there's also an antigovernment mood in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is misspending your dollars and and they're all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> and you know throw throw the bastards out that kind of thing and there's a notion that somehow
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		if someone isn't as much as a government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they're less corrupt and they're more likely to be good which is really strange because i mean if i'm hiring a plumber i want a real plumber i want someone trained in in it i'm very like
 		
 		
 	