
 
     		
 	
 		here we go
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Janet</ENAMEX> could you tell me what your thoughts are
 	
 	
 		well i think the idea of public uh health services is a good one i think that we all
 		um perhaps have a civic duty but i don't know as though it should be uh and i don't know if this uh was my interpretation was that perhaps it should be uh like a forced thing
 		um i think it should all be voluntary as it is now but um i do agree that i think it is a good thing because i don't know how else a lot of these um things could happen if they didn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah they uh
 		um the example they gave was like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i'm not so sure if i i agree with that
 		see uh
 		back in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> camps
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know about down in your area but
 		like up here they built <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> and they built uh uh waterways leading from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX> to get to the city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in fact in my area it's it's kind of a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> and it's and the waterways are still in place you know they're uh they're beautiful they're all stone walled
 		and
 		it it just leads from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX> way up in the hills and it just leads down into other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX> some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> are still standing too i mean some of them need repair now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but because of
 		the recession back then or the depression whatever you want to call it
 		uh there was a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of work so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> brought them in i mean they they performed a a public service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yet they were paid for it too
 	
 	
 		well that's true and of course there was the need there and they didn't have any other resource and and uh i guess it it served it's purpose
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		right is that what it was meant to do but as you say they were paid and i'm not all that familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> although i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> that are in it and um
 		um they generally go abroad and and uh serve but they don't get a salary and they give up uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of their lives to do this
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah but they must get some compensation somewhere
 	
 	
 		um
 		i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that just came back from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and uh they they are degreed and once they got their degrees they're a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> and they went off they got uh some they got some compensation but it wasn't a whole lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was was it like a sabbatical
 	
 	
 		yeah more like a sabbatical i would imagine and uh i guess a lot of it was a learning experience for them i i imagine it takes just different kinds of people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now they're uh back in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so maybe they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the beginning that just want to
 		be in a constant learning environment i i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh yeah like yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think we need it in this country
 	
 	
 		yes i i agree i so much so many of our things are going outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to benefit other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and okay that's fine but what about here
 	
 	
 		right we're uh
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		you know we're supposedly on the leading edge of technology which uh that can be disputed i guess by a number of other countries
 		um i do now that our rapid transit system uh is in terrible shape i mean most areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we don't have anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where overseas uh they do their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail lines</ENAMEX> their their uh
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX> are in much better condition than ours
 		if we put
 		if we put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to work in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> building
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of rapid transit <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> you know just from say outlying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> of downtown especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> where the i saw a program on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> last night they're saying the average
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the average speed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty six miles an hour</NUMEX> and it's roughly
 		uh a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> wait to get from the outskirts of downtown
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they figure by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> the average speed is going to be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eleven miles an hour</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll be
 	
 	
 		that's that's atrocious
 	
 	
 		you know maybe we've um got a turn around here maybe in the beginning we thought it wasn't such a good idea but perhaps if we instrumented it here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 		rather than taking all that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manpower</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and providing a service for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to join here and do some good we could come up with some of those things
 	
 	
 		we have we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in college and we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that  for one reason or another that that can't get into college either they can't afford it or or perhaps they don't have the abilities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's all more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manpower</ENAMEX> and and one of the ways where we're we were coping with that was they were going into the military and they were getting  a semblance of an education
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s laying off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think there should be mandatory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are not in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> should at least get into some kind of a career program i mean they can help build the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> back up
 	
 	
 		that's uh that's a good thought now see i hadn't thought about it that way my first uh thought was when they mentioned that was to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who go abroad and do service abroad
 		and perhaps there might be as you say more of an effort here needed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		and we've done
 		we've sent
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> abroad and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do go abroad are are usually
 		um
 		college educated
 	
 	
 		yes that's true
 	
 	
 		they're taking the knowledge that we have and bringing it with them which is which is fine because
 		in the long run if we educate those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and we build up their economy they're going to want to buy products that we make
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so but i don't know if that if that is really taken place like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> with the the massive corruption in there i mean a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got it and the rest of didn't
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> same thing a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got it and and the rest of them don't so in theory if you build up their economies and help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> yes it can work
 		but the corruption at the top i think limits that
 	
 	
 		i agree it doesn't always work that way the way it was intended and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> change in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> too and not and are not able to see it through our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> changes also
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm kind of uh a dreamer i guess i still i still believe in
 		we could put this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> back to work we could bring the steel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> back in we could we could build our own rails we could we could create all kinds of jobs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if we just had the incentive like
 		um
 		i'm not sure who started the national
 		highway system you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if it was if it was if it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> or sometime before them the way they decided that yes we're going to have uh  i guess we've got some of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> in the world
 		we could do that too i mean we could we could get a national program
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> had a national program to land uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the moon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we did it
 		so i i think if we if we put our minds to it we can do just about anything we want yeah sounds like i'm on a soapbox
 	
 	
 		i i think i'm inclined
 		
 
 		but it's been interesting it's been an interesting soapbox
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah there's i just i just remember how it used to be and it seems like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">everything's</ENAMEX> just deteriorating you know you you can't go anywhere without waiting in line you can't um
 	
 	
 		now i thought that was just a sign of the times we're all stressed out that's what they're trying to tell us that that we now get upset because we have to wait in line or wait in traffic but in in reality there's so much more traffic and so many more lines and
 		really like you say something needs to be done about that too
 	
 	
 		yeah it just seems to be a waste of time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it takes it takes longer and longer to get back and forth to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're adding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> in the in the world whether that's creating the greenhouse effect or not whether it is or not uh it's still being debated
 	
 	
 		apparently uh if we could get like we were discussing some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like they want to be involved in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> maybe we could do some some real good here
 		you know and not take so long to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it could happen
 	
 	
 		it could the the main thing is um
 		like you said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> in the conversation
 		if we make it a mandate and say you have to do it then we're going to create all kinds of problems
 	
 	
 		that's very true
 	
 	
 		but i don't see why we can't say that i don't see why we can't you know you contribute well
 		you don't go to school well spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> doing something
 	
 	
 		or put these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in prison
 		you know
 	
 	
 		we have a welfare system that
 		
 
 		is defeating itself because they get more money from welfare than they can working at
 		ordinary jobs
 	
 	
 		that's very true
 	
 	
 		so what's the incentive for them to go to work
 	
 	
 		yes exactly
 	
 	
 		the prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> right that's there's i don't know how many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now are incarcerated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is uh which is a huge drain on society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you do with those people
 	
 	
 		and supposedly we're uh reeducating them and putting them back out in the public so give them some public service
 	
 	
 		yeah but are we really doing that educating i i suppose some
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i suppose to somebody's way of thinking we are but um i know that when they do get out the majority of them aren't able to find jobs are they or get back into society because they have that stigmatism
 	
 	
 		no
 		that's right and as much as you say yes you know i've paid my debt to society and all that it's still there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're going to be apprehensive and if you had to choose between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or the other
 		you know you wouldn't you just wouldn't look at those people
 	
 	
 		that's very true if you had uh uh a public health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> that took and say a lot of the
 		
 		
 	