
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> laws are more
 		uh what's the word i want more real i think realistic because they do believe in capital punishment and they do every once in awhile exercise that
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		uh we're as i said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s very conservative and i cannot remember the last time anyone was electrocuted or
 		whatever method they use nowadays to carry out a death sentence
 	
 	
 		do they have a law on the books up there
 	
 	
 		they have uh uh
 		you know i'm just not even aware of what the law is it's uh been so long since anyone was executed that it might be legal but it's not done
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> would know whether it's legal or not but
 		i am not very
 	
 	
 		so what's your uh opinion on capital punishment
 	
 	
 		i believe in capital punishment for certain crimes do you
 	
 	
 		yes uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		there's
 		you know there are some things just that just are inexcusable
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		brutal crimes
 		serial serial serial crimes things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know to me the punishment
 		doesn't even fit the crime but you can't get any worse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they uh  i think to me i think they have to come to that with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as you say brutal crimes because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison system</ENAMEX> being so crowded that seems like just because you don't have a place to put someone doesn't seem like a very logical reason to kill someone else
 		which of course is what it is but
 		i think it would be a detriment to crime or would be a deterrent to crime because
 		i know someone who's mad isn't going to think well gosh i can't do this or they'll put me away but
 		somehow i think if the punishment doesn't fit the crime the crime's more likely to happen
 	
 	
 		right i think in a way it's unfortunate they've come up with with nice ways to
 		um execute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i guess to me if if i was a uh
 		potential serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> or something it wouldn't stop me to be uh to die of lethal injection i mean it's as painless as you can go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i think if i was in a bad accident and they gave me the option i might say yeah you know give me an injection but uh
 	
 	
 		go with it huh
 		you think they should go back to crucifixion then
 	
 	
 		i don't know about that um but uh you know the electric chair on the other hand is probably a pretty painful way to go i don't know
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't know personally i'll never be in that position
 	
 	
 		well we certainly hope not
 	
 	
 		so but i don't i think it should be something that is
 		that is a deterrent that's something that that
 		that's
 		scary and it's something that's going to make you make you be afraid to uh afraid of the consequences
 	
 	
 		do you think uh you know uh lately they've had oh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> they've had some cases where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have killed abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> do you think that they should be faced with the death penalty
 		
  
 	
 	
 		depends on the nature of the abuse and i really don't uh
 		you know that that's it's something that's got to be evaluated on an individual case you know because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's there's really no excuse for abuse but then
 		there are other options there are ways to get out
 	
 	
 		it does happen though doesn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean there
 		you would hope but i guess it's really a
 		it's easy to say but uh you'd hope that someone in that situation would
 		you know get out there are enough support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> enough
 		you know over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade or so</TIMEX> anyway there's been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you don't have to kill your uh kill your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> because he's
 		beating you up all the time you can can leave and have support it's not like you'd be stuck on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah even in our small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> we now have a crisis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and it's been in existence for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> so even in this area where you would think there might not be the help
 		uh there is help for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are abused or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are abused or whatever uh i can't imagine uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> standing by and watching something destructive happen to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		but i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's is a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and she has a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> who is suffering abuse and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is aware of it and is not
 		protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> which just makes your skin crawl to even think about it but
 	
 	
 		this is almost as much of a crime and i guess
 		and i guess
 		i don't know it's to me it's almost as much of a crime to just let it go
 	
 	
 		yes yes she's as guilty as he is
 	
 	
 		and i think i guess it gets back to if if if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> kills her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> because he's been brutalizing her or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> there's maybe more of a reason and it's not an irrational
 		you know just a brutal crime for the sake of
 		just i don't know without a conscience or something like like some of these
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's kind of what i think what capital punishment should be for is you know somebody that's just
 		you know missing something upstairs or just goes out and
 		you know rapes and brutalizes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and
 		turns around and does it again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's like there's just no excuse you
 		there's no reason i should pay for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to spend the rest of his life in in prison
 	
 	
 		so you think our our uh values have to come down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> and cents
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no but i don't think uh i don't think it's right for somebody to uh for me to to uh pay for something i mean the way the way it is right now the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> are overcrowded
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and we're giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that aren't going to change
 		we're just we're just housing them until they die
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if they've you know caused as much pain and suffering as they have for for no reason and they're going to do it again if they get the chance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just just doesn't seem uh
 	
 	
 		i guess the most frightening thing to me uh you're probably young enough that you've not aware of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Speck</ENAMEX> case uh it happened in
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> area but it was certainly broadcast nationwide he broke into this uh complex uh apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> and killed these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>
 		and every once in awhile
 		you know one of them did survive she crawled under a bed and he missed her somehow
 		and she did survive and she did identify him and there is no doubt that this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who did that and every once in awhile he comes up for parole
 		and it's scary to think that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is sitting there trying to decide whether he is
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		rehabilitated to the point that he can go back out in society when these young <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty two twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> are all dead it just doesn't seem
 		he should i think have made that his life should have been sacrificed for what he took
 		as you say the punishment has to fit the crime doesn't it
 	
 	
 		uh it's just like uh back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course he'll never i don't think he'll ever get out on parole just because it was so well publicized
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		but uh you know he comes up every so often
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirhan Sirhan</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah of course also believe in deportation but that's another subject isn't it
 	
 	
 		maybe they ought to have an island out in the middle of the ocean we can drop them all off
 	
 	
 		take them back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> used to do
 	
 	
 		yeah  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> might not care for that these days
 	
 	
 		i see they've gotten a little narrow-minded about things like that
 	
 	
 		on an island so far away there's no chance they can ever get off
 	
 	
 		yeah nice talking to you
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		alrighty bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	