
 
     		
 	
 		okay the recording started what kind of habits hobbies do you have
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main hobbies one of them is painting and the other one is collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> but from your from the description it sounds like they're more interested in painting
 	
 	
 		oh  well i'm interested in wine i like the wine
 	
 	
 		oh that's good that's fine i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> do you like
 	
 	
 		well i'm a very big favor uh much in favor of red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a thousand</NUMEX> bottles down in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX> and i've been collecting it now for oh fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		my goodness red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> huh i'm a white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> drinker myself i i'm on the white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zinfandels</ENAMEX> now i i've come up the ladder the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chablis</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhines</ENAMEX> now i'm got uh on uh Zinfandels
 	
 	
 		oh okay see white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zinfandels</ENAMEX> are not a big favorite of mine though
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> i like are these very okay <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chardonnays</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kessler Kessler</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you don't have any vineyards up there do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there are some but and in fact their white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> are better than their red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> because they don't get enough sun to make good red wine
 	
 	
 		are there
 		oh okay now see i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grapevine</ENAMEX> that's uh used to be we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">winery</ENAMEX> here but uh it used to be uh
 		i think they had a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wineries</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but they do grow grapes here that's where they get the name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grapevine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso Texas</ENAMEX> and i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vineyard</ENAMEX> actually it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Yunon New Mexico</ENAMEX> which is just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Paso</ENAMEX> up the valley
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 		uh-huh i understand i understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> has a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">winery</ENAMEX> down in south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> some place really big one
 		but i don't know they're
 		i guess they're bottling it i don't what they sell it under what name they sell it under have you ever visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wineries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes some of them
 	
 	
 		i uh i've uh gone to a couple my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> so i visit there but back to hobbies i guess uh
 		and what what kind of painting do you do
 	
 	
 		oh mostly mostly figures i've few done landscapes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> so when i was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 		i was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sat in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> so i learned to mix paint by watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> mix paint things like that so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay that's a good idea i used to paint uh you know i just dabble and i really think i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> for it but i've never really
 		explored it like i should what little i have done i think is pretty good but as i said i never have gone on with it maybe i should have
 		if i'd uh you know taken a lessons or something but  i in through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> i've just i'm not any good any more when i was younger i i used to be pretty good
 	
 	
 		oh for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i used to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that hire a model and draw once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and used to work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Labs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'd go twice a week for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> and you do that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten years</TIMEX> you get to where you can actually draw pretty well
 	
 	
 		yes i would imagine i would hope so anyway  well i  when i was in high school i think i drew a mural behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concession</ENAMEX> stand at the local theatre and you know stuff like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i won <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>  prize painting the front of a bar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> soaping windows they wanted us to paint you know windows in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and i painted something won <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> prize on that but like i said i never did go on with it and uh
 	
 	
 		oh i still paint occasionally not as much as i used to but i still paint i have some stuff set up the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> things in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> are my painting stuff and the wine cellar which is
 	
 	
 		wine we have wine cellars that's nice let me
 	
 	
 		well i built it i you you have to way have some way of storing them so
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 		oh uh-huh well you know we don't have not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basements</ENAMEX> here for some reason i don't know why the the ground's
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		not wet like it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> so i don't why they don't have basements you don't see too many of them
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you probably don't get very good
 		very good number of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square feet</NUMEX> for your dollar building a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> there that's probably why
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so guess so well i  only hobbies i have is i jog and uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>
 		and
 		that's just that and my yard work i love to i work in the yard i i have my yard work done but i do my <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> you know and stuff i i like to do stuff like that and i have quite a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>
 		i work on that every all the time
 	
 	
 		so you must have a lot well you ought to be seeing lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> this time of year
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they really are beautiful gorgeous time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> because uh they're really out and especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses roses</ENAMEX> do grow good down here
 		i guess that's probably my best hobby and then i do volunteer work at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> that's kind of a hobby i guess i work in intensive care at a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 		just  um <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> a week
 		and that's kind of fun and different and kind of like a hobby i guess
 	
 	
 		you find out what it's like in that kind of business
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i'm amazed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh the different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've met that the rude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are so inconsiderate of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i it just boggles my mind how many i find like that that
 		think they're the only ones that are grieving or having a hard time they don't have any respect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know sitting across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> you know and they'll be laughing and carrying on and here are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are
 		sad and i just  i just can't get over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are i'm really getting getting a rude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">awakening</ENAMEX> to how the human nature is i guess
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last last night</TIMEX> i just there's big signs telling them not to go in without checking with the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteer</ENAMEX> and you must be twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years of age</TIMEX> to go in and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no more than two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at a time and so this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> walks in
 		you know just walks up without even checking with me with his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> so that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them just you know there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> rules right there he busted you know just walked right on in and i thought
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		golly you know he didn't even follow any of the rules and i
 		and didn't even seem to bother of course they kicked him right out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		and he probably didn't like that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah very highly insulted you know how dare they  but i just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		can't i just can't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i it this is the that's some place you need to work to really see how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really are  when it comes right down to it anyway
 	
 	
 		well working in a research place where i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute of Standards and Technology</ENAMEX> which used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bureau of Standards</ENAMEX> that's kind of an ivory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower place</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah
 		i know used to know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> that was uh real big in standards uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Tu</ENAMEX> that worked at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and he was
 		uh over the standards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> and everything i believe there
 		and i was always impressed by all the clocks and you know the when we take things to be calibrated and what have you in the standards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> and it was kind of interesting
 		that what you all do calibrate and
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		yeah there's lots of stuff the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i guess i know at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> are either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work in the speech program who run this this computer program or if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the semiconductor area i used to know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pallab Chatterjee</ENAMEX> and those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i don't know don't know if you'd know him or not
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no i had worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventeen years</TIMEX> but i uh
 		quit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years six years ago</TIMEX> i guess and went with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marietta</ENAMEX> and then came up here with another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two and a half years ago</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 		they're just back in the same area but i enjoy it here i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i'm not a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> but i love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i wasn't happy till i got back
 	
 	
 		well i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i moved away and never came back so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		never came back huh oh well  my all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i just i don't know i just couldn't stand being away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i kept coming back
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it feels good i i'm real happy here i like the weather and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> too they were nice uh i enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> but i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> better i guess but
 		anyway i guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our five minutes</TIMEX> is up
 	
 	
 		i guess they are it's been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		it's been nice talking to you bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	