
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay um
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they're older <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> but um i found it very difficult to find good child care when i was looking for a place to for stay while i taught school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i wanted when they were very young when they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> say till they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years old</TIMEX> i preferred that they had an individual take care of them in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and that's what i looked for and i was lucky enough to find one right across from my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and that worked
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah that worked out real well but when they got older i wanted them to be in a school type situation three i think they were both <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> when they started where they could learn to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and be around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> their own age because i think that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that would prepare them for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> also it's real important that they do that um that they get that preparation for school
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so but i had i have switched schools several times because i did i really didn't care for what was going on at that the school i wanted them to learn to play i didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> forced on them at an early age
 	
 	
 		yeah i um that that's oh oh you mean you switched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		well well i'm just recently married so i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> though we plan on having them soon but i think um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i think um that i that that's probably one of the biggest difficulties uh i think um i'm lucky though that um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will probably not have to work while our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> yeah because because i'm a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> so and that's also and it's nice for me because um
 	
 	
 		wonderful
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		most of the time you have so much flexible hours so that i could probably work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three days a week</TIMEX> and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> evenings so that if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> does um does go back to work part time um
 		there probably will be a possibility that i could stay home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> that she would go to work and that i would have to teach at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah so it will probably workout real nice for us uh i think we're very lucky because just my job sort of builds in flexible schedules
 		i can even teach on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> and and things like that  yeah um i do know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> have a terrible time finding uh child care and one of the things they made in um uh real
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		they're number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> priority was that um they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> didn't have to leave their home so they um um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> is a uh
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful too
 	
 	
 		um a clinical speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologist</ENAMEX> so she is also i guess her most recent position after she returned back to work
 		she applied for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s position and and got it so i guess she's very well qualified for her field i guess and even though she took off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> for um
 		i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> all together it would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> how old's Kayla <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> yeah i guess she took off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> all together um
 		for because i guess they have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> and yeah and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two almost two</NUMEX> so i guess she took off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> all together and then when she decided to go back to work um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she was able to find good position and pay for somebody to come into their home
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they were really lucky there but i think they've lost this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> she will she will not continue and and she won't do it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are home from school
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know what they are going to do
 	
 	
 		oh you know that's an ideal situation but not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can afford something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think i think they they're both they were both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> unlike me they're um they'll my they were married
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> younger then she is so she was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven</TIMEX> when they were married so she already had had gotten bachelors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> and established herself in a profession in a practice almost um
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um where you know he then they waited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> and and he got himself pretty far along i guess they didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> until he was about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty seven twenty six so</TIMEX> by that time she was so well
 		established you know i guess it made it a lot easier but uh i think the longer you wait the easier the easier it is if you have that
 	
 	
 		sure
 		oh i do too
 	
 	
 		that professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> where you can change
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but they're they're are just so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that aren't that uh lucky um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no yeah that's right that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		because i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and i uh you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i ex-husband and i got a divorce um when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were small and so i uh was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i uh still am <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and it was really difficult to find affordable child care that was that was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was what i wanted where i could have piece of mind and when i taught school and i knew my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were being taken care of yeah and plus i
 	
 	
 		yep yeah definitely
 		we're safe yeah
 	
 	
 		i uh wanted them to get something out of it i just didn't want it to be a day where they went and slept and ate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's you know that's so important i um
 		i i guess
 		it's so funny now with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know they don't take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> into kindergarten and when i guess when they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and sometimes they flunk kindergarten now and they don't let them into kindergarten unless they can
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		count to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and they know their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABCs</ENAMEX> and i think that's so funny because um
 		i don't i don't know if i want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s very important i'm an educator myself and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> teaches and i it's a very important part of your life and i hope to read with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but i don't know if i want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to go to school at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
 		or three you know i can see that that when you make that point
 	
 	
 		i agree with that
 		well the thing is i teach <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> grade and i i can see very readily the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that didn't never learn socially how to get along with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they're the ones that are having problems not only getting along with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but academically because
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were not they're should be there's to many things in their way and so i want my i wanted my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they did learn to get to get along with other people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's a really important point
 	
 	
 		yeah and i mean i feel a lot of maladjusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and i bet if we trace back to their early childhood we could see some
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know times they didn't get to play or be with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> their own age really learn how do get along with people
 	
 	
 		i think that's really that's important i i've seen the same thing i i think you're exactly right because you know i've gone out or before i was married i went out with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and you know um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> after you know after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two months</TIMEX> i realize this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> really has some deep set emotional problems and i bet and they could be traced back to just not being uh you know being moved between
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and two</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX> and never always being a bit snippy and spiteful i bet you could trace all the way back
 	
 	
 		i bet you could too because it you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have to learn how to get along with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and if they don't they just don't turn out to be really you know good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> i should say you know really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it is a big problem and you know i have lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> right now that uh have young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> have problems with with whoever is taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">th</NUMEX> ey switch a lot which is not good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep that's true yeah that's really true uh
 	
 	
 		so you need because you need that consistency when they're young like that and it would be ideal like you you hope when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> gets to stay home i would have have given anything if i would have been able to stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yeah you are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i think i'm i'm very lucky um because of having you know flexible higher education provides a flexible schedule
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		especially i teach a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> so it's it's one of things where i'm paid a little bit better then a History or an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and i'm also um you know they have vocational type <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		almost everywhere and you know you can take you can teach <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two three hours</TIMEX> classes on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> which means that you know whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> so that lets you be available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> during the week
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		you know so you be will home with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i you know it's really funny is that i  i picked this career when i was in college because uh i think with my commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and um wanting to spend more time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're very wise
 	
 	
 		you know because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had very um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> type job with uh forty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minute commute</TIMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty five commute</TIMEX> home so by the time he got home he was so tired and
 		he was all rung out from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and i think he he missed a lot of um our up bringing you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i i came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> stayed home until we started school um
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i i don't uh it's funny i don't think she had to work until we started school i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> become much more expensive
 	
 	
 		oh don't they though that's what i have right now thirteen and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year old</TIMEX> oh it is they really are expensive yeah
 	
 	
 		for it
 		it's probably costing you a fortune
 		
 
 		my goodness if if you want them to be able to drive the car the insurance bill the um
 	
 	
 		exactly well and they most of the area where we live in most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know right now i'm looking for a little truck for my for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> so that you know an older older older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> so i can afford it but you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i just look forward to him helping me out because i i for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> just <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> driven carpools all over the place and
 	
 	
 		carpools uh-huh
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did a lot of that
 	
 	
 		and it will be nice just to be able to have him say will you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> will you take
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> somewhere or something like that
 	
 	
 		that's right yep and just to save you trips to and from you know uh ball games and athletic events and activities at the school yeah isn't that something how you know you think about child care and it lasts along time
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 		right
 		that's right
 		it does forever
 	
 	
 		it  it lasts a long time
 	
 	
 		and then when you get through with your own you've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> so  it's not ending is it  you think we've talked a long a long enough time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		well normally they come in uh
 	
 	
 		oh they come in see this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've done this
 	
 	
 		oh oh cause they'll come in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in ten minutes</TIMEX> normally and stop us
 	
 	
 		oh in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> you have to talk that long
 	
 	
 		well you don't have to but they they um you go the length and sometimes if it's a very busy time period you'll go about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		depends on how old the tapes are at that time
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see are you from the where are you from
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh i'm from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> which is which is outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well most of most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i talk to are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah because that's where <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is that makes sense
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah and i've discussed i've discussed um
 		
 		
 	