
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i have uh i guess a lot of thoughts about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> um
 		i i guess i feel like i was pretty young while it was going on and so there's probably a lot of things i remember and a lot of things that i really didn't have a clue as to what was happening
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um looking back like maybe some of the things that i know now i i'm not sure i do believe it was worth the cost in dollars and lives that was one of the questions that she asked us to think about because i
 		because we never went to war i don't think we were committed to winning it and getting out and i i feel like it went on and on
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i i guess i see such a contrast like as opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> War we just had where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> went out and got worldwide support for for what was happening
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i just feel like maybe we went in to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> and i'm not sure that's our role
 		but
 	
 	
 		yeah i i agree with that i was i was fairly young at the time too i i really don't have very many memories about it at all
 		in fact and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> and i you know he in looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> war that just went on he i
 		it frustrates him because of the support that they have and the support that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vets</ENAMEX> did not have from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> either one
 	
 	
 		don't you think that maybe that's why we had it this time i mean i do think that i i it's been too long in coming but i feel like maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
 		and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are aware of the things that we did wrong that we didn't support that
 		that those so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were opposed to the war what it translated into was they were opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> that were there fighting it and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were there doing their duty
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right i mean they weren't there by choice and and i think
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i think that we learned from that and i think it it's one of those things that you learn the hard way it was a tragic mistake the way that they have been treated over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and i believe that's just now turning around
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		turning around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Just now</TIMEX> you know trying to be rectified and i'm and i'm not sure you can undo the damage that was done emotionally on so many of the people
 	
 	
 		right
 		no i don't think you can and i i agree with you that i i think that the the time difference between the two wars has allowed a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to see the mistakes that were made in in in every aspect of it
 		and i i agree with you also that i feel like it was not worth the money spent or the lives lost to fight that war i mean they're still not settled over there
 	
 	
 		no they're not
 	
 	
 		and i have a feeling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> crisis is going to be the same way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think we're going to end up back there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> or if if not sooner
 	
 	
 		well i i appreciate the feel i feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is in a hard spot he went over there to get them out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
 		which he did
 		and then he has backed out he has pulled out and i realize they're still saying well here you're encouraging us to get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> so why aren't you helping us and you see i think him going in and doing that would be putting us in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> situation
 	
 	
 		i think it would too
 	
 	
 		and i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> will stand for it i don't think he would do that uh i think we learned too much
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah i agree with that
 	
 	
 		of the effects uh you know whether it was justified or not i know
 		that they probably felt like we were going in for a good cause i i feel like maybe they felt like we were doing the right thing to try and help maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> over there and and beat the communism but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think somewhere that got lost you know in the long term effects of the of the war and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well you have to i you know you have to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> a lot of credit for he he said that's what we were going there to do and he did what what he said and he did pull out before it got any further than that where where it would have turned into more of a police action
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or more of a political action i guess you getting into their governmental affairs which you really can't do as as another country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean that
 		my my biggest problem with all of these wars is we spend all of that money on all these other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and we have so many problems here at home that we don't address
 	
 	
 		that we don't get fixed
 	
 	
 		that's right and and that's that's what frustrates me more than anything
 	
 	
 		i know
 		and i i believe that we have to have a military and i believe that we have to have a defense to keep anybody else from walking in and doing it to us
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i also believe that we need to turn so much of that inward
 	
 	
 		i think there's a lot of waste and and they don't i if they could just cut out all the fat and and get it lean
 		and start addressing some of the other issues i think we could take care of everything and quit taking care of all these other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> all across the world you know who just end up using things against us later on anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know i do think that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> war um i think that maybe a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that were so hateful towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> have come away with uh kind of a different attitude
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think that maybe we're not their big bad enemy any more
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh and i think that's good you know i think that's a good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah a lot of good has come from this one
 	
 	
 		i think so too
 	
 	
 		and i think i guess in in uh ironic way a lot of good came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> toward this war because like we we said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> that you know the a lot of eyes were opened after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of of that war and and
 	
 	
 		and perhaps the reason that good came out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid East</ENAMEX> war is because we had the experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		so i i i do think that
 		we've learned from it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i i wish there weren't war
 	
 	
 		yeah no kidding
 	
 	
 		but uh i do think we learned
 	
 	
 		and i just i just hate the emotional price a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> paid
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		for you know uh nothing i mean it was they're they still don't know what they were there for
 	
 	
 		no there was no feeling of accomplishment no goal no
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		we went in but what did we do we lost lives and and what were we trying to do who knows
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and i i think you're right uh
 		i think you're right there
 		um i do remember when it was over i remember when they were coming home
 		uh
 		but
 		i remember the feeling back then you know like i feel like right now i feel like this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has been behind this war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that aren't for war i'm not for war
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i believe that the way that it was done and the way that was handled were right i don't remember that feeling back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i just remember oh yeah our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are over there and it's sad and we shouldn't be fighting a war but there was no let's support them you know
 	
 	
 		right well the when this war broke out it frustrated me all this the antiwar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know their all the demonstrations that were going on i felt like they got way too much media coverage and publicity because those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean
 		you know they're the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are w ho've always got to have a cause whether it's good bad of indifferent they've got to have a cause and
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and i you know nobody says because you're supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> that you're you're supporting the war you you have to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are there
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and some for some reason those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't see that
 	
 	
 		they don't see it as supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> the people
 	
 	
 		no no they don't and you know they're just real shallow people
 	
 	
 		i would agree with you there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i agree
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i and i recall when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said that you know he said look i you know i'm sorry that you're opposed to the war there's a lot of us that are opposed to war but uh you're not helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are over there by what you're doing and i remember a lot of it kind of stopped after that
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean they're not helping anybody that's the that's the whole point they're not doing anything for anybody except themselves
 	
 	
 		but
 		their not
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and i don't even know what they're doing for themselves you know
 	
 	
 		uh
 		giving a soapbox to stand on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but well i just i i'm glad we've learned i'm sorry we had the experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and i'm i'm i'm especially sorry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are you know have spent all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> trying to deal with it emotionally because
 		you know until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last past four or five years</TIMEX> nobody ever really worried about that for them
 	
 	
 		that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		and and i think that's where we as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really failed you know failed them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		i don't know
 		well
 		do you have anything else you want to say on this
 	
 	
 		no i guess not
 	
 	
 		i think this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that i haven't been cut off by the computer
 	
 	
 		i know we get cut off all the time too
 	
 	
 		usually i can talk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> but this is something to me that's sad
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		so well have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> and i appreciate the conversation
 	
 	
 		thanks same here
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	