
 
     		
 	
 		are you are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">TIer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i am
 	
 	
 		oh and you work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> uh whereabouts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh in the front end the wafer fab
 	
 	
 		oh okay good deal oh i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i'm in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QRA</ENAMEX> i i'm kind of a worldwide quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> based here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh mostly the offshore assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where do you work
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh great
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		except i'm fixing not to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIer</ENAMEX> after a week from today
 	
 	
 		you going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm going to Onum
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcontractor house</ENAMEX> they uh they builds in fact they build product for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> but it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> so i mean i've i've served i've done my time
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		okay you ready to talk about taxes okay
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		were you happy with your return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>  were you happy with your tax return this year
 	
 	
 		huh
 		what did you say
 		no  no
 	
 	
 		was it negative
 	
 	
 		okay i guess we're on the air now
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh well what do you uh what do you think uh uh what's your biggest gripe do you think is it the proposed state income tax or the or the gigantic federal income tax we seem to be paying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> or what
 	
 	
 		i think my biggest gripe is the gigantic federal income tax i came from a state that paid
 		uh state taxes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> and that seemed to be relatively small compared to like the uh the tax you pay on sales sale items
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i don't know i think uh my biggest gripe is with federal
 	
 	
 		what what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Indiana you had a state income tax there are you able to credit that against your federal income tax
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah though it's a percentage you divide that well you uh how much you paid or something by your federal
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you do get some credit but not the whole thing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		okay because
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of tax breaks for like
 		you know a lot of things if you're involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> like uh giving to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and things like that they'll break you for
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		okay what uh uh what generally what percent of your income is it
 	
 	
 		um not even sure because i was a student so i didn't pay that much
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		because as as you know where uh there's there's uh a ugly rumors on the horizon out there that we may be faced with that here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right and what percent would that be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i have no idea i i i uh i'm i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> but they didn't have a state income tax when i worked when i lived there so i have uh no and i know they have one now uh and i have no idea i have no idea what it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know getting to the back getting back to the Federal income tax i remember during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> i think it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform Act</ENAMEX> of nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> or something like that when the taxes were reduced and it was made simpler and all that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't believe it it's worse
 	
 	
 		i know well you can't deduct for credit card interest that type of thing
 	
 	
 		oh sure and i seem to have more of that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and yeah the only thing that's left deductible is uh is mortgage uh interest basically
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and would then and and that's significant and every once in a while they make noises like they're going to take that out and that would just kill the housing industry if they did
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and and uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other things that i only found out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and uh uh i thought at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 		and and had more money than i knew what to do with so i started making accelerated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> payments and i said gee you know this would be great because i'll i'll have a lot of equity in my house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are old enough to go to college i'll get a equity loan which will increase my mortgage so i'll be able to get money to send them to college and then get the mortgage interest deduction part
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		guess what
 	
 	
 		what happened
 	
 	
 		that that's not legal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that it's not legal everybody else can do it but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and and so i i got this <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three thousand foot five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom house</ENAMEX> that i've got almost paid off
 		and have all kinds of equity in it and don't have  and you know struggling to keep i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in college and i'm going to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh man
 	
 	
 		but but uh it it was just my fault not checking it up because i've heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing it so i thought it was pretty good deal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so but the uh uh i i it just seems to me that the that the income tax is getting a bigger and bigger hunk of us every year
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and and i'm not exactly sure what what we get in return i was listening to a talk show i don't know we ever get any talk shows from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> up there but i listened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Gold</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLIF</ENAMEX> and he was saying that in nineteen fifty four
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about one cent</NUMEX> on the dollar in taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now we're paying something like a little over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty fifty cents</NUMEX> when you consider federal income tax <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FICA</ENAMEX> tax sales tax and all the other things we get hit with
 	
 	
 		fifty cents
 		it's incredible
 	
 	
 		and it is it is absolutely incredible and
 		and and the mentality that you cure ills by throwing money at it and you throw and you raise the money to throw at it by raising taxes is just absolutely terrible
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is you know do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in school
 	
 	
 		no i don't i just got married i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you know you just got married okay well you one of the worst things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> how long you been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well you'll find out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> because you probably came from a state that's got a very decent public school system and you'll find out that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we've got uh i think we rank fiftieth out of fifty states
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and the way they keep proposing fixing that is to raise taxes spend more money
 	
 	
 		i think what would cure that problem is to consolidate some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and they wouldn't have so much money going to so many different schools
 	
 	
 		yeah well that plus that fact that you look into the we've got some very good private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here and more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are sending their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and what you look in the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is they've got a higher proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the payroll that are teaching
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		than they do in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and and my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> goes to a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> school district which is one of the better ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and and</ENAMEX> and uh however my goodness they got an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> for everything
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and and and they've got uh i don't know what the ratio is but they've got a tremendously high ratio of administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are actually out there teaching
 		and it is sor t of like we do at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is was getting ready to
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we get we get fat in those areas and yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and we got they they got a lot of overhead in those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and rather than throw more money at it they got to figure out how to get get the most out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they got
 	
 	
 		yeah and then all your money goes to overhead
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and get them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> plus
 		uh i don't know it seems to me that that more so than when i went to school there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that aren't going allow <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first first</NUMEX> of all they're not college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prep courses</ENAMEX> and i don't think they're going
 		help a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> make a living they're just sort of things to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> credits so they can graduate
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and  and and all that and so i'm not i'm not overly pleased with that either but the uh uh the tax thing and i think our sales tax is uh uh somewhere around <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> now isn't it
 	
 	
 		right in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it uh might be a little less here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah i i think right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> we're paying <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about eight percent</NUMEX> and you know uh i say i was initially from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> i've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> but they used to call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxachusetts</ENAMEX> and uh i was there on business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and i i made a few purchases and i realized that as bad as their reputation is their sales tax <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about five</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and i know there were several things that i bought that were something in the order of a dollar and i noticed it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about five cents</NUMEX> added onto it plus it doesn't cut it as early you know you buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ten cent candy</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven eleven</NUMEX> here and you pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> cents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		for it and and i notice theirs doesn't cut in much below <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty cents</NUMEX> i think
 		so so the little items you pay what the price tag says
 	
 	
 		well
 		now if they propose this the if this you know state income tax goes through are they going to lower the sales tax
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i don't i bet they're not i i'll absolutely bet they're not it it's interesting i wish i knew this question was coming up because i've only heard of it in bits and pieces
 		but apparently there was a bill before the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> today to uh lower social security tax but the other end of it they were going to raise income taxes
 	
 	
 		oh man
 	
 	
 		they were going to they were going to give with one hand and take away with the other and i i just heard bits and pieces on the radio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and i i hadn't uh uh i haven't heard that i haven't heard that much about it
 		uh what what kind of a sales tax was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		think it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and a half percent
 	
 	
 		uh-huh okay yeah did you go to school there in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana  Indiana University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> okay you were you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boilermaker</ENAMEX> huh yeah yeah you follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we were we're tremendous uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> here and we saw them we saw them play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> Regionals down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> last year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		oh great
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and we were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Longhorn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> naturally but we did see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> so we're aware uh that they've that they've got a very good program there
 	
 	
 		yeah they well it's just been the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three or four years</TIMEX> actually they had poor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> before that but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and i think they went further <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> uh i i think they got into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> round of the of the play-off this year
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 		yeah they've been exciting to watch
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh that's an  what did you get get your degree in
 	
 	
 		supervision
 	
 	

 		okay supervision supervision that's an interesting degree uh what what sort of things does it entail
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		lot of theory um it's pretty it's pretty broad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> took some engineering courses some math a lot of uh a lot of theory lot of practical like personal um problems and personnel problems and that type of thing
 	
 	
 		are you are you actively in supervision now have have you taken some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> supervisory skill courses
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">The Boss Course</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boss Course</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that was a really good course
 	
 	
 		yeah and and i was i was going to ask you what did you think of it relevant to some of
 		
 		
 	