
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i'll let you go ahead
 	
 	
 		okay i uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all together
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh my oldest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are already out and about in the world and i uh have a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> that are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> and uh my youngest is twelve
 	
 	
 		oh
 		that's great i always thought it'd be great to have twins
 	
 	
 		uh yeah if you like doing everything twice
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		uh at any rate um
 		my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh
 		i didn't spend a whole lot of time with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and you know was a a problem with having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> needing to work a uh full-time job that was more than a full-time job i worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about fifty one hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> because i worked every worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eleven hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Sunday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so i didn't get to spend as much time with them as i as i should have as i really wanted to
 	
 	
 		your first ones you mean it was this way
 	
 	
 		yeah the yeah the family well it was with all of them but it was uh more an impact i think on the oldest two
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because um
 		oh about the time i got out of working
 		that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX> was when the uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years old</TIMEX> and uh they never you know i don't think they
 		noticed i wasn't around that much you know with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it's kind of hard to notice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> isn't around very much um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what i've tried to do uh now
 		that i've uh finally went back to school and got my degree when i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years old</TIMEX> and uh so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then i came out and was making as much money forty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> a week as i did fifty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hours</TIMEX> a week so i've tried to spend more time with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> since then um what i'm currently doing is uh taking a lot of time um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> more with their homework in the evenings um we just started a thing where every other week we go to uh movies there's a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> that offers dollar movies on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every couple of weeks</TIMEX> we will go to the movies because that's how often they change the movies and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's working out pretty well um we're spending more time together i feel like i'm a lot closer to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> that are still living at home than i ever was to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that were living there before um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in fact i found that i'm a lot closer with uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who's gone and i don't even know where he's at um he's taken off for parts unknown but uh yeah and and uh my
 	
 	
 		huh
 		that's difficult yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is um
 		has moved out of the house her and i get along a lot better now that she's moved  out of the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  it happens that way
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh so it's it's it's
 		it's been difficult to try to find the time and i think it's important that we do because um i notice that uh when i had spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> down there they all have a uh
 		a me kind of attitude
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> not spending time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and going out and doing things and you know i knew like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> next door were all into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it just you know i saw the family falling apart down there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is much worst for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i mean it was bad enough every place else but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are extremely bad
 	
 	
 		yeah and so i think it's kind of important that i that i you know nurture the relationship i have with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now and i'm doing my best to keep that up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's all you can do
 	
 	
 		yeah what's your been your experience
 	
 	
 		well i i was going to ask too does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> work
 	
 	
 		um she didn't up until the last oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh she just recently started working then
 	
 	
 		uh
 		she just recently started working uh she worked a job until we moved to our new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh she quit that job because it was too inconvenient and uh she starts a new job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> which should take her out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four days</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		oh uh-huh uh-huh
 		so that sounds great well uh we also have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and but ours are all out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX>  so uh as when they were growing up i probably we had a lot of similar things like like you had
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know having the time when you have younger ones to take care of
 		you maybe sometimes do not take as much time for the older ones but uh we were we're very active of course at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Boy Scouting and Girl Scouts Four</ENAMEX> H
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and those activities helped a lot in giving us things to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we try to take a vacation with them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> camping of some sort something that wasn't expensive
 		and uh
 		our youngest is uh expecting her first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> so they're they're all out and on their own they're and we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to get married yet  and they'll all be married
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they're they're all doing pretty good they uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> you probably don't know where that is
 	
 	
 		certainly do
 	
 	
 		okay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> live there uh one i like i said lives near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> in in around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> he works right on the border of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> lives just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> over the hill  so we'll get to see her a little more than uh what we do the other ones
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that sounds great i've i've noticed uh another thing um when i was younger my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was always working and
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well they have to
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh you know he uh he worked a full-time job and a part-time job and i never saw him so i didn't have much of a role model to go by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		to go to follow uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know to learn how to be a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and a parent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that kind of thing because i i can't ever remember playing ball with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> or catch with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> or doing anything with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and that does make a big difference
 	
 	
 		yeah and it if you don't have i don't i it's my feeling that if you don't have a role model to follow then it's kind of tough you know everybody's not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father Knows Best</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's that's well none of us are let's face it you know we're not none of us like they portray portray it on those shows i mean life's much more difficult than that
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean the the the capability to uh create <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> doesn't necessarily mean you have the uh the mental capacity to raise them  and
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		right right now our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> our well she's our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> oldest she has she's the only that other one that has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and she works full time
 		and i have mixed feelings about that she's able to do that and i don't know if she'd be happy to stay at home
 		but yet on the other hand i i've got the mixed feelings that i think you should be at home with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i'm kind of old fashioned i guess that way but they seem to they seem to give uh quality time
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when they are together and and so it seems it seems for them that it works out all right
 		so i don't know i i don't think i ever would have had what it would take to work full time and raise a family i
 	
 	
 		yes it's it's not easy i've uh you know i've helped out extremely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh well i can't say that but i've helped out  as best i could at home and uh you as you know with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it takes a lot of work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes it does it it yeah
 	
 	
 		even if even if someone's home all the time there's still a lot of things that have to be done
 	
 	
 		yeah what line of work are you in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> since you went to school and
 	
 	
 		uh well now i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> so so i'm in computers
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've that's called i've talked to work for uh
 		for the same
 	
 	
 		yeah and so i've uh prior to that i uh i worked in a food store
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know work
 	
 	
 		which your income would be a lot better now
 	
 	
 		uh right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it uh it was uh it was a a smart move to make um i was more intelligent than the position i was holding
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh it was
 	
 	
 		and it's kind of a waste of a person
 	
 	
 		yes i i felt that it certainly was i mean i was smarter than most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i was working for and uh you know every time something new came up i was explaining it to them and uh i had
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> and you you recognized this and was able to you know do something about it
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh
 		yeah i uh started back to school in fact i was going to school while i was working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifty one hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and that's why i you know if you're working if you're taking twelve credits at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and you're working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifty one hours</TIMEX> a week there's not much time left to spend with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it puts a strain on everybody your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and your family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the only thing you can remember is to  try and stay together as much as you can because it's very easy to uh become go your own direction when you're so when you're working so hard and going to school too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah well it it all paid off um so uh you know i got my degree and got the better paying job and
 	
 	
 		well that's wonderful
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know we i think as a family we're a lot better off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it sounds to me like uh you're doing well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s retired so uh he's been retired for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> now yeah that's quite a change
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah well my goal is to try to retire by the time i'm fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well he made it at fifty  it was a magic number for him and and uh he went at fifty and he still works part time at other thing you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		same job as he was doing only he's retired and doing it independently but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nevertheless retired
 	
 	
 		well i'm
 		
 		
 	