
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so eating out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what are you interested in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right um
 		we eat out quite a bit it's just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i at home now so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh once a week twice a week
 	
 	
 		oh at least once a week
 		we're we're retired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when we working out we ate out more than that
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh but we both work and we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and
 		we normally manage to eat out once a week anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well what type of restaurant do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		really i'm kind of open on food i'm
 		what you might call a culinary adventurer i'll
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'll try anything once
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		been on a real barbecue kick lately
 	
 	
 		oh have you we like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> we eat a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		excuse me uh
 		yeah
 		we usually have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> once a month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what do you look for in a restaurant
 	
 	
 		uh i hate franchised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you what you
 	
 	
 		i despise franchised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> i i
 	
 	
 		oh i
 	
 	
 		always prefer to go to
 		something that seems more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> run uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		some place where you
 		seem to have the attitude like you're going into their home for dinner almost
 	
 	
 		i know what you mean i like some ambience and
 		i like good food i don't like fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX> and all of that
 	
 	
 		i don't
 		but i don't like something fake or put on either uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if i could have the the good small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or a good large restaurant i'd go to the good small restaurant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		i don't know why that is
 		i think it's probably due to
 		pricing often
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh i don't care to go to a place just
 		for the price of it huh
 	
 	
 		well yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it's uh continental <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or something really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		with high prices and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> isn't what i usually look for
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it is what you usually look oh isn't isn't
 	
 	
 		it isn't no that isn't what i look for
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i try to
 		get my money's worth
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		not just that i try to
 		well that's a big part of it i try to get my money's worth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 		and not just in quantity you know but but quality and and
 		flavor and and texture and care
 	
 	
 		presentation and
 	
 	
 		well presentation's not always all of it either it's it's important
 	
 	
 		well like
 		we we've been eating some in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that that just changed hands recently and we're trying to give them a little patronage but
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> we went there and i had a
 		pretty good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grilled pork chops</ENAMEX> and a baked apple
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i said if they would just add a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cranberry sauce</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah something a little extra
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's what i mean by right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and just for color if nothing else
 	
 	
 		it would mean a lot to the looks of the plate
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		what i miss up here is
 		i'm originally a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>
 		and i'm
 		miss
 		home cooked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> yeah yeah home cooked Tex-Mex uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> where
 	
 	
 		Tex-Mex Tex-Mex
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's not owned by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> or a corporation
 	
 	
 		right i know
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and we've really gotten to like we like the real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food better than the Tex-Mex
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well there's real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food and there's real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tex-Mex Mexican</ENAMEX> you know by
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> generation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> heritage
 	
 	
 		it's all pretty good isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh yes  and and there's big differences of course and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course when you talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> cuisine you that's kind of like talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> because
 		its regional too
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh that's true
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> so we like seafood too and that's something we don't get here and we're in the mountains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood</ENAMEX>'s frozen
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ah yeah that's  the way it is here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> also
 		no fresh  or almost no fresh seafood
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and
 		
 
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we got it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh true lots of shrimp
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> on vacation
 		and i think everything except breakfast was seafood for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a week</TIMEX> and it was
 	
 	
 		i know it
 	
 	
 		i was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> starving at every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know the feeling
 		we do the same thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> and when he goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> he eats lobster i guess at least twice a day all the time he's up there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ha</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's a lot cheaper there isn't it lobster
 	
 	
 		oh yes yeah it's like
 	
 	
 		it's like shrimp on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two ninety eight</NUMEX> a pound for a pound lobster
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two ninety eight</NUMEX> a pound
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's as cheap as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> some places
 	
 	
 		oh yeah or cheaper right yeah a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> you can get
 	
 	
 		i mean in a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">pound two one pound</NUMEX> lobsters for like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten ninety nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh  i've got to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> then i you may have sold a trip for some time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah it's a good place to go
 	
 	
 		uh it sounds wonderful uh so
 	
 	
 		lots of little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> too with home cooked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that up there
 	
 	
 		that sound good i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> i've eaten a bunch of those little
 		oh seafood <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX> we've called them
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh it's just it so much different than to eat something that's been frozen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shrimp</ENAMEX> straight out of the bay bay
 	
 	
 		we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> after right after well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first of this year</TIMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh ate in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and they claimed to have the best shrimp on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was it true
 	
 	
 		no it wasn't on the way across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> we pulled off we saw a billboard and just pulled off taking a chance on a place
 		and they had it was a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> just kind of out of the way
 		and they were set up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> buffets one for their regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and everything and then one complete seafood buffet
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that was the best shrimp i have ever had in my life they had shrimp fixed probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different ways
 	
 	
 		ah yes the cajuns
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right it was wonderful
 	
 	
 		they can they can do things to shrimp that that no one else can so have you eaten crawfish yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh i tried it but i didn't care for it not there but at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> i tried it
 	
 	
 		oh as with anything it's preparation
 	
 	
 		that's probably true it
 		i wasn't hungry it wasn't a meal we just he went down and bought some at a local place that steams them just so we'd try them
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it there's all kinds
 	
 	
 		probably needed some cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> with it and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so you do eat out a lot
 	
 	
 		quite a bit
 	
 	
 		uh one of our other
 		real problems with going out to eat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> brunches
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> brunch all all you can eat brunches
 	
 	
 		right
 		we used to do that once in a while but we don't anymore
 	
 	
 		uh we still find it fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's fun but it's just so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>  hate to come away feeling uncomfortable
 	
 	
 		but
 		well am
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i work in machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and do a lot of physical labor
 	
 	
 		do you well that makes a difference
 	
 	
 		and so
 	
 	
 		where do you go to brunches like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah uh actually one of our
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> is a chain
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and in spite of the
 	
 	
 		we eat at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		and in spite of the fact i've spoken so badly about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains chain restaurants</ENAMEX> uh
 		
 
 		we uh do like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney</ENAMEX>'s pretty well but then there's a
 		place up the pass up in the mountains
 		that we pretty reliably like to go to on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>
 		drive drive up to i think it's about
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight thousand</NUMEX> foot elevation and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and
 		and drive through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodland Park</ENAMEX> and
 		go for a short drive in the mountains and have breakfast and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that sounds nice
 	
 	
 		it it
 		it's the way to spend a a nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right i imagine it is
 	
 	
 		i think it's as much the the trip to the mountains as it is the breakfast brunch you know  and it's not that far it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> miles
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		where out of which direction from out of which direction from there west uh-huh
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> what
 		west west out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	