
 
     		
 	
 		some of the TV shows that uh i i like are usually something that shows me something about a profession that i don't
 		necessarily know how it operates and one of the earliest shows that uh taught me something was the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bewitched</ENAMEX> shows when i was growing up
 		i remember thinking so that's how the advertising game is played that's how they developed these things that's where commercials come from and i really didn't uh before that i think that was the very first show that i ever realized that on and then
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh a little bit later i don't particularly like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> as a series but i do like some of the insights not so much into the legal profession but into the
 		the fact that some of the well for instance some of the deals that are made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DA</ENAMEX> you know you read about some of these things and it sounds really bad well you don't know what's gone on before
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case where uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DA</ENAMEX> had been injured she had been hurt and you know was a little bit fearful of of making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> uh any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> at the moment
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so uh just little things like that makes well there's a human behind this little story you know that that was was written up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DA</ENAMEX> cuts a bad deal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as well as some of the the arguments on you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gets arrested for DWI well depending upon
 		what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> says he's going to say in court regardless of the truth what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> says he's going to say is you know is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes later</TIMEX> before they gave me the test and
 		all these kinds of things and you could probably get away you know get off on it so they just plea bargained it out and is just done with it
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		oh i i those little things i guess i have to be reminded that there're there're so many details that just don't get out that you can't uh can't take the reported word
 		for some of these things so i guess i like shows that that show me something some insights into other parts of of living that i don't always get exposed to how about yourself
 	
 	
 		right i
 		i don't know i've i like tend to like a lot of the old uh
 		older TV shows like uh for instance there there's i love watching old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twilight Zones</ENAMEX> and uh they've
 		they've been there's a station <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> here that runs mostly syndicated things and that's one thing i like to catch on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX> is the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twilight Zones</ENAMEX> but uh
 		for TV that's out right now i i the shows i like to see for one reason or another that i've been
 		catching um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> for some some are i guess are my TV night and i like to see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Heat of the Night</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> shows that that i like to see after seeing the the television show <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Heat of the Night i</ENAMEX> wanted i haven't never seen the movie but uh i think i'd like to check out that movie sometime it's uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know it's just kind of interesting they have great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in that uh TV show and it's interesting from i just saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> to it
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or two ago</TIMEX> and it was a special <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> thing but it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> like like i said a pilot and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in it were the white police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> when the black the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> went down there were much more bigoted and more the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>
 		in that episode and now over the time in the television show they're all very much uh uh
 		not not bigoted or very more more you know more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twentieth century</TIMEX> now let's say or or very  unbigoted and they even have added uh this uh other
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police officer</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> so it's interesting how they kind of got away from the original i guess the premise of the movie as well was the problems that that uh
 		he had with the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and now it's more concentrated on the problems they have in the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the south and it it's kind of interesting because it's supposed to be this little tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in down in
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh down south but uh i live in this little teeny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> up here in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and it's not too much different so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got a lot to learn everywhere
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh that's interesting yeah yeah i i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heat of the Night</ENAMEX> through off and on through out it's uh
 		television career as it were and i i wonder if uh if they did that intentionally or if they just had uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		whether they decided to do away with the the racial problem as the main thrust of it or whether they were going to show that eventually that would die down somewhat that um
 	
 	
 		right i i don't know either i don't
 	
 	
 		quite possible that they wanted it to become more of the subtle problems that it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as opposed to the the hitting over the head type problems that it was then
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh they they have uh uh pretty good
 		bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and well acted parts i mean you can take a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and put him in a bad part and it doesn't do any good but uh they they found a good combination of roles and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and actresses on that show and it's a pretty good one
 	
 	
 		sure
 		it's a lot different seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carroll O'Connor</ENAMEX> in that role than uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie Bunker</ENAMEX> it's like
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and maybe a little more versatile than anybody ever gave him credit for
 	
 	
 		didn't get the
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah there're there're just starting to rerun those uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All in the Family</ENAMEX> down here on a particular on a major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and it's
 		uh i never did like it particularly and i've watched a couple of them off and on uh just to get a feel for what what was being said then but it
 		uh the i i don't know it's it's it's a pretty simplistic deal and i mean they they pound whatever message they're going to say over and over and that's about the end of it so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i would have liked it when it was current and and being discussed maybe it would have been a little better but uh
 	
 	
 		course the this is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Heat of the Night</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		no the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All in the Family</ENAMEX> reruns that are showing showing now
 	
 	
 		oh oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All in the Ha Family</ENAMEX> right right right
 	
 	
 		they they really take whatever point they're wanting to make they they reiterate it over and over you know it's as if the the intelligence level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that watch this or something other they handle over a wide you know range of
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		of uh topics but uh the uh i don't know maybe it would have been better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX> through when it was more
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh when the public was talking about it you know sit around the table and talk about the this that and the other but some of the issues seemed a little out dated but of course that's what reruns are for and
 	
 	
 		right when is relevant or
 		yeah well you've got old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meathead</ENAMEX> there and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> at the where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meathead</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Sally Struthers</ENAMEX> there with the um the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>
 		the the supposedly correct view at the time and then uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie Bunker</ENAMEX> with his uh antiquated uh the rednecked uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		ideas i don't know it the old meets new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on and  whatever but now it's all old so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you could have another one you could have a new TV show with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Reiner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Struthers</ENAMEX> in with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> moving in and uh
 	
 	
 		right going another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s problems
 	
 	
 		yeah and have them be uh oh i don't even know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX> are passe now i'm not even sure what uh
 	
 	
 		what to latch on to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know well i hear one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kiddos</ENAMEX> coming in the door so i'll wind this one up and go see what they need
 	
 	
 		okay well it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		maybe we'll cross paths again later
 	
 	
 		
  
 		all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		um bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	