
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are knowledge as knowledge about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> as i am
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		can i guess your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> if you had one might be the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Steelers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> i can understand that i you know i kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you
 	
 	
 		they've had some great games in the past
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i i always enjoy watching this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> together you know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh me too
 		it wasn't nearly as much fun when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradshaw</ENAMEX> was playing for you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i'll tell you he lives in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area now as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		
 
 		does he really
 	
 	
 		well actually it's probably closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> but it's it's in the same area he bought uh bought a big horse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> out in a little town called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roanoke Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he pops up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> scene quite often as a matter of fact there was some talk about trying to get him involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in some sort of a coaching job
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh wow i wonder if he'd ever do that
 	
 	
 		i don't know he'd be good at it he's such a motivator he primarily you know with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> that would be his specialty i wished i wished they could work something i really like him i really do
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Oilers</ENAMEX> do you like them
 	
 	
 		yeah okay i'd love to see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> play in a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> that would be really great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that may not ever happen i don't know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> has had some wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> you know down through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX> they really had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Moon</ENAMEX> is is proving himself quite well right now
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		he certainly is he's very good
 	
 	
 		uh-huh he's one of the few uh black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> that there are
 	
 	
 		he's very good
 		that's right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Cunningham</ENAMEX> was with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but he's no longer with the team
 		so you're right there are very few black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> or at least that are starting anyway how do you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steelers</ENAMEX> are going to do this year you have any idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know i hope they they do better they they during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> they've been doing a little bit better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i think they still have a little i think they're still such a a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i think they still have a little bit to go before they reach the potential  that it did when ever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradshaw</ENAMEX> was playing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah that was just such super team
 	
 	
 		or if they even reach that potential again you know they may never reach that again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's a tough it would be tough to do it really would they have such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super team</ENAMEX> for years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that won what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowls</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in a row
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in a row i don't know if that could ever be duplicated again or not
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know shooting for one for the thumb now is what they were saying but basically everyone that was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> then is gone now so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right  and
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Webster</ENAMEX> was left but then he he just left uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		he may have been the last of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think he is i think he was
 	
 	
 		yeah they had such a super team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you been following the big draft that occurred yesterday
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i didn't
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's quite a bit of activity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> of course they had so many you know nice uh choices because their record was so lousy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> they picked up you know quiet a few
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		of the of course you never know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they pick you know may may never play a game you just never know it's it's a gamble it really is they may get hurt or not be able to participate at that level if you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well who would you say is your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> or has ever been your favorite player
 	
 	
 		ever been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that played probably before you were born  his name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Huff</ENAMEX> he used to play for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that was one of the toughest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that i've ever seen in my life as far as you know dedication he just went all out every single play of course there have been some other great ones too <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Butkis</ENAMEX> and Bradshaw you know there's been so many
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but if i had to pick one i would probably pick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Huff</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		oh you know that's really funny um well i i come from a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and there there's quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> so that's kind of how i got in with the football either watch that or watch nothing and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i could name all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steelers</ENAMEX> you know and but even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradshaw</ENAMEX> was playing i i don't know i i didn't particularly care for him i thought he was kind of cocky or something uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		he is he is of course there a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> has a big ego
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		they really do they have to have they can't survive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they always think they can win you know which is the way it should be and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he never gave up i'll tell you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco Harris</ENAMEX> i really didn't care for the either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean they were good but i you know you couldn't deny that but i didn't i thought you know well i just didn't really care for either one of them uh today  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> out of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were probably um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambert Ham</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stallworth and Swan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh absolutely i can't disagree with that they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super players</ENAMEX> they really were they really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh i i i like not just with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> i like watching on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> when they'll have like the plays or the the best plays from you know from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah highlights yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i love watching that then i like watching their bloopers too you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah that's kind of funny too as a matter of fact  some of them a a bit embarrassing
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah well they make mistakes too i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh it's funny that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't get hurt
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		you know especially i would say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">receivers</ENAMEX> when they're in the air and they get tackled
 	
 	
 		uh-huh go ahead
 		they take such a beating
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's funny some of their necks don't get broken
 	
 	
 		absolutely i don't know how they do it it's it must just take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent concentration i guess because they know they're going to get hit it's just a matter of how hard you know or where
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		an they have to be in ideal physical shape basically
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely they look like sometimes they're just broken in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> like a match stem gosh what a beating they really do take a beating they really do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well what did you think of um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> the refrigerator
 	
 	
 		i think he was just probably a passing phenomena i think  i don't know i i'm
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		knowing what you know of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ditka</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> is knowing his or you know knowing of his temperament i'm just surprised he ever you know kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> around i really am he's such a he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a half</NUMEX> hot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> anyway such a temper
 	
 	
 		oh you know and to me he does um oh he's just so big and fat he doesn't even look like he's in shape he's just so big no one can move him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right yeah absolutely there's just so much mass there i guess they just can't i don't know you know i probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is you know probably physically strong i you know obviously not very fast but i guess it's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like you say a mass that nobody can seem to to get out of the way as far as him scoring touch downs you know i think that was kind of weird i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh his name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nate Newton</ENAMEX> now he has a real weight problem too he fights it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single year</TIMEX> but he manages to still keep playing but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he has a terrible weight problem
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		they watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> watch him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> long they they weigh him several times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> just to make sure he's not you know completely out of control
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i guess most every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has some has someone like that i don't know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah there's there are some really big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> playing in football
 	
 	
 		absolutely they get bigger and bigger it seems every year i guess you have to to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		know to stay in the game i guess yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah you would
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh um</ENAMEX> now who would you say that you have a favorite i mean other than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> would you say that you have uh a favorite quarterback i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX>'s seem to get most of the the attention you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah sure well you'd have to uh or i would have to say you know someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> i guess who's done so well for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i really i i enjoy watching him play
 	
 	
 		yeah his age is about to catch up with him though
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's no Spring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> anymore and like you say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Moon</ENAMEX>'s an excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Moon</ENAMEX>'s an excellent but he's very exciting to watch uh-huh sure uh-huh absolutely
 	
 	
 		no but he's still performing
 		yes he is i i i enjoy watching him also
 		what about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marino</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i'm obviously he's a very good quarterback i'd i never was you know too a whole lot of a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		i think he'll get better as he gets older
 	
 	
 		yeah he may uh-huh
 	
 	
 		because he he well was he was the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> there was wasn't he
 	
 	
 		yes he was i believe that's right at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in time yeah but he's a very young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> can look so good if he's got a lot if he's got a good supporting cast you know  if not he gets beat to death like poor old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Aikman</ENAMEX> has the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of years</TIMEX> anyway you know well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> did better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> hopefully they'll do better this year
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 		uh probably around twelve
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um i didn't i don't know i i just think you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marino</ENAMEX> will get better and uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s not as good as what it was when he went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> you know so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right that's right yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>'s had some down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they all do i guess it's it's cyclical i guess as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> get older get slower
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah  that's true yeah and with age comes you know the the i'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> sets in with them you know right yeah
 	
 	
 		get slower
 		
 
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		oh yes very much so hip injuries and things like that yeah yeah that that forces a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to get out of the game
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and they're so young but they're retired you know and their so young still
 	
 	
 		that's right uh-huh yeah i read some time well not too long ago that the average
 		uh professional career only lasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> so that's when you think about it that's really not a very long time of course
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah but then you think about how many have been in there longer than that
 	
 	
 		yeah but if the average is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> that means a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> don't make it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of them would have to get out like in just a couple
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		holy smokes i didn't  that doesn't seem like very long
 	
 	
 		that's that's a pretty short career on average
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course they play their you know cards right and do some good investments they'll you know they'll do all right but a lot of them don't unfortunately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um what do you think of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Raiders</ENAMEX> used to the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they they're always branded you know as a bunch of outlaws and if their if their
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know arrest record won't let able won't let them play anywhere else they seem to go to they seem to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> but that just may be you know perceived
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know perception i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Davis</ENAMEX> is he's a kind of strange character strange strange looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> apparently he's
 		kind of a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i don't really know for sure they've had some excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> though obviously i'm not sure they've yet decided where they want to play they keeping talk about you know going
 	
 	
 		yes they have uh-huh
 		
 		
 	