
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		i guess i'll start um one uh big thing that the advise that i would give to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> to give to his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is
 		to let their let their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> experience college
 		in a kind of general sense i like large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> because i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> they have fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> there and i feel like that now if i went
 		if i had gone to a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that only had a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> that i wouldn't have have gotten as much exposure to different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and different uh
 		i don't know different languages different cultures and things like that just by being around those fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's interesting i went to a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>  of probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three thousand thirty five hundred</TIMEX> and i i i thought that was the best experience in that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more one-on-one</NUMEX> since we seemed to know everyone on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and we had a broad spectrum of languages and cultures and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and backgrounds and so forth so i thought it was wonderful to be a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and not so much a number um
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of fifty thousand i was one of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three thousand and</NUMEX> and you know different perspectives i uh but it sounds like we were both kind of looking at the same sort of sort of thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum yeah
 		yeah yeah i i could see i could see that point i could see how it would be i'm sure your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> were a lot smaller um because like we would have biology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> that did main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that everyone has to take i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> so actually yes you were a number
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um i i just i don't know i'm thinking in a sense of uh
 		just being exposed to more
 		it just seems like in a larger college you i don't know you're exposed to so many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the world and i'm sure a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come to you know small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> also but just that they're more
 		of of the different cultures there not that it not that it's better but i'm just saying that i think that big
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		that's one thing to definitely consider
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh i think uh a lot of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> now would probably be afraid of a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that i talked to even here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> they go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor um</ENAMEX>
 		they or they're considering going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX> they're also considering going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT Austin</ENAMEX> but one of the big
 		no no is because of the fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and i have to tell them that just like just Waco like i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> it's a large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i can still function in my own kind of
 		area in my own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> i have a job i have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and i'm really not as as concerned about the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> so when you go to a big
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a big university you're not as concerned about the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> but your group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> your classes your interests your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think that's probably key to me is not so much the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but what what are the particular needs of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and whereas some would immediately feel very comfortable in this um larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> setting some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> um when i was when i was teaching school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would not have been comfortable with that they needed uh at at least at first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum right
 	
 	
 		they needed a smaller setting that that was more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> where they could get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> from from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers professors</ENAMEX> and so forth and then after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or two move on to
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a little bit bigger pond where where when they had a little more self-confidence built up oh yes i can do this oh i've done this before it's just in a bigger setting and so maybe to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		the key would be what what are what are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s needs and what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> can best meet those those needs besides education you you you can expect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all of them with uh uh uh accreditation accreditation to give the education
 		but it's these other things that you and i are are keying off on that that are really more of an education that but they're the things that don't show up in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		on paper um-hum exactly that's that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> important thing that i think about school i'm i'm not a kind a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that i didn't i i was kind of a B student i guess you'd say and i didn't really
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		i was  i strived strived to be an A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> but it wasn't like a real priority to my my priority was just
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		being as worldly as i could possibly be  getting into as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> as i could possibly could and and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other point i was going to make was that i can understand i can see that probably if i had gone to a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> i would probably have
 		more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		because you like you said you know
 		you know everybody knows everybody and so you probably come out of it knowing and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i mean like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> for when you get out of school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know you just you may walk into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and see someone you went to school with more so at a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> then a large college you may have gone to school with them but you wouldn't you wouldn't know them uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess let me think of another important thing to look at when you look into college
 	
 	
 		i guess i guess now i've been out for i i'm i'm older than you i've been out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one years</TIMEX> and i was looking at an annual last night uh something had sparked it sparked a question and i went to a
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		small private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> um and it was church related and i got to looking at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty nine</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i realized that even though that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two hundred miles</NUMEX> from here and i've lived in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and done other things for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past twenty years</TIMEX>
 		where i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> now there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that went to school at the same time in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> as i and it it's neat to know that we have that contact that goes back that some of the same
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> if not the same
 		education education in you know we we weren't all out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or or whatever so we didn't have the same classes but we had a common thread something that still ties us together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty odd years later</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		wow
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and it's it's it's kind of neat just knowing that those kinds of things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those are what i carry beyond just that piece of paper that allows me to be an exempt at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		i have something more important to me than that
 	
 	
 		that's great that's great yeah that's what i that's basically what i and when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> i've been out of college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two years</TIMEX> now so it's still pretty fresh on my memory um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but now that i'm out when i went into school my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> told
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> okay let me let me go back to my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> now is is in college and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was really interested in getting her in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would look good on her on her uh diploma etcetera and so forth and and i kept pushing her towards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U UT</ENAMEX> or a larger school
 		and it was just a big conflict between us because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and i wanted her to get
 		the life experience out of it and so it was you know she went the academic way because she's a straight A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> which is yeah yeah yeah so she you know that's probably
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i was going to ask who won
 	
 	
 		you know what she what she wants anyway but that was the big deal and
 	
 	
 		in in that case uh regardless of what you or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> pushed for it sounds like she was going for what she needed and finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that that met her specific requirements and and made the best fit for her
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		and that that's another point is that the a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> should tell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to be
 		or or to give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> the leeway to choose their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> not so much choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for them but you know kind of guide them along but let them more or less choose what they need and what they're going to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think it helps uh uh now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was going to pay if i went to uh what's now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> because it was there in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> i could live at home but i chose to go to another school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and even though he was pleased that it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> he was not willing to pay any at all even the same amount of money and and i think i value my my education more because i had to work for it
 	
 	
 		hum
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		and because i knew all along that's what i wanted even even though i had to buck the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in order to to do what i needed to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right well that was pretty courageous
 	
 	
 		so um i i guess i guess it was it was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s support that got me through it that and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> of of uh loans  after i got out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah yeah i i'm
 		i'm dealing with the loans right now  so so oh yes very every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>  that memory just shoots back in my mailbox
 	
 	
 		sounds familiar huh your it's very fresh in your memory
 		well
 		uh yeah
 		yes well sorry about that Tanya
 	
 	
 		so oh well i guess i'll get over it  but oh yeah yeah okay
 	
 	
 		i'm sure it was worth it though
 		if if nothing else because i work in training at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> now if nothing else just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those experiences beyond and and including your educational classes that help give you the self-esteem to do and achieve whatever you set your mind on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the you you made the right choice in going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that met all of your needs to make to give you the the potential to do whatever you wanted
 	
 	
 		right because when you when you do want when you do finally graduate
 		that that's what you need the most i'm finding out now that what i'm needing the most now is not smarts not what i can do on paper it's stamina courage uh
 		words it
 	
 	
 		young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> you have gotten your education then that's that's right
 	
 	
 		yes i'm needing you know myself i'm needing to rely on myself and i think i learned a lot of that in school too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	