
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Jay</ENAMEX> where do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right at the intersection of the busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> in the state and a uh that goes east and west and a north south tollway
 	
 	
 		what's that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-30</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Express</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's no it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">635</ENAMEX>'s the highway it's the looper that goes around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and then uh the tollway is called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas North Tollway</ENAMEX> just moved here about uh
 	
 	
 		okay yeah
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one about a month ago</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one years</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> miles to the east
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 		oh how about that
 	
 	
 		so it's a very different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> from the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh house</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a new home
 	
 	
 		it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years old</TIMEX> it's uh it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX> type thing uh very modern and um very open and airy light
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> years
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's different than those than the long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> ramblers um-hum
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh well we we live in a brick story and a half um
 	
 	
 		what's your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Cod</ENAMEX> style i guess you'd call it and uh a big
 	
 	
 		oh great yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX> room on the back of it
 		it
 	
 	
 		so it's got a lot a openness openness openness and light also
 	
 	
 		no  have
 	
 	
 		oh it doesn't well that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> really wanted and so uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		with openness and light i understand that i would love that too
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 		uh our our last <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> wasn't too bad but it was just too traditional and so if uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah this is very traditional
 	
 	
 		the next the next time uh probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX> from now we're gonna try to build
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so make one really um contemporary and and very modern and very open and very light
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		no i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in college they they usually get back for the least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> oh boy
 		you still need space plenty of space
 	
 	
 		but
 		still need a little bit of space we we have a lot less than we had uh recently already cut back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		uh-huh well
 	
 	
 		how big is your place
 	
 	
 		it's uh oh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twenty five thousand twenty five hundred square feet</NUMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		oh that's  good size
 	
 	
 		it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we we had
 	
 	
 		and that it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> built on it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and then uh big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> on the back
 	
 	
 		yeah we had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four bedrooms two and a half</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths uh</ENAMEX> in the place we just left
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so down now we're down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um-hum so it won't be terribly wonderful when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are home but it won't be that long because we not for sure you know how long they're gonna stay or whatever
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh i was just reading an article um
 		that there were nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> properties available in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh for sale by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resolution Resolution Trust Company Corporation</ENAMEX> repossessed
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes and if you can get in the if if if you can find one in the right area you can really pick up a steal
 	
 	
 		i i guess so
 	
 	
 		uh we we really didn't go that route and didn't look uh but um
 		the plenty of them and the and the housing market probably still gonna even go lower there are many many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> just for sale just by the regular route
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		that's discouraging if you own property
 	
 	
 		yeah and we just decided uh uh sell and we got we got a pretty good price uh for for what we had uh not as good as it would've been
 	
 	
 		few years
 	
 	
 		say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years ago</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that um
 		that was just the timing
 	
 	
 		right well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> moved up back up here he's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but course she's from here um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and had their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on the market down there and they never did sell it so they stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> and she got her job back and he got a job down there because
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well yeah they're not moving very well for sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		and that's a good uh
 		example of it
 	
 	
 		they live in Rowlett
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i know where that is i've been we've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		have you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i teach i teach at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> here so it's uh
 		it's sort of home now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> are you teaching at
 	
 	
 		i'm uh uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven</ENAMEX> uh it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven College</ENAMEX> it's one of the community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it's just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two miles</NUMEX> to the west of where i'm living so it's very nice very convenient
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> i know is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland College</ENAMEX> is out it serves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> and that's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about nine miles</NUMEX> to the east of here so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Garland uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		anyway well it's good to hear from you and i hope we hope we did them some good uh on their little computer dealie and uh
 	
 	
 		well enjoyed talking to you
 		i hope so  right
 	
 	
 		uh have a good life the rest of it bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay thank you same to you bye-bye
 		
 		
 	