
 
     		
 	
 		so how do you keep abreast of the world's happenings
 	
 	
 		when i'm driving to work i listen to a radio station which is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour</TIMEX> news and that's how i get most of my stuff that gives me about uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">thirty minutes thirty five minutes</TIMEX> each way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> so that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour and  hour and ten minutes</TIMEX> worth of
 	
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>'s that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh KRLD</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		KRLD i listen to uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> point one which is KERA
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh that's the same way i do it i drive about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> actually so listen to that going and coming
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh
 		i don't usually watch the news at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> time because uh i'm you know just got home ready for dinner and and all that and by the time i get done with dinner it's already over and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what a deal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well do you feel like you're kept abreast
 	
 	
 		pretty much yeah because they have the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> uh world news on on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX> on the radio so i get all of that stuff then plus i get all the local news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well what do you think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> to get out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> areas
 	
 	
 		uh what do you think i don't know that's pretty strange
 	
 	
 		it's a it's a different bold move i mean uh with still regardless if we won the war or not it's still uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah you know i mean uh with with like with regard to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> we're telling the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> you know hey the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baltic States wanna</ENAMEX> separate go ahead and let us separate that'll be good you know what what if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> south wanted to separate like they tried to do in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen sixties</TIMEX> would we be so forgiving and say ah sure go ahead form your own country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		you know i mean  seems kind of hypocritical hypocritical of us to to be telling other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to like go ahead and let part of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> separate off you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> he's the one who wants to keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> together which i can understand you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that wanna separate they wanna get away from all that garbage the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> i don't blame them either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's it's an interesting uh kind of a catch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not something
 		that's something that they got to work out for themselves we shouldn't be involved in that we shouldn't even be talking about it you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should just stay away from them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and just let them figure out for themselves what they need to do
 	
 	
 		that that is uh
 		that is a bit difficult
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> should not do anything but as as as for the rest of but though i don't you know we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'll i'll flip through that you know once or twice but not  won't won't read it cover to cover
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		do you read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T News</ENAMEX> at work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh i used to read that all the time
 	
 	
 		i do that all everyday so that's another way but that's mainly you know that doesn't have like a whole lot just a few things on there which is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you notice what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> stock closed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i didn't either
 	
 	
 		huh
 		i didn't see it
 	
 	
 		i hear it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty two</NUMEX> though yeah no it well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week ago</TIMEX> it was at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right is that up
 		wow
 	
 	
 		but that was uh i believe because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>' meeting
 	
 	
 		should've sold
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> i was in well it guess you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		i guess you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		i did until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh that's how come i don't read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T News</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah you got surplused i got i got surplused <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> myself yeah
 	
 	
 		did you that's that's great  did you just find a a place in another
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> yeah they
 	
 	
 		another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> organization
 	
 	
 		they needed somebody just like me whereas before i was not even doing what i was supposed been doing but uh that's not that's not the topic i guess but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's kind of interesting that they can you know say get out of here in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX> and then the other side say come on over here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that worked out pretty well for you i was talking talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> who is
 	
 	
 		it did quite a bit better
 	
 	
 		implied or inferred definitely that he has been surplused from up there and he didn't know what he wanted to do he's been with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for fifteen years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		so it's uh and he's a nonexempt uh he doesn't know what he's gonna do they're just shutting down the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's gonna be a tough time for all around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i mean you look at the  look in the paper and you see all the stuff about you know layoffs here layoffs there and you think oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> what's gonna happen
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know thank goodness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> got that big contract because that'll least bring some money to the area
 	
 	
 		right who who got the contract
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well yeah i always get mixed up who's their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> with that late latest deal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> on this
 	
 	
 		is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> i used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and at the time i was there they were developing the prototype for the uh that fighter
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it was pretty big stuff there then now they got the contract for it so
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GD</ENAMEX> didn't get it or is not associated
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they're they're in in partnership with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> yeah it's a it's a threesome
 	
 	
 		oh they are okay
 		so it's i thought it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX> or was that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX> lost out they lost the contract they were in partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX> and they lost the contract and so
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah that'll be a biggie i wonder what they do with those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> now that they've made as uh test
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		test plane
 	
 	
 		probably sell to somebody who wants to pay for i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah becomes a new corporate jet
 	
 	
 		yeah there you go old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> can use that
 	
 	
 		there you go
 		yeah exactly alrighty well it's been good talking to you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye
 	
 	
 		okay you too bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	