
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the subject is how we feel about immigration
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		would you like to get started or would you like me to
 	
 	
 		well i am very much in favor of closing our door to some extent i'm afraid i've gotten a little bit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America</ENAMEX> first when i get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		almost any large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> barely speaks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		that's happened to me too
 	
 	
 		yes of course it also happened to us in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sidney Australia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this</TIMEX> Summer uh or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Summer</TIMEX> we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> and
 		again it was an oriental person
 		and we asked him to take us to the opera <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and he did not know what we were talking about
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		so maybe my isolation isn't for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>  might be a little bit for the world i don't know but uh
 		i just feel like
 		we are we have accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> so well to the point that we have not taken care of our own how do you feel about
 	
 	
 		well i have i'm really torn on the subject i'm not a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for this one i see what you see and i agree with you
 	
 	
 		however
 	
 	
 		well the other side i see
 		because we have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> as a neighbor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i can tell you right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that if i were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 		and trying to raise several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i could see across the border where the good life would be for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would i swim that river <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> twice if that's what it took you know i don't care whatever it would take i have real sympathy for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i really do and you can
 	
 	
 		um you betcha
 		i
 		um
 		however if you were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> in those conditions would you have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably they don't have birth control
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		they have no concept of it it's against their church
 	
 	
 		but yourself you yourself would not do that you would not have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> if you couldn't
 	
 	
 		well but they don't have if you know if i had to put myself in their shoes i have to do it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah but you don't have
 	
 	
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> doesn't teach birth control they preach against it
 	
 	
 		that's not my fault
 	
 	
 		i understand what you're saying but i'm saying
 	
 	
 		i know
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i feel real sympathy for them so i really and and and by the way i feel the same way when i i just got back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i tell you happily happily i can i can understand just a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just a little bit
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which was about all i wanted to understand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i it's amazing because they're they're bilingual
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everything is is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish English</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and i didn't particularly enjoy it quite frankly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point and i cannot say that it's true <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> but at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> was
 		required by federal law to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> so that they could teach to the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> there who only spoke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spanish</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and our language is English
 	
 	
 		that's right and i'm sorry that business
 		that's right and i'm sorry that business of making it mandatory i don't like mandatory anything
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		because it just doesn't work all the time it doesn't fit there are circumstances that are different but i do think if you come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and you're going to live here and you're going to go to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and do all of this speak our language
 	
 	
 		uh
 		um
 		i think so too
 	
 	
 		i really do and it's only fair to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i think making giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> an out that they don't have to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is just encouraging them to drop out later on because they'll never make it through high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh-uh well it's English
 	
 	
 		and if they do it won't make any difference because there's not a job for them
 	
 	
 		it's encouraging them to not speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right and that is the wrong message
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just
 		i don't know i feel so sorry for them but at the same time
 	
 	
 		but that's the same thing you're saying about the little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that you feel sorry for them and you would swim the river twice but i
 	
 	
 		i would if it were if they were my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i would so i have to sympathize with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that come over here and work and send money back
 	
 	
 		sure but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's right on the survival level and we do what we do to survive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		absolutely and and i know what you're saying we do what we have to do for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> regardless regardless of what that is
 		but i'm a little bit unsympathetic with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> right here in our own small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> who have not limited their family we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and that happens to be what we could afford but
 		i don't really feel like i ought to help even if they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> support <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that's not fair i didn't get a say whether they had them or not so i don't think i ought to have to help raise them
 		too critical i i'm concerned about world birth control and
 	
 	
 		oh i'm i'm that's that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on me too i mean
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		there are too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are just conceived and produced and dropped on society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		without a thought these crack babies
 	
 	
 		oh isn't that awful i was just reading this thing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who was a crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and she was put in a foster <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and was having a wonderful life and then her mother
 	
 	
 		are so sad
 	
 	
 		claimed to have her self her act together and she was given back to her birth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who she had never seen i mean it was just one of those awful things where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child Protection Service</ENAMEX> completely broke down
 		and now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ordered that she be given back to the foster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i it's just awful it's just awful the whole thing
 	
 	
 		doesn't make any sense
 	
 	
 		it's just awful i i as i say i'm isolationist i think we need to
 		to close our doors to some of the immigration and now they're talking about how we're bound to have an influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from the latest war from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq Iran</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> so on and so forth and uh i'm i'm really sorry that i feel the way i do but i just think that we need to not take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as we have over the many last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we had
 		there there's a little background here but it it builds up to what we're talking about our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> had a long
 		long
 		discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and basically the question started out
 		that as at the time when there were starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> i believe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the question was should we save these people
 	
 	
 		yeah because
 	
 	
 		and our bottom line answer was no
 		because we cannot save the world
 	
 	
 		because
 		well and
 	
 	
 		we cannot feed the world and we should not please the world this
 	
 	
 		and i think probably they have said that if you save these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by feeding them then they reproduce and then you have a later more serious famine yeah
 	
 	
 		this
 		and the other thing
 		is we can feed them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but they'll be hungry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> what'll we do with them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> do we feed them again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> well how long how long can we continue to feed the world we can't do it are they starving to death yes and that's very sad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sad but we cannot save them we you know okay we can save one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's good but what's you know
 		back to what you're saying if you want to save somebody there's plenty in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that need it to
 	
 	
 		when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> at home our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh is still a very giving caring wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> she's making a career of uh
 		well she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> at a care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> close to here in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> there anyhow was uh she got us involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Children's Fund</ENAMEX>
 		and we were sponsoring a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chattanooga Tennessee</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> then and that went on for oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> and finally we had a letter from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Children's Fund</ENAMEX> that they were no longer going to
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor children</ENAMEX> within the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that all of the money would be going to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> overseas because
 		for however much money we were sending a month they could buy so much more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> and so on and so forth for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> overseas well at
 	
 	
 		so they're taking the world viewpoint
 	
 	
 		yeah well at that point we said no we're not doing this any more we wanted to help somebody here within the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> it wasn't our choice to
 		to send and then too i think that money gets watered down in administrative costs when it all goes overseas and i always wonder if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need it actually get it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but by profession
 		i negotiate for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> a lot
 		and i'm somewhat cynical
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and their behavior
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i have had
 		many interesting examples of human behavior
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when you're talking about money you'd be surprised how human we all get very quickly
 	
 	
 		it all turns different doesn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we were on a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist Church</ENAMEX> were talking about how their
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church diocese</ENAMEX> had poured <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> and it had been used for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa Doc</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s wedding
 	
 	
 		uh-huh there you go
 	
 	
 		which  i'm sure that's not what they had in mind when they were pouring that money in the
 	
 	
 		but see that's what happens And the other sad thing i heard about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	