
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		um  one thing you know that i always think about when i think of public education because i went through the public um school system of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i always felt
 		that i graduated high school and i still didn't even i i i couldn't put together a map of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know what i mean and yet i felt that i got a good education and and i did well in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but you tell me to name you know
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> continents and i couldn't do it  i just feel like there are some real basics that are missing from education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>  not even knowing some common sense things
 	
 	
 		yeah when uh well talking about public education um
 		i was just just i'm we're doing a proposal at we're doing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we're trying to improve the computer science curriculum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's kind of at a higher level
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it's interesting that you chose that topic
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> did you go through a a public school system or a private
 	
 	
 		yeah well i went through private until <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		um-hum  did you notice a big difference
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah big difference
 	
 	
 		like in what sense
 	
 	
 		well um
 		in uh public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i guess
 		there were there are a lot of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can take lower level <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and get away with learning nothing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um in private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> you couldn't do that you know you had to learn
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i work in a temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that come in you know everyday to fill out an application and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they'll have to bring somebody with them and they will show that they completed um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of high school yet when it comes to even answering the questions on a simple application
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they can't read enough to be able to fill out the answers by themselves
 	
 	
 		it's bad
 	
 	
 		it's just incredible
 	
 	
 		yeah our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> just cut a whole bunch of uh like
 		think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten million</NUMEX> dollars out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> budget
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		so we're making all kinds of cuts in college
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cannot i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> can't make tests anymore and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>'s canceling all it's subscription
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's pretty sorry
 	
 	
 		i know um they uh i forget what i think it's um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">someplace</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 		because they're having budget problems they're closing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean they're not getting rid of any of the sports
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		or  anything like that they're not cutting in any other corner they're closing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> that to me shows a little uh switch in priorities you know
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so do you go to college right now are you in
 	
 	
 		yeah it's my last year
 	
 	
 		you're so you're a senior now
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm working on my projects trying to
 		graduate
 	
 	
 		oh good for you that's great um is is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC University</ENAMEX> is that uh uh state what'd you say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX> that's a state university then i see  and you're from there also
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well yeah i was uh
 		i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> and then i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winston-Salem</ENAMEX> rest of my life
 	
 	
 		um-hum i see
 	
 	
 		so now i'm back here  going to school
 	
 	
 		well pretty soon it's gonna get to the point where no one's gonna be able to afford to send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to college or to go to college
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just outrageously expensive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luckily State</ENAMEX>'s the cheap one of the cheap ones
 	
 	
 		oh is it well still though i mean you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s not that bad
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh well that's good that's good i went to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i don't know i look back now and i i think that i probably would've done it differently if i um you know could do it over again but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that went to state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or
 		didn't even go to school some some of them and i still feel like they came out knowing just as much as i did
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i really do and that's probably a pretty sad thing to say but um i don't know i i what
 	
 	
 		yeah where'd you go
 		where did you go sorry
 	
 	
 		i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandeis University</ENAMEX> it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i i really felt like i've been working now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i feel like what what i've learned working is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times more valuable than what i learned in school
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i know that i'm drawing a lot on what i learned in school you know i i probably just subconsciously rely a lot on on learned but um
 		i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and one thing that she's trying to instill in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids um</ENAMEX> besides just reading and writing
 		um are just some the golden rules she calls them just some basics about um  you know you don't take what's not yours
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and if you want to you know you don't touch anybody else unless you have their permission like no hitting you know no pulling hair or anything like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that she's in is a um  it's basically for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> um there's uh a large minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she's really noticed that
 		even some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that work there i think they don't value that type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> as much as you get in some
 	
 	
 		yeah that's sorry that that that they like pick on you know that the advanced stud ents and pay more attention to them ignore the others
 	
 	
 		yeah it's true um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i don't know if it makes them feel better i mean do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> get i mean personally i would get more satisfaction out of taking somebody that wasn't as successful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and seeing what they could do versus somebody that you know did excel in in areas and just watching them get better you know that's not much of a challenge
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		but
 		are do you have any idea what you're gonna go into when you graduate
 	
 	
 		um graduate school  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		do you know where yo u're going
 	
 	
 		i think i'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where's that
 	
 	
 		that's in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX>  that's the name yeah never heard of the Tarheels
 	
 	
 		oh is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> oh okay
 		no i don't know that area
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACC Tarheels UNC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know it
 	
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		i don't get down there very often
 	
 	
 		they were in the final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> don't watch basketball
 	
 	
 		oh really well the way i pick the final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> was um by the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that had the warmest climate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's how i chose all mine so you can tell that i didn't really have
 		that much to do with any of it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but so obviously you're into education if you can be going my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> went to is in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> actually right now
 	
 	
 		no yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know i give you a lot of credit i i couldn't do it i i couldn't wait to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and have it be all over
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 		ah i can't wait to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> either now i got all these stuff due oh wow
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah i kind of know what you mean
 	
 	
 		overloaded
 	
 	
 		well it was really nice talking to you  okay good luck alrighty take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right
 		all right thank you
 		all right bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	