
 
     		
 	
 		okay so um
 		seeing we're both from different parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> um i imagine that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> changes have happened in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> but you know is rapid i'm not sure could you tell me some of the things that's happened in your area
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i thought the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of the question you know how do you perceive life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> differently
 		you know as opposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that one  my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are
 		are fifteen
 		so
 		that's huh you know that that was immediately what clicked in my head what do i see now
 		different than i do you know when they were born
 	
 	
 		when they were born yeah
 	
 	
 		you know um i have my oldest are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> they are fifteen and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		so not quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen</TIMEX> the um
 		i think we're seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> and lots of  of changes as regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> you know at that point i felt like i was one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that truly wanted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and now i think you're seeing that a little bit more it's coming back again
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are certainly having their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> later
 		you know it's not
 	
 	
 		uh yeah in some cases uh
 	
 	
 		and the ones that are having them earlier they're having them a lot earlier  like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven  or ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's yeah that's early uh i was kind of young i i got married as soon as i got out of school and started raising a family so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my oldest is uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four</TIMEX>
 		and my youngest is going to be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		so that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		definitely makes a difference my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was quite a bit older when we married and
 		we decided to you know we wanted to
 		to get our family pretty quick you know and
 	
 	
 		yeah right yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		that was you know really a definitely uh identifying factor you know we began
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i i'm not sure about that  excuse me
 	
 	
 		in having a
 		well i know that uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> we have the unfortunate um
 		reputation as being i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth</TIMEX>
 		largest of uh i'm trying to think how that was <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> on the list
 		of teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we have i think in nineteen it seems like the statistic was for nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas County</ENAMEX> there were
 	
 	
 		yeah the problem yeah
 	
 	
 		i want to say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred and fifteen</NUMEX> gosh that seems like an awful lot
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> born to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> under the age of thirteen
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but  under thirteen probably what do you contribute that to then as compared to say uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 		you know with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it can't be education because you know there's more and more family related issues being raised at school
 		um
 		you know they're lot more progressive more pointed sex education programs all over the country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right right i grew up in kind of uh there was a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> and there was nothing but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and
 		mostly mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy</ENAMEX> and orchards apple orchards and you know peach orchards uh
 	
 	
 		one thing that i really see a difference and i guess you know overall uh you know that it's a negative
 		is that
 		you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we live in suburban a suburban area
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do not have the aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>
 		the cousins
 		you know that built-in kind of security
 		you know
 	
 	
 		why because we're a more mobile society
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just moving out getting jobs and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> on
 	
 	
 		you know of course you have lots and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> working
 	
 	
 		that's that's a big problem because at least i i see that up here when when i was growing up and going to school uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> never locked their doors and uh you know you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that was
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		generally in the area most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of stayed put you know very few moved away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so there's kind of a nucleus of cohesion there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that you could rely on you know if you were ready to just
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> back then was naive
 	
 	
 		strangle your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you kind of had
 		course there's just a different uh just different feeling as to who who's in control i don't think we ever talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s rights
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know we didn't talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights  you know we sure didn't talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' rights
 	
 	
 		yeah right and and
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have responsibility but i think the the biggest thing now is that uh information is is passed on a lot quicker with with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX> and radio and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are under a lot more pressure because from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> than than it used to be
 	
 	
 		well you know i can remember as a teenager
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know we would
 		get things fashion wise you know we always consider considered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> coast you know i mean you know feel very uh um
 	
 	
 		yes right yeah
 	
 	
 		always felt like we were on the edge of of new trends and you know i had a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and in
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> because that's where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were from
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and we would go there they were always seeing movies that had been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> before and they were wearing clothes and saying lingo using new lingo that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we heard way before and so we always felt you know a little you know kind of thumb your nose and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but now that's not so you know if those those those parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> aren't behind you know they're getting the movies if not you know
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		right at the same time they're getting them you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks later</TIMEX> it's not you know not so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		and yet i think i think we're really evolving right now i
 		you know the seventies and eighties were so uh get all you can cause you may not be here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> and money hungry  i think we're seeing some comeback to family um
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i
 		yeah it's uh
 		a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> yes um
 		but you can't trust anybody anymore
 	
 	
 		it's it's a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> unit though
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		you know it's not the same that we  traditionally thought of
 	
 	
 		no it it goes back i guess way way back  peo ple had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they and they they were kind of uh they most of them were on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> i guess or they worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>
 		at least in the east you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> before him always worked at this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> so then i would work at this place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um out in the rural areas we were always <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> or was always going to be farmers
 		so you had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they kind of money didn't seem to be important back then
 	
 	
 		when we uh moved to this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> this a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> there was still a lot
 		lot of agriculture of of land that was used for agricultural purposes and that is just you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> just a little bit more a little bit more slips away
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 		yeah but with a uh  excuse me with a uh
 		run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> or or were the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> going out into the world and then they were bringing in
 	
 	
 		i don't know um
 	
 	
 		you know labor is to to take care of the crops
 	
 	
 		i think probably main a lot of it was you know contract labor um
 	
 	
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wanted something more i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> want something more there's a great deal of respect in this area for agriculture and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> that it has given this particular community
 		and we still have a couple of very viable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who are you know make large contributions time money you know emotionally to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and preservation preservation of its heritage but we don't uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but but even their concerns are becoming more diversified
 	
 	
 		yeah i i your
 	
 	
 		but you know one thing that and this is just totally off the wall but it's another uh another element as we see the encroachment of
 		of progress on
 		just the ecosystem ecosystem when we moved here and the the fields were mowed every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> we would have this massive influx of crickets
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		from the fields into our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> you know just  i mean crickets so thick you couldn't walk without stepping on them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and course that then brought different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> that didn't normally come to our area and i don't know what all other effects on the ecosystem because that's not my bailiwick but see we don't have that anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you wonder what other little
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s changed it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i was reading in uh
 		i think it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX> about
 		
 		
 	