
   
   
      
         
            Property Is Theft

            When your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> installs
a burglar alarm, thoughtful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">burglars</ENAMEX> are encouraged to choose a different
target--like your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, for example. It's rather as if your neighbor
had hired an exterminator to drive all the vermin next door. On the other hand,
if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> installs video cameras that monitor the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in front of
both your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, he might be doing you a favor. So the spillover effects of
self-protection can be either good or bad.

            Consider
the different ways that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> self-protect against car theft. Devices like
alarm systems and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>" have a social upside: Their proliferation might
make car theft so unprofitable that potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> would decide to seek more
useful employment (though, on the other hand, it's possible that they'll seek
employment as, say, arsonists or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> for hire). But those same devices have
a social downside: They encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> to prey more heavily on those who
haven't bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. From a social viewpoint, if the total number of thefts does
not change, then the expenditure on alarm systems is pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX>.

            For a much lower cost, you can install "fake"
self-protection--say, a little blinking red light that looks like it's attached
to an alarm system, or a cheap piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foam rubber</ENAMEX> that looks from a distance
like the heavy metal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>. Here again you're imposing a cost on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>:
If these devices become common, the value of the real thing is diluted.

            That point was driven home to
me the last time I shopped for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acura</ENAMEX> offered a security system as
mandatory equipment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> allowed you to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> without a security system.
You could then go out and install your own system for considerably less than
what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acura</ENAMEX> was (implicitly) charging.

            But I
decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acura</ENAMEX>'s system--even at a much higher price--was the better deal.
Professional car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> know that the security system is mandatory on
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acura</ENAMEX>, and therefore know that my blinking red light is for real. With the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>, even if I do install a real security system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> might suspect me
of trying to fool them and smash my windows to find out.

            
There's another kind of security system,
available only in a few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lojack</ENAMEX>" is a hidden radio transmitter that
can be activated after your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is stolen, to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX> (or,
better yet, to the chop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> that employs the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>). The transmitter is hidden
randomly within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> cannot easily find it and deactivate
it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> is completely
hidden. There's no way to look at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and know whether it has a Lojack
installed. So unlike, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> will never prevent any particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> from being stolen; it will only increase the chance of its being recovered.
But from a social point of view, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> has the huge advantage of
helping your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> rather than hurting them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> convinces
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> to steal someone else's car instead; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> convinces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> not
to steal.

            And it does so with
remarkable effectiveness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Ayres</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Levitt</ENAMEX> have examined
the effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 10 years</TIMEX> (its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> introduction was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>). Their task wasn't easy, because just
as the prevalence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> affects auto-theft rates, so auto-theft rates
affect the prevalence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX>--first because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> buy more security
equipment when theft rates are high, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> behave
differently when thefts are high.

            But after
sorting all this out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayres</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levitt</ENAMEX> found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> has an
astoundingly large effect on auto-theft rates. It turns out that a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>
increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lojack</ENAMEX> sales can reduce auto-theft rates by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> or more.
What's happening to all those car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>? Are they moving to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, or
are they becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> burglars, or are they turning into socially useful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayres</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levitt</ENAMEX> examined these difficult questions also, and their
bottom-line conclusion is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> really does prevent a lot of
crime, rather than just moving it to other venues.

            In fact, although it costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only about $100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to have a
Lojack, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayres</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levitt</ENAMEX> estimate that each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Lojack</ENAMEX> prevents about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in losses due to theft. In most cases, that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX> benefit
accrues not to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, but to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>.

            By the criteria that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> usually employ, this suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojacks</ENAMEX> should be heavily
subsidized, just as visible security systems--like my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s home burglar
alarm or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>--should be taxed. When you're doing something that makes
strangers better off, you should be encouraged to do more of it.

            If we all used the same
insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, you might expect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to supply the appropriate
subsidy. As long as your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> reduces the number of insurance claims, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> should be willing to pay you to install it. But with multiple insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, that doesn't work so well: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that insures <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 10 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> will reap <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 10 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX>'s benefits, and so will
undersubsidize them. Worse yet, large insurance discounts are illegal in many
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have recently paid
a lot of attention to research on other kinds of self-protection, most notably
the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mustard</ENAMEX> on concealed handguns. But the Lojack
research is in many ways more informative, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> were able to do
a thorough job of distinguishing between benefits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchaser</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lojack</ENAMEX> and benefits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> at large. That discrepancy is the sort of
thing that leads markets to fail--in this case by providing too many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Clubs</ENAMEX> and
not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Lojacks</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
