
   
   
      
         
            Quotas and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>

            "The issue, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>,
is not affirmative action but racial preferences," declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town Hall</ENAMEX>" discussion on race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> returned the volley: "Do you favor abolishing the affirmative-action
program that produced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>? Yes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">or No?</ENAMEX>" Thernstrom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of an
anti-affirmative-action tome (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in a current dialogue on race in

                  Slate
               ), responded that she does not "think that it is racial
preferences that made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>."

            In the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX> amplifies: Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> benefited from
affirmative action. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> has a good kind of affirmative action,
which expands equal opportunity without making racial preferences. She offers
as an example <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>'s promotion to brigadier general by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford Alexander</ENAMEX>. When originally sent an all-white
list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for the position, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> rejected it, demanding a list
that included some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. From the revised list, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> noted
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s 
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of reverse discrimination often
insist that they support affirmative action. And they often point to the
military as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> that's got the distinction right. The
military, by all accounts, has indeed done a great job of integrating its
higher reaches and achieving racial harmony without harming its ability to
serve its mission. Affirmative action in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is a success. But has the
military avoided the alleged poison of reverse discrimination? Not at all. The
real lesson of affirmative action in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is that reverse
discrimination is not so poisonous. It gave us <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX>'s anecdote about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brigadier general</ENAMEX> is ambiguous on
its face. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> asked for a list that included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and then chose a black
off the list. Equal opportunity or reverse discrimination? A little more
information resolves the ambiguity. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> wasn't on the original
list is that he was, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>, below the age normally considered eligible for
promotion to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brigadier general</ENAMEX>. An exception was made in order to give
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> a black as he had requested. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>, who has always been
forthright in his defense of affirmative action, says himself that he wouldn't
have appeared on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> list or been made the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
if it had not been for preferential treatment.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX> and others imagine the military as a
place where (in her words) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rise or fall according to their merits, not
their race." But this is a misconception. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> set stringent guidelines
for minority recruitment and promotion that sometimes surpass the supposed
excesses of racially obsessed university admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. For instance the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>, long the most resistant of the services to affirmative action,
recently changed its promotion policy to increase its number of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>.
Now, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> are accepted, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20 percent</NUMEX>
of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>. Do you believe this is the result of pure "equal
opportunity," with nary a drop of "racial preference"?

            Both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> have set themselves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> deadlines to make their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer corps</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-percent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-percent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latino</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-percent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX>. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> article supporting these quotas, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-Marine recruiter</ENAMEX> boasts of his tactic for meeting these goals: "I routinely
turned down long lines of qualified white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> to save room for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. I
denied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> interviews. I put their names on waiting lists. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every few months</TIMEX>
I threw stacks of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumés</ENAMEX> into the trash."

            But what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>--the service most celebrated for
its history of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">colorblindness</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> implemented its affirmative-action
policy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'70s</TIMEX>, responding to rising resentment of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>
among the black rank and file, which had resulted in race riots on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>. To
diversify its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer corps</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> began targeting scholarship money
disproportionately to ROTC programs at historically black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and began
heavily recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Point</ENAMEX>. At least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> of each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Point</ENAMEX>
class must be black. That's an order.

            Army
guidelines explicitly require that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>-promotion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> take
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' race into consideration. Promotions, the guidelines say, must
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> match the racial composition of the pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The regulations
naturally say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> should not lower standards simply to boost
numbers, but affirmative-action plans often say similar things, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
usually have little trouble seeing through it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the panels are under
heavy career and political pressure to meet goals. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>,
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have been appointed to promotion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explicitly</ENAMEX> instructed to act as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> for the minority and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> candidates
who appear before them. To see that as expanding "opportunity" and not granting
"preference" is wildly naive.

            
Promotions are reviewed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> agency
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Equal Opportunity Management Institute</ENAMEX> to ensure that the
process was racism- and sexism-free. A recent article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
Standard showed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> who serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> on a rotating
basis are trained in lengthy seminars, rife with the goofiest sort of political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correctness</ENAMEX>. In one class on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Male Club</ENAMEX>," an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> lectured: "Q:
Who are the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> that sustain power over us? A: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>." In other sessions, they were required to confess
their own biases and were shown videos from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey Racism</ENAMEX>
Series .

            So if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of affirmative action in the military mimic those of affirmative
action in higher education, why hasn't the military taken the same flak? Unlike
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> has none of the notorious statistics about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropouts</ENAMEX> and racial separatism and it has many success stories, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>'s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer corps</ENAMEX>, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s, has been
successfully transformed from a clubby elite, where promotions depended on
golfing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, into a more integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">meritocracy</ENAMEX>.

            To be sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s program insists, though more vaguely
than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> admit, that affirmative-action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> must meet the same
minimum qualifications as their white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. But there is a critical
difference between being qualified, in the sense of meeting some minimum
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard</ENAMEX>, and being better qualified than all those who are rejected. Choosing
a black over a better-qualified white is still racial preference, even if they
both are "qualified" in the absolute sense.

            The main difference between
military and civilian affirmative action is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> has an
overabundance of minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Consequently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> can eliminate its
weakest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>--and still
have a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>
and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> must compete aggressively over a much smaller pool.

            When affirmative action
works, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> deny its essential nature. For affirmative action to do
anything, it must involve advancing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are slightly less qualified.
Not, one hopes, un qualified, but less qualified, under otherwise
prevailing standards, than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get passed over. It is necessarily a
sloppy process that injects another arbitrary standard into an already
arbitrary decision-making process. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> shows the process can work, and
can help.

         
      
   
