
   
   
      
         
            Booked Up

            Following a survey of our
wall space, plus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>, and every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has estimated that I own something on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX>
books--enough, she points out, that if I read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a day for the rest of my
life, there's an excellent chance I won't live long enough to finish them all.
Still, I keep buying books at an alarming rate. That's only partly because I'm
attempting to deny my own mortality. It's also because buying books is so much
fun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.

            Of
course, there have always been plenty of ways to have fun buying books--such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prowling</ENAMEX> through cavernous used-book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in search of hidden treasure or,
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, driving <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> through glorious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
countryside to attend the equally glorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Valley Book Fair</ENAMEX>. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
recent innovations have ushered in a true golden age of obsessive book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shopping</ENAMEX>: You can head over to a luxurious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>,
lounge in comfortable chairs, sip <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, and listen to music while you
contemplate your selections. Or, if you prefer, you can shop from a Web-based
service such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, which offers a sophisticated search engine, reviews
at your fingertips and, best of all, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-click ordering. Ordering from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>
is so easy that I often come away from a virtual visit with the exhilarating
sense of not having the vaguest idea how many books I've just purchased.

            By and large, the amenities you get from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>
are quite a bit costlier to provide than the amenities you get from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX> One
reason B & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> feels so comfortable is that it's spacious--and space costs
money. By letting you browse among physical books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B & N</ENAMEX> invites damage and
theft. The well-stocked shelves require a substantial investment in inventory.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> avoids most of those costs, and it passes some of the savings on to the
consumer--popular hardbacks (except for best sellers) are typically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX>
percent cheaper at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX> You can enjoy luxury at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B & N</ENAMEX>, or you can enjoy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX> and low prices at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX>

            So far, so
good. The market offers a range of options. Those options that provide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> with sufficient value will thrive; in the long run, those that fail
to justify their costs will face extinction. If enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are willing to
pay B & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> prices for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B & N comfort</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B & N</ENAMEX> will prosper; if not,
not. Either way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> will applaud the triumph of consumer sovereignty.
Likewise, if enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are willing to sacrifice physical browsing for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> discounts and convenience, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> will prosper; if not, not. Once again,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> will stand ready to endorse the judgment of the marketplace.

            
But there's another potential outcome, and it's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> would not endorse. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> browse in the
comfortable atmosphere of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> but then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> home to buy their
books from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> at discount prices. In sufficient numbers, such consumers
could spell B & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>'s demise. (Even in much smaller numbers, those consumers
surely limit B & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>'s growth and its willingness to provide even greater
comforts to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX>.)

            It's one
thing to watch a business fail because of its own inefficiency; that's just the
market doing its job. But its quite another thing to watch a business fail
because it's efficiently providing a service for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> have managed
to avoid paying. In the scenario I've envisioned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B & N</ENAMEX> falls victim to the
economic equivalent (though not, I think, the moral equivalent) of theft. Among
the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> are book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> themselves.

            How can this disagreeable outcome be avoided? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> solution
is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> to own the Web sites; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B & N</ENAMEX> won't mind losing
business to one of its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX>. And to a certain extent that's
happening: It, and other large "superstores" such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borders</ENAMEX>, has begun
operating <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>-like sites. But as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> itself remains independent
and holds a substantial market share, at least a part of the problem
remains.

            In
principle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> could come to B & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>'s rescue by pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> to
raise its prices. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> relies on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> for timely book shipments, so
the instruments of pressure are readily at hand.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> might or might
not want to play that role. On the one hand, they have a considerable stake in
the success of large and luxurious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>; on the other hand, they also
have a considerable stake in the success of services like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX> My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in
the publishing industry tell me that, on balance, they wish <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX>.

            
At other times and in other industries, things
have gone the other way. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwinn Bicycle Co.</ENAMEX> famously
refused to supply <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discounters</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>
of mattresses, patent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>, electronics equipment, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">herbicides</ENAMEX>, and light
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bulbs</ENAMEX> have insisted that their products be sold only at the full retail
price.

            Why would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwinn</ENAMEX> want to maintain a high retail price for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX>? The naive
explanation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> always like high prices. But that's
too naive: The price <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwinn</ENAMEX> cares about is the wholesale price, and it
controls that directly. A more plausible story is that bicycle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> like to
visit fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX> with knowledgeable sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> but then buy from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discounters</ENAMEX>. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> recognize that there is no reward to
offering quality service, and the fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX> disappear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Customers</ENAMEX> are made
worse off, and so is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwinn</ENAMEX>, as there is now less reason to prefer a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwinn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bicycle</ENAMEX> to others.

            By forbidding its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> to compete with each other via
prices, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwinn</ENAMEX> forces them to compete with each other via quality of service,
to the ultimate benefit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. That was exactly the reasoning endorsed
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, when it upheld the right of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharp Electronics</ENAMEX> to
terminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> of a chronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discounter</ENAMEX>.

            In its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharp</ENAMEX> decision, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> showed an admirable understanding and respect
for economic theory. Not so the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Times , which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">editorially</ENAMEX> called for legislation to overturn the ruling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
asked for compromise legislation that would give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> the right to
"set high standards for service and refuse to supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> who don't meet
them," while denying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> the right to set prices.

            
But in the presence of competition among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, there is no difference between setting a standard of service and
setting a retail price: For a given service standard, competition will lower
the price until it's commensurate with the service standard, and for a given
price, competition will raise the service standard until it's commensurate with
the price. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' prescription is comparable to allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
choose how much to sleep while forbidding them from choosing how much to stay
awake; the reality is that you can't choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> without choosing the other.

            So, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
recognized, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discounters</ENAMEX> can be clearly detrimental to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> in the market for electronics or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX>. But when it comes to
books, the analysis is a lot less clear-cut, and here's why: A discount bicycle
dealer offers nothing but low prices, whereas a Web-based discount book dealer
also offers special services you can't get from a bookstore--such as the
convenience of shopping from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. That's why bicycle and electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>
have been so keen to stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discounters</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> have laid out a
tentative welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
