
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorilla Warfare</ENAMEX>

            The current effort to
sexually integrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is not without precedent. Consider the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">natives of New Caledonia</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX>, who earned their place in
military annals by subduing and then eating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> survey ship in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1850</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> typically headed off for war in unison, although their
roles did differ once the fighting began. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would fall back to the
rear; then, as one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> put it, "whenever they see
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the enemy fall, it is their business to rush forward, pull the body
behind, and dress it for the oven."

            OK, so these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aren't
quite the role models that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of sexual integration would order up from
central casting. But history has provided few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for that job. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Davie</ENAMEX> noted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX> in his cross-cultural survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Evolution of</ENAMEX>
War , "war is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the human race."

            As a
rule, the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have not traditionally performed a given role has no
bearing on their competence to perform it now. Centuries of female exclusion
from academia or civil engineering haven't rendered modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> unfit for
those professions. However, male dominance of the killing business seems to
have been going on for a lot longer than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few centuries</TIMEX>--maybe long enough to
have influenced human evolution, shaping the biological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of human
psychology. If so, does that mean male and female psychology are so different
that the sexual integration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is misguided? The question breaks
down into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> subquestions.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> designed by natural selection for warfare?
As regular "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Earthling</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may recall, the premise of evolutionary
psychology is simple: Those genetically based mental traits that, during
evolution, consistently helped their possessors get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> into the next
generation became part of human nature. Careful thought experiments have shown
that, in a context of regular violence, mental traits conducive to killing
would do more for your genes than mental traits conducive to getting killed
would. So if during human evolution <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> often fought in wars and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> didn't,
then indeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> might be naturally better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            Of course,
the frequency of war in prehistory is not well recorded. (Hence the term
"prehistory.") But various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>-gatherer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>--the nearest real-life
models of the social environment of human evolution, and thus the purest
observable expression of human nature--have been known to engage in
intervillage raids. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aborigines</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>,
according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chronicler, made it a point "to massacre all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> who
fall into their power." In some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a fourth</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> die violently.

            
And whether or not our distant male ancestors
often participated in actual "war," they probably fought other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and
sometimes killed them. The warless !<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kung San</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter-gatherers</ENAMEX> of the Kalahari
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert</ENAMEX>, once romanticized as The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harmless People</ENAMEX> , were found a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX> to have homicide rates between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 and 80</NUMEX> times as high as
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. (And some of this killing is coalitional--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend gang</ENAMEX> up on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, etc.) So, ethnographic evidence alone
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> could well be designed by natural selection to fight, and
perhaps to do so in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.

            There is
more evidence, which we'll get to shortly. However, the policy implications of
any male propensity to fight would depend on other questions. For example:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> by nature shrinking violets, innately
repulsed by war, incapable of violence? Hardly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feuding Australian</ENAMEX>
Aborigine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would sometimes square off and whack each other with yam sticks
until somebody intervened. Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ainu</ENAMEX>, the indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>-gatherer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would go to war and actually fight, though only against
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            Even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">combatants</ENAMEX>, they hardly shy away from the thought of war, or from its gore.
Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayak</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borneo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would surround a
returning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>, singing songs of praise, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> sat nearby on a decorative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass tray</ENAMEX>. Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanomamo of South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> watch the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> fights" that sometimes escalate into
intervillage conflicts, screaming insults and egging their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on. Among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ba-Huana</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one 19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ethnographer</ENAMEX> reported, "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief instigators</ENAMEX> of war are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>." If their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are insulted by other men
and don't retaliate, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> make fun of them: 'You are afraid, you are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, we will have no more intercourse with you! Woma, woma [afraid]! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hu</ENAMEX>!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hu</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hu</ENAMEX>!' Then out go the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and fight."

            All told,
though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> are less combative than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, they are not wholly averse
to combat. And plainly, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are more eager and capable fighters
than some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. (I'm male, but no one has ever confused me with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronson</ENAMEX>.) So why deny high-testosterone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> an opportunity to join in the
fun? If there is a good reason, it has to do with our final question.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> fight so much? Here we come
to a problem that will prove stubborn if the military tries to sexually
integrate ground combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX>. The problem isn't so much
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are designed by natural selection to fight as what they're designed to
fight over: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> .

            Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanomamo</ENAMEX> men
raid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and abduct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for procreative purposes. Moreover,
tough, mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> enjoy high social status, which attracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and helps the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> into the next generation. The anthropologist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon Chagnon</ENAMEX> has
shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanomamo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who have killed other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and more
offspring than average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.

            It's not
just a question of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> disinclined to violence getting killed off. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
might fight over a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> until <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> submits and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
Or, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> might fight for seemingly nonsexual reasons, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> still
enjoys the high social status that wows the ladies. Indeed, it's possible that
non-lethal violence has done more to shape the male propensity for violence
than simple killing has.

            Male combat is common among primates. It is the reason
that, in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">primate species</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> are so much bigger and stronger than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the more polygynous the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>--that is, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> a
dominant male can sexually monopolize--the larger the size difference between
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX>. The toughest male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> get a whole harem of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> to
themselves, and the wimpiest get zilch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eons</ENAMEX> of combat over such high genetic
stakes have led to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> that are about twice the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>. In our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, the more modest but still marked difference in size and strength
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is hard evidence that violence, whether lethal or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-lethal</ENAMEX>, has paid off for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> terms. Among the other evidence
is the fact that testosterone makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aggressive.

            The
problem with fielding a sexually integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> wouldn't be that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> can't fight. Try stealing a female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and see how you
fare. The biggest problem is that if you put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> together with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unattached female, esprit de corps will not ensue.

            
Yes, of course human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> are better at
controlling their hatreds and rivalries than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> are. But are humans
so good that it makes sense to sprinkle a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into a group of infantrymen
and send them all off to war, where everyone's prospects for survival will
depend on their solidarity? Hoping (even subconsciously) that one of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> will die seems a poor frame of mind to carry into battle.

            Does the
same argument apply to nonmilitary workplaces? Doesn't sexual integration sow
dissension there as well? I'd say that any downside to sexually integrating
nonmilitary workplaces is not severe enough to restrict the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>). And--in many workplaces--there may be a big upside to sexual integration.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is special. The cost of dissension is death, not lower
earnings. (And during big wars, when the draft is on, many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who didn't volunteer for the job. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big difference between this
issue and the issue of sexually integrating police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.)

            This logic has no direct bearing on the currently topical
issue of sexually integrated basic training. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> that take basic
together don't go off to war together, so their bonding isn't a matter of life
and death. Still, basic training is meant to model some of the rigors of war,
and it turns out to be a useful model indeed: The complaints of sexual
harassment that deluged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aberdeen</ENAMEX> scandal (which itself
didn't involve basic training) show how male and female psychology can
complicate life for a sexually integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. Obviously, the more conspicuous
problems--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> propositioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, for example--can be minimized with
sufficiently harsh punishment. But the underlying psychological forces will
still be there, taking their toll. And remember: When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> go from training
camps to actual war, things get more primitive, not less.

            One can imagine combat roles
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that wouldn't fly in the face of human nature. (Why not try ?) But
reflecting on human nature doesn't seem to be a common pastime at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>.
Sexually integrating ground combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> is now favored by one assistant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Togo West</ENAMEX>, has said he is open to
the idea. And already combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are somewhat integrated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
(squadrons of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> (ship <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX>). (These things, though, as
integrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX> would be.) Given the stakes, shouldn't such decisions
be informed by some knowledge of sexual psychology? Or, instead, we could just
wait for a war and use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-olds</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guinea pigs</ENAMEX> in a poorly researched
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> experiment.

         
      
   
