
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poison Gas</ENAMEX>

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> became
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Foreign Relations Committee</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, many of his
missteps have been harmless, even amusing. Who among us didn't chuckle when he
introduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> as "the distinguished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>"? But now comes the horrifying prospect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>
could actually play an important role in world history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical Weapons</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX>, signed by roughly the entire civilized world, awaits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
ratification and is bottled up in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>.

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> large defects. First, the treaty's verification rules
would violate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sovereignty, allowing foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> to swoop down on a
factory "without probable cause, without a search warrant," and "interrogate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>," "remove documents," and so on. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the treaty isn't tough
enough to reliably sniff out chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to please.

            Let's leave aside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' factual errors (he's about the
search warrants) and look at his basic paradox: that the treaty is too tough,
yet not tough enough. This is not logically impossible. Chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> could,
in theory, be so elusive that even a sovereignty-crushing inspection regime
couldn't find them. But if that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' view, then he is opposed not just to
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>, but to the very idea of such a convention. Why doesn't he just
admit it?

            In any
event, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' paradox is the claim now being emphasized by
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in their crusade against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>. Via radio, TV, and op-ed pages,
we're being told that the treaty is "not verifiable." In a sense, this is true.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convention</ENAMEX> will definitely not succeed in sniffing out all chemical weapons
everywhere. But it will definitely do a better job than is being done--or not
done--now. Given this upside, the question becomes: What's the downside? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Helms</ENAMEX>
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> offer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five downsides</NUMEX>, all of which vaporize under
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX>.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Huge regulatory burden. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of
the treaty initially exercised the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> reflex of complaining about
the cost to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> will have
to fill out some forms. But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> doesn't join the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treaty</ENAMEX>, these same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> lose sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that do join. That's one

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Medium-sized
regulatory burden. Faced with the big chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' support of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treaty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> tried arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> an unwarranted burden. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms resoundingly</ENAMEX> declared on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor
Unfortunately, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFIB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> then pointed out that this isn't true. It is
"our belief," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , that "our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are not going to be impacted" by the treaty.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in
uniform. Some treaty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> argue that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> destroys its
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, it will have surrendered a vital deterrent to chemical
attacks. But you don't need chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to deter chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Cole</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Eleventh Plague</ENAMEX> , has observed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> refrained from using his vast chemical stockpile during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War</ENAMEX> not because he feared retaliation in kind , but because he
feared retaliation of comparable, or greater, magnitude . (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
Schwarzkopf, who has retired and thus needn't toe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s line,
supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>.) Even before the treaty, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had decided to
destroy its chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>, deeming it a needless headache. No one had even
bothered to complain about this until the treaty linked it to the dreaded New
World Order.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Surrender of
sovereignty, Part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> op-ed piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> asserted that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">treaty</ENAMEX> would "require that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> assist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> in modernizing
their chemical-weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>." That would be strange, wouldn't it? A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treaty</ENAMEX> expressly devoted to eliminating chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> obliges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to
help build them? This claim is based on of a somewhat opaque section of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treaty</ENAMEX>, and is widely considered ridiculous.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
Triumph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rogues</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>--all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal sponsors</ENAMEX> of terrorism and repositories of chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>--are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">signatories</ENAMEX> and won't be affected." Well, it's true that these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">signatories</ENAMEX> (though most suspected chemical-weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">possessors</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, are). But it's quite false to say that they "won't be affected." In
fact, they will be shut out of the market for many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, including "dual
use" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that are ingredients of both nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and things like ink. This
is part of the innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of the CWC: permanent economic sanctions
against nonmembers.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Right now</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are suspected of
pursuing chemical-weapons programs, and they do so with impunity. After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treaty</ENAMEX>, they will fall into one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) those that suffer economic
sanctions and a clear-cut stigma, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) those that have agreed to allow
short-notice inspections of any suspicious site in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>. That's not
progress?

            It's true
that once an inspection is demanded, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> (for example) can stall. Though the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort inspectors</ENAMEX> to the perimeter of the suspected
site, it can then argue that the search violates its constitution, or whatever.
(If this national prerogative weren't preserved, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would be the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to object.) Such a standoff, when it occurs, will trigger a global media
event, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> broadcasting satellite shots of the suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>, and so on. If this drags on for too long, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> (say) seems
inexcusably obstinate, it can be judged noncompliant by a vote of convention
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and sanctioned accordingly.

            
All told, the treaty is so much tougher than
anything in the history of global arms control that to call it an important
evolutionary step borders on understatement. And it comes just in time, because
technology for making biological weapons is spreading. What, you may ask, is
the key difference between chemical and biological weapons? Oh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corpses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrious</ENAMEX> CW-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> could kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
subway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> in a day. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrious</ENAMEX> BW-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> could more or less do
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> in the same time. Right now there is nothing approaching an
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> for keeping biological weapons out of the hands of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. If there is ever to be one, it will have to resemble this treaty at
least broadly: surprise inspections of suspicious sites, the economic and moral
ostracism of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that don't cooperate, etc.

            Will this approach work? We
don't know. It depends on such questions as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) how effectively the
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> can monitor the average rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> once they start
synergistically pooling their intelligence, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) how tough economic sanctions
have to be before even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syrias</ENAMEX> of the world fall into line. It's much better
to answer these questions now, with chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years from now</TIMEX>,
with biological weapons.

            The basic flow of world
history, as I'm not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to note, is toward interdependence. Increasingly,
the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> face common problems soluble only through concerted effort.
This often involves some marginal sacrifice of sovereignty: an agreement by
each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to constrain its future behavior so long as others do, and
systematic deference to international judgment. You see this logic at work in
environmental issues (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio</ENAMEX> accords, now being toughened), economic issues
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>, growing in importance), and other areas. The
the future, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX> is a paradigmatic, if imperfect, solution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>
is a paradigmatic relic.

         
      
   
