
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel Gas</ENAMEX>

            Nobody said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> was infallible. It did, after all, give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> the peace
prize in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX> have traditionally been conservative
about whom they bestow scientific awards upon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX> got his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> in
physics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX> after he published his work, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> declined to
endorse that reckless relativity stuff.

            What,
then, is one to make of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> in physiology or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> awarded to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neurologist Stanley Prusiner</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s hypothesis is that fatal
brain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maladies</ENAMEX> such as mad-cow <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creutzfeldt</ENAMEX>-Jakob <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> are caused
not by viruses, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, fungi, or some other mundane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> but by something
startlingly new that he has discovered--mutant, rampaging <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> known as
"prions," short for "proteinaceous infectious particles."

            But do prions cause these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most distinguished scientific
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX>, have published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> suggesting that the causative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> are not prions, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> of
prion research is simply wrong. The latest of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> was published last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2</TIMEX> issue.

            Before
moving on, a quick course in molecular biology: All living <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>, from
viruses on up, pull off the feat of self-replication by encoding the necessary
information in nucleic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>--in particular the double-stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> discovered
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> or, for a few renegade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viruses</ENAMEX>, single-stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> or even
single-stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. These nucleic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> then code for and generate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>,
which are the stuff we're made of. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s proposition is that it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>, not "slow viruses," that are the infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in mad-cow-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. This is what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s hypothesis so radical: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prions</ENAMEX> would be
the only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> on the planet that reproduce--not to mention infect and kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>--and thus the only known exceptions to the rules of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick-Watson</ENAMEX>
paradigm of molecular biology.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s proposition has been controversial
from the get-go. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> who did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California at San Francisco</ENAMEX> quit over the publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s very
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> prion paper in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prusiner</ENAMEX> was overinterpreting the
available data to push the prion hypothesis.

            Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 15 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX> won over virtually everyone to his prion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypothesis</ENAMEX>--the lay press, the scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>--but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>. He got his share of bad press, for which I take--and am given--entirely
too much credit (read my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1986</TIMEX> feature story in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clicking</ENAMEX> ). By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> were still suggesting that the
prion hypothesis was at best a long shot, he won a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4-million</NUMEX> congressional
award "to determine the structure of prions and how they cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>." In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX> reported at a major conference that he had proved that the
infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> were proteins free of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acids</ENAMEX>. In
particular, he had created <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with a genetic mutation that caused what was a
normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>--the prion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s lingo--to become abnormal and
produce disease. He then took brain matter from these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and injected it into
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, which promptly got sick, showing that no viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX> were
necessary to transmit the disease. But there was still no paper proving the
results to the scientific community.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years later</TIMEX>, when he presented the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> work at
another conference, the news pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Nature</ENAMEX> wrote it
up as if it cinched the prion hypothesis. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s work had not been
replicated by anyone and he had still not published these supposedly seminal
findings that prions cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> in a peer-reviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, he won the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prestigious Albert Lasker Award</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1994</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lasker Award</ENAMEX> is
considered a short-list for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>.) When he finally published his
proof-of-prion paper, it was only after it had been rejected by the journal
Cell . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX> managed to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proceedings</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy of Science</ENAMEX> , where it wouldn't have to be
peer-reviewed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> was largely ignored, and it was dissed even by
Prusiner, who admitted to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncompelling</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> who read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> suggested that its findings could
be explained by contamination, which is to say, by sloppy laboratory
procedures. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prusiner</ENAMEX> was still describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> work
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American</ENAMEX> 's lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> as "a persuasive experiment."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s
boilerplate response to prion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> has been that if mad-cow <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> or any
of the other "prion <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>" is caused by a virus, then surely that virus
would have been discovered by now. The fact is, it's damned hard to find a
virus in a mishmash of animal brains, which is where you have to look. One
reason a virus hasn't been found--if indeed a virus causes these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>--is
that no one is doing the laborious and expensive work to find it. It can take
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> to find culpable viruses--<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> C is a famous example.
But at least those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> got funded to look, which has not been the case
in the prion field. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX> has received in the neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> in
who request money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> to look for viruses are told by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>
that if the virus turns out not to exist, then their study will have been "of
insufficient significance and scientific merit" and thus not worth doing.

            
Despite the vindication offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX>,
the prion hypothesis is still rife with loopholes. For instance, the diseases
that allegedly are caused by prions come in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few dozen</NUMEX> different strains, the
same way that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> come in different breeds. It's easy to imagine variations in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">viruses</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, because they contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acids</ENAMEX>, which encode for
variations. But even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prusiner</ENAMEX> hasn't been able to explain how a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that
has no nucleic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> could encode for the variations. His own grant proposals,
available on the Web through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH CRISP</ENAMEX> database, are evidence of the problem. One
describes the problem of prion strains as a "fascinating conundrum," while
another explains that the goal of the research project is to find out "whether
the strains differ in the properties of the scrapie form of the prion-protein
... or [whether] a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> component is responsible for strain specificity, the
obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> being a nucleic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>."

            Strains
aren't the only problem with the hypothesis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX> has yet to show, for
instance, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein sans nucleic acid</ENAMEX> can be infectious, and consequently,
he has invoked the potential involvement of yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in the disease
process (although he insists it has no nucleic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and calls it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Protein X"</ENAMEX>).
Some of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prion researchers</ENAMEX> suggest it might be a "viral co-factor,"
which is doublespeak for saying that the prion ain't the infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, a
virus is.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel Committee</ENAMEX> says his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> were
aware of unanswered questions in the prion hypothesis but awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prusiner</ENAMEX> the
prize in recognition of the wealth of information he has unearthed on
mad-cow-like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. But if it turns out that viruses do cause the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX> will have won the prize for the discovery of something
spectacularly wrong.

            Good science, not just <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prize-caliber</ENAMEX> science, depends on hypothesis and test, and then the rigorous
demonstration that the preferred interpretation of the data was the only
interpretation. In other words, remarkable results demand remarkable evidence.
In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel Committee</ENAMEX> has settled for enthusiasm
and single-mindedness.

         
      
   
