
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Fleece Panic</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>

            The capitalist horn of
plenty emitted a flat note <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 days</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. Or, at
least, that was the sheet music provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' Page <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
story "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tardy Catalogue Shoppers Risk Losing Out as Supplies Run Short"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1996</TIMEX>).

            "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]hat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-Tex hat for
your brother-in-law" was out of stock at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lands' End</ENAMEX>, wrote
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Steinhauer</ENAMEX>. And the red silk pajama top from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secret</ENAMEX> catalog you had your eye on? Forget it. What's more,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the mail-order-apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> were running out of
all sorts of outerwear and slippers and silk undershirts and lace nightdresses
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two weeks</TIMEX> away from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>!

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoppers</ENAMEX>
may find they won't be able to get what they want if they don't order this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinhauer</ENAMEX> warned, sounding more like a copywriter than a newswriter.
"The most popular items appear to be outerwear and all things made of fleece.
But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> order went completely unfilled when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> was called on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> for
a 'cardinal' blanket, a hat, a pair of moccasins, a silk undershirt and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stellar Scope</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story set off a panic--not among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>--but among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinhauer</ENAMEX>'s fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. You may think of the
Times as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspaper of Record</ENAMEX>; its competition thinks of it as the
Racing Form , a national news tip sheet, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' choices
about what's newsworthy are automatically cribbed by those lower in the
editorial food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>
Star , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS Evening</ENAMEX>
News all did variations on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story, flogging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> with alarmist to semialarmist pieces about how
mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> were running out of stuff.

            Joining the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Buy Now</ENAMEX> or
You'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regret It</ENAMEX>!" conspiracy was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX> economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Brady</ENAMEX>,
whose derivative story aired <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story hit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> started with the "good news"--retail sales were up--but quickly
uncovered the "bad news" embedded in the good news. (Economic news is like
that. If somebody is making a killing, then surely somebody is dying.)

            "It's getting tougher and
tougher to find what you want, especially if you're shopping from catalogs,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> said, stoking the hysteria with his report of "tight stock" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">at Lands' End</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX>.

            Then, doing Steinhauer one
better as a copywriter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> alerted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to similar shortages afflicting
department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, reporting that the shelves at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carson Pirie Scott</ENAMEX> were nearly
empty! "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carson</ENAMEX>'s said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, forget that last-minute stuff. Get here quick.
Stocks are short. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> already are running tight on sizes and colors,
particularly cashmere and outerwear: coats, hats, gloves."

            Stocks are
short! Running tight! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS Evening News</ENAMEX> have
reported that the taupe-and-mauve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polartec</ENAMEX> sky is falling!

            
Was there a great apparel shortage during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas 1996</TIMEX>? Keeping her perspective through the media madness is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hartnett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX>, who says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX> marked a return
to mail-order normalcy . The anomaly, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story sort of
acknowledges, was the downturn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year of 1995</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lands' End</ENAMEX> overordered and
was left holding the excess inventory. (For some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lands' End</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
surplus didn't spawn a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Procrastinating Catalogue Shoppers Get Whatever They</ENAMEX>
Want as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late as They Want It</ENAMEX>" story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .) As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lands</ENAMEX>' End overreacted to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the bad year</TIMEX> by ordering <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> less
merchandise for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, and suffered for it.

            So, once
again, was there a great apparel shortage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas 1996</TIMEX>? Part of the
"shortage" was pure perception. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shoppers</ENAMEX> hold mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to a higher
standard than department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> when it comes to keeping things in stock,
because the catalogs afford them a photo and item number for every parka,
turtleneck, and blazer ever placed in inventory. When those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> shop
at a department store, they have no way of knowing that it has sold all of its
fleece-lined <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage booties</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scotchgard triple-stitched Velcro</ENAMEX> workboots
unless they ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> or keep notes from previous visits.

            Also, the fact that mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> run out of their
"most popular items" shouldn't be much of a surprise. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, you define
your "most popular items" by what you run out of. And for another, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>
hope to start running out of stuff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks before Christmas</TIMEX>. If
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lands' End</ENAMEX> kept everything in stock until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX>, they'd go broke warehousing the unsold surplus or marking it
down.

            The
mail-order "shortages" also reflect the new-found fashion consciousness of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lands' End</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> made their mark
selling sturdy commodities like chamois cloth shirts and field boots that are
easy to keep in stock because the demand for them is stable from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year to year</TIMEX>.
Not so with trendy new items like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lands' End</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$395</NUMEX> "ultimate cashmere
sweater." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> despaired to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> that he couldn't
purchase enough of them to meet demand, but that he was swimming in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> canvas
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">totes</ENAMEX>. Good economic news, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> once said, always comes bundled
with bad.

            
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> stocks
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10,000</NUMEX> items. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> conspired with the forces
of capitalism to herd recalcitrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> into buying, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was down
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 7,000</NUMEX> items. As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> weren't insistent on a specific color
or style, there was still enough stock on hand to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> from falling over and to clothe the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militias</ENAMEX>.

            And, even at this late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX>,
there's plenty of cold-weather gear available. If you doubt that, check your
mailbox for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Winter '97</TIMEX> sale catalogs from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lands' End</ENAMEX> and the
others. The horn of plenty is still gushing Headwall jackets and Penobscot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parka Gore</ENAMEX>-Tex <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shells</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Double L</ENAMEX> shirts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter Woods</ENAMEX> hand-knit sweaters
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> wool-blend herringbone scarves.

            At markdowns of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 40</NUMEX>
percent.

         
      
   
