
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect Tax</ENAMEX>

            The expansion of government
is limited by the consent of the governed. Once upon a time, that consent was
harder to come by. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">American colonists</ENAMEX> took up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> against a
government far less oppressive than the one that now spends <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of our
incomes. We're more docile now, but the threat of revolution--or at least mass
dissatisfaction--remains an important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for good. We can harness that force
by designing laws and institutions that require each new government burden to
be widely shared. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> are less likely to risk annoying <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>.

            That
wisdom underlies the "takings clause" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>, which says, in effect, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can't take your front
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawn</ENAMEX> and turn it into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> without paying you for it. The takings clause
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces taxpayers</ENAMEX> to share in the cost of any taking, and so ensures that
frivolous takings will meet broad opposition. Inspired by the same logic, I
propose a constitutional amendment capping everyone's tax bill at (say) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
times the average. Thus, if the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> in taxes some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> could be required to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $50,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>. That
would force many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> to share the cost of any new government spending,
and so ensure broad opposition to the growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            It's traditional to evaluate tax proposals according to the
twin standards of "equity" and "efficiency." Before I subject my own proposal
to those standards, let's talk a bit about the standards themselves.

            A tax system is "inefficient"
when it discourages beneficial economic activities. By discouraging working,
saving, and investment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> tax code--like any tax system--meets
that standard with ease. The only completely efficient tax would be one that
does not depend on anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> can control--such as a "head tax" of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> per year. If your behavior can't affect your tax bill, your tax bill
won't affect your behavior.

            That kind
of head tax is interesting not as a realistic policy proposal but as a
benchmark for comparison: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economists</ENAMEX> like to say that a head tax has the
advantage of being perfectly efficient (it does not discourage any economic
activity), but the disadvantage of being perfectly inequitable (the rich and
the poor pay equal amounts). But those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> are wrong on both counts.

            
Let's talk first about equity. It is an act of
violence against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language to describe as "inequitable" a tax that
charges everyone an equal amount. In the rhetoric of tax policy, the word
"inequitable" almost never means "inequitable"; rather, it means something like
"less redistributionist than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> would prefer."

            But I
don't want to dismiss a substantive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> just because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> frequently
choose the wrong word to describe it. Instead, let me make a substantive
response: Even if you believe that the tax system should be used to iron out
income differentials, it's still perfectly easy to devise a head tax that is
consistent with your redistributionist philosophy. The key is to make taxes
dependent on variables that are good predictors of income but entirely
outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>'s control. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> (on average) earn more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> do. A direct tax on income might discourage work. But taxing whiteness
would not discourage anything, while still redistributing income (on average)
from the relatively rich to the relatively poor. A tax of "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> per year if
you're white and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> per year if you're black" is a perfectly .

            On similar grounds, we could tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for being male or
tall or beautiful; all these traits are positively correlated with income. In
the case of beauty, though, we'd have to be careful to tax only natural beauty.
Otherwise, we'd discourage expenditure on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shampoo</ENAMEX>, cosmetics, and dentistry.
(In fact, if we enjoy having beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, we might want to
subsidize beauty rather than tax it; you can't always pursue two
goals--in this case income redistribution and an attractive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>--simultaneously.) Regardless of what you mean by "equity,"
therefore, you can always adjust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-tax system to conform to your
philosophy. Thus "inequity" (or, more accurately, "insufficient redistributive
power") is not a good .

            But just as the alleged
inequity of head taxes is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>, so may their vaunted efficiency be no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX>. The problem with an efficient tax system is that it provides no
built-in brake on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s avarice. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that takes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>
from everybody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> could decide to take <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
That is much less likely under an inefficient tax system. The income tax, for
example, is gloriously inefficient. The higher the tax rate, the less people
work. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> raised the income-tax rate to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>, we'd all
stop working, and tax revenue would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. To convince us to earn an income
worth taxing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is forced to let us .

            The challenge is to make
taxes more efficient without making them too easy to raise. This brings
me back to my proposed constitutional amendment: capping individual taxes and
tying the cap to the average tax bill. Adding a cap to the current system would
improve efficiency (there would be no disincentive to earn income beyond a
certain level), while maintaining the natural safeguards against confiscatory
government that are built into the income tax. In fact, those safeguards would
be strengthened by the fact that any tax increase would have to be quite
broad-based. As a bonus, a cap would bring the income tax closer to being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equitable</ENAMEX>, in the true sense of the word. The offsetting disadvantages? None,
as far as I can see.

         
      
   
