
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwitcherbellyachin</ENAMEX>'

            Do you worry that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> debt will impoverish your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>? Are you incensed about paying
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> in taxes just to cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s interest costs? And do you
long for a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> who will dare to close the budget gap, even if it
means raising taxes? If so, I have one word for you. I learned it from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landers</ENAMEX>. The word is: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kwitcherbellyachin</ENAMEX>'. Your share of the debt is an
entirely voluntary burden. If you don't want it, you can dispose of it this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. You can do the same with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s share. All you have to do
is pay off what you (or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>) owe.

            Be
careful, though: There's a wrong way and a right way to handle this. The wrong
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> is to send the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Treasury</ENAMEX> a contribution earmarked for debt reduction.
They'll accept your gift all right, but they won't credit your personal
account. Instead, your share of the burden--like everyone else's--will fall by
a tiny fraction of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a cent</NUMEX>.

            Here's the right way to retire your share of the
debt. First, calculate how much you owe. Suppose, for example, that you're the
average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>. Your share would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about$15,000</NUMEX>. All you have to do is lend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
The easiest way to do this is to buy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bond. From that moment
on, you will owe <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> to yourself , which is as good as owing it to
nobody at all. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX>, you'll pay taxes to cover your share of the interest
on the debt, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, that money will come right back to you as interest
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your</TIMEX> bond. For all practical purposes, you'll have opted out of thedebt burden entirely.

            If it's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
you're worried about, give them the bond. Let them collect interest
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of reckoning when that political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> finally arrives to raise
taxes and retire the debt. Then they can sell the bond and use the
proceedsto pay their
taxes.

            The
only possible objection to this scheme is that you have to come up with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX>
to buy a bond. But on the other hand, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> take your advice and
raise taxes in order to pay off the national debt, you'll have to come up with
that same <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> to pay your share of those taxes. So buying bonds is no
more attractive than being taxed for debt reduction, but it's no
less attractive either. If your mantra is, "Go ahead and tax me but
spare me this debt burden," it's time to stop chanting and essentially,tax yourself.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ageneration ago</TIMEX>, economics textbooks used to dismiss the
debt burden by asserting that we "owe it to ourselves," meaning that some of us
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>) owe it to others of us (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX>). That was scant
comfort to those who paid taxes but didn't hold bonds. But the old semi-wisdom
becomes genuine wisdom when embellished with the observation that anybody who
wants to can become a bondholder--and that buying bonds is no more painful than
paying taxes to alleviate the debt.

            Whenever I hear somebody
griping that the national debt is too high, I nod in apparent agreement and
point out that the problem is more general than that. "Not only is the debt out
of control," I say, "but so is my front lawn. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> is ridiculously high.
When will the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> finally face reality and force me to mow it?"

            This
usually has one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> desirable effects. Either the griper moves to the far
end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, or he asks, "Why not just mow the lawn? Why would you need the
government to force you?" In that case, I reply: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, why not just buy a bond
and eliminate your share of the national debt? Why would you need the
government to raise your taxes?" I don't mean to say that everyone should buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds. I'm saying only that everyone who complains about the
debt should buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds--and then stop complaining.

            In dismissing bogus concerns about the national debt, I do
not mean to dismiss legitimate concerns about government spending. Your share
of government spending is something you can't opt out of, short of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emigrating</ENAMEX> or resorting to felonious tax evasion. That makes government
spending a fair target for your indignation.

            Suppose a reckless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> decides to appropriate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> of your money to finance a worthless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft carrier</ENAMEX> or a worthless social program. Then one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things must
happen: Your taxes will rise by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>, or else, your share of the debt will
rise by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>. Either way, you've got a legitimate gripe.

            But if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> opts for
debt over taxation, you can count on thoughtless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> to denounce the
interest payments on that debt as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, and separate, outrage. That's
wrong, because you can (if you wish) buy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bill that will
bring all your interest payments right back to you--thereby, in effect, taxing
yourself to pay off the debt right away, and limiting your damage to the
initial <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>.

            The great burden of
government is that it spends your money. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who have devoted
their lives to exacerbating that burden--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>--would
prefer to divert your attention to relative nonissues like the deficit. Don't
fall for it.

         
      
   
