
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uncompensated Victims</ENAMEX>

            Suppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of a
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> (call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>) discriminates against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in hiring and
promotion. Who are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of that discrimination? The most obvious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who are denied suitable positions. But there's
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> class of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>: the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, who are denied
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of those black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            You might
guess that when there is discrimination, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> suffer less than the
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> do. In fact, it's more likely to be the other way around, for
reasons I will explain as I go along. In that light, boycotting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> products
would be cruelly ironic. Boycotts lower corporate profits, which punishes not
the discriminatory management but the innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>--that is, not the
sinners, but their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. There is even greater irony in the reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> will atone for its sins with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$176 million</NUMEX> payment to black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>--all of which will come directly from the pockets of those now doubly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">victimized</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>.

            To see why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> bear many of the costs of
discrimination, let's think through a few alternative scenarios.

            
               Scenario <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suppose</ENAMEX>
that jobs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> are pretty much interchangeable with jobs at, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>, and other competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>; suppose also that discrimination is a
problem only at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>. Then it's easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to escape
discrimination by taking jobs elsewhere. The positions vacated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> will be filled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, presumably of about equal competence. (Because
we've assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> jobs are interchangeable with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> jobs,
there's a large pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> to draw on.) In this
scenario, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> ends up with an all-white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX>, but no harm is done to
anybody: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> who would have worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> end up in equally desirable
jobs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon; Texaco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> who would have profited from the wisdom of
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> end up profiting from the equal wisdom of white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>.

            
               Scenario <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suppose</ENAMEX>
again that jobs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> are interchangeable with jobs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>, but
suppose this time that discrimination is rampant throughout the industry. Then
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> can treat its own black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> badly, but no worse than the industry
standard; if conditions at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> get worse than conditions at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>,
all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> will move to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Similarly</ENAMEX>, if there
are comparable jobs available in other industries, the oil industry as a whole
cannot treat its black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> any worse than the standard set by those other
industries.) So, in this scenario, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> can be harmed by discrimination in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>--but they do not suffer any additional harm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s
policies in particular.

            In this
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> scenario, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> who suffer for the sins of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. To see why, consider this example: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suppose</ENAMEX> that throughout the oil
industry, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> while otherwise identical black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> because of discrimination. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> could slash its
payroll by firing all its white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to replace them
at, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX> each. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> is too blinded by discrimination to
pursue that option, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> end up paying an unnecessary <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX>
per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> per year.

            
You might want to argue that paying blacks
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX> to do a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> job is itself a form of discrimination. I'd want to
argue otherwise, because in the case I'm envisioning, the wage differential is
driven not by racial preferences at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> but by profit opportunities created
elsewhere in the market. But that is just a matter of definition, and we can at
least agree on this: No matter how you define discrimination, hiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX> is surely less discriminatory than refusing to hire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX>. And, again, no matter how you define discrimination, the
bottom line is this: If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> discriminates less than everyone else, it ends
up with lots of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and a tidy profit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>; but if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> discriminates <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as, or more than</NUMEX>, everyone else, that profit
opportunity is thrown away. So when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s management is highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discriminatory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> are the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>.

            

               Scenario <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suppose</ENAMEX> that, contrary to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> scenarios,
it's not true that a job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> is pretty much the same as a job at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>. Suppose, instead, that each job requires skills so specific that there
is a single best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for each job and a single best job for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. In
this scenario, discrimination at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> is indeed costly to those black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who are thereby excluded from their ideal jobs or forced to accept
lower wages in order to remain in those jobs. But in this scenario,
discrimination becomes even costlier to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, who now own shares in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that does not make the best possible use of its black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>--and even
drives some of it away.

            To summarize: In Scenario <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>; in
Scenario <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> are the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>; and in Scenario <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. The truth is probably some
combination of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three stylized</NUMEX> scenarios. So, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> has indeed
discriminated against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> (and it's worth noting that the evidence for that
proposition is shaky, but I'll accept it for the sake of argument), it's quite
likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> have borne most of the cost.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> had
indulged their personal tastes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX> oil paintings at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multimillion</ENAMEX>-dollar cost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, it would be self-evident that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> had been plundered. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> indulged their personal
tastes for racial discrimination at a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion dollar</NUMEX> cost to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, the same conclusion should be equally obvious.

            If there was enough
discrimination at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> to merit a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$176 million</NUMEX> settlement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>,
then there was enough discrimination to merit a commensurate payment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>--not from corporate coffers, but from the personal assets of the
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> who bilked their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> by failing to hire the best
bargains in the labor market.

         
      
   
