
   
   
      
         
            Taken to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cleaners</ENAMEX>?

            My dry cleaner charges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.65</NUMEX>
to clean and press a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s shirt and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.25</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s blouse. What's going
on here?

            The laws
of arithmetic allow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> possibilities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s clothing must be associated
either with higher costs or with higher profit margins for the dry cleaner.
Unfortunately, neither theory seems terribly plausible.

            Let's start with the "higher cost" theory. In its most
naive form, this theory predicts that if I move the buttons on my dress shirts
from the right side to the left, the cost of laundering them will more than
triple. That one's not going to fly. So, to give the theory a fair chance, we
have to look for more significant differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
clothing.

            Well, like what? You could
argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothing is typically made of more delicate fabrics than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s. But if that's the relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX>, why don't dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX> just quote
different prices for different fabrics? (For some materials, such as silk, they
typically do quote separate prices. The question is why this practice
does not completely displace that of distinguishing between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s clothes and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s.)

            An
alternative version of the theory is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothes are costlier to
process because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> demand higher quality work. I can't disprove that
version, but I have no real evidence to support it, either. So, in a search for
better alternatives, I called <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX> and asked for
their explanations. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s shirts are machine
pressed, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s are hand pressed. That left me wondering why they don't
simply quote different prices for different kinds of pressing. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s shirts require specialized treatment because they are typically
doused with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perfume</ENAMEX>. That left me wondering why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who use after-shave are not
chronically dissatisfied with their dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> said that this was
their pricing policy, and if I didn't like it, I was free to shop
elsewhere.

            
In the absence of a clear, convincing story
about gender-specific costs, let's see what kind of story we can tell about
gender-specific profit margins. In other words, let's ask whether my dry
cleaner is exploiting female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> through higher markups.

            To make
sense of that theory, you have to ask why dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX> would want to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discriminate</ENAMEX> specifically against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, as opposed to, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. That strategy
makes sense only if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are more price-sensitive than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and hence more
likely to walk away in the face of a high markup. But why should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> be more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">price-sensitive</ENAMEX>? You could argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are less diligent about cleanliness
and so more likely to respond to high prices by wearing unlaundered shirts. But
as long as we're dealing in stereotypes, you could argue equally well that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are more willing to do their own laundry--in which case women
would be more likely to walk away from a high price, and it would make more
sense to discriminate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            So it isn't clear which gender is the more natural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for getting soaked at the cleaners. But there's a more fundamental
reason to doubt that either gender can be victimized by price
discrimination, and here it is: There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half a dozen</NUMEX> dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX> within
easy walking distance of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. If they're all earning higher profits on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s blouses than on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s shirts, why hasn't any of them decided to
specialize in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s blouses?

            Let me
make that more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX>. Suppose the going prices are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.65</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s shirt
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.25</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s blouse, even though (under the theory we're currently
entertaining) they are equally expensive for the cleaner to handle. Then if I
were a dry cleaner, I would announce a uniform price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for all shirts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blouses</ENAMEX>--thereby attracting all the women's business and none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s.
Because nobody has adopted that obvious strategy, we should suspect that
despite appearances, the profit margin on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothing can't be much higher
than on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s.

            
In fact, the process wouldn't stop there. As
soon as I announced a uniform price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> would announce a price
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.75</NUMEX>. Ongoing competition for the (temporarily) more lucrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
business would quickly eliminate any profit differential.

            That
argument rests on the fact that dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX> are highly competitive. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> ran the entire dry cleaning industry, it might very well choose to
discriminate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, depending on market conditions). But in the
world we live in--or at least in the neighborhood I live in--there are
so many interchangeable dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX> that none of them should be able to get
away with exploiting anyone.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> insists I've got this
wrong--she says she's so loyal to her own dry cleaner that no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discounter</ENAMEX> can
lure away her business. If most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are as devoted as she is, then each
dry cleaner is like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, with its own captive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer base</ENAMEX>. In
that case, price discrimination can survive. But I am instinctively skeptical
that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are as fanatically loyal as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.

            The theory
that only a monopolist can price discriminate is standard textbook fare, and
it's borne out by a lot of observations. Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> have a certain amount
of monopoly power (on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, a given moviegoer is likely to have a
strong preference for a particular movie at a particular theater), and they
price discriminate by offering discounts to senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> (which is
equivalent to discriminating against everybody under the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> have even more monopoly power--once you know where and when you want
to fly, you are likely to have an extremely limited choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>--and
they heavily discriminate against business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> by charging more for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midweek</ENAMEX> flights than for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> flights (when most travel is for leisure).

            
By contrast, in the most competitive
industries, there is no price discrimination. As I am fond of pointing out to
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, you've never heard of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> who offers senior citizen
discounts. Likewise for gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, which are ubiquitous and sell to everyone
at a single price.

            Well, at
least that's what I used to tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. But I might have to make a
small change in my lesson plan. The gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> nearest our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> has just
announced a policy of senior citizen discounts on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX>. Is this
price discrimination in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, or does it reflect a genuinely lower
cost of serving them?

            If you push me hard enough, I can probably concoct some
kind of story about lower costs. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> tend to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> with bigger
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, so they buy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 gallons</NUMEX> at a time instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, thereby saving on
the cost of processing credit cards. (A significant part of that cost is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> spent waiting for the card to be approved, during which the pump is
unavailable.) But if this cost saving is significant, why has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> local
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> recognized it? And why is it significant only on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX>?

            I have suggested to my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> that none of us should be permitted to present ourselves to the
world as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> until we figure out what this gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> is up to. Nobody
has risen to the challenge. A few have suggested that perhaps the gas station
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is just a little quirky. Maybe that's right. But it would be far harder
to believe that the entire dry cleaning industry is just a little quirky.
Either there is enough monopoly power to sustain price discrimination, or there
is some reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothes are incredibly expensive to clean and press.
But I have no idea which.

         
      
   
