
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stolen Dream</ENAMEX>

            It's a common debating
tactic to assert that some respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> of the past would endorse your
position on some controversy of the present. There is little doubt that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">originals</ENAMEX> would find the views attributed to them surprising sometimes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, for example, has been claimed as a forbear by everyone from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dixiecrats</ENAMEX>. Lately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of affirmative action have donned the mantle
of the civil-rights movement, claiming direct descent from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> The idea, presumably, is to insulate themselves against charges of racism
even as they pursue policies certain to prove detrimental to large numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.

            To
achieve this feat, they define <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of "colorblind laws," and
reduce the civil-rights movement to an effort to end the classification of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> by race. In this way, programs that take <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX> into account can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demonized</ENAMEX> as violations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s memory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> of the ingeniously named
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Civil Rights Initiative</ENAMEX>, which would forbid all state government
affirmative-action policies, routinely invoke the sentence from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream</ENAMEX>" speech looking forward to the day his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would be judged not by
the abolition of affirmative action in his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End of Racism:</ENAMEX>
Principles for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Multicultural Society</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinesh D'Souza</ENAMEX> claims to be
following in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King</ENAMEX>'s footsteps even though he <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> repealing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights Act of 1964</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s crowning achievements.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ahigh</ENAMEX> or low point in this invention of a usable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> came
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Bolick</ENAMEX>, a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> and frequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> for the anti-affirmative action view, used the centenary of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plessy</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> decision (which upheld racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">segregation</ENAMEX>) to argue that since segregation was a system of "racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classification</ENAMEX>," affirmative action is its modern equivalent. Thus, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolick</ENAMEX>'s
view, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX>, of affirmative action are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s legitimate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>.

            But the
revisionists are quite wrong. His writing and actions make it clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> was a strong supporter of what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would be called
"affirmative action." The phrase itself was not widely used during his
lifetime, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> spoke repeatedly of granting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> special preferences in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX> and education to compensate for past discrimination.

            In Why We Can't Wait , published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> as the
movement to dismantle segregation reached its peak, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> observed that many
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of civil rights "recoil in horror" from suggestions that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> deserved not merely colorblind equality but "compensatory
consideration." But, he pointed out, "special measures for the deprived" were a
well-established principle of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> offered
all sorts of privileges to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX>, given their long "siege of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">denial</ENAMEX>," were even more deserving than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> of "special, compensatory
measures."

            King
said much the same thing in his last book. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do We Go From Here</ENAMEX> was
published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, and in the intervening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s optimism had given
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to foreboding prompted by the emergence of a white backlash and the
realization that combating the economic plight of black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> would prove far
more difficult than eliminating segregation. He called for a series of
programs, including full employment and a guaranteed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> income, to uplift
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> of all races. But he saw no contradiction between measures aimed at
fighting poverty in general and others that accorded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> "special treatment"
because of the unique injustices they had suffered. "A society that has done
something special against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>," he wrote,
"must now do something special for him."

            Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> targeted both economic and
racial inequality. His policy proposals embraced a variety of approaches, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colorblind</ENAMEX> assaults on poverty to demands, such as setting specific goals for
the employment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> by private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would be called
"racial quotas."

            In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, what King
believed has little bearing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. The civil-rights era has long passed,
and affirmative action must be defended or attacked on its merits. King aside,
what is most striking in current discussions of civil rights, race, and
affirmative action is the absence of any sense of history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Segregation</ENAMEX> was not
simply a matter of racial classification (or "thinking by race," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX> has written) but part of a complex system of racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordination</ENAMEX> whose political, economic, and social elements all reinforced one
another. The slogan of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">March on Washington</ENAMEX> was not colorblind laws but
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX>," and the movement's ultimate goal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> insisted, was to
"make freedom real and substantive" for black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> by absorbing them "into
the mainstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life."

            This goal remains as
elusive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as it was during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s lifetime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> are those
who, like him, see affirmative action not as a panacea or an end in itself, but
as one of many ways to reduce the gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> bequeathed to us by history.

         
      
   
