
   
   
      
         
            Slanted

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
runs a lot of headlines about scandals, but rarely does it run a headline that
is a scandal. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28</TIMEX>, it came pretty close. The headline
over its lead Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> story read: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">DEMOCRATS</ENAMEX> HOPED TO RAISE <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 MILLION</NUMEX> FROM
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASIANS</ENAMEX> IN <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>" On the inside page where the story continued, the headline was:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DEMOCRATS' GOAL: MILLIONS FROM ASIANS</ENAMEX>." Both headlines were wrong. The story
was actually about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> document outlining a
plan to raise (as the lead paragraph put it) "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>."

            Memo to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>" are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ancestry</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>," in contrast, are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. And
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>" are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> who are visiting or residing
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. This is not . It gets at the heart of the subtle,
probably subconscious racial prejudice that has turned a legitimately
medium-sized scandal into a journalistic blockbuster.

            Would a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> headline call <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>"? (Or, in the jump headline, just "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Europeans</ENAMEX>"?) And the
headline was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the problem with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s story. The story itself was
wrongheaded, implying that there's something inherently scandalous about
Asian-Americans giving money to a political campaign. In fact, the inaccurate
headline was necessary to prevent the story from seeming absurd. Can you
imagine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> running--over its lead story--the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DEMOCRATS HOPED TO RAISE MILLIONS FROM U.S. JEWS"</ENAMEX>?

            Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> target
ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for fund-raising all the time (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> recently showed
in these pages). They target <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, they target <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, they pass the hat at
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dinners. To be sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> fund-raising plan was,
in retrospect, no ordinary plan. It went quite awry. Some of the projected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $1.2 million</NUMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --wound up coming
in the form of improper or illegal donations (which, of course, we already knew
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX>). Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> funneled money through domestic front men
or front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. And sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> thus got to rub elbows with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. For all we know, they influenced policy.

            But the
truly scandalous stuff was old news by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 27</TIMEX>. What <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>'s story added was
news of the existence of this document outlining a plan to raise money from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> descent. And that alone was considered worthy of the
high-scandal treatment.

            
Leave aside this particular story, and consider
the "campaign-gate" scandal as a whole. What if the same thing had happened
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> descent? It would be just as improper
and/or illegal. But would we really be so worked up about it? Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> write a column about it every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> and use the loaded word
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>" to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> noncitizens? If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX>
looked like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX>, would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> have put a huge, ominous, grainy
black-and-white photo of him on its cover? ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> connection"
wouldn't pack quite the same punch as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> connection"--the phrase
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> put on its cover and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> has used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.) Would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> be billing minor investigative twists as lead
stories?

            Indeed,
would its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> even write stories like that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s? The lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraph</ENAMEX>, which is supposed to crystallize the story's news value, is this: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> and a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> helped devise a strategy to raise an unprecedented <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> from
Asian-Americans partly by offering rewards to the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, including
special access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s records show." You mean
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> actually offered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who cough up big
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dough</ENAMEX>? I'm shocked. Wait until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> discover this tactic!
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> is a slow news day, but it's not that slow.
And as for the "unprecedented" scale of the fund-raising goal: Virtually every
dimension of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> fund-raising was on an unprecedented scale, as
we've long known.

            There are some interesting nuggets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
story. But among them isn't the fact, repeated in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> paragraph, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> that "political contributions were the
path to power." And among them isn't the fact, repeated (again) in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraph</ENAMEX>, that "the quid pro quo promised" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> was "in
many cases a face-to-face meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>." And, anyway, none of
these nuggets is interesting enough to make this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s main story. The only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to do that is to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> file <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> in the "alien" section of your
brain. That's why the story's headline is so telling.

            The funny
thing about this scandal is that its root cause and its mitigating circumstance
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the same. Its root cause is economic globalization--the fact that
more and more foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have an interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX> is also the reason that the scandal's premise--the illegality of
contributions from "foreign" interests--is increasingly meaningless. Both the
Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (in its blockbuster-lite
front-page story, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>) cited already-reported evidence that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$185,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">donation</ENAMEX> (since returned) may have originated ultimately with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.P. Group</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.P. Group</ENAMEX> is "a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> with interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and
elsewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ) and is "among the largest foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). But of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, and so on are also huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with interests in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and elsewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. They, no less than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, at times have
an interest in low <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> tariffs, treating oppressive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gloves</ENAMEX>, and so on. Yet it is perfectly legal for them to lubricate such
lobbying with big campaign donations.

            
Why no journalistic outrage about that ?
Well, for starters, try looking at a grainy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsweekly</ENAMEX>-sized photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lou</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerstner</ENAMEX> and see if it makes you remember <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>. (By the way, neither
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> noted that the ominous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.P. Group</ENAMEX> is
involved in joint ventures with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nynex</ENAMEX>.)

            You might think that, in an
age of globalization and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' fate increasingly tied to the
fate of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> would be careful not
to run articles that needlessly feed xenophobia. Guess again. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six weeks ago</TIMEX> a
Times op-ed piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucian Pye</ENAMEX> explored the
formidable mindset that governs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have
"distinctive characteristics" that give them "significant advantages" over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> in foreign policy. They "see politics as exclusively combative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contests</ENAMEX>, involving haggling, maneuvering, bargaining and manipulating. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the cleverest ploys and strategems [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ]."
Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are "quick to find fault in others" and try "always
to appear bold and fearless." Finally ("in a holdover from classical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
political theory"), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> "insist on claiming the moral high ground,
because top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are supposed to be morally superior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>." In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
"distinctive" edge lies in combative, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Machiavellian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud-slinging</ENAMEX>, blustery,
self-righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Gosh, why didn't we think of that?

            These peculiar traits, Pye
noted, aggravate another disturbing feature of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. It seems that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vacillate "between craving foreign goods and giving vent to
anti-foreign passions." In other respects, too, they evince a "prickly
xenophobic nationalism." Imagine that.

         
      
   
