
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wound</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is "reluctant,"
"reticent," and "loath" to discuss it, claims the press corps. Or "even to
think about" it, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine S. Povich</ENAMEX> wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>, "because
to do so would unearth the demons that he has lived with--and mostly hidden
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--for the majority of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73 years</TIMEX>."

            "It," of course, is the war
wound, the battlefield maiming of his arm and shoulder during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>--or,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Maraniss</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have upgraded
it for their journalistic purposes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wound</ENAMEX>.

            The press
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">loves the Wound</ENAMEX> for the reductionist power it affords them when they write
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> on behalf of hacks
everywhere, the otherwise estimable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cooper</ENAMEX> (now bound for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ) calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wound Dole</ENAMEX>'s "Rosetta <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> speaks in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shorthand</ENAMEX>? Explanation: Infirmities prevent him from scribbling much beyond
his signature, so he's trained himself to compress the world into verbal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hieroglyphics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> refuses to give up? Explanation: He was left for
dead in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and marked a goner several times in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, and he'd be taking
the dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nap</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> if not for his interminable spirit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is a hatchet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, a mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> given to angry outbursts? Hell, goddamnit! He grew up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hardscrabble</ENAMEX> and was crippled in the bloom of his handsome prime! He earned
everything he has, unlike softies like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, who had the world
handed to them, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who was anointed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fulbright</ENAMEX> and got his own free
ride!

            But most of all, the press corps loves to touch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wound</ENAMEX>
because they've convinced themselves that subject was previously taboo. Give a
listen:

            
               Most
revealingly, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is] willing more and more to speak of being shot in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War II</ENAMEX>, and of his lengthy recovery from wounds that almost killed him and left
his right shoulder incapacitated.
            

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24, 1996</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Dole</ENAMEX>, the laconic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansan</ENAMEX> who for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than three</TIMEX>
decades in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has been to reluctant to draw attention to his wounds from
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, returned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to a hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where he suffered
excruciating pain and nearly died.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15, 1996</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>
stoicism being what it is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> still seems uncomfortable talking about the
wounds that nearly killed him as he lead (sic) a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon</ENAMEX> up an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> hill
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1945</TIMEX>.
            

            
               As he
wrapped up his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s nomination, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> experience is
at the heart of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> run for the presidency. But he talks about it
reluctantly.
            

            
               "I've
just never done it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said in an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNS</ENAMEX>. "I've always felt it
was private."
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Service</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22, 1996</TIMEX>

            
               Recently,
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>] has given up his reticence to discuss his war wounds.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPI</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17, 1996</TIMEX>

            
               Dole
specifically chose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX> to jump into the race, marking the 50th
anniversary of when he was wounded in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> to highlight
his military record.
            

            

               Showcasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1945 grenade</ENAMEX> explosion which kept him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and left him with a useless right arm signaled a change in the very
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has been reluctant to discuss the episode.
            

            --Agence
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France Presse</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15, 1996</TIMEX>

            
               Once
reluctant to discuss his injuries and his grueling recovery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has been
warming up to the subject in interviews and speeches.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1996</TIMEX>

            But the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is just now exiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wound</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cocoon</ENAMEX> is a perennial press fantasy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is always talking about his Wound,
and the press is always asserting that he is doing so reluctantly, for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, and so on. He blabs about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wound</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988 and 1996</TIMEX> editions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unlimited Partners</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our American Story</ENAMEX> , his book with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>,
and his reflections on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wound</ENAMEX> and the aftermath consume a great chunk of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ben Cramer</ENAMEX>'s nonpareil book about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What It Takes:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> . And he discussed it candidly during his last
run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, as this déjà vu clip by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Walsh</ENAMEX> from the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> proves:

            
               For the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in his public life, he has forced himself to speak openly about the
horrible war wound that turned a strapping, athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> into an emaciated,
bed-ridden hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. The experience left him bitter and disillusioned,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
            

            
               But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> have also sought to turn the toughness that enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> to overcome
his injury into an asset, the counterpoint to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "wimp" image that is the
other side of the deeply personal contest between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
            

            Did the press miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>'s story? Have they forgotten the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> campaign? If so, one would think that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
non-reticence on the hustings, including a pit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where he recuperated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wound</ENAMEX>, and a full
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> after the release of a campaign video, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An American Hero</ENAMEX> , in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> himself describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wounding</ENAMEX> in graphic detail ("Some
high-explosive bullet entered my right shoulder, fractured my vertebrae in my
neck. I--I saw these--things racing--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. I couldn't move my
body, I couldn't move my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, my legs."), the press would finally say with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is not only comfortable with talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wound</ENAMEX>, he's
practiced.

            Not a
chance. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the final hours</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National Convention</ENAMEX>, reporters
were still writing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was only just coming to grips with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infirmity</ENAMEX>.

            
               One
touchy subject is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s grievous war wound. He has always been loath to talk
about it, but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> have viewed it as an asset--a symbol of his will to
survive.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia Inquirer</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 15, 1996</TIMEX>

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s misperception about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wound</ENAMEX> pairs
nicely with their other blind spot: that a "new, sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>" has emerged to
replace the "mean hatchet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> misted up at the convention,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> wrote as if the "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> stoic" had finally found his heart, when in
fact a sluice of his tears courses its way through his recent career. He sobbed
when he paid a recent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX>'s boyhood <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>; when he
retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this summer</TIMEX>; when he visited his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>; when he helped plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whittier</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>; when
he talked on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> about his father visiting him in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX>; when he attended a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> for the defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>;
whenever he hears "You'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Walk Alone"</ENAMEX> (which he played continuously
during his recovery); during a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> campaign stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> (he always
seems to cry in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, which he included in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a later</TIMEX> campaign
video.

            Why then,
does the press paint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> as a New Age '90s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who is finally making the big
hug with the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who was ravaged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wound</ENAMEX>?

            Don't blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. He hasn't exploited his war record for
political purposes any more than did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> "PT109" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grumman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenger</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. And while he hasn't rubbed his game <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> directly in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
draft-dodging face in pursuit of votes, he'll probably do whatever it takes to
win if he's woefully behind in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>.

            Neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploiting the Wound</ENAMEX> nor shunning it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has folded it into his life,
establishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dole Foundation</ENAMEX> to help the disabled, pushing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Disabilities Act</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and going out of his way to align
himself with the physically impaired. When he gave the commencement address
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallaudet University</ENAMEX>--the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for the deaf--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> wasn't
engaging in political grandstanding. He was working his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>.

            
The only disability that needs more exposure
this election cycle is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign Cognitive Disorder</ENAMEX>, a seemingly
incurable condition whose symptoms are amnesia and treacle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCD</ENAMEX>-impaired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists blot</ENAMEX> out the past and embrace the mawkish. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>,
afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> repeat the well-grooved narrative of his <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wound, Recovery,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Sensitivity</ENAMEX>, because it makes for a good and easy story--and because it
fits with their line that the formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taciturn</ENAMEX>/stoic, mean/hatchet-wielding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has evolved, even when the record shows that he's been a serial blubberer
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> and, despite the tears, is just as mean as ever.

            
Meanwhile, the crybaby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> must be chortling about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s naiveté.
He's probably been chortling for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than three decades</TIMEX>. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> profile
published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> talks about chauffeuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to campaign stops during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>
re-election bid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. Even then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> knew the political value of the
Wound--and of his reluctance to talk about it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports:

            
               Few
gatherings passed without a tactful mention of [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s] military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the frozen right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. It hit home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stern</ENAMEX> warning to dike the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> tide in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> rarely fished for
sympathy when he retold the tale of his battle injury, leavening the reference
by saying it won him a "bedpan promotion" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               But "if
a meeting wasn't going good, sometimes I'd have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the back of the room
ask him about the war wound," says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. "It would switch the conversation to
make it more positive."
            

         
      
   
