
   
   
      
         
            My Thoughts Exactly

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> I published a
book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Moment on the Earth: The Coming Age of Environmental Optimism</ENAMEX>,
precisely when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were inclined to think my central idea was crazy. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thesis</ENAMEX> was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> environment is not declining but improving, and that
this demonstrates that federal health and safety regulations really work. But
the book appeared just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> seemed poised to repeal the 20th
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> and public opinion was retreating to the view that nature is doomed.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> crashed and burned, while liberalism has grown eager
for arguments that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> provides genuine benefits. Suddenly, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypothesis</ENAMEX> is catching on.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1995</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">environmentalist Jessica Mathews</ENAMEX> torched A Moment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> op-ed page. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathews</ENAMEX> called me a dope for saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
environment is recovering. She rejected my contention that ecological
initiatives represent "the leading postwar triumph for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,"
and slammed me for using the word "success" to describe environmental
regulation. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, writing again for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathews</ENAMEX>
rhapsodized about the marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ecological recovery. She called reduction
of pollution "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s one resounding success of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>." Her
repeated use of that word--"success"--was especially galling.

            The
column was so amazingly familiar I had to check the byline to see if I'd
sleep-written it. Could this possibly be the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mathews</ENAMEX> who had
debated me on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, scowling as she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>
environmental optimism was an appalling notion? This must be the next frontier
in stealing ideas, I thought: Discredit someone, then write the same thing
yourself as if you'd thought of it. Then I cheered up a bit. A Moment on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earth</ENAMEX> predicts, "Soon we're all going to be environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX>." Could
I actually have been right?

            Sure didn't seem that way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. On publication my
book was blistered by enviro <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX>, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Defense</ENAMEX>
Fund, which issued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> book-length attacks on my thesis, one weighing in at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX>
pages and boiling down to, "How dare you call us successful!" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDF</ENAMEX> hoped,
for fund-raising reasons, to stamp out optimism before it gained a foothold.
With enormous self-restraint, I'll spare you my own analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDF</ENAMEX>'s
analysis of me. But, to my mind, I was the victim of standard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
splatter tactics: Throw enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>, some will stick. Stick it did, and the buzz
turned cold.

            Conspiracy theory was rolled
out to explain my sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cheerfulness</ENAMEX>. The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> declared that
I must be in the pay of the electric-utility industry. (What is holding
up those checks?) In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sci</ENAMEX>.environment section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usenet</ENAMEX>, I found a posting
from a research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> "for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>" seeking
information on "who is behind" and "who is providing the money" for my work.
The notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>--my corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> is called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking Penguin</ENAMEX>--apparently was too prosaic.

            Then in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX> held a photo op to defend the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Endangered Species</ENAMEX> Act. The event was staged atop a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peregrine falcons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> that have rebounded from the brink of extinction owing
to federal protection, now nest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Babbitt</ENAMEX> hailed this as "a symbol of hope" for
the environment. Where'd he get that idea? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Moment on the Earth</ENAMEX>
begins by describing wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">falcons nesting</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> as a symbol
of hope for the environment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protocol</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babbitt</ENAMEX> should have invited me,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> can lend photo ops extra credence. But the grapevine said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX> didn't want me around because my theory had lightning-rod status among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>.

            
In the meantime, I was attempting earnestly to
persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that environmental optimism could be a potent political
idea. Perhaps anyone who tries to be his own spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viking</ENAMEX>'s publicists had shifted their attention to another book,
the slightly more remunerative <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Road Ahead</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> of
your sales, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>. It's all I ask.) I huddled with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Leadership</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s centrist policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Committee</ENAMEX> (run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>), urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to become
environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> stole the march. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> seemed taken but--or so I was told--were asked to steer clear by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wham</ENAMEX>! I
had hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> glass ceiling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> has staked out doomsday
as a favored issue, and will brook no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX>. An example: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last October</TIMEX>, I
arranged for the normally anti-regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Howard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Peters</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Osborne</ENAMEX> to join me in condemning environmental rollback attempts on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> to read our statement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who
works for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> under her maiden name, rolled her eyes, saying,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is never going to let you get away with the credit." Sure
enough, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> read our pitch, my name had mysteriously been dropped from
the top of the (alphabetical) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">signers</ENAMEX>' list.

            Meanwhile, it turned out my fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expropriate</ENAMEX> environmental optimism was unfounded. The last thing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
wanted to hear is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> is a blessing. I even heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX>, even banned the reading of A Moment on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. (True? Who knows? But I take comfort in believing
it.)

            Naively, I had thought
environmental optimism would appeal to many political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> would be
happy that regulatory intervention was protecting an essential aspect of life;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> would be happy for proof that nature and industry are not
incompatible. Instead, left and right united in a screwball shared interest in
rejecting any positive environmental tidings. The left was using alarmism about
nature to raise money, while the right was raising money with alarmism about
regulations. Now with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> in hiding, that dynamic has changed. Progressives at
last are noticing that the best argument for government activism is that it
works. Maybe even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> will soon exalt with a broad smile the vibrant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ecology</ENAMEX>. Don't faint when it happens.

         
      
   
