
   
   
      
         
            Styles of Polygamy

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applause-getters in Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s acceptance speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Convention</ENAMEX>
was, "It does not take a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> to raise a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. It takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to raise a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>." Pretty nervy line, coming from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who left his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. Then again, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> found it nervy when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> church in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, delivered his famous sermon on family values. All that
stands between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bushels</NUMEX> of illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, after all, is
contraceptive technology.

            It seems
to me we have rough parity between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> in the personal failings
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, at least as far as "family values" go. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s escapades are
generally perceived as constituting a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>" problem, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX> gets only the occasional raised eyebrow. Am I confused, or is America
confused? In an attempt to settle this question impartially, I will now put on
my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> coat and take up the tools of modern science. We will dissect the
question of which (if either) is worse--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s infidelity or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
divorce.

            
But first let me stress that, although I will
eventually shift into moral-indignation mode, I have deep sympathy for both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. They are, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earthlings</ENAMEX>. They were created by the process of
natural selection and thus, are inherently absurd--driven by impulses that
exist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> only because they helped our ancestors transmit their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>.

            Consider the extreme thirst
for status and power found in male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homo sapiens</ENAMEX> in general and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
in particular. According to evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>, this thirst exists
because during evolution, it led to lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>. Those of our male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ancestors</ENAMEX> who most doggedly climbed to the top of the local status hierarchy
were often rewarded with sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>--either multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
approach) or multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> approach).

            Hence the
cruel irony facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and, to a lesser extent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: From nature's point
of view, a central purpose of pursuing status is to convert it into sex. Yet,
demonstrated success in making this conversion is now deemed a disadvantage in
the quest for the highest-status slot in the world. The very point of being
alpha male is considered evidence, in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, of unfitness for the job!
Talk about defeating the purpose.

            
How did our culture get mired in this
puritanical paradox? Well, consider the limited menu of options:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polygamy</ENAMEX> . This is the natural state of our species. Then again, the
natural state of our species is also a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter-gatherer</ENAMEX> society, with
little wealth and thus, only mild inequalities of status and power among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
In this "ancestral environment," large harems were rare; competition for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
though intense, was seldom epically intense. But then came agriculture and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of economic surplus. Suddenly some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> could be way more
powerful than others. The commensurately massive sexual rewards made men
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ill</ENAMEX>-inclined to play by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquess of Queensberry</ENAMEX> rules. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guinness Book of World Records</ENAMEX> , the most prolific genetic replicator in
the history of our species was the last Sharifian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>, who had
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">888</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>. He was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moulay Ismail</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloodthirsty</ENAMEX>. Get the
picture?

            And, in polygamous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">societies</ENAMEX>, low-status <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> weren't exactly pacifists either. With scads of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> monopolized by the well-to-do, less fortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> could get mighty lonely
and become very unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX>. This volatile discontent may be the reason
that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Betzig</ENAMEX> has shown, polygamy and authoritarianism
have gone hand in hand. Back when the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zulu king</ENAMEX> was entitled to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, coughing or spitting at his dinner table was punishable by death.

            In this
sense, monogamy meshes better than polygamy with the egalitarian values of a
democracy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>-man-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-vote, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, monogamy is hard
to sustain given our species' naturally polygamous bent. And that's especially
true in a place like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, with great status inequality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> or powerful
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> feel an extravagant sense of sexual entitlement, and many women
feel like gratifying it. Hence option No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>:

            
2Serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monogamy</ENAMEX>. This is what we have now. You
can acquire a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> so long as you discard the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. This is
basically a covert, and mild, form of polygamy: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>-status <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> get to
monopolize <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> fertile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, having risen from crippled
war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, traded in his 47-year-old <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>--as her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fertility</ENAMEX> was expiring--for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39-year-old</TIMEX>. (This isn't to say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was
pondering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>' relative fertility.)

            But serial monogamy has a big
downside not shared by polygamy: Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get reared either without fathers
or with stepfathers, who often lack the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> devotion of a biological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--and who may even be downright hostile. As evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Daly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo Wilson</ENAMEX> showed in their book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Homicide</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> not
reared by both biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are at greatly elevated risk of physical
abuse, even murder. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece of the larger truth at the heart of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-values" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">crusade: Divorce</ENAMEX> and unwed motherhood are bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

            True
monogamy, then, would seem a very worthwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>. But if monogamy is at
odds with human nature, how do you keep it from metamorphosing into serial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monogamy</ENAMEX>?

            
3Monogamy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> style. When high-status
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> leave their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> for a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, you can stigmatize them, damaging
their social, and even professional, standing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, this tough love helped keep the divorce rate near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> even amid the
stark status inequality of a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Note its ingeniousness: To repress
the powerful polygamous impulse in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, you employ their equally powerful
thirst for social status. The irony facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>--that converting your status
into multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> can threaten the status itself--is thus a remnant, though
greatly diluted, of our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> heritage.

            The central theme of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
campaign is that he embodies the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> values that were still robust in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> of his youth. He says he stands for "God, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, honor, duty,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." Well one duty, back then, was to stay with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. In explaining
his divorce, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> says his marriage had become unhappy. But if doing your duty
was easy, they wouldn't call it "duty," would they?

            It's not
enough to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> when he divorced, and now
seems well adjusted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> of her socioeconomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> obviously stand a
better-than-average chance of recovery. But the (factually correct) premise of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victorian</ENAMEX> morality was that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s transgression, if unpunished, invites
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emulation</ENAMEX>. That's true in spades for society's biggest role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>, etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s divorce, in some incalculable but not trivial way,
makes other divorces more likely--including divorces with more vivid casualties
than his; including divorces that will push <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> into poverty. To
elect a divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is to reject a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pillar</ENAMEX> of the moral order
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> says he'll rebuild.

            
And what about re-electing a world-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">philanderer</ENAMEX>? Obviously, infidelity is a less-direct contributor to the divorce
rate than divorce. Indeed, in some cultures, permissible infidelity is paired
with stigmatized divorce as part of the family-values formula: high-status
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> as compensation for sticking with their aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. And
even in Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>--and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infidelity</ENAMEX> was forgiven more readily than his desertion.

            But this doesn't add up to an
alibi for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s infidelity, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s divorce, has consequences
that aren't merely local. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is role model in chief. So it's not an excuse
that he didn't get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> pregnant. Sometimes, casual sex does
get single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> pregnant. And unwed motherhood is as big a part of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-values" problem as divorce. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> sometimes cite the
trysts of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WW</ENAMEX> II <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. Well,
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lived back when it was possible to keep such things a secret. Which
made them less culpable, under the perfectly logical hypocrisy of Victorian
standards.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, I would say there
is indeed rough moral parity between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> on the family-values
front. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is marginally more vulnerable because his moralizing is more
detailed, and thus its irony is more glaring. ("If I could by magic restore to
every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who lacks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, I
would," he said at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> convention. How about starting with your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>?) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> historically have been more guarded in their family-values
rhetoric. This probably represents a failure of vision, but it may partly
represent a certain clarity of vision as well. It's harder to be smug if you're
aware of your own failings. And it's harder to yearn so unreservedly for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> age of Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> if you realize that morality is like economics:
There's no free lunch.

         
      
   
