
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stock Market Chicken-Counting Orgy</ENAMEX>

average is up by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. The NASDAQ Composite Index and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">500</ENAMEX> are up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 40 percent</NUMEX>. Thanks to the portfolio tracking
services on financial Web sites like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Investor</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
aware of their rising net worth, to the dollar, on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX>
basis. Troubadours of capitalism celebrate each new high as evidence of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>'s ability to create wealth.

            But in
what sense has the stock market boom created wealth? This is not a
philosophical question. It's a mathematical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Nor is my point that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>
breaking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> is necessarily a speculative bubble that will burst (though I
reserve the right to claim that was my point if it happens). But when we
imagine how we will spend our stock market wealth, we're engaged in an orgy of
pre-hatch chicken counting. Is there any way the "wealth" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
spending in their minds can be spent in reality--that is, converted into goods
and services?

            Here's the puzzle. The shares traded on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Exchange</ENAMEX> are worth a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $8 trillion</NUMEX>. "Worth" in the sense that a)
this is the sum of the prices they're trading at, little bits at a time; and b)
this is the sum of the numbers their proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> mentally fondle. Perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trillion</ENAMEX> of that "worth" has been added in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, though,
the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy produces goods and services of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $7 trillion</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, and grew <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> percent growth is, in
fact, very healthy. But it means that the increase in goods and services in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$280 billion</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> of the increase in claims on
goods and services implied by the rise in prices on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX>
alone. Add the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX>, real estate, and various other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investments</ENAMEX>, and the growth in the economy's capacity to produce real wealth
shrinks into insignificance compared with the increase in "wealth" as perceived
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of these investments.

            
No one loves a share of stock for its own sake.
Even shares in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as wonderful as, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> are treasured only for
their trade-in value. So what would happen if everyone suddenly tried to trade
the "wealth" we've accumulated during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> for real stuff--<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX>, vacations, new washing machines, whatever? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> things would happen:
Stock prices would plummet and the price of "real stuff" would rise. As a
result, much of our perceived wealth would melt away.

            Of course we're not all
going to cash in our stocks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. One thing sustaining current stock-price
levels is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> socking money away for retirement. But many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have
predicted that this pleasant dynamic will reverse itself when the boomer
generation starts withdrawing and spending its retirement nest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. Instead of
sustaining the market, the aging-boomer factor will be depressing it. The
result needn't be a crash. But some combination of stock-price stagnation or
decline and general price inflation will deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> the value they think
they're accumulating.

            (This is
another reason that the notion of solving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> problem by
investing payments in the stock market is such folly. The infusion of these
extra <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> will drive prices up when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> are all buying, and the
subsequent withdrawal will drive prices down when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> are all selling.)

            So the alleged wealth accumulated in the stock market can't
be realized all at once now, and probably can't be realized all at once decades
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. Can it be realized gradually over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sell off a
little at a time? It's possible, but pretty unlikely. Stock prices represent
the discounted present value of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s future earnings stream. In other
words: What you're willing to pay for a share of stock is, or ought to be,
equal to what you would pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> for the right to claim that share's fraction
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s profits from now on. If prospects for future earnings have
actually improved by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, the economy will
generate enough wealth to cover all the new chits in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s pockets.

            There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways the present value of future earnings might have increased by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 or 50</NUMEX>
percent during a period when the economy's general productive capacity
increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 4 percent</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were radically
undervalued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. The other is that something happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>
to improve general corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>. In either case,
stock prices and profit potential are, in theory, now correctly aligned.

            
But do you know of any dazzling new insight
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the past</TIMEX>, or revelation about the future, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> that would
justify a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> upward valuation of all of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> a while back attributing the bull market to new understanding
about the lack of risk in equity investments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> notes that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> has brought good news about the economy's ability to tolerate low
unemployment without igniting inflation. "But this news," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> says, "makes
us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> richer at most--nowhere near enough to justify the rise in
the Dow." What's more, if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>'s huge rise in stock prices reflects a
new but accurate optimism about future economic growth, this means the payoff
for that future growth is already in the past. In other words, future
stock-price increases will have to trail economic growth.

            A related
possibility: The increase in stockholder wealth could reflect a transfer from
those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who don't own stocks. Or from our own non-stock repositories of
future value--i.e., our labor. Could it be that the rise in stock values
reflects the ongoing shift, from labor to capital, of the return to production
in our economy? In other words, we're not producing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> more, but more
of what we do produce goes to corporate profits and less to wages? Well,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> maintains that no such shift is taking place. (Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Mishel</ENAMEX>, takes issue with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> in the current issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX> .)

            Then there's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> call the wealth effect. Even
if the impression that we're a lot richer than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> is a fantasy, the
very fact that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> believe it might help make it come true. Prosperity is
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinker Bell</ENAMEX>: It lives on belief that it lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Folks</ENAMEX> who believe (even
incorrectly) that their net worth is up by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> will spend with zest, and
the economy will thrive and grow as a result. Of course this kind of
"demand-side" thinking is extremely out of fashion. After all, if spending
money you don't really have is the key to prosperity, big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> deficits
would do the trick just as well. Yet deficits are deeply unpopular, most of all
with the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who celebrate the new wealth created by the stock
market.

            Of course this whole line of
reasoning would apply to stock market crashes as well as to booms. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX>
crash of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'87</NUMEX>, for example, reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s net worth by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> without
directly reducing by as much as a single doughnut the amount of goods and
services or the economy's ability to produce more of them. Maybe the moral is
just the obvious one that stock prices occasionally overshoot the mark in both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX>. But maybe the moral is that the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who are going to get
their full chicken's worth out of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> market are those who stop counting
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and start trading them in.

         
      
   
