
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Cuts</ENAMEX>

            
During the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> presidential and vice
presidential debates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> were hit by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> attacks from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> times. That's an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
attack every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four minutes</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s sins: Not only did he
want to slash <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$270 billion</NUMEX> from the program--more than needed to protect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> "trust fund"--he wanted to hike premiums, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force seniors</ENAMEX> to pay more
out of pocket for care, and push them into managed care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> said, wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to
"wither on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX>." All these were, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> put it on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
recently, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> measures that would have devastated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>."

            Thank God <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was there
to stop it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
limp response was that he would honor his mother's word not to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. He
needn't be so defensive. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself proposed basically the
same package of reforms for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>--a fact everyone seems to have forgotten
since it was embedded in his massive, ill-fated <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Health Security Act</ENAMEX>. Here's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rundown</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Cuts</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slower Growth</ENAMEX> . Consider
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> in the veep debate:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>:
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> himself suggested that the reduction in the growth of Medicare
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five or six years</TIMEX> ought to be held to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>. Under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan, irrespective of the numbers, it will grow at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> or even more
percent."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>: "I think Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>
has unintentionally made a mistake in saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called for
a reduction to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>. ... It is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s position."

            Nobody bothered to check out
this one. But the fact is that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> boasted he could cut Medicare
growth to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> while protecting the program.

            Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> speaking to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> are going up at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the rate of inflation. We
propose to let it go up at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times the rate of inflation." Given that prices
were expected to climb <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> meant <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> growth for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>.

            "That is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> cut," he reassured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>. "So when you hear all this business about
cuts, let me caution you that that is not what is going on. We are going to
have increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and a reduction in the rate of
growth."

            A draft summary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
Security Act, released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September of 1993</TIMEX>, contained a chart showing
projected growth for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> slowing to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 6 percent</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, and less
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. And in its independent review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plan,
health-care consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewin-VHI</ENAMEX> noted that the act "attempts to slow the
growth in public and private health spending to the rate of growth in the CPI
plus an allowance for population growth." That puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> growth at just
over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            Far from devastating, this
slowdown was, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> said at the time, good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Magaziner</ENAMEX>
told a press briefing that "slowing the rate of growth actually benefits
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> considerably because it slows the rate of growth of the premiums
they have to pay."

            But looked at in the terms
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> uses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was proposing cuts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> spending
beyond the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$270 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> dared propose.

            Like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wanted to take a big chunk of savings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">providers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>--by cutting back payments to them.

            

               More <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cuts Than Needed</ENAMEX> . At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> warned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> cuts were "more than was necessary to repair the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> trust fund." The implied political point was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> cuts were
going to pay for tax cuts for the rich.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Security</ENAMEX>
Act, however, also cut Medicare more than was needed to repair the trust fund.
Most of the savings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> were to be plowed back into new federal
health programs. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> put it: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reductions</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> spending would provide a major part of the funding for the
Administration's proposal." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a quarter</NUMEX> of it, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
calculations.

            
               Raise Costs to
Seniors . Several times during the debates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>-reform plan would have boosted costs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>. "It
would have charged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> more for out-of-pocket costs as well as more in
premiums," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point.

            Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
Security Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a quarter</NUMEX> of the savings came out of the hides of
seniors. They were to be charged higher premiums for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> Part B, the
program that covers physician services. New copayments were to be added for
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> services that are now <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> covered. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, those
costs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> would have totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33 billion</NUMEX>.

            To be
sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> concentrated the premium hikes for Part B on the
well-to-do--those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or more. The rest would pay
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a quarter</TIMEX> of the premium cost, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> picking up the rest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
set the contribution rate at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just under one-third</NUMEX> of the full cost, but they
also "means tested" the premiums so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> with incomes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $75,000</NUMEX>
would pay a bigger chunk.

            

               Push Seniors <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Into Managed Care</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> plan ... would have forced a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> into managed care,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said. That's something of a misrepresentation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> plan would have
expanded the managed-care options open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, and encouraged them to take
it. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> can stick with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, or opt for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Maintenance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> (HMO) coverage, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> ponying up the premiums. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> plan would have opened that door to the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alphabet soup</ENAMEX> of
private managed-care plans, such as preferred-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider organizations</ENAMEX>,
point-of-service plans and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.

            So would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
reforms, and even his more recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> proposals. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> section in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
Security Act was titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Encouraging Managed Care</ENAMEX> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> Program."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s current reform proposal suggests expanding managed-care options for
seniors. The only difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on this score
is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> wanted to give seniors <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> extra option--to enroll in a
"medical savings account" plan.

            Both
parties used basically the same regulatory machinery to try to make their plans
work in the market without creating a huge "adverse selection"
problem--healthier seniors opting into lower-cost plans. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">machinery</ENAMEX>, in fact, was borrowed almost verbatim from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan--which, in
a double twist, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> had previously attacked as unworkable.

            

               Let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Wither</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Vine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
twice said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> would "wither on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX>" under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> reforms.
The reference is to a comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, who said that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> to wither on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX>, as seniors
opted for the private plans. But the quote has been misused by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> ever
since.

            In any case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also
forecast the decline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>. New <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> under his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
Security Act would be able to stick with the plan they had when they worked.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would pay the premiums instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>. Current retirees
could choose a private managed-care plan. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan would have moved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
into private plans in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> alone.

            To be fair, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
wanted to sweeten the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> pot at the same time it was making these cuts by
adding a prescription-drug benefit.

            It has also claimed since
that its proposed cuts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> were acceptable because they were in the
context of "universal health care reform." But that wasn't the argument it made
at the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> told a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> that savings in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> were easy because "we have too many examples now of how it can be done
better at lower costs with the same or better quality, and that's what we're
counting on."

         
      
   
