
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA Smoke Rings</ENAMEX>

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was the supreme
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, promising each of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> cash subsidy
from the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX> if they did not partake of nicotiana before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and his offer usually came as he filled the air with smoke
and ash. He so despised his deadly habit that he routinely thumped any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
caught sneaking puffs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX>.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> won't have to regulate their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>-tempted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, because
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has taken the job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigar</ENAMEX> (I mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>) made
teen smoking a federal affair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> when he unleashed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug</ENAMEX>
Administration on the problem. And there is a problem: A recent study shows
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX> of high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> now smoke, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David A. Kessler</ENAMEX>, inserted the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> into the fray by diagnosing teen smoking as a "pediatric
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>." Assuming regulatory control over the noxious <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s history, he defined tobacco as a "drug" and tobacco products
(cigarettes, cigars, chew) as "drug-delivery devices" under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Food, Drug</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cosmetic Act</ENAMEX>. Discovering these regulatory powers--which had escaped the notice
of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 80 years</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kessler</ENAMEX> issued a slew of
rules designed to suppress teen smoking, most of which were upheld by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William L. Osteen Sr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last month</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osteen</ENAMEX>'s
decision is currently under appeal, he approved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kessler</ENAMEX>'s ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> sales
to anyone under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>'s various prohibitions on
cigarette-vending machines, self-service cigarette displays, and free samples
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. He also approved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s new warning label for cigarette packs:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nicotine-Delivery Device for Persons 18</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Older</ENAMEX>."

            Of course, the evil tobacco
bastards recoiled from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kessler</ENAMEX>'s rules. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, they argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>,
Drug<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, and Cosmetic Act</ENAMEX> limits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s regulatory powers to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and medical
devices that provide medical benefits . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tobacconists</ENAMEX>' perverse logic
held that poisonous products like cigarettes, for which no health claim
is made, should fall outside government regulation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bastards</ENAMEX> didn't
actually call their product poisonous in court, but that's their
take-home message: Regulate us if our product heals, but don't regulate us if
our product kills. And make no mistake about it, tobacco kills: The average
cigarette smoker lives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight fewer years</TIMEX> than the average nonsmoker.

            But just
because the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are evil doesn't mean that we should sympathize
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, which has convoluted the law to wound its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> were
regulating marijuana. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> here is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THC</ENAMEX>, and the delivery system is a
joint.) Or it would police <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX> and shot glasses. Or it would go after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX> as an unhealthful fat-delivery device. (You laugh. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> currently
regulates that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat</ENAMEX> delivery device, olestra.)

            
So how did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> succeed in regulating
tobacco? In the guise of protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            Don't get me wrong. Some of
my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--but I don't want to live in a childproof world,
and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't want to grow up to inherit such a safe place, either. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joy</ENAMEX> of being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> lies in the freedom to take chances--even if you have to
pay the consequences. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osteen</ENAMEX>'s decision proves that almost any liberty can be
nibbled away if suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can be associated with it. But even the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> approved only the most overt nanny-state measures requested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>,
acknowledging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s power grab by rejecting the proposals that don't
directly deter teen smoking. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> wanted to bar tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from sponsoring sports events or placing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marlboro Man and Joe Camel</ENAMEX>
logos on T-shirts, caps, and other gear.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
claims that its ad-busting rules are the best way to achieve the
administration's goals of halving teen smoking in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next seven years</TIMEX>. But
young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> aren't as helpless in the face of the tobacco-industry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juggernaut</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> would like to imagine: Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> are
already hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s goals.

            A1995 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> study found that while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38 percent</NUMEX> of white
teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> smoke cigarettes, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 19 percent</NUMEX> of their black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>
do. Young black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are even more resistant to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX> percent of
young white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> smoke vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 12 percent</NUMEX> of young black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.

            It wasn't
always so. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just 20 years ago</TIMEX>, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> smoked in equal
percentages. What changed? One theory holds that young white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> (unlike
young black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>) subscribe to a cult of thinness, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> to block their
appetite. Some black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> that they feel that society has so
thoroughly stacked the deck against them with racial discrimination, crime, and
poverty that their very survival depends on resisting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. And still others
maintain that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are quicker to see through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX>'s charms than
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologists</ENAMEX>' speculations, add <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>. Everybody likes a
little danger in their lives, but perhaps most black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are already
experiencing all the hazards their psyches can take. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> (of all
races) who live inside elaborately constructed safety cones--airbags; mandatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bicycle</ENAMEX> helmets; mommy pagers; home-security systems; anti-drug campaigns;
anti-sex propaganda; and sanitized-for-your-protection suburbs--yearn for
something to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> against. At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 cents</NUMEX> per protest, smoking is a cheap ticket
to danger. (The buzz ain't bad, either.)

            
Another reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> got away with the power
grab is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> has been moving in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s direction
for some time. Our culture now interprets nearly all pleasures as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">addictions</ENAMEX>--or potential addictions. Case in point: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>'s
reductive cover story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX> on the neurotransmitter dopamine. According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , dopamine explains how and why we become "addicted" to sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">booze</ENAMEX>, gambling, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, cheap thrills, and yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. Shall we call in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to protect us from our addictive desires? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> may have no
current plans to dispatch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referees</ENAMEX> to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> to enforce safe sex, but
when it does, you can be sure it will be in the guise of protecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> eventually
quit the cigarette habit, as did my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sister</ENAMEX>. The
juvenile delinquent in the brood smoked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX> before he died in an
accident at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 26</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> still smoke, although both would
press the magic button and quit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> if they could.

            I alone collected the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bounty</ENAMEX> posted by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>. I've still never smoked a cigarette, although I'll
enjoy a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> cigar if you're buying. I collected my C note at my
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21 st</TIMEX> birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> planted it in my birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> on a
makeshift flagstaff. I don't remember what I spent the money on, but I do
recall how I rebelled my way through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>. I drank to howling, puking
excess.

         
      
   
