
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiss Really So Awful</ENAMEX>?

            I blurbed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiss</ENAMEX> .
The book scared me, not because it concerns incest or happens to be true but
because of the malign figure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who reminded me of the character
played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mitchum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Night</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX> . I also appreciated
the drugged cadence of the prose, with a chasm between every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sentences, and
the frozen stare of the insistent present tense. I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>, having encountered them professionally and socially (we live in the
same neighborhood, but literary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, anyway), but I don't
know them well enough for it to carry gossip value. I judged <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiss as</ENAMEX>
a book.

            Obviously
I was well aware of the holy-shit factor, sufficiently high that it could swamp
all discussion and become the sole focus of criticism. But I naively
underestimated its effect, imagining a bunch of dumb reviews and one or two
hand-wringing op-ed pieces. Instead came a flood of both, with a tone that rose
from shrill to vindictive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> went out of their way to attack not just the
book--some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidly</ENAMEX> admitted they hadn't bothered to read it--but Harrison
personally, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> for good
measure.

            Bad publicity is better than none, of course, but after a
time you could no longer ignore an odor of smoke, and it wasn't your usual
book-chat roast. It began to seem like a witch trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> has been accused
of being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX> to all segments of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, an
unfit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, to have written the book solely for the money or the
attention--everything short of having fucked her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in order to write about
it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss</ENAMEX> has been called "slimy, repellent, meretricious, cynical"
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and things to that effect by
sundry others. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's teaser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">triumphantly</ENAMEX> reads: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolcott Smacks Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kisser</ENAMEX>."

            No tort is
too trivial for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. Take self-plagiarism, a well-documented
failing among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of all sizes. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s case, it became the
centerpiece of a multiple-count indictment handed down by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Shnayerson</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , the fallout of which was that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> killed a scheduled excerpt. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, attempting damage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, rushed the book into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> before the publication date.
Self-plagiarism is usually a consideration for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, not feature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>; a
textual weakness, not a matter of morals.

            
There's no question that the book is a long way
from perfect. But literary matters are not of much interest to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>--self-plagiarism is an exception because it sounds like a crime.
Comment has instead tended to focus on familial betrayal, dubious motives, and
the moral sink that is the memoir <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            There are
those who fret about the effect on her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. While this is
reasonable, it is worth noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> has said she wanted to publish the
book now, "before our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were any older and more aware of the media
around them." She has a point: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs bark</ENAMEX>, the caravan passes. The furor
will be over long before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are able to understand it (the spotlight
would only be harsher if they were older), and the subject itself would either
come up or be repressed to everyone's detriment.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is still
alive; the book could hurt him. These tend to be the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who describe
the relationship as "consensual," a word that could not occur to anyone who has
read the book. Of course, there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who seem to think that rape is a sex
act rather than an act of violence. But the very notion of incest-- the last
taboo --unhinges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, and they transfer blame onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>, in effect
accusing her of having engineered her own defilement. (Shnayerson calls the
book's sexual inexplicitness "either proper ... or a tease.") Besides blaming
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, this attitude is also provincial and illiterate, if not
disingenuous.

            We're
sitting at the tail end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William Burroughs</ENAMEX> and Georges
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bataille</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Story of O</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> in which literature would seem to
have shed its last gratuitous prohibitions. It is also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-daughter</ENAMEX> incest continues all around, and not just up in the hills. But
you'd think, judging from the press, that recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of memoirs had called
incest or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> or any number of species of abuse into being by writing
about them. When the reaction is not faux-naïf, it is censorious: Shut up
and sublimate . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Practitioners</ENAMEX> of self-exposure are many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, of
course, and none of them is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Jacques Rousseau</ENAMEX>. Literature might be better
served if rage or remorse were diverted into parlor comedy. Who knows? Again,
that isn't the point for many of your bien-pensants , who fear mess and
complication more than they care about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of literature.

            
Aknow-nothing cynicism is pervasive now.
Everybody wants the inside scoop, the shoddy truth that lies at the core of all
decisions. Accordingly, it is widely believed that books are always planned and
written with marketing in mind. Fortunately or not, though, calculation usually
results in failure, and for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, the foolproof concept that briefly
shone at conception looks like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mirage</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> at the keyboard. Also
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underfoot</ENAMEX> is the venerable "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>" theory of literature--you know: "You're
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>? You should meet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>. He's got a story that will make you
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX>!" The can't-miss story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Passage</ENAMEX> of letters, a myth.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 36</NUMEX> possible plot situations, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playwright Carlo Gozzi</ENAMEX> determined, and we already know them all.

            And then there is the vexed
question of memoir vs. novel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are as frantic about saving their novel
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> as they were about killing it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX>. Their panic is
reminiscent of the moral defenses of painting that were worked up when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photography</ENAMEX> began to look like a threat. That debacle should have taught the
world that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> can coexist, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> can even migrate between them
depending on the flavor they seek. (The analogy is imperfect, because there's
no fixed line of demarcation between fiction and nonfiction, only a broad gray
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>.) And anyway, who cares whether your kitchen-sink epic features short,
fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> or tall, thin contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>? As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">André Breton</ENAMEX> wrote of
fictionalization of actual events: "I do not regard such a thing as childish, I
regard it as monstrous. I insist on knowing the names, on being interested only
in books left ajar, like doors; I will not go looking for keys." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiction</ENAMEX> has
its glories, but concealment is merely squalid.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>'s status as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">voodoo</ENAMEX> doll has nothing to do with the actual merits or failings of her book,
but is entirely owing to how economically her case concentrates the fears,
resentments, misconceptions, and idiocies prevailing right now. It also
reflects the fact that most cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are under constant pressure,
whether from above or from within, to whip up instant controversies tied to
some product on the shelf. They're over quickly and forgotten by all--except,
perhaps, their often hapless targets. In the meantime, they don't tend to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elevate</ENAMEX> discourse.

         
      
   
