
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Corbin Jones</ENAMEX> comes before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>--as
expected--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, all eyes will be on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>. Will a
flicker of emotion crease his usually impassive glare as he ponders a she-said,
he-said fact pattern so hauntingly reminiscent of his own ordeal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> still disdain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> as a sexual harasser. But a comparison
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> episodes suggests that the evidence against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is far stronger than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> has let on--and far stronger than
the evidence against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' evidence, which I
detail in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX>-word article in the current issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> , includes clear proof, scattered through the public record, that
then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trooper-bodyguard</ENAMEX> interrupted the
then-24-year-old state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> on the job on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 8, 1991</TIMEX>, and took her to meet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>--alone in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs suite</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>
hotel, for the apparent purpose of sexual dalliance.

            The evidence also includes
strongly corroborative statements made to me by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, complete
with tellingly detailed, seamy specifics remarkably consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
allegations.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Ballentine</ENAMEX> first told their stories in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX> in
exclusive interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>, then of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . But to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s chagrin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> printed only sketchy
fragments of their accounts, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 weeks later</TIMEX>.

            Other evidence, of course, warrants skepticism about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
account, including the claim by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' trooper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX> that she happily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">volunteered to be Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>" just after leaving his hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Yet
a careful review of the evidence makes clear that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX>
logically possible scenarios: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> lied in a most convincing manner, and
in stunning, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technicolor</ENAMEX> detail, to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballentine</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 8</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, and to her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> soon thereafter; that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all four later</TIMEX> conspired with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> to concoct a monstrous lie; or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' allegations are substantially
true. And after conducting interviews and studying other evidence, I'm all but
convinced that--even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> embellished somewhat--whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did was
worse than anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> was even accused of doing.

            Meanwhile,
not one of the feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that clamored <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>, and then for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, has lifted a finger on behalf
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> episodes have in common
is that each prompted a rush to judgment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on both sides of the
ideological divide. And most striking, in my view, is the hypocrisy (or
ignorance) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> bias of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>--who proclaimed during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> uproar that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't make these things up," and that "you just
don't get it" if you presumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> innocent until proven guilty--only to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spurn Jones</ENAMEX>' allegations of far more serious (indeed, criminal) conduct as
unworthy of belief and legally frivolous.

            
               She Said: The
Proposition
            

            
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 8, 1991</TIMEX>, encounter began in the
conference-room area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excelsior Hotel</ENAMEX>, where a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Management Conference</ENAMEX>" was in progress at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made a speech.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> claims, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackard</ENAMEX> confirms, that both noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> staring intently
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> while fielding questions from television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few minutes</TIMEX>
later, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trooper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Lee Ferguson</ENAMEX>--who had previously
introduced himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">detail</ENAMEX>--approached
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> said you make his knees knock."

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
complaint, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> later returned to the registration desk, handed Jones a
piece of paper with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> on it, and said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> would like to
meet with her there. According to the complaint, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> stated during the
conversation: 'It's OK, we do this all the time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.' " Blackard
told me, as she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, she generally recalls such a conversation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX>'s carefully lawyered answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' complaint, in which she seeks
damages from him as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, confirms that he then escorted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs floor</ENAMEX> and pointed out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>.

            All this
amounts to clear and convincing proof of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' allegation--which has never
been specifically denied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> personally or by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>--that then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sent a state trooper to interrupt a state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX>'s performance of her job and bring her to his hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            And that seems pretty shabby no matter what, exactly,
happened in that hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>--shabbier than anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> was ever
even accused of doing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, had
persistently pestered her in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1981 and 1982</TIMEX> to date him and talked dirty to
her about pornographic movies and his own sexual prowess. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> did not accuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> of a single overt request for sex or a single unwelcome touching. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> was not too horrified to follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' rising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
Education to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EEOC</ENAMEX>), nor to keep in
touch with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">subsequent years</TIMEX>--getting him to write a letter of
recommendation that helped her land a law teaching job, phoning him repeatedly,
inviting him to make an appearance at the law school, and more.

            
               "I Know He Grabbed
Her"
            

            
The most impressive evidence supporting Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' allegations comes from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Blackard</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Ballentine</ENAMEX>, whom I interviewed separately by phone, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sisters</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>--including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impugned Jones</ENAMEX>' motives--have said they believe her account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
conduct.

            As an
eyewitness to some of the events, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackard</ENAMEX> provides especially strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corroboration</ENAMEX>. "I could see her shaking" as she came walking back to the
registration desk, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackard</ENAMEX> says. After "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five or 10 minutes</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackard</ENAMEX> recalls,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> related what had happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackard</ENAMEX> says she has difficulty remembering
the details offhand but that "I know he grabbed her. She said he just kept on
moving close to her and putting his hand on her knee, and every time she
stopped him he did something else." I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackard</ENAMEX> if she recalled Jones
describing something dramatic. "He dropped his pants," she responded, "and I
don't remember his exact words, but you knew what he wanted." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackard</ENAMEX> added,
"... and she said, 'I don't want you ever to tell anybody.' " Why not, I asked?
"He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackard</ENAMEX> responded. "He's powerful. And we both had state
jobs."

            In her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX> affidavit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Debra Ballentine</ENAMEX> swore that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> had come to her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and, after describing the
circumstances, told her "she rebuffed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> separate unwelcomed sexual advances
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> described in detail the nature of the sexual
advances which I will not now recount."

            In a fuller recounting to me
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballentine</ENAMEX> confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' essential allegations: "She said he was
putting his hands on her legs and he was trying to put his hands up her dress.
... She said, 'Debbie, he pulled his pants down to his knees and he asked me to
[perform oral sex] right then.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballentine</ENAMEX> adds: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> also told her he knew
she was a smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>--what's his name? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Harrington</ENAMEX>?--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'is</NUMEX> a
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine,' and he told her, 'I know you're a smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and you're
going to do the right thing.' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballentine</ENAMEX> recalls that Jones
also told her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> about the mysterious so-called "distinguishing mark"
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' complaint says she saw on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> say
they are relying to corroborate her account.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sisters</ENAMEX> say she also gave detailed accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conduct to them. In an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 9</TIMEX> telephone interview, I asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lydia Cathey</ENAMEX>, if Jones
described what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had done. "Down to the very last detail," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathey</ENAMEX>.
"Dropped his drawers and tell [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX>] her to 'kiss it.' "

            The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, has drawn more publicity than the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> combined, because
she has trashed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' motives in going public. Nonetheless, in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX>
interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> noted, "Asked if she believed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s story, [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>] said she did because she had never known Jones to lie."

            Taken
together, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> contemporaneous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> provide far stronger
corroboration than has ever been mustered on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> testified that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> had told them in vague, general terms of being
sexually harassed, only one of them (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Hoerchner</ENAMEX>) said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX>
had identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> as the harasser. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> had complained
of harassment by an unnamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>."

            
               A Question of
Character
            

            
It's reasonable, and legally relevant, to
speculate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' appearance, demeanor, and willingness to meet with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> alone may have emboldened him to think that sexual overtures would be
welcome. But it's odd to hear such traits held against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> who
would ordinarily go ballistic at any suggestion that a flashy-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was
"asking for it."

            It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>'
legal, as distinct from her factual, claims have their weaknesses. But her
legal theories are hardly frivolous. A single, extremely outrageous act of
sexual harassment, without much more, can arguably support a "hostile working
environment" claim under federal law.

            Given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>'
claims against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> are both more serious by far than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>'s
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>, and supported by much stronger corroborating evidence,
why have the media and a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> acted as though the opposite were
true?

            Part of the explanation is
class bias against what one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> called "some sleazy woman
with big hair coming out of the trailer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>." But that's not all of it. Not,
that is, unless you believe that the press would have given similar coverage to
a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>, making similar allegations, supported by similar evidence,
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
