
   
   
      
         
            Buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lose Your Job</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Governments</ENAMEX> around the world
encourage homeownership in the belief that it fosters prosperity. But
unemployment statistics tell a different story. Higher rates of homeownership
seem to correlate with higher rates of unemployment. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, where
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-fourth</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> own their homes, unemployment is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 2.9 percent</NUMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, where homeownership is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as common, unemployment is a
staggering <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18.1 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>'s homeownership is midway between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Switzerland's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s, and unemployment is a low-to-middling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.1</NUMEX>
percent.

            These
numbers come from a recent paper packed with evidence that homeownership and
unemployment generally move in tandem. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Oswald</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Warwick</ENAMEX>, points to similar patterns all over the
industrialized world. The patterns show up in comparisons between countries
(such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>) and in comparisons between regions within
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Anglia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>), and they
show up whether you look at snapshots in time or at trends that span
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>.

            The data suggest that, on average, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-percent</NUMEX> increase in
the rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> occupation is associated with a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-percent</NUMEX> increase in the
rate of unemployment. If that's right, it accounts for a substantial fraction
of the world's joblessness. What's going on here? Does homeownership cause
unemployment? Does unemployment cause homeownership? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX> endorses the first
explanation--homeownership causes unemployment by tying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down
geographically. The jobless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX> looks for jobs within commuting distance
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The jobless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renter</ENAMEX> is willing to move to where the jobs are.

            That
theory is testable, because it predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> suffer longer
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX> of unemployment, as opposed to more frequent periods of
unemployment. And in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX>'s theory passes at least one version of that
test: As homeownership has risen over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few decades</TIMEX>, there has been an
increase in time spent unemployed but little change in the frequency of job
loss.

            
Alternative theories are possible. Maybe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">causality</ENAMEX> goes backward: Unemployment causes high rates of homeownership. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irreverent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Bils</ENAMEX> points out that if you lose your job, you'll be
spending a lot of time at home, and you'll want to buy a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. A more
plausible explanation is that when jobs dry up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX> move out, so that only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> remain. The other side of that coin is that booming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> tend to
draw a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> who want to rent for a while.

            But when
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things occur in tandem, it isn't always right to ask which is the cause and
which the effect. After all, mistletoe and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eggnog</ENAMEX> tend to appear in the same
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, but neither causes the other. Instead, they're brought on simultaneously
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX>. Perhaps it's the same with unemployment and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homeownership</ENAMEX>. But then what plays the role of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, the background force
that causes both phenomena? The most obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are age and wealth,
either of which can increase the odds of both homeownership and long-term
unemployment (the young and the poor scramble harder for jobs).

            My cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Stockman</ENAMEX> suggests an alternative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, namely, the regulatory climate. He points out that where regulators
run amok, they tend to disrupt the rental market and the job market
simultaneously. Consider the housing market in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, where rental
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> are outrageously expensive. That's largely because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
real-estate laws make it nearly impossible to evict a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX>, so landlords
are skittish about leasing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>. At the same time, labor laws make it
hard to fire a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are conservative in their hiring.

            It's also
possible that the numbers themselves are wrong, because of some hidden bias in
the way they're collected. Maybe when you're counting the unemployed, it's easy
to overlook a transient and hard to overlook a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX>. So you can tell a lot
of different stories to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX>'s numbers. But for the sake of
discussion, let me go back to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> (and, I think, most interesting) story:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homeowners</ENAMEX> stay unemployed longer because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> are less mobile. If that
story is true, what is its moral?

            
Oswald speculates that mass unemployment exists
in the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because of the rise in homeownership and the decline in
private renting--trends that are, in turn, the results of long-running attempts
by most Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to raise the degree of homeownership (largely
through subsidies). Where those attempts have been most successful, the
efficiency of labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">markets</ENAMEX> has declined most dramatically.

            You could
interpret that as a story about well-meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">do-gooders</ENAMEX> who hurt the very
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they're trying to help, but such an interpretation would be hard to
defend. Surely <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> are well aware that they're sacrificing mobility.
That's a voluntary sacrifice, and so (in the judgment of those who choose to
buy) it must be more than compensated for by the benefits of ownership. In
other words, high unemployment might be the price we pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> occupancy,
but apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>-occupants are convinced that it's a price worth
paying.

            That analysis is guided by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>'s faith in the
maxim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are generally pretty good at looking out for their own
interests. The companion maxim is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> often make no attempt at all to
look out for the interests of others. So if we really want to pull every
possible moral out of our story, we should think about the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose
interests are at stake when you decide to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. In other words, we
should think about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            Residential stability is
extremely important for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. If your family moves during your school years
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 6-15</TIMEX>), your chance of graduating high school falls by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX>, the
chance that you'll be "economically inactive" (out of school and out of
work) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 24</TIMEX> rises by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>--and, if you are female, your chance of
getting through your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> without an out-of-wedlock birth falls by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>.
(I learned this from the book Succeeding 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generations</ENAMEX> , by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Haveman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Wolfe</ENAMEX>.) Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX>'s numbers on housing
and unemployment, these numbers might allow a variety of explanations--like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that move are more likely to be poor, and that's why their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't
do as well." But in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haveman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s statistical analysis is designed
to rule out this and similar alternative theories, leaving us to conclude that
the moves themselves are harmful.

            Perhaps when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> move,
they carefully weigh the damage to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> against competing benefits
and act in the interests of the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Or perhaps when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> move,
they selfishly put their own interests ahead of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s. In the latter
case, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that cares about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would want to discourage household
moves (say through subsidies to homeownership), even at the cost of higher
unemployment.

         
      
   
