
   
   
      
         
            Therapeutic Laws

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> wants to be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist chief executive</ENAMEX>, but a paradox of his own making stands in the way. In
his last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address, he repudiated big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. "We know
there's not a program for every problem," he said. "The era of big government
is over." With the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has turned this paradox,
this--let's face it--logical contradiction, into an electoral strength. Clever
rhetoric has helped. But so did his embrace of what might be called
"therapeutic legislation."

            Therapeutic legislation is
intended to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel good, not actually to accomplish anything.
Sometimes, it addresses a virtually nonexistent problem or, at least, a problem
that ranks lower on any sensible scale of national concerns than the fuss and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-congratulation</ENAMEX> would indicate. Sometimes, it addresses real, major
problems, but in an almost totally symbolic manner. Often, therapeutic
legislation exploits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>'s short attention span, its capacity to
become suddenly obsessed with an issue and then--especially if provided with
legislative catharsis--to forget it just as quickly. In any case, therapeutic
legislation costs the taxpayer little or nothing and generally offends almost
no one. (In an important subclass of therapeutic legislation, however, stagily
offending an unpopular interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>--e.g., the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>--is part of the
therapy.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed
another of the many therapeutic laws for which he has taken credit. This one
makes stalking across interstate lines or on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government property a federal
offense, punishable by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The law was sponsored by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Bailey Hutchison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, proving that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> aren't
alone in the dirty habit of pleasuring themselves this way. The anti-stalking
law is typical of much therapeutic legislation in that it addresses a hunger
for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to do something about a matter--usually crime
or education--that is properly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. I wouldn't be so
callous as to suggest that stalking isn't an urgent problem, fully worthy of
immediate action by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that can't pass a budget on time. But is
stalking across state lines or on federal property really such a
pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>? Undoubtedly it is terrifying when it happens (as it
apparently happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX>). The reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the president
have outlawed it with such a flourish, however, is as a way of expressing
symbolic concern over stalking in general. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> concedes
that it has collected no information on the number of interstate stalking
cases.

            Indeed,
if there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of interstate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalkers</ENAMEX>, if they did pose
a serious law-enforcement problem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX>'s legislation would have smoked
out some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> to oppose the bill. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalkers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> itself
didn't pipe up, at least civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> who deplore the double-jeopardy
implications of a federal stalking law would have criticized it. Instead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX>'s solution to the nonproblem passed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-0</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. A law that
passes with no opposition is a good bet to be therapeutic legislation. (And it
is doubly hypocritical for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who claim to believe in less government
and in state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, to be clotting the federal statute books with laws
that mess in areas of state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> >any therapeutic laws are superfluous. Some are passed unanimously.
But the defining characteristic of a therapeutic bill is its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>: It doesn't
increase the budget; it requires no new taxes; and it offends no
special-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The anti-stalking bill cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> absolutely nothing, but allowed them to inflate their
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">anti-crime résumés.</ENAMEX>

            A good <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
therapeutic laws passed on his watch or new ones he wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to
consider:

            He called for a ban on
"cop-killer" bullets; reiterated his support for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>'-rights
constitutional amendment; argued for an extension of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family and Medical</ENAMEX>
Leave law and a measure to keep moms and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> longer than
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>; promoted a measure that would place taggents in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>; and asked
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady Bill</ENAMEX> amendment to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> out of the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> of
domestic violence.

            He touted the television
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-</ENAMEX>chip; praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy-Kassebaum</ENAMEX> law (an ultra-therapeutic law that
guarantees portability of insurance but places no ceiling on the rates insurers
can charge); applauded the ban on "assault" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>; and bragged about the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> regulations that curb the advertising and sale of cigarettes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            To much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applause</ENAMEX>, he deplored the fact that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> live within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just four</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> of a toxic waste dump" (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four miles</NUMEX> ?) and urged that we make it
illegal "even to attempt to pollute" (whatever that means).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> isn't the only therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>,
just the best. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Linguistic nationalists</ENAMEX> are pushing their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-first
measures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ultrapatriotic</ENAMEX> want an amendment to ban flag-burning (hell, why
not just mandate flag-waving?). The spit-and-polish crowd campaigns for
school uniforms. The drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> seek more drug-free zones. To ward off child
molesters, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Mateo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, has proposed background checks and
fingerprinting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>, den <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, and others who volunteer
their time to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (never mind, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports,
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 10 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molestations take place in an
institutional setting; that most accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molesters have no previous
convictions; and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse is down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>). And with the continued
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Balanced Budget Amendment</ENAMEX> follies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> indulges itself in the grandest of
therapeutic fantasies. If it really wants to balance the budget it should just
do so, rather than passing feel-good laws that say the budget should be
balanced.

            No doubt
somewhere in the above list I've included a law that you, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, support
and believe is more than merely therapeutic. Your particular law, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>,
address problems fully worthy of a national fuss and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX> signing
ceremony. But surely even you will agree that most of these laws are merely
therapeutic. We can all agree on that, without agreeing on which are the
exceptions.

            Therapeutic laws become props for rhetoric that might be
called demagoguery, except that it disgraces the memories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe McCarthy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huey Long</ENAMEX> and the ambitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a demagogue. The
genuine demagogue assails <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and labels his foes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>. The modern
"semigogue" speaks liltingly about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and education and health and public
safety. He artfully constructs his debate to make his foes sound as if they are
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, for gun violence, against safe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and for pollution.
The semigogue in chief has buried <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> with so many positives during this
election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, it's enough to make you long for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of negative
campaigning.

            And for genuine activism.
Even though my personal tastes in legislation tend toward the kind that begin,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> shall pass no law," I admired the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> who attempted to
reorganize the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 trillion</NUMEX> health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and who forthrightly called for
a workfare program that would cost more, not less, than simple handouts. That
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't pussyfoot around. He stood for what he believed in. He
stimulated a thunderous and enlightening debate. He demonstrated to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> that real change is not cheap and easy.

            He also got his ass
kicked.

         
      
   
