
   
   
      
         
            The Changelings

            When did the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post swap identities with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX>, it seemed,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> rollicked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with its cheeky personality and the next
suffocated them with the sort of overcast official news that made the
Times famous. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> sloughed its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Gray Lady</ENAMEX>
persona for the daredevilry that was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>.

            The
switch dawned on me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX> as I found myself flipping through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> because I had to, not because I wanted to--and reading the
Times for the joy of it, not because it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of record. I
know this sounds like the beginning of an encomium for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> at the
expense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , but it's not. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> traded places, they
exchanged virtues as well as vices .

            In the traded virtue category: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> takes a lot
of risks. It has turned its back on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> boroughs to become a national
newspaper, even purchasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">burrowed</ENAMEX> deeper locally. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX> dish the
sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas von Hoffman</ENAMEX> and the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> once served at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . It continues to innovate, with new sections like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Business Day</ENAMEX>" (a k a "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Industries</ENAMEX>") and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> and
Ideas," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> hasn't contributed anything significant to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">template</ENAMEX> since the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. Its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is the best
general interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> in the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post 's</ENAMEX> isn't.

            Other
traded virtues: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> prints in color, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't
(yet). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> sports an aggressive and handsome design. The recent
Post redesign aches like a bad face lift. Times Editorial Page
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howell Raines</ENAMEX> writes barrelhouse editorials demanding action--such as
the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>--that stir substance and fanfaronade. The
Post editorial and op-ed pages are so evenhanded that if Scotty Reston
were resurrected, his soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> would appear there, alongside that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoagland</ENAMEX>. And the Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> its reporting with opinion, while the
once liberal-and-proud-of-it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> prides itself on cool neutrality (some
would count this as a swapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> and not a swapped virtue). On the news side,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Downie Jr.</ENAMEX> boasts he's so bias-free that
he doesn't vote.

            
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice side</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, the
Times ... takes a lot of risks. It's now the primary exponent of what
Post ie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> famously called the "holy shit" story--pieces so
astonishing that you scream spontaneous profanities when you read them. The
downside of holy shit stories is that they can turn out to be wholly bullshit,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> learned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> under his editorial watch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooke</ENAMEX>, got caught making up a story about an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroin addict</ENAMEX>.

            In its
pursuit of holy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shit</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> routinely spins out of control. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>,
it published the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX> of
rape--for no particular reason--and then apologized for it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That same year</TIMEX>, the
paper digested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX>'s spuriously sourced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> biography on Page
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. In a transparent lunge for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
published a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-part series alleging that the downsizing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">workforce</ENAMEX> was creating "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of casualties." Actually, job creation was
booming. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that year</TIMEX>, the paper spread its legs for the theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>
Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> was downed by foul play, based on the discovery of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PETN</ENAMEX>" residues
in the wreckage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported: "Law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> said it
was impossible to know, for now, whether the explosion was caused by a bomb or
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PETN</ENAMEX> is an explosive component commonly found in both.
Still, the discovery would seem to knock from contention the theory that
mechanical failure caused the airplane to explode on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX>, killing all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">230</NUMEX>
aboard ." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emphasis</ENAMEX> added.) Eventually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> abandoned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PETN</ENAMEX>/bomb theory for the mechanical failure
theory.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just this spring</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reckless Times stories slid
off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Kolata</ENAMEX> prematurely announced a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cure (while shopping a
book proposal on the subject) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Bragg</ENAMEX> botched a simple story about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> corruption in small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bragg</ENAMEX>, a writerish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who would
be at home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Style</ENAMEX>, earned in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . The jailed sheriff
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27 months</TIMEX> behind bars, not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27 years</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bragg</ENAMEX> originally reported. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bragg</ENAMEX>
also got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of the crusading</TIMEX> newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> wrong, misstated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
circulation, and mistakenly described the method by which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> defrauded
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> cashed checks improperly made out to him; he did
not cash checks made out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>).

            Horrible!
Just horrible! But consider the alternative. Who wants to read a porcelain
white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that has flushed all its holy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shit</ENAMEX>? Whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> drive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvos</ENAMEX> to work?

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> isn't powered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>--yet.
But in adopting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old New York Times</ENAMEX> values of cautiousness and fairness
and dullness, in striving to become the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspaper of Record</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has lost its verve. Sometimes a loss of verve is not a bad thing.
Compare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> satellite story.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gerth</ENAMEX> implies that illegal campaign donations from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> + the extravagant campaign donations by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral Space & Communications</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> coffers = <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s OK of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> satellite
launches. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's sober coverage expands the theme to detail how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was as happy to fulfill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> dreams of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> who lobbied heavily and donated sparingly as he was to
satisfy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> who gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of
dollars (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mintz</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25</TIMEX> article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Hughes Got What It Wanted on China</ENAMEX>"). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's version is probably closer to the facts, but I'd be lying if I
didn't say that I've enjoyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' sensationalist coverage
more.

            Of course
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't tiptoe all the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign finance
pieces struck a chord that still rings, and I predict a similar impact for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton Gellman</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part series <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> nearly went to war in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> (click here and here). At its best, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> can still swarm a
breaking news story like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. But at its worst, it sits on hot news. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> delayed its exposé of masher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Packwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, until
after the election, thereby assuring his return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spiked Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> reporting, so he left for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
where he has led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> story.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Timesmen</ENAMEX> don't pay much attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
except to periodically raid the paper--as if it were a minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>--for
some of its better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defectors</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celestine Bohlen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Ifill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Preston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Specter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Tyler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patti Cohen</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Richards</ENAMEX>--who defected back. Few careers, outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.J. Dionne</ENAMEX>'s, have
been made by going the other way.) But it should pay closer attention. It
desperately needs something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Style</ENAMEX> section, where it can run imprudent
stories that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are dying to read but have yet to acquire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heft</ENAMEX> and
Importance of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times News Story</ENAMEX>. Then again, if the
Times were to embrace the virtue of a Style section (or is that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>?), would its news sections lose their current virtue of attitude?

            

               Post ies, on the other hand, obsess on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's annual "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pugwash</ENAMEX>" editorial retreat, outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kaiser</ENAMEX> began his speech with the preposterous boast that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , with a staff half the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ', "does more for
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, day in and day out." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser</ENAMEX> obviously lusts for the Old
Times as he repeatedly calls for "authoritative journalism" and higher
journalistic "standards," and petitions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ies to be more intellectual
and creative. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Authoritative</ENAMEX>, creative journalism that meets the highest
standards must have intellectual content," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> says at speech<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'s end</TIMEX> as he
road-wrecks his themes. Somebody get this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>!

            
The question of how the audacious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> turned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stodgy</ENAMEX> floats over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> like a thought balloon. The easy
answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Bradlee</ENAMEX> departed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 years</TIMEX> at
the top. This theory singles out current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downie</ENAMEX> for abuse, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complacency</ENAMEX> took root as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as 1981</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's cross-town
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competitor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Star</ENAMEX> , folded, allowing the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> to
diddle all it wanted without paying a price. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Graham</ENAMEX> took over as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, he picked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downie</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who would help steer the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> away
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> and toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>, away from national
competition and straight at the suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>. You're reading the paper they
wanted to make.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s biggest handicap is that he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> who came after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katharine</ENAMEX>,
and he's fearful that he'll blow her legacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downie's</ENAMEX> is that he came after
Bradlee, and he's afraid he'll blow his. Who remembers the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who canoed
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>? No wonder they operate the paper as if the frontier has
closed behind them. In that context, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s conservatism makes business
sense. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claims the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> penetration in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and is
immensely profitable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX>, a major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholder</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
whispers into his ear that he's a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. Why disturb the money-making
machine?

            The last time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> took an editorial risk was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>,
when it barred no expense in relaunching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>

               Magazine as a prestige <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> on the scale of the New York
Times 
               Magazine . But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> never got to compete with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> : It was bushwhacked by a black talk-radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demagogue</ENAMEX> who
unfairly labeled the debut issue racist and targeted the paper with
demonstrations and a boycott. Its momentum shattered, the extravagantly funded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Magazine</ENAMEX> limped along for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> until the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> abandoned its grand financial and editorial ambitions and
downscaled it.

            Various
sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> have improved since then--it has invested heavily
in zoned suburban coverage, expanded its business page, improved the quality of
its travel section, extended the heft of its sports coverage, experimented with
an advertorial insert about consumer electronics, and added a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> midbrow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science/</ENAMEX>history section (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Horizon"</ENAMEX>)--but it's taken no publishing risks.

            
The boldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> stroke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downie dethroned Kaiser</ENAMEX> as managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and appointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Coll</ENAMEX>, a 39-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX>, who most recently served
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coll</ENAMEX>'s vision for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , also
laid out in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pugwash</ENAMEX> speech, sounds like a description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New New York</ENAMEX>
Times : "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> depends mightily on our ability to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">excel</ENAMEX> at enterprise journalism--on our ability to think more creatively, to
tear the skin off of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> more often, to write better, to go deeper, to
be more alive, to make more of a difference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>." Good luck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>,
you'll need it.

            Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
derives its edge from its succession politics. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bradlee</ENAMEX> served as
Post <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>-for-life, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> places an informal term limit on
its executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> job, and this turnover has helped to reinvigorate the
paper: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> know they must make their mark in haste,
before their tenure is over. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX> reinvented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> during his
tenure from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977 to 1986</TIMEX>, stealing from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay Felker</ENAMEX>'s playbook to explode the
Times into a many sectioned national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Frankel</ENAMEX>,
brought vivid writing to the paper from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986 to 1994</TIMEX>, making sure that one
story made it to Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> just because it was fun to read. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
Lelyveld, who took over from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankel</ENAMEX>, has stayed their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile, the 56-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downie</ENAMEX> is now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> into the job. If he were a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, they'd be
farming him out to write a column right about now. Instead, he's ensconced like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
