
   
   
      
         
            Pay Scales in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>

            This column is about racial
discrimination. But more importantly, it's about how a little arithmetic can go
a long way toward settling a controversy.

            The controversy I have in
mind is, Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> earn less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> do? The easiest hypothesis is that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> discriminate. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> have attempted to dismiss that
hypothesis on the grounds that discrimination is costly (because it entails a
willingness to pay premium wages for white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>) and therefore unattractive
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> with an eye on the bottom line.

            But that
kind of dismissal is too glib, because it is not based on any estimate of how
much it costs to discriminate. Without that estimate, we can't even
begin to think about whether the cost is high enough to make much
difference.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwant</ENAMEX> to provide the missing estimate, starting with a few
assumptions that are reasonably commensurate with reality. First, I'll suppose
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I'll suppose that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, because of discrimination, earn <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> earn. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>,
I'll make an assumption (again guided by real-world observations) about what
happens to corporate revenue: I'll assume that for every dollar paid to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, a half dollar gets paid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>
collectively--let's say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> each get a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>.

            To make those assumptions
more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX>, suppose you're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, paying the black <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> apiece.
That makes your total wage bill <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$960,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>
each receive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, thus each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$240,000</NUMEX>.
So your payouts look like this:

             

            (The
specific numbers in the preceding paragraph don't matter. If you assume 100
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, or wages of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000 and $10,000</NUMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>, the conclusions to follow will remain unaffected.)

            
Now we can estimate the cost of your
discrimination. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice first</ENAMEX> that discrimination must be quite common in your
industry; otherwise your black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> would have gone elsewhere long ago. That
means there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> working for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> in this industry. If you
could put aside your racism, you'd fire your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine $100,000</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and
replace them with some of those <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> blacks--cutting your wage bill by
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$360,000</NUMEX>.

            Where would the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$360,000</NUMEX> in
savings go? The same place any corporate savings go--into the pockets of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, increasing their earnings from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$240,000 to $600,000</NUMEX>--a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>
percent increase <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. Your payouts now look like this:

             

            When the
return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> rises by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX>, so must the price of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock. That's enough to put you on the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>
as the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. To continue discriminating is to throw
away an opportunity for unprecedented financial success.

            In fact, that same opportunity is available to every other
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> in the industry as well, and they're rejecting it too
(remember that discrimination must be widespread or all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> would move to
nondiscriminatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>). So in order to believe that discrimination explains
the black/white wage differential, you must believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> throughout
the industry are so blinded by racism that they are willing to throw away a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>
percent gain for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, and the acclaim of all Wall Street for
themselves. Personally, I find that wildly implausible.

            That's not an irrefutable
disproof that discrimination exists, but it's at least a calculation that needs
to be taken seriously. If we had come up with a number like <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> rather
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX>, it would have been far easier to maintain a belief that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> discriminate.

            The figure
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX> is based on numerical assumptions that are reasonable but not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ironclad</ENAMEX>. If you juggle those initial assumptions a bit, you'll get a number
other than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX> coming out at the end, and you might or might not
discover a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX> in which discrimination is plausible. (My guess is that you
won't, but then again, you and I might have different standards for what's
plausible.) Regardless of how that experiment turns out, it's well worth
performing. Without some such test, there is simply no way to know whether
discrimination is a credible hypothesis.

            
If we rule out employer discrimination, there
must be some other explanation for the black/white wage differential. Suppose,
for example, that there is discrimination not by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> but by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>,
who are willing to pay a premium for goods and services produced by white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. To advocate that theory convincingly, you'd have to estimate the size
of the premium and assess whether it's something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> would plausibly
pay. I invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to do their own arithmetic.

            Alternative theories posit
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> earn less because they have fewer marketable skills. Like theories
of discrimination, these theories are best judged by quantitative criteria, but
now we have to go beyond what can be computed on the back of an envelope and
look, for example, at what we can learn from standardized test scores.

            According
to recent research by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Neal</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson of the University of Virginia</ENAMEX>, black/white wage differentials are
largely explained by differences in skill levels which are already detectable
at an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard J. Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX> had previously
reported similar findings in their best-selling book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> .) To
explain those skill differentials, one can try pointing either to training or
heredity.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> argued that heredity plays a
substantial role, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s more recent findings tend to refute
that interpretation. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> report that the
performance gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> is considerably larger for young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> than it is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>. That's hard to explain if the gap is caused
by heredity (why should an inherent difference become larger over time?), but
not if it's caused by training (if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> get inferior schooling, then it's not
surprising that the effects are greater after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> of schooling than after
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>).

            Much research remains to be
done, and is being done, and will be done. All of that research, at least when
it is useful, will be quantitative in one way or another. Some of it requires
sophisticated techniques and sophisticated measurements. But there are
cases--and discrimination is one of them--where the inherent plausibility of a
theory can be well tested with nothing more than the back of an envelope and an
open mind.

         
      
   
