
   
   
      
         
            Giving Your All

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARE</ENAMEX> is a noble organization
that fights starvation. It would like your support. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>
is a noble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that fights disease. It would like your support, too.
Here's my advice: If you're feeling very charitable, give generously--but don't
give to both of them.

            Giving to either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is a
choice attached to a clear moral judgment. When you give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to CARE, you
assert that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARE</ENAMEX> is worthier than the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> society. Having made that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX>, you are morally bound to apply it to your next <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> donation.
Giving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> society tomorrow means admitting that you were wrong
to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to CARE <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            You might protest that you
diversify because you don't know enough to make a firm judgment about where
your money will do the most good. But that argument won't fly. Your
contribution to CARE says that in your best (though possibly flawed) judgment,
and in view of the (admittedly incomplete) information at your disposal, CARE
is worthier than the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> society. If that's your best judgment when you
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shell</ENAMEX> out your first <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, it should be your best judgment when you shell out
your second <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>.

            When it
comes to managing your personal portfolio, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> will tell you to
diversify. When it comes to handling the rest of your life, we give you exactly
the same advice. It's a bad idea to spend all your leisure time playing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>; you'll probably be happier if you occasionally watch movies or go sailing
or talk to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            So why is charity different? Here's the reason: An
investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> can make a serious dent in the problem of adding some
high-tech stocks to your portfolio; now it's time to move on to other
investment goals. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Two hours</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> makes a serious dent in the
problem of getting some exercise; maybe it's time to see what else in life is
worthy of attention. But no matter how much you give to CARE, you will
never make a serious dent in the problem of starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The
problem is just too big; behind every starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is another equally
deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            That is
not to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> is futile. If you save one starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, you have
done a wonderful thing, regardless of how many starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> remain. It is
precisely because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> is so effective that we should think seriously
about where to target it, and then stay focused once the target is chosen.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> constantly ignore my good advice by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARE</ENAMEX>, and public radio all in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX>--as if they were thinking, "OK, I
think I've pretty much wrapped up the problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>; now let's see
what I can do about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>." But such delusions of grandeur can't be very
common. So there has to be some other reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> diversify their
giving.

            I think I
know what that reason is. You give to charity because you care about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, or you give to charity because it makes you feel good to give. If
you care about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, you'll pick the worthiest and "bullet"
(concentrate) your efforts. But if you care about your own sense of
satisfaction, you'll enjoy pointing to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> and saying, "I
gave to all those!"

            Here's a thought experiment for charitable diversifiers.
Suppose you plan to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to CARE <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. Suppose I mention that I plan to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARE</ENAMEX> today
myself. Do you say, "Oh, then I can skip my CARE contribution and go directly
on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>?" I bet not.

            But if my <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
contribution to CARE does not stop you from making CARE your first priority,
then why should your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> contribution to CARE (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>) stop you from
making CARE your first priority <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>? Apparently you believe that your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
is somehow more effective or more important than my <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>. That's either a
delusion of grandeur or an elevation of your own desire for satisfaction above
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>' need for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.

            We have been told on
reasonably high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> that true charity vaunteth not itself; it is not
puffed up. You can puff yourself up with thank-you notes from a dozen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, or you can be truly charitable by concentrating your efforts
where you believe they will do the most good.

            Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> offered this advice to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>: When confronted with an
economic problem, first translate into mathematics, then solve the problem,
then translate back into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and burn the mathematics. I am a devotee of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX>'s and frequently follow his advice. But in this instance, I want to
experiment with a slight deviation: Rather than burn the mathematics, I will
make it available as a link.

            I propose to establish the
following proposition: If your charitable contributions are small relative to
the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>, and if you care only about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> (as
opposed to caring, say, about how many accolades you receive), then you will
bullet all your contributions on a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>. That's basically a
mathematical proposition, which I have translated into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in this column.
If you want to see exactly what was gained or lost in translation (and if you
remember enough of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman calculus</ENAMEX> to read the original), then .

         
      
   
