
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theatrical Indecision</ENAMEX>

            With the opening of another
Broadway season imminent, you might be wondering about the health of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> dying or thriving? Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> nd
Street playhouse portend good things or bad things for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great White Way</ENAMEX>?
Will extravagant productions funded by the megalomaniac <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drabinsky</ENAMEX> revitalize or destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> musical? Whither serious drama?
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the answer to these questions is
yes.

            In the
Times ' pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> has died a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> deaths and prospered in a
thousand booms. No <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> has ever been plain average. Consider this classic
example: a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Lawson</ENAMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater Enjoys Biggest Boom in</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>." The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> assesses the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982 season</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Broadway Is</ENAMEX> in its Worst
Slump in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a Decade</TIMEX>."

            Plotting a trajectory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> headlines from the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last five years</TIMEX>, you begin to suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> is mechanically acting out
some dialectical process that dooms it to fall on its face every other year.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Broadway, the Lights Get Brighter</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Broadway Blues</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Numbers Are on the Rise</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Entertainment Is Killing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Hit Season for Broadway: Seems Like Old Times With Influx</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatergoers</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>: "Despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway Boom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Serious Plays Face Serious</ENAMEX>
Peril."

            
Compounding the confusion caused by these historical fluctuations are
contradictory assessments of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>'s condition at any given moment. Take
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Reasons to Have Faith in the Theater</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5, 1996</TIMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Brustein</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End of Broadway's Run"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 8, 1996</TIMEX>). Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Broadway Pays Big Dividends"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17, 1994</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Weber</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make</ENAMEX>
Money on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>? Break a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leg"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 1993</TIMEX>).

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is torn constantly between
touting and panicking. It takes very little to set off alarms. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tony-winning Jelly's Last Jam</ENAMEX> announced that it had failed to recoup
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' money, the paper editorialized, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great White Way</ENAMEX> is ailing." In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the cause for concern was the opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Albee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNally</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">off-Broadway</ENAMEX>: "Some of the most beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> in the world
are on the brink of permanent obsolescence."

            It is not
just a matter of theatrical exaggeration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">deep-seated anxiety</ENAMEX> about the future of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> they write about. A
LEXIS-NEXIS search shows that the metaphor of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> as an "endangered
species" has been reprised <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> times since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> in the headline or lead
paragraph of an arts-section piece. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> 
               Magazine
piece titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Broadway Is Dead; Long Live Broadway</ENAMEX>" excerpted quotes from the
paper's greatest drama <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kerr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>. Apparently,
for most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX> have been convinced that
they were celebrating an antiquated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> long displaced by movies and
television. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks Atkinson</ENAMEX> wrote: "As usual, the theater is dying.
... From an economic point of view, the legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> is like its
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>: it is obsolete." This anxiety colors these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' assessment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broadway</ENAMEX>'s prospects. Any evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>'s prosperity is instantly and
optimistically greeted as a potential watershed, an end to the perpetual
crisis. All negative data merely exacerbate the fatalism.

            To be fair, it is possible to argue with logical
consistency that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> is simultaneously booming and busting. For instance,
the line adopted in several recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> pieces is that while
extravagant musicals can score funding and bring in huge crowds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>,
serious plays using experimental techniques and tackling risqué subjects
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languish</ENAMEX>. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> is thriving as a business but dying as an
art form. But wait. Maybe it's thriving as an art form but dying as a business.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> celebrated the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 season</TIMEX>, he qualified his enthusiasm for the shows
by adding, "As a business <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> remains, more unhealthily and nervously than
ever, the oldest floating crap game in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>."

            Whatever.

         
      
   
