
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax the Knickers Off Your Grandchildren</ENAMEX>

            As of this writing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' estimated net worth is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24 billion</NUMEX>. On the conservative assumption that
he's earning <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> after taxes and inflation, his investment income is
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2 million</NUMEX> a day.

            It's difficult for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to
even imagine what it would be like to have that kind of pure income. But it
won't be as difficult for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> per capita income manages
to grow in real terms at a plausible <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> per year, then in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 400</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> will enjoy a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> income of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. And those are not some future, ravaged<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-</NUMEX>inflation dollars--I'm
measuring everything in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

            More remarkably, if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> could achieve the growth rates that have been reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of decades</TIMEX>, it would take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about 100 years</TIMEX> until
the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s income approaches <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> per day. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
grows like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> can live like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>--unless they rise above mediocrity and live even better.

            So each time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX>
impedes economic development to preserve some specimen of natural beauty, it is
asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live like you and me (the relatively poor) to sacrifice for
the enjoyment of future generations that will live like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>.

            Taking from the poor and
giving to the rich is the opposite of income redistribution as it is usually
practiced. If we were consistent, we'd insist that those wealthy future
generations owed us something, not the other way around. If some moral
principle allows the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> to confiscate <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' income,
that same moral principle should allow the unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lumberjacks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> to
confiscate your rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>'s view of the giant redwoods.

            (I am
accepting, for the sake of argument, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX>'s presumption that it can
accurately foresee what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> will value. But it's worth mentioning a
separate reason to be skeptical of the conservationist agenda: For all we know,
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> might prefer inheriting the proceeds of economic development
to inheriting the redwoods.)

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservationists</ENAMEX> are not alone in
their pathological concern for future generations. The same impulse has
launched an epidemic of hysteria over federal deficits. The national debt is to
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> what the nuclear freeze was to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>: It's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> issue you don't
really have to understand before you can start feeling morally superior to your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. From that point of view, it's even better than the nuclear
freeze--not only does your expression of deep concern put you on the moral high
ground, but you actually get to stand on that ground and prescribe suffering
for everybody else.

            Thus we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concord</ENAMEX>
Coalition types, who are always whining that the national debt forces them to
live well at their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>'s expense. I have news for them: Nobody
can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> you to live well at your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>'s expense. If you think your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyle</ENAMEX> is too extravagant, spend less and bequeath the savings to your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>.

            The arithmetic works. If the
government cuts your taxes by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> and sticks your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>--say <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> with accumulated interest--you don't have to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the $1,000</NUMEX>.
You can put it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, where it will grow to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> by the time your
grandchildren withdraw it to pay their taxes.

            While it makes no sense to
worry that you are living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> at your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>'s expense, you
might <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> worry that someone else is living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> at your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandchildren</ENAMEX>'s expense. Maybe your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> applies his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> tax cut to buy
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> made of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> that could otherwise have been a girder in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> that
might have employed your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> disagree about how plausible
that story is, but we all agree that if you're out to protect your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> from the national debt, it's basically the only story you have to
worry about.

            If you are worried about that
story, it means one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things. Either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) you believe that your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> has
no right to live well at your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>'s expense or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) you believe
that your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> has that right, but you'd prefer to prevent him from
exercising it. In Case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, I assume you have sufficiently little interest in
moral niceties that you wouldn't be reading a column like this one in the first
place. That leaves Case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>. But if you believe that your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> has no right
to live well at the expense of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fabulously</ENAMEX> wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>, you must
also believe that your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> has no right to live well at the expense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. In other words, if you're unhappy about the national debt, you
should be doubly unhappy about the progressive income tax.

            The popular philosophy of
income redistribution requires us to transfer income from the few high
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, while the popular philosophies of conservation and "fiscal
responsibility" require us to transfer income to the many high earners
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. Those who embrace all these philosophies at once--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
comes to mind--have about them at least a mild air of intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>.

            (For a
more technical analysis of what we owe to future generations, click .)

         
      
   
