
   
   
      
         
            

            This idea that harmony
between the races is impossible--let's call it the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fallacy</ENAMEX>"--rests largely on confusion about a form of natural selection known as
"kin selection." The issues are a bit arcane, but I'll try to provide a rough
sketch of some of them.

            "Kin selection" accounts for
the evolution of altruistic impulses toward close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. The textbook
example of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kin</ENAMEX> selection is a newly minted gene that inclines a ground squirrel
to stand up and give an alarm call upon seeing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance,
this gene would seem to have no chance of proliferating via natural selection,
since it attracts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX>'s attention and thus endangers the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> in
which it resides. But remember: The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> will also reside, on average, in half
of that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX>--and their survival <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> are enhanced
by the gene's effect (i.e., by the warning call). So, even if this "warning
call" gene occasionally causes the death of its possessor, the gene itself may
still flourish by natural selection, as long as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> are
saved for every one ground squirrel that is lost. (If this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cliff Notes</ENAMEX>
version of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kin</ENAMEX> selection doesn't seem to make sense, then please go and read
the excerpt from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Families</ENAMEX>" on the Web site for my book,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Moral</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animal</ENAMEX>, then come back, and keep reading.) In our species, the result of
this evolutionary process seems to be a kin-directed altruism that is roughly
proportional to the closeness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be more inclined
to risk their lives for a sibling than for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, and for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> than for
the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>. (This assumes, among other things, that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been
reared in close enough proximity to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> to develop the emotional
bonds that mediate kin-selected altruism.)

            Here is where confusion
enters the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> eager to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are innately
hostile toward one another. They try to extend the logic of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kin</ENAMEX> selection
beyond the scope of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and carry it all the way up to the level of
whole races. They are assuming, in other words, that there is a universal law
dictating that altruism between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> be proportional to their degree of
genetic relatedness--and that natural discord among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thus will be
proportional to their genetic difference.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> major
problems with this logic. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is a fairly technical (though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consequential</ENAMEX>) analytical flaw, first identified in another context by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> and labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washburn</ENAMEX>'s fallacy." (See his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Twelve Misunderstandings of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kin Selection</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitschr</ENAMEX>. Tierpsychol, no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>]: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">184-200</ENAMEX>). I won't
even try to explain the fallacy here, except to say that a) It consists of
assuming that kin selection would make altruism proportional to overall
genetic relatedness--that is, the percentage of all your genes that you
have in common with another <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>; and b) This assumption has been memorably
characterized as implying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> should, in theory, be "nicer to mosquitos
than to marigolds." That characterization was made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Daly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Salmon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo Wilson</ENAMEX>. For their explicit application of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>' analysis
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> fallacy (they don't call it that, of course), see
their chapter in the forthcoming textbook <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evolutionary Social</ENAMEX>
Psychology , edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Kenrick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Simpson</ENAMEX>, and published by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> problem with the
idea of some iron law correlating altruism with genetic relatedness--and thus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correlating</ENAMEX> natural discord with genetic difference--is at least slightly more
accessible. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Kin</ENAMEX> selection isn't some inexorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of evolution. It's just a
theoretical possibility, one that will only be realized if the circumstances of
evolution are conducive to its realization. In the case of altruism directed
toward close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, we know that circumstances were indeed so conducive:
Throughout human evolution, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were reared a) near close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>; and b)
near <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who weren't close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. Thus there was lots of opportunity for
the flourishing of genes that led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> to discriminate between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>,
favoring the former at the expense of the latter. But in the case of comparable
discrimination between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of one's own race and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of other races,
there was no significant opportunity for the evolution of such a trait. Because
during human evolution (that is, during that short span of human evolution that
took place after distinct races began forming), there was roughly zero
contact among different races; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> didn't vacation on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riviera</ENAMEX>
back then. Saying that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> evolved an innate aversion to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> an innate aversion to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, is like saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> evolved an innate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aversion</ENAMEX> to some poison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that grows only on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>; the opportunity simply
wasn't there.

            None of this is to suggest
that human nature doesn't vastly complicate race relations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are
obviously inclined to derogate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> whose interests seem to clash with those
of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, and to identify those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> by whatever means are
available. Skin color can be an unfortunately handy means of doing the
identifying. What's more, kin selection itself may complicate race relations in
various subtle ways. For example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepotism</ENAMEX>, one legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kin</ENAMEX> selection, is
often de facto racial discrimination, since your close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> are usually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of your race. When a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> promotes his niece, he is
discriminating against some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> (the ones who aren't in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>), but
against all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.

            All told, the obstacles to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intergroup</ENAMEX> harmony posed by human nature are big enough that there is little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exaggeration</ENAMEX> in saying that xenophobia is a part of human nature, at least in
this sense: Uncritical hostility toward an identifiable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--identifiable by language, dress, color, whatever--is an inherent
capacity, activated under certain predictable circumstances. But that is very
different from saying we are designed to automatically dislike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
particular skin colors, and that racial harmony therefore is impossible--which
is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> article said.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX>-disclosure paragraph:
The article in which the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> fallacy" appeared was a review
of my book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Moral Animal</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the review's major complaints was
about my alleged failure to realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darwinism</ENAMEX> is a thoroughgoing
vindication of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">reviewer</ENAMEX>'s various political beliefs (e.g., the
impossibility of racial harmony). No doubt some of my animus toward the article
is related to these comments about my book. Still, I'm not inventing the idea
that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> fallacy" is indeed a fallacy. The same opinion
is held by, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Williams</ENAMEX>, one of the greatest evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> and arguably the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of evolutionary
psychology. By the way, his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adaptation and Natural Selection</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton University Press</ENAMEX>), which laid the theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> for the
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> study of social behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, still is in print.

         
      
   
