
   
   
      
         
            More <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time With My Family</ENAMEX>

            Nobody in the press wanted
to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> when he announced that he was
quitting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day job</TIMEX> (plotting and scheming against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leadership</ENAMEX>) to spend more time with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suby</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molinari</ENAMEX>. Less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molinari</ENAMEX> left her seat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> to
become a TV anchor and, according to news reports, to spend more time with her
family.

            So
reluctant were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxon</ENAMEX> a prevaricator that most of them waited
a decent interval--a few paragraphs--before reporting the apparent reason for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX>'s resignation: His challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> was doomed and
he faced a career as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backbencher</ENAMEX>, a fate the ambitious pol
apparently couldn't face.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANexis</ENAMEX> dump indicates that at least twice a day somebody
tells the press he or she has swapped the horrors of work for the bliss of
family. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one recent week</TIMEX>:

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> (who was in hot water for performing a gay marriage ceremony) doffed
his collar to spend more time with the missus.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFOs</ENAMEX> of both the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Co.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente</ENAMEX> copped the family plea when they left their
jobs--though a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> felt it necessary to add that the
resignation was unrelated to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$270 million</NUMEX> loss in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
coaches hung up their clipboards, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> stored his last file, and a
village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> cast her last vote because they allegedly wanted more time
with their loved ones.

            
Obviously, I don't think all these fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are lying about their motives. It's safe to say that in the course
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the planet really do quit so they can
watch their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> grow up. Another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half-dozen</NUMEX> or so may be deceiving themselves
rather than us, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delray Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lynch</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynch</ENAMEX> quit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> because he wanted more time with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and his
business. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch</ENAMEX> has since learned that the sure cure for wanting to spend more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is spending more time with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>: He's just thrown
his hat in the ring for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delray Beach School Board</ENAMEX>.

            Many
tender the family alibi because they're ashamed of having been fired, or
embarrassed to admit that they've conceded defeat to the god of success
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX>'s case, I'm sure), or because they're going nuts on the job. By citing
family, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> neutralizes the stigma and efficiently blocks further
questions. No responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> will allege a firing if she can't prove it,
because that would risk a libel suit. Besides, only a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pit bull</ENAMEX> would continue
to tear into the flesh of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> that has rolled over on its back to signal
surrender.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the time-honored lie is to pair a new
interest in one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with a profound disgust for the system. Or to say that
you want to get back to the "real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vin Weber</ENAMEX> left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> rather than face the "vicious, negative, and highly
personal campaign" he saw looming. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber</ENAMEX> labors in the genial, positive,
and highly impersonal business of lobbying, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>. Then there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX>'s variation: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> he
announced that he would not seek <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because he wants to spend
more time on civil rights issues.

            (I fed the
family alibi to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> when I quit my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> job in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. I did, however, add that I had failed to acquire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and I hoped to
secure a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as soon as possible so we could spend more time
together.)

            
Another indemnifying exit strategy is to claim
that you're seeking "new opportunities," without naming them. This excuse
usually appears in the form of a corporate press release, because nobody can
keep a straight face when it's spoken out loud. In a more honest world, it
wouldn't be tacky for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> of industry to say they're leaving to pursue a
fully deployed golden parachute as they bail out.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who actually does quit to spend more time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> may discover
that paid work is almost always more rewarding than the "tedious work" of child
rearing. Or so says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlie Hochschild</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Time Bind: When Work Becomes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Becomes Work</ENAMEX> . The modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is like an assembly-line
factory, with an endless stream of clothes to clean and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX> and
broken windows to fix and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>. Why not escape the noise and the
pressure of being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superadult</ENAMEX> for the rewards of the workplace, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> are trained to understand you?

            Let's call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">bluff</ENAMEX> and see if he stays close to home
to nurture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suby</ENAMEX> or takes another demanding job. Of course, I'm betting on the
demanding job. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the farewell</TIMEX> tour of his legislative district, Paxon
indicated the depth of his enthusiasm in raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suby</ENAMEX> when he let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molinari</ENAMEX>
change the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">diaper</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> touched down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> His technique is
"too methodical and slow," she said.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, though, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Heseltine, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overseas Investment Trust</ENAMEX>, who resigned earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> in opposition to the business plan forced on him by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>.
Heseltine declined to enumerate his disagreements with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> but said:
"Put it this way, it's nothing to do with ill health, it's not to pursue other
interests, it's not to spend more time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
