
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Squeal</ENAMEX> or Deal?

            Suppose you're a convicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> with some juicy private information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. An aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> offers to purchase that information
with a lenient sentencing recommendation. Do you take the deal?

            If all
your motives are selfish, you'll probably first make some discreet inquiries to
determine whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is prepared to outbid the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>--say with
the promise of a full pardon.

            But suppose it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can't
risk granting a controversial pardon in the midst of the campaign. If you
choose to remain silent, you'll have to wait till after the election to collect
your reward. Do you dare wait that long?

            A lot depends on just how
juicy your information is. If you know enough to trigger an impeachment, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> won't dare cross you. You might as well sit tight, confident that
you'll get your freedom on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second Wednesday</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.

            On the
other hand, if the offenses you know about are embarrassing but short of
impeachable, you've got to make the best deal you can right away. Once the
election has passed, your leverage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will be severely limited.
You'd better call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>.

            
There's also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> hand: You might know
nothing at all. Then, assuming you can't get away with bogus accusations, your
only option is to serve your time in silence.

            Consider
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends of Bill</ENAMEX> who now await sentencing. At the moment I write this
(though not necessarily at the moment you read it), reports indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX> is negotiating with special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
McDougal adamantly refuses to cooperate. From those reports I conclude that if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> knows anything, she knows
a lot more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> does. Her silence means either that she knows nothing
or that she knows enough to extract a high price for her silence. If she knew a
middling amount, she'd be following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>'s lead.

            That analysis is an excursion into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of economics
called game theory--the study of strategic behavior. Unfortunately, game theory
is notorious for its ability to generate radically different conclusions in
response to small changes in the underlying assumptions. Thus I have only a
moderate degree of confidence in my deductions.

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of economics
yield far more reliable predictions, and the theory of competitive markets is
the most reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of all. So that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> we should climb out on if
we really want to use economics to get at the truth about the scandals
surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            I'm not
sure how to apply competitive-market theory to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, but fortunately
there is no lack of additional scandals to analyze. Take the case of the late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX>, who was accused of selling favors to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for a
price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX>. Those favors, involving arrangements for international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>, appear to have been worth many <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>. In
other words, if the stories are true, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> got a fabulous
bargain.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F ></ENAMEX>abulous bargains don't come along <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. When they do, it's
usually because of heavy competition among many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX> had been
the only administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> willing and able to sell out to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>, he could have extracted a price commensurate with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multimillion</ENAMEX>-dollar value of his product. So by selling out for a mere
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX>--if he really did--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> revealed his expectation that competitors
(presumably other high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> with the means to influence trade
policy) were prepared to undercut him.

            I don't
know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX> was guilty. But economic theory tells me that if the
charges against him were accurate, there must have been others in the
administration who shared his ethical laxity. Those others are presumably still
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. It might be worth an attempt to ferret them out.

            Similar reasoning could be useful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> who are
concerned with national security leaks. It would, for example, be interesting
to determine whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> case was an anomaly or a symptom of
widespread corruption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> sold information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> for a
price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.6 million</NUMEX>. As with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX>, we'd like to know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monopolist</ENAMEX> or one of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> in a competitive marketplace.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to
find the answer is to begin with a different question: How much was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX>'
information worth to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>? If it was worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only 4.6 million</NUMEX>, then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> were paying top dollar, indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> was the only willing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seller</ENAMEX>. That would be reassuring. If, on the other hand, the information was
worth many times <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.6 million</NUMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> sold cheap, suggesting that he was
forced to underbid a host of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. In that case, those
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> constitute an ongoing security risk.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to find out whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> has been
infiltrated by moles is to conduct elaborate investigations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and
institutional procedures. A much faster, cheaper, and more accurate way might
be to investigate whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX> offered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> a bargain.

            More generally, when someone
is behaving surreptitiously, we frequently have to guess what he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to</NUMEX>. We
can't hope to guess right all the time. But we can strive to make our
guesses consistent with all the evidence and with the basic laws of human
behavior. In that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, a little economic theory goes a long way.

         
      
   
