
   
   
      
         
            My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Trade Deficit</ENAMEX>

            To my vast delight, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Noble</ENAMEX> superstore has arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a mile</NUMEX> from my
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brighton</ENAMEX>. I shop at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> several
times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>--mostly for books, sometimes for music, occasionally for software,
and nearly always for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>.

            My trade deficit with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsford</ENAMEX> has grown explosively since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> arrived. In other
words, I spend more money in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsford</ENAMEX> than I did before. A trade deficit is
the amount you spend in a given place minus the amount you earn there. (A trade
surplus is just the opposite: The amount you earn in a given place minus the
amount you spend there.) I don't earn any income in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsford</ENAMEX>, so my trade
deficit is equal to the amount I spend.

             

            I've been thinking about trade deficits because I picked up
the local newspaper <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> and read an op-ed piece about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade
deficit with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. It says that, pre-NAFTA, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had a trade
surplus with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>--the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> than he
spent there. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Producing</ENAMEX> goods for sale to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> counts as "earning in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>"; buying goods made by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> counts as "spending in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.") Today
the opposite is true: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has a trade deficit with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, and
it's growing.

            According
to the op-ed piece, that's proof that the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> was better off
without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>. But the identical logic "proves" that I was better off without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>. Not only is the conclusion false, it's the exact opposite
of the truth. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take advantage of new opportunities to buy things
they want, it usually makes them happier.

            
The truth is that any change in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> position with respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>--in either direction--is evidence that
free trade has been good for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> got a job at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Noble</ENAMEX>. His trade surplus with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pittsford</ENAMEX> grew, just like my own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> deficit . In both cases, the changes meant that our lives had got
better.

            The same
analogy illustrates another point: Although NAFTA-induced changes in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> trade deficit are evidence of improvements, the actual
level of the trade deficit means virtually nothing. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX> had located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penfield</ENAMEX> instead of in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsford</ENAMEX>, I'd have a
higher trade deficit with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penfield</ENAMEX>, a lower trade deficit with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsford</ENAMEX>, and
my life would be about the same as it is now.

            Amore interesting number is my overall trade
deficit--the total of all my spending minus the total of all my earning. My
overall trade deficit was pretty high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: I spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600</NUMEX> on a living-room
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rug</ENAMEX>, and I earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0</NUMEX>. (It was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and I didn't feel like working.) My
overall trade deficit was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600</NUMEX>.

            Traditionally, business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> describe every increase in the overall trade deficit as a
"worsening." According to that tradition, I had a very bad day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. But
it didn't feel like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad day</TIMEX>--I like my new rug, and it would
have been inconvenient to put off buying it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> when I felt like
earning enough to pay for it.

            When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s overall trade deficit increases, it means that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, on average,
are spending more than they are earning. Maybe that's because your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
are behaving foolishly; maybe it's just because they have the good sense to
realize that you can sometimes spend more than you earn--provided you're
willing to draw down your savings.

            
In any event, foolishly excessive trade
surpluses are a greater danger than foolishly excessive trade
deficits . That's because excessive trade deficits are self-limiting: If
you run a trade deficit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, bankruptcy will eventually force you to
stop. But excessive trade surpluses can go on forever. A perpetual trade
surplus is likely to mean you're either working too hard or consuming too
little; either way, you're not getting enough enjoyment out of life.

            Here's the final thing you
should keep in mind when you read about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s overall trade deficit: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> is nothing but the sum of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. But there are limits to
how much you ought to care about what goes on in other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.
Even if you are convinced that the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> spends too much, or earns
too little, or spends too little, or earns too much, it's not entirely clear
why it's any of your business. As long you have your own household in order,
fretting about your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s spending habits is a lot like fretting about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> of his living-room rug. Maybe lime green was a big mistake, but it's
his mistake to live with.

         
      
   
