
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vote for Women</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, we're
told, is reckless. He was reckless with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> (in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> during
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>), with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> (just off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>), and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> (ditto, ditto, ditto). Heedless of the consequences, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> again and
again has followed, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Campbell</ENAMEX> used to say, his bliss.

            All this
may be true. But if it is, how do we reconcile it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior in
the political realm? There he has carried risk aversion to rarely reached
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heights</ENAMEX>. He will pay almost any price, in terms of policy, to marginally reduce
the chances of losing an election.

            To pick up some superfluous Slavic-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> votes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
decided to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, something virtually no policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> anywhere near him
on the ideological spectrum considered a good idea. To pick up some superfluous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuban-American</ENAMEX> votes, he signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms-Burton</ENAMEX> law, which predictably enraged
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, over in domestic policy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lodestar has been the focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            How can it
be that these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> identities--bold, reckless pursuer of bliss and timid,
desperate pursuer of office--exist in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?

            
There are to resolve this paradox. One is to
remember that the pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> can lead to bliss. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fondness
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monicas</ENAMEX> who are the perks of a job like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> keeps him from taking policy risks that might deprive him of the job.
Maybe his emulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s lifestyle is what keeps him from
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">abiding by Profiles in Courage</ENAMEX> .

            Come to
think of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> himself, though nominally the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of that book, didn't
glaringly exemplify its message of principle above politics. Hence, a general
theory: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> who obsessively convert power into sex are less willing to risk
power for principle.

            We can test this theory by using as our control group
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. For all we know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had a tryst or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>--but he can't hold a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">candle</ENAMEX> to the legends of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Try picturing him cavorting in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> pool with nude staff nymphs or confidently steering a beautiful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s hand southward.

            So does our theory hold? Did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s presumed freedom from sex addiction leave him free from addiction to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, no. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had more than a casual attraction to power is a fact
to which various convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> can attest. If we want
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">principled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, electing more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and fewer like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
wouldn't seem to be the ticket.

            On the
other hand, it might make sense to elect fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> generally. The point here
isn't just the well-known claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> by nature are more blindly libidinous
than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> corollary of that claim: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> by nature pursue
power more desperately than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do.

            
During evolution, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX>
point of male power--lots of sex, lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>--didn't compute for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, lots of sex didn't mean lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>. Power, to be
sure, brought other benefits to a female's genetic legacy, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> naturally
like having power. They just don't like it as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chimpanzees</ENAMEX>, our nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, are political <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. As the primatologist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frans de Waal</ENAMEX> has observed, male chimps "seem to live in a hierarchical world
with replaceable coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and a single permanent goal: power." For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">females</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, "coalitions withstand time." Thus a male
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chimp</ENAMEX>--call him Bill--might be making nice to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> internationalist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">friends</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and signing simian bills sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> the next. In
contrast, a female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimp</ENAMEX>--call her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Schroeder</ENAMEX>--would hew truer to her core
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>.

            So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> paradox--his reckless pursuit of sex
and his timid clinging to office--is indeed no paradox. The former does
seem to explain the latter. But only in a broad, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>-wide sense. The reason
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to put power above principle is because during human evolution, power led
to sex. This evolution-bred hunger for power is built into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> generally,
including those (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>) for whom translating power into sex is not a
high personal priority.

            The
solution is obvious: If you want elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who put principle ahead of
power, voting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> gives you better odds.

            
But do keep in mind that gender differences,
even fairly firm ones, are only aggregate differences. The average woman
will surrender less principle for power than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. And women
who become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are not average. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>,
certainly, was no stereotypical female. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> over a
few barren islands, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> prosecuted with the zeal of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>, has
been compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bald <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> fighting over a comb.)

            Still, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> may
have been more ambitious than the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, she was a paragon of
ideological fidelity compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>). Just as female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are more power-hungry than the average female, so also are male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> (even) more power-hungry than the average male. While admitting
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of my gender, I must add, on behalf of men
everywhere, that he's an especially egregious example.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> have argued that his alleged treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> is a
betrayal of the feminist values he professes. Maybe. But in another sense his
feminist credentials look better than ever. He has provided--indeed, he has
become--a potent argument for bringing more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you
missed our links in the story, click to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s evolutionary take on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can be and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) why .
            

         
      
   
