
   
   
      
         
            Let the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rabbi Split the Pie</ENAMEX>

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> dies, leaving more
debts than assets. How should the estate be divided among his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX>? Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sages</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylonian Talmud</ENAMEX> addressed this question
in a mysterious way--by offering a series of numerical examples with no hint of
the general underlying principle. According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, the
reasoning of the ancient rabbis is best understood in the light of modern
economic theory.

            Take a
concrete example. Suppose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> are owed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>,
respectively--a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600</NUMEX> in debts--but there is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $600</NUMEX> to
distribute. Who gets how much? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kethubot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">93a</ENAMEX>) makes the following
prescriptions:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) If there is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to
distribute, then everyone gets an equal share; that is, everyone gets
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33.33</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) If there is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> to
distribute, then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditor</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, while the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX>
each.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) If there is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> to
distribute, then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditor</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX>. (In this case, the payouts are proportional to the original
claims.)

            Where do these numbers come from, and how should we behave
if there is, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> to distribute? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX> does not tell us. But
certain patterns are evident. Apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbis</ENAMEX> reasoned that nobody can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> claim more than the value of the entire estate. Thus when the
estate contains <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $100</NUMEX>, the claims to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> are treated as
equal. When the estate contains <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $200</NUMEX>, the claims to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 and $300</NUMEX> are
treated as equal (but superior to the claim of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>).

            Another
clue can be found elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baba Metzia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2a</ENAMEX>): "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> hold a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">garment</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> claims all, the other claims <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. Then the one is awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/4</NUMEX>,
the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/4</NUMEX>." The rabbinical reasoning seems to have gone something like
this: "Both claim half the garment, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> claims the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. So
we'll split the disputed half equally and give the undisputed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> to its
undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>." Elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX>, the rabbis apply similar reasoning
to settle a case where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> claims all and the other claims a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.

            
Now we've stated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> principles: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, claims
cannot exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the estate, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, we should follow the
contested-garment rule. With these, we can prescribe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of any
bankrupt estate, provided there are just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX>. Here's an example:
Suppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">estate</ENAMEX> consists of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> claim <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 and $200</NUMEX>,
respectively. By the first principle, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> claim is immediately reduced to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX>. Now there is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> in dispute and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> undisputed. According to the
contested-garment principle, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> is divided equally. Therefore the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">claimant</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> claimant gets the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX>.

            But what
should we do when there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX>? According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Aumann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Maschler</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, we
can solve this problem by introducing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> more principle, which they call
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consistency</ENAMEX> . According to the consistency principle, any pair of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> must divide their collective share according to the principles we've
already enunciated. To see what consistency means in practice, think again
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> estate, to be divided among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> who claim <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX> awards <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>; thus the first
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> have a collective share of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX>. And this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> is divided between
them exactly as we prescribed in the preceding paragraph. So the Talmudic
prescription satisfies the consistency principle in this instance. It's not
hard to confirm the same would be true if you started with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and third
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second and third</TIMEX>.

            But wait! All we've done is checked that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> divided their collective share of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> appropriately; we haven't
explained why their collective share is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aumann</ENAMEX> and
Maschler have an answer: Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> other than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-75</NUMEX>-125 would be
inconsistent. (That is, with any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>, some pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> would
have its collective share divided incorrectly.) In fact, they have proved more
generally that every bankruptcy problem has exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> consistent
solution. Once you've found a consistent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>, you can be sure that no
other is possible.

            So perhaps
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmudists</ENAMEX> proceeded by trial and error, considering various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> and
rejecting each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> as inconsistent until they hit upon the unique consistent
division of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-75-125</NUMEX>. Or maybe they had a more systematic approach. Systematic
approaches are possible but a bit complicated. Click for an explanation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simplest</ENAMEX>.

            
Whatever method the rabbis used, they appear to
have used it--pardon the pun--consistently. It's not hard to check that
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmudic</ENAMEX> examples always satisfy the consistency principle. And
the consistency principle gives a complete explanation for each example, in the
sense that, in each case, only one consistent solution is possible, and we can
imagine that the rabbis kept trying until they found it. The consistency
principle is both universally applicable (because a consistent solution can
always be found) and universally unambiguous (because there is never more than
one consistent solution).

            Suppose,
for example, that an estate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> is to be divided among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> who claim
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>. A consistent solution is to award them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for help on seeing why this is consistent.) But from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aumann</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maschler</ENAMEX>'s work, we know that if you've found one consistent solution, you've
found them all. So this is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> that obeys all the
principles we've stated. Although the ancient rabbis failed to consider this
particular example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aumann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maschler</ENAMEX> express confidence that if they
had considered it, they would have endorsed this unique consistent
solution.

            Why is the consistent solution the right solution? Aumann
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maschler</ENAMEX> argue that consistency appeals to our intrinsic sense of fairness.
But, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Talmudic</ENAMEX> tradition, if you don't like that argument, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aumann</ENAMEX> and
Maschler have another.

            Imagine that all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> are put in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and told to agree among themselves on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX>; if they can't agree, nobody gets anything. Suppose also that any
creditor who is offered <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of his claim (by a consensus among the
others) is required to accept it and leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. What would the bargaining
process look like, and what would the outcome be?

            There is a
branch of economics called "bargaining theory" that attempts to answer such
questions; unfortunately, the answers turn out to depend rather heavily on
auxiliary assumptions. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aumann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maschler</ENAMEX> have proved that in the case of
the bankruptcy negotiation, it follows from reasonable assumptions that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> would eventually agree to divide the estate in accordance with the
consistency principle. Thus, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aumann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maschler</ENAMEX>, all the Talmudic
prescriptions coincide with what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> themselves would have agreed to,
given appropriate bargaining rules and sufficient time.

            
               If you missed the
systematic way to solve the bankruptcy problem, click . If you'd like to review
why the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225</NUMEX> distribution of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> estate is consistent,
.
            

         
      
   
