
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boycott Nike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two decades ago</TIMEX>, when I went
from a middle-class public high school to a fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, I
noticed an irony. The jumbo egos that now surrounded me were less conspicuous
than the garden-variety egos I'd previously dwelt among. In my new cultural
milieu, it was considered bad form to note that you'd made a good grade, or to
engage in any other obvious form of self-advertisement. Adjusting to this new
environment, I soon began to affect a fairly convincing air of humility.
(Sounds like an impressively deft adaptation, I know, but--really--it was
nothing.)

            The basic
principle here is that the higher the socioeconomic class, the less conspicuous
the self-promotion. "Less conspicuous" doesn't mean "less chronic," and it
certainly doesn't mean "less effective." On the contrary. What my college
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classmates</ENAMEX> knew is that, as a rule, less overt self-promotion is more
effective. Having an obviously high opinion of yourself threatens and alarms
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>, often to your ultimate detriment. All of which, I
contend, explains how ill-suited the ethos of inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> is to
economic advancement, and how big shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>, and
Converse make the problem worse.

            College <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al McGuire</ENAMEX> once said that, whereas
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> took white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and tried to get them to play black, he took
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and tried to get them to play white. He was alluding to a rarely
spoken but widely known truth: There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cultural styles of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>,
which we can conveniently label with the familiar code words "inner city" and
"suburban." In inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playgrounds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> is more conspicuously
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">egotistical</ENAMEX>. There is less passing to set up the open shot, more driving to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hoop</ENAMEX> and other forms of mano a mano confrontation. More showboating,
more trash talking. Vividly humiliating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> guarding you is highly
prized.

            One can argue about whether
this style of basketball reflects only the general tendency of lower-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to self-advertise conspicuously, as described above, or reflects also
the unique historical travails of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. (The latter, I'd say.) One
can even argue about whether the inner-city or the suburban style of play is
better basketball. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> cannot argue about which ethos is more conducive to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advancement</ENAMEX> in the wider world. Like it or not, the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy
is culturally suburban.

             

            
Try this thought experiment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> job candidates
sit before you. One is an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>. There are no visual cues to bias you--no tattoos, no purple hair, no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pantyhose</ENAMEX>. Just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>'s in-your-face attitude, complete with a sensibility
that perceives roughly all human behavior as a sign of disrespect. (Recall his
recent kicking of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> for sitting courtside, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>
always sit.) The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hakeem Olajuwon</ENAMEX>,
the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Rockets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> who, though black, is a stereotypically
"suburban" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>--selfless and humble, yet exuding quiet self-assurance on the
court and off. (Obviously, "inner-city" and "suburban" are ultimately cultural,
not racial, categories. Olajuwon twice won <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> championships with all-black
starting fives that had a suburban playing style. By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX>, a
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> of low-income origins, was a noted trash talker.)

            OK, faced
with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> and the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olajuwon</ENAMEX>, whom do you hire? Correct:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olajuwon</ENAMEX>. Ergo, who would be a better role model for poor black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>? Correct:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olajuwon</ENAMEX>. Now, which of the two has a big shoe-endorsement contract? Correct:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> (with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Converse</ENAMEX>).

            Aside from athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, nothing is more helpful in
getting you a big shoe contract than being an asshole. There are exceptions,
yes, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detroit Piston Grant Hill</ENAMEX>, who wears <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fila</ENAMEX> shoes. But the good-guy
shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">icons</ENAMEX> are vastly outnumbered by the likes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Supersonics</ENAMEX>' of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Payton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn Kemp</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scottie Pippen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> 76er <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Iverson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iverson</ENAMEX> has done jail time and is
famous for employing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> in awe-inspiring ways that do his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> little
good. And humility is not his specialty. When he won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rookie of the Year</ENAMEX>
Award <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, he said: "I thought the award should go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who had
the biggest impact. I know we only won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> games [out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82</NUMEX>] but if you look at
impact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> as a rookie, I thought I had the greatest impact." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>,
enchanted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iverson</ENAMEX>'s charisma, has designed a new shoe in his honor.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> is
fast displacing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX> of the shoe world. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> sponsors, and
thus elevates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaquille O'Neal</ENAMEX>, a huge mass of self-absorption whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iverson</ENAMEX>'s, seldom fulfill expectations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Neal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> just got blown out
of the playoffs by perhaps the most suburban (and ethnically whitest) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Utah Jazz</ENAMEX>--whose black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Malone</ENAMEX>, is another good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who gets dissed by the shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Neal</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iverson</ENAMEX>, in the average job interview.

            
Obviously, it's easy for me to complain about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who aren't big on self-effacement or deference to authority. My
ancestors weren't slaves. I didn't spend my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> being viewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cops</ENAMEX> as a likely shoplifter. Maybe in that sense, the behavior of the Pippens
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iversons</ENAMEX> of the world is defensible. But when that behavior is in some
small way helping to keep young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> trapped in poverty, defending it is not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> thing to do. Certainly celebrating it isn't. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>, beyond a
point, defending it is patronizing.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike CEO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Knight</ENAMEX> likes to pose as capitalism with a human face, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> devoted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. Witness <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>'s ostentatious donation to the legal-defense
fund of blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skater</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonya Harding</ENAMEX>. (Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> doesn't make
ice-skating equipment, that's the closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Knight</ENAMEX> could come to subsidizing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sport</ENAMEX>'s biggest asshole.) Well, let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> truly put his money where his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mouth</ENAMEX> is. Pick a great basketball role model, put him on a pedestal, and let
the financial chips fall where they may. (No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> as a great role
model.)

            Abit of genuine morality at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Converse</ENAMEX>)
needn't be vastly expensive. Surely <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> has enough brains to make a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hakeem</ENAMEX> ad--or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Drexler</ENAMEX> ad, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> ad--that appeals to inner-city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Remember, I'm not asking for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Say No</ENAMEX>" ads or any other form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moralism</ENAMEX>. Those don't work anyway. On the contrary, I'm asking for ads that
make their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> look cool, thus boosting the prominence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> who, in
their on-court conduct and post-game interviews, are good influences. And I'm
asking that a shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s elevation of someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iverson</ENAMEX> become a source
of stigma among socially conscious shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. Let's have a real boycott!

            Which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to boycott? A
tough call, since no shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with a big-name hoops line is wholly without
blame. For now, is that we start with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> and let <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Converse</ENAMEX> off with
a stern warning, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX> is its first major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>. And remember:
We're boycotting not just hoops shoes, but running shoes, hiking boots,
sweatpants, socks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> logos are now officially declared badges
of shame. Of course, it will be hard, with those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> dominating the
shelf space of every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foot Locker</ENAMEX>, to sniff out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saucony, Asics, Fila</ENAMEX>, or
New Balance. But go ahead. Just do it.

             

         
      
   
