
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gays</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>

            "This is tough news. It's
not pleasant to hear," said former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week Nov. 9</TIMEX>. "But it's very important, and it's part of telling the
truth." The occasion for tough-but-needed truth telling: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
first-ever presidential speech to an organized gay-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX>
Rights Campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had conferred respectability--wrongly--on the gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quest</ENAMEX> for approval when in fact, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, he "should tell the truth on
this one": Homosexuality "takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> off your life." The average life
expectancy for gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> declared, was just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>.

            Many a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s heart around
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> must have sunk at that moment amid premonitions that she would
outlive her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. A well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> figure would think twice before delivering
tidings that grim, right? And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s statistic was no slip. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only days later</TIMEX>,
in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 24</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , he repeated the assertion phrased for
maximum emphasis:

            "The best
available research suggests that the average life span of male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> is
around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43 years of age</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forty-three</ENAMEX> ." (Italics his.)

            Yes, it's a sensational, arresting number, which may soon
pass into general circulation. Already, for example, the National

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> has repeated it unskeptically in an editorial. Where did the
figure come from, and how plausible is it?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bennett</ENAMEX>
got the number from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Cameron</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> well known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of gay
controversies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>, a former assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> who has consulted for such gay-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> as former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
Dannemeyer, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, heads a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Institute</ENAMEX>.
later formally terminated from membership following complaints about his
research methods. He has had run-ins with other professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska Psychological Association</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sociological</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Pietrzyk</ENAMEX>'s exposé in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3, 1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> initially hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> as an expert
witness to defend its statute restricting gay-rights ordinances, then elected
not to use his testimony after it got a closer look. His life-span figures have
circulated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in religious-right circles, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s comments appear
to represent their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real breakout into wider public discussion.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>'s method had the virtue of simplicity,
at least. He and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-authors</ENAMEX> read through back numbers of various urban gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, mostly of the giveaway sort that are laden with bar ads and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personals</ENAMEX>. They counted up obituaries and news stories about deaths, noted the
ages of the deceased, computed the average, and published the resulting numbers
as estimates of gay life expectancy.

            What do vital-statistics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> think of this technique? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Eberstadt</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> sums up the reactions of several of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demographers</ENAMEX>: "The
method as you describe it is just ridiculous." But you don't have to be a
trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statistician</ENAMEX> to spot the fallacy at its heart, which is, to quote
"you're only getting the ages of those who die." Gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of the same generation
destined to live to old age, even if more numerous, won't turn up in the
sample.

            Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> rattle off further objections. The deaths reported in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>,
mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> deaths, will tend to represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> defined by such papers
or directly known to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. It will include relatively more subjects
who live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and are overtly gay and relatively few who blend into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suburbs</ENAMEX> and seldom set foot in bars. It will overrepresent those whose passing
strikes others as newsworthy and underrepresent those who end their days in
retired obscurity in some sunny clime.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is a busy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but even he has access to the back
of an envelope. A moment's thought might have suggested a few simple test
calculations. Suppose he assumes--wildly pessimistically, given current
incidence data--that half the gay male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is destined to catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
virus and die of it. The actual average age of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at death has been
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Presumably</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protease inhibitors</ENAMEX> will extend average longevity, but
that will only increase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s difficulty.) For the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> to be the true
average death age for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-negative gay men
would, on average, have to keel into their graves at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>. Looked at another way,
if even half the gay male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> stays <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-negative and lives to an average
age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>, an average overall life span of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> implies that gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
die at an implausibly early average age (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>, actually).

            Against
this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> argue that, according to their survey of
obits, even if they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual males</ENAMEX> tend to die by
their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-40s</TIMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late 40s</TIMEX>). Some downright peculiar results
followed from this inference. One is that--contrary to the opinion of virtually
everyone else in the world--<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in fact hasn't reduced gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>' life
expectancy by that much--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>, at most. Moreover, the obits also
recorded lots of violent and accidental deaths. From this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> and company
concluded not that newsworthy deaths tend to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>
must experience shockingly high rates of violent death. With a perfectly
straight face they report, for example, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 300</NUMEX> times
more likely to die in car crashes than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> of similar ages in general.

            
Unfortunately there really is no satisfactory
measure of actual life expectancy among gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, the
he's unaware of evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> have a lower life expectancy
than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX> also points to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason to think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-negative
gay male may actually live longer on average than the straight male: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gays</ENAMEX> may
have higher incomes and more education on average than straights--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> factors
powerfully correlated with longer life spans. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> himself appears to share
this view, terming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, "as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, wealthy and well educated.")

            Challenged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX>
Rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Birch</ENAMEX> in the letters column of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, remarkably, dug in to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> numbers,
which he said coincided with the views of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satinover</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Homosexuality and the Politics of</ENAMEX>
Truth , does discuss gay life spans, but cites as its authority ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>'s study. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is not adducing a second authority for
his assertions but merely falling back on the first via its recycling by
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.

            Throughout the controversy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> has made much of the cause of "truth" with a capital T. His
Standard article, portentously titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gays</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>,"
accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> of scanting that important commodity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is right
to the extent that there's no excuse for telling falsehoods in the course of
raising otherwise legitimate issues. He should mind his own lesson.

         
      
   
