
   
   
      
         
            Smack Happy

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the press
reprised one of its favorite stories: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heroin</ENAMEX> is back. The news hook was the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12</TIMEX> death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smashing Pumpkins</ENAMEX> side man <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Melvoin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>, while
shooting scag in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> obit
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melvoin</ENAMEX> claimed--without substantiation--"a resurgence in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> use in the
'90s," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> asserted that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin vogue</ENAMEX> has been
building since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 1993</TIMEX> and shows no signs of ebbing."
Trainspotting , the new movie about young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX>, provided
another useful occasion for noting this alleged trend.

            "Smack
Is Back"? For the press, smack is always back. It never goes away, but
it's always returning. Boarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX> wayback machine, we find that nearly
every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has sounded the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin clarion</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Latest Drug of Choice for Abusers Brings New</ENAMEX>
Generation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heroin</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Return</ENAMEX>
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deadly Drug Called Horse</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heroin Making a Resurgence</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heroin Is Making Comeback</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin Comes Back</ENAMEX>,"
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"As Cocaine Comes off a High</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heroin May</ENAMEX>
Be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Filling Void</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Plain Dealer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Police</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fear Heroin 'Epidemic</ENAMEX>,' " <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin: Back on</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charts</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Times</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin People: Deadly Drug Back</ENAMEX>
in Demand," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin Makes Comeback</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>);
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin Makes an Ominous Comeback</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trenton</ENAMEX>
Record ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Heroin Comeback</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Smack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabbling</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin Finds a New Market Along</ENAMEX>
Cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edge of Style</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smack</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>); the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo News</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"More Dopes Picking Heroin</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Sentinel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin Makes a Comeback</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>); the
Times-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picayune</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin Is Back</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major Problem</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>); the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazette</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"State Gets Deadly Dose as Heroin Reappears</ENAMEX>,"
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> again (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>); and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Heroin's New Popularity Claims Unlikely Victims</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>).

            The granddaddy of the genre appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years ago</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Middle-Class Junkies</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 10, 1981</TIMEX>), with language that
reads as fresh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as it did then. We learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> has breached its
ghetto quarantine: "[C]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hildren</ENAMEX> of affluence are venturing where once the poor
and desperate nodded out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is being retailed at rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lunch-time crowds</ENAMEX> in predominately white business
districts." As always, part of the problem is a glut of white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]heer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abundance</ENAMEX> is prompting concern about a potential 'epidemic' spilling across
demographic divides." And <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin purity</ENAMEX> is increasing dramatically: "Purity
levels <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as high as 90 percent</NUMEX> have been found in seized wholesale caches, with
street-level purities averaging <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 20 percent</NUMEX>--around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times the typical
strength of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> blend."

            Having hit <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, you wouldn't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin purity</ENAMEX> could keep rising. But for the
press, it has. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's story about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melvoin</ENAMEX> reported that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin purity</ENAMEX> has risen from "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as low as 4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decades</TIMEX> to upward of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' piece noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>
had gone "from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">purity</ENAMEX>] in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>." After Melvoin
died, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> he shot was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> pure.

            
Depending on where you drop the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX> plumb line you can find references to
more potent street <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> in the recent past. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
story pegged the potency of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> placed average purity at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent to 40 percent</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
Times story from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Enforcement Administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> who
said that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> was typically <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent to 30 percent</NUMEX> pure, but
that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> seized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX> was now topping the scales at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 percent</NUMEX>
pure. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> government study puts purity at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59 percent</NUMEX>, so if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right a few years ago</TIMEX>, recent purity actually has declined somewhat.

            There is good evidence that potency isn't the most
significant risk factor in overdose deaths. A study of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin overdoses</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, the findings of which were published by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forensic Sciences</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), found no relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin purity</ENAMEX> and
death<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-overdose</NUMEX> or nonfatal overdose. (On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvoin</ENAMEX> shot that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> and died, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pumpkins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Chamberlin</ENAMEX> shot the same
junk and survived.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> attributed most overdoses to intermittent
or post-addiction use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>--meaning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who OD'd tended to
misjudge tolerance when returning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. Another risk factor that never
gets enough ink in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is the danger of using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> in
combination with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. The mixture has an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX> effect: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drinker</ENAMEX> could
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spike</ENAMEX> himself with a lower-than-lethal dose and still OD.

            What do we really know
about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> use? For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Drug Control</ENAMEX>
Strategy for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict population</ENAMEX> is basically stable. It
reports that the number of "casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than weekly</TIMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> came
down by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1988 and 1993</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">539,000 to 229,000</NUMEX>), the most recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> measured, while the number of "heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least weekly</TIMEX>) dipped from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">601,000 to 500,000</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> statistic feeding the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> "revival" stories is the
increasing number of emergency-room visits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who mention <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> as a
reason for seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> treatment. But the statistics, which come from the
government's latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Abuse Warning Network</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAWN</ENAMEX>) survey, come with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disclaimer</ENAMEX> suggesting that the explanation may be multiple visits by aging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">druggies</ENAMEX> who are using the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> for a variety of health problems.

            My bet is that when the
medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiner</ENAMEX> releases his report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Melvoin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, it will
disclose that the smashed pumpkin was drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> while shooting, a fatal
error that pre-'50s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> almost never made. We'll learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melvoin</ENAMEX>--like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>--was an amateur who didn't really know what he was doing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>.

            
               What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hell Are</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flame Posies</ENAMEX>"?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Heaney</ENAMEX>'s poem
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
Canticles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asturias</ENAMEX>, which appeared in the debut issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>, contains
a mesmerizing image of a "smouldering <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">maw</ENAMEX>/ of a pile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> lit long
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>," fanning "up in the wind, breaking off and away/ in flame-posies, small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airborne</ENAMEX> fire-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heaney</ENAMEX>'s verse reminded me that everything--even awful
newspaper stories--is beautiful when it burns. Such was the inspiration that I
embraced "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flame Posies</ENAMEX>" as the name for my occasional column on the press. I
also hope that the oxymoron will remind me to include applause as well as
condemnation in my dispatches.

            
               Illustrations by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Neubecker
            

         
      
   
