
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Katz</ENAMEX> has
achieved the impossible: He's recast some of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most fortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in a cultural civil war.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are self-appointed,
not made, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX> is no exception. After a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journeyman</ENAMEX>'s career as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and several other big city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dailies</ENAMEX>, he made his first electronic news as the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> 
               Morning 
               News in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>. There, he says, he
"was run out of journalism" and turned free-lance media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. His first
(belated) taste of cyberspace came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, when he connected to the WELL, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX> bulletin-board system. "I'd come home," he writes, and join the
"raging debates about media, religion, politics, and the cyberculture."

            Plying his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>-crit trade
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , he eventually joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired</ENAMEX>
and its Web sibling, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HotWired</ENAMEX> , becoming "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Rant</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netizen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1996</TIMEX>. He struck an instant pose as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">troubadour</ENAMEX> and great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX>, simultaneously promoting it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> and
protecting it from arrivistes like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, which launched <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX>
later. The persona worked. He quickly became one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s signature voices,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Garroway</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Berle</ENAMEX> who defined the nascent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> for most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--inside and outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Webworld</ENAMEX>. Brainy, quick to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and
flame them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX> indulged the clannishness of the Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> who swarmed to
the site. And they indulged him, answering and amplifying his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">provocations</ENAMEX>--call-and-response style--in threaded discussions linked to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rant</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX>'s
adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>--Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>, rap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, violent-film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX>,
pint-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Super</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX>, Web-porn peddlers, and TV-talk-show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>--make for unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. Who can shed tears for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> who are blessed
with smarts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, leisure time, and moxie, and who own <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">$2,000</NUMEX>-plus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentium</ENAMEX> computers? If any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has a right to consider itself vulnerable in
these cybertimes, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s computer illiterates, who stand in awe of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katz Corps</ENAMEX>.

            But in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX>'s world, cybernauts are oppressed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> by "The
Mediaphobes," the old-media-worshipping, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Judeo-Christian</ENAMEX>-ethics-preaching,
backward-facing "windbags and pious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who presume to know what is moral for
you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." They despise the fact that you now get your news directly
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usenet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, untainted by effete <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>; they fume
because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> speak directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>
Live and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>; they are furious because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play interactive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> games
instead of passively watching television cartoons.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Da Man</ENAMEX> may jam Ice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>'s signal, he's been extraordinarily good to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> have just published his new book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Virtuous Reality: How America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Surrendered Discussion of Moral Values to Opportunists</ENAMEX>, Nitwits 
               &
Blockheads Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> --and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> at the New York
Times excerpted it in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts and Leisure</ENAMEX>" section.

            "Their
loss of control has been jarring to our traditional media and political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, who had sat astride a tight monopoly over politics and news,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX> writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Virtuous Reality</ENAMEX> . "They fought back and have been
fighting ever since, complaining that these new interactive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are dangerous
and destructive of public discourse. New <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have brought with them enormous
cultural displacement--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> who controlled most of our information flow have all been, to varying
degrees, pushed aside. They don't like it."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX>'s fury against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mediaphobes</ENAMEX> is
impressive; yet, only rarely does he name those conspiring to deny him and his
cyberweeny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> their maximum media liberty. (He insinuates on many pages
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Media</ENAMEX> suffer from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mediaphobia</ENAMEX>, but he mostly leaves them off the
hook.) At the top of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">short</ENAMEX> hate list resides popular scold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s books on "virtues" sell well. But how effective a censor is he? Well,
he did succeed in coercing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> into selling its interest in the
gangsta-rap heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Interscope</ENAMEX> label--only to see the label and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
thrive under the patronage of its new co-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owners MCA</ENAMEX>. Also infected with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mediaphobia</ENAMEX> is the opportunistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> who passed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>, knowing full well that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supremes</ENAMEX> will overturn
it. And don't forget <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX>. During her brief and brilliant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'80s</TIMEX>
career in rock 'n' roll <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comstockery</ENAMEX>, she convinced some labels to affix
"voluntary" warning labels to mature material--a ratings system that many
younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> embraced as a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Housekeeping Seal of Approval</ENAMEX>.
Today, she's a ribbon-cutting <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who avoids controversy. Oh, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> cried wolf about the prevalence of porn on the Net.

            Some
cultural civil war.

            If there is a cultural civil war going on, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mediaphiles</ENAMEX>--led by Wall Street--have routed the 'phobes. Big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> has
wagered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of billions of dollars</NUMEX> on the development of high-tech,
low-cost media technology--broadband services, satellites, encryption
technology, miniaturized computers and communications devices, you name
it--that is largely impervious to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bennetts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> of this world.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX>'s war
is won, but declaring victory and resting his vocal chords would mean giving up
his career as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremiah</ENAMEX> of cyberspace and finding a new hustle. Still,
commercial calculation isn't sufficient to explain his stand. He identifies so
deeply with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> he has invented, the aggrieved Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> and
the chastised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, that he's become one of them. Lest one think
I'm exaggerating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">martyr complex</ENAMEX>, check out <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Virtuous Reality</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 7</ENAMEX>, in which he chronicles the life and times of another political rebel
who embraced a new technology to speak truth to power and suffered greatly for
it: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Paine</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz-equals-Paine</ENAMEX> is an awful stretch, but his
book invites the comparison. Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katz</ENAMEX> better resembles that other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iconoclastic 1990s</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>, the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>. Not to
imply that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX> would threaten murder to get published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : To the best of my knowledge, he hasn't maimed or killed anyone except
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suburban Detective Mystery" series-- Death by Station</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wagon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Housewife , The Father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> , and The
Family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stalker</ENAMEX> . But, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX> is driven frothy by a world
that won't conform to his expectations. Consider the parallels:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX> brooded alone
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>, limiting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> to the outside world to letters and books
obtained through the interlibrary loan systems. He stands accused of authoring
an impenetrable screed titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Industrial Society and Its Future</ENAMEX> , and of
building bombs.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Katz</ENAMEX> broods in the
isolation of his suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement office</ENAMEX>, apparently limiting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> to
the outside world to e-mail from other self-pitying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>: He composed his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manifesto</ENAMEX>, that impenetrable screed called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Virtuous Reality</ENAMEX>. I
hope it bombs.

            Not
really. I wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtuous Reality</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX> great success, because he
deserves it. Wrapped tightly in his Web cocoon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Netizen of the Church</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyberspace</ENAMEX> suffers <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of his new media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>: the
timorous who prefer the Internet to the terror of face-to-face contact; the
paranoid who extrapolate "the world is out to get me" conspiracies from the
detritus of politics; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Game Boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>; phone phreaks; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> down at the Smut
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shack</ENAMEX>; and the teeming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> whose idea of a reality check is consulting a
Web address.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX>'s basement sounds like a clammy and frightening place
to work, but it's not the scariest place he knows, as he confided to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> magazine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX> in a piece about his suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of
Montclair, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            "[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Montclair</ENAMEX>] is a place where
I'm totally comfortable walking my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>--which I do
all the time," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX> said. "But I'm far too frightened to go to a schoolboard
meeting."

         
      
   
