
   
   
      
         
            Glass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houses</ENAMEX>

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, there's a bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBL</ENAMEX> who
keeps a hand-held urinal at his desk so he never misses a market turn. And
according to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times of London</ENAMEX>,
the booming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> novelty market includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> items, such as
"Monicondoms" (designed for oral sex), talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> dolls, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
birthday cards ("I'll blow out your candle!").

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
stories, both false--cribbed from articles by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX> in the New

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> . Glass was fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reporter</ENAMEX> alerted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Lane</ENAMEX> that an article about a
teen-age computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Hack Heaven</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18</TIMEX>) was full of fabrications, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane</ENAMEX>'s own investigation confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> had made things up wholesale in
many New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> pieces. (The details are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Tool</ENAMEX>.)

            Checking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexis-Nexis</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> mentioned in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>' articles, you do not come up empty-handed.
Although there are often no references before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> published his fantasies,
there are often references afterward . These are generally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>--or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in places to which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> brought the benefits
of advanced civilization, such as hack journalism.

            Between
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nexis</ENAMEX>, and the good old telephone, it took little effort to discredit
such apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> inventions as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Memorabilia Convention</ENAMEX>,
Monicondoms, or the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBL</ENAMEX>. Other untraceable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriotic</ENAMEX> Profits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.J. Hozell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>
Tyo, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Climate Lookout, Truth in Science</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association for the Advancement of</ENAMEX>
Sound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Policy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sackman</ENAMEX>, Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked Truth</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Hogin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Zubitsky</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt-O-Meter</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Herbert Walker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> for the Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Integrity</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Tellis</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tellis Times</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restore the Presidency</ENAMEX> to
Greatness.

            
Listed here, it all seems transparently bogus
or at least deeply suspicious. Yet I'm embarrassed to confess that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>
story passed my stink test when first published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> .
Now, plowing through the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nexis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dump</ENAMEX>, my hindsight is golden. Glass moved
monumental piles of bullshit past me, a vain skeptic. I shouldn't have believed
his story about the alleged sex orgy staged by of a bunch of pot-smoking young
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> convention. It's just too good to be true. And why
weren't my suspicions aroused after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> pieces
discovering bizarre cults centered on implausible political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>? First, he
documented the adoration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX> by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>," an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> with no last name. Then he discovered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Herbert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker Christ</ENAMEX>. Finally, he stumbled upon an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan Shrine</ENAMEX> at an
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.

            I can't
say why the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> failed to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> did.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX> declined to answer my questions. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York PR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> called with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s regrets.) Glass could not be reached for
comment. But I can speculate about my own failure to see what seems so clear in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hindsight</ENAMEX>.

            One explanation is that factoids such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bondsman</ENAMEX>'s
portable urinal, which seem starkly implausible when presented alone, are less
so when woven in with easier-to-believe fictions. Glass skillfully eases you in
by "reporting" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> serve bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> lunch at their desks and do
their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas shopping</TIMEX> for them. Like the famous frog, you would jump out if
dropped in boiling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> to death in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that heated up
gradually.

            Another
partial explanation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> built up credibility as each story was
published and went unchallenged. You figured that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBL</ENAMEX> didn't have a bond
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> with a urinal on his desk, someone from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBL</ENAMEX> would call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">bluff</ENAMEX>. What you didn't figure is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> would make up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBL</ENAMEX> itself. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> in his stories didn't complain about the falsehoods for the simple
reason that they often didn't exist.

            
But the main reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> spoofed everybody's
radar is that his stories were, in the self-mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' phrase "too
good to check." As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, not his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, it was not my job to check them.
But I didn't even bring my usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s skepticism to reading them, because I
wanted them to be true.

            The
Glassworks contain what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> crave--stories with energy and imagination and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">originality</ENAMEX>. The filigree of detail dazzles. Some of his better pieces read
like textbook examples of New Journalism, fusing the world of fact with the
literary power of narrative. He doesn't just write about teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>, he
tracks a pimply <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the species down to his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where a
software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is signing him to a contract. He interviews the adoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
No wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s failed to snoot out the stink factor and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assigned</ENAMEX> pieces to him. (
                  Slate
                published a piece co-authored by
Glass <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. See "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme</ENAMEX>" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s comment.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colleagues</ENAMEX> describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> as an extraordinarily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hard-working</ENAMEX> and personable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> who gladly pulled all-nighters to
improve his pieces whenever his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> asked him to. He was completely open to
criticism. He regularly entertained the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at editorial meetings with
previews of the dish to come in his next piece. It's a testimony to his energy
that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> questioned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker</ENAMEX> piece, he erected a Web site to prove
the existence of a nonexistent software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. A layabout would simply have
written a true story. When you like somebody, you tend to trust him. (Let this
be a lesson to us all.)

            But where
were the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> 's fact checkers? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> does have a
fact checking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. It was established following <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">staffer Ruth Shalit</ENAMEX>'s serial plagiarisms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in charge of setting it
up? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX>. That is ironic, of course, but the joke is not on the
New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> . It's on the conceit of fact checking in
general.

            
No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> is safe from a trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
who makes things up. And hindsight is easy. That said, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> can make
scamming its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> more difficult than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> made it for
Glass. Giving young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> unimpeded access to anonymous quotations is like
handing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> a loaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years ago</TIMEX>, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-lancer</ENAMEX> submitted a
story to me about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> that was filled with anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. I asked
for their names. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> doesn't tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bradlee</ENAMEX> who his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are!"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> objected. "Well, you're not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>, and I'm not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bradlee</ENAMEX>,"
I responded. As he coughed up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> he sheared the sharper edges off his
story. I never used him again.

            The conventional wisdom in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> is that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> who crack up deserve
sympathy because the system pressures them into becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> before they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journeymen</ENAMEX>. Please. This explanation exonerates dishonest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> while
providing protective cover for careless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. If there's any moral to be
taken from this story, it should be "No more excuses."

            One final clue should have
alerted us--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>' deception: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> is not so good that
it places <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> at the center of action as frequently as it did the young
Glass. And he wrote so well. Anyone can doubt a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. It's the good ones
who need watching.

         
      
   
