
   
   
      
         
            Highbrow Tribalism

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign-policy
circles, everyone is waiting for the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X. "X"</ENAMEX> was the byline on the famous
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> essay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX> , actually written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Kennan</ENAMEX>, that
analyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> communism and laid out the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX> policy of
"containment." Where is a comparably compelling vision of the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
world, a new lodestar for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy? Who is the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennan</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Huntington</ENAMEX> has a suggestion: How
about him?

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civilizations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remaking of World Order</ENAMEX> is now hitting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bookstores</ENAMEX>. The jacket copy says that the germ of the book--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX> essay "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Clash of Civilizations?</ENAMEX>"--drew more
discussion than any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX> piece since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennan's</ENAMEX> (at least,
"according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of that distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>"). Blurbs from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brzenzinski</ENAMEX> (effusive) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> (guarded) reinforce the air of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eminence</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>'s book is devoted to a currently ubiquitous theme: tribalism. In
politics, the tribal theme shows up in the rhetoric of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir</ENAMEX>
Zhirinovsky, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Marie Le Pen</ENAMEX>, and so on. In the intellectual world, the
tribal theme shows up in treatises about the importance of the sentiments
aroused by such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Now that the bipolar order of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> is gone, we're
told, the primal bonds of ethnicity, language, and religion will be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">central</ENAMEX>--if not the central--organizing principle in world affairs. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Huntington</ENAMEX>
carries this idea to new heights of theoretical elaboration. Surely tribalism
has never sounded so cerebral. But it's one thing to analyze a phenomenon and
another thing to encourage it. Huntington crosses the line so easily as to make
you wonder: How different, really, are the lowbrow and highbrow expressions of
the vogue for tribalism?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> essay was, by design, a downer. The end
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> had inspired such upbeat visions as the inexorable triumph of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">liberal</ENAMEX> democracy (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Fukuyama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End of History</ENAMEX> ) and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New</ENAMEX>
World Order" (global peace mediated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huntington</ENAMEX> insisted
we recork the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>. The world would remain strife-torn, he said, only now
the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> would be not ideological blocs or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpowers</ENAMEX>,
but distinct "civilizations"--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic, Confucian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>,
Slavic-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>. (In the book, he adds a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ninth</ENAMEX> civilization, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>.) "Civilizations are the ultimate human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>,
and the clash of civilizations is tribal conflict on a global scale," he writes
in the book. Relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> from different civilizations will be
"almost never close" and "often hostile"--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> and friendship will be rare."
Wars will tend to break out along civilizational "fault lines" and will tend to
expand along the same lines.

            How should we respond to this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tribalism</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribally</ENAMEX>. The very "survival of the West" depends on Westerners
"uniting to renew and preserve" their civilization "against challenges from
non-Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>." Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> should abandon efforts to mesh with its
local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milieu</ENAMEX> and instead should join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should
de-emphasize engagement with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and turn back toward <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            How exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosis</ENAMEX> (perilously deep fault lines) leads to his prescription (further
deepen the fault lines) is a puzzle to which we'll return. But first, a word
about the diagnosis. Does his notion of "civilizations" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> writ large
make sense?

            Back in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> said no, and this book is unlikely to change their
minds. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> has renamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confucian</ENAMEX>" civilization "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinic</ENAMEX>,"
but that doesn't tidy up the concept. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> are very motley and definitely not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. In fact, the
thriving capitalist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> seem to blatantly
violate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>'s logic, showing how fast cultures can switch orientations
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> "civilization" to another. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> not only sees hidden
coherence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sinic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX>; he sees the bloc as part of an even larger
threat--the "Confucian-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> connection." This consists of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> "cooperating" with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> to
thwart the West on such issues as arms proliferation. But the grab bag of
national policies that supposedly add up to this grand transnational
"connection" doesn't even include most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sinic</ENAMEX> or most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. If we
wanted to use one variable to predict whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is involved in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntingon</ENAMEX>'s Sinic-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> "connection," we'd be better off knowing whether it's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorships</ENAMEX> than knowing whether it's one
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sinic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> predictive power vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>).

            
I could , as others have, about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">civilizational</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paradigm</ENAMEX>'s lack of analytical elegance. But that's not what
really bothers me. Though ancestral cultures aren't the mystical epoxy that
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Huntington imagines</ENAMEX>, language, religion, and other aspects of cultural heritage
do matter a lot in the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War world</ENAMEX>. The "civilizations" part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>'s thesis is less troubling than the "clash" part. Why is it an
inherent property of intercivilizational relations that they be "usually cool"
and "often hostile"? Why, for example, must Western relations with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sinic</ENAMEX> bloc
be typically tense? Obviously, current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> relations are
pretty tense. But why can't this change with, say, a new, more cosmopolitan,
regime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, or firmer and more consistent diplomatic signals from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>?

            It isn't enough to say, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huntington</ENAMEX> does, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sinic</ENAMEX> civilization lacks the West's bent for democracy.
The cliché that democracy hobbles the conduct of a coherent foreign policy is
true. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are freed from the burden of domestic pandering, they
should be able to calmly find their zones of common interest with the West and
cut the appropriate deals. So why does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> think we can't do business
with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>? Are only Westerners capable of perceiving their rational
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-interest</ENAMEX> and acting on it? Are only Westerners reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX>?

            Sometimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Huntington</ENAMEX> seems to think so. After criticizing naive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> attempts at
"constructive engagement" and "dialogue" across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, he writes, "To the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concessions</ENAMEX> are not to be reciprocated, they are to be
exploited." Ah, yes, those wily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> couldn't have said it
better. (Here, again, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> conflates with other explanatory
variables.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>--claims not to be a cultural
supremacist: He is defending the integrity of all cultures, theirs and ours.
Indeed, he sounds almost like a lefty relativist when he says we must accept
"global multiculturality" and discard the "linear" view of history, which sees
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> values as the inexorable fate of humankind. But of course, that's just
another way of saying that liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>--a value <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> surely ranks
above the alternatives morally--may never fit some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> as naturally as it
fits us. In this light the meaning of his call to "maintain the
multicivilizational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of global politics" seems clear: separate but
equal. You let one alien <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> move into your trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX>, and pretty soon the
whole neighborhood goes downhill. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX> already, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> worries, the West is
suffering "decline" and "decay.")

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbarians</ENAMEX>, in short, are
at the gate--and conspiring against us. The future, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> says, may boil
down to "the West against the rest." Raise the drawbridges!

            And yet,
toward the end of this book, just when I was about to file <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Huntington</ENAMEX> in the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>" section of my brain, he underwent a miraculous transformation.
Up until this point he has been ignoring or downplaying the interdependence
among modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. He doesn't seem to think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> reliance on Western
markets, say, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s thirst for Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, can help keep
trans-Pacific relations smooth. And God knows he doesn't waste time talking
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> environmental problems soluble only by international cooperation. On the
contrary, hovering like white noise throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 1993</TIMEX> essay, and through much
of this book, is the that international relations are typically zero-sum, so
that "natural conflicts of interest" dominate world affairs.

            
But then, in the book's final few pages,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huntington</ENAMEX> does his sudden turnaround and finally sees what he missed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>:
It is in the interests of civilizations not just to "coexist" but to actively
cooperate. We live in a world not just of "transnational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>" but of
"transnational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafias</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartels</ENAMEX>," problems that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> can solve only
by acting in concert. In the book's final paragraph he repeats that, "in the
clash of civilizations, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will hang together or hang
separately," but he adds that in "the greater clash," the "global" clash
between chaos and order, "the world's great civilizations ... will also hang
together or hang separately." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>, who set out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> to debunk the New
World Order, is suddenly talking like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>!

            On behalf of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-worlders
everywhere, I celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Huntington's Road</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX> experience and officially
disassociate him from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. But before we teach him the secret New
World Order handshake, we'd like him to resolve some paradoxes in his thinking.
In particular: the tension between his prescriptions of (a) the West turning
inward for its own salvation; and (b) the world's different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> cooperating
for global salvation. Clearly, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> can complicate the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. If, for
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> focuses on nourishing its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> kinship and is wary of
joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, then building a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> will be
tricky.

            One can imagine another book
that would synthesize and elaborate the of this one. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>
suggests putting an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX>--an interesting
idea, and proof that thinking "civilizationally," or at least culturally, has
its uses. But the growing academic fad of thinking in primarily, almost
obsessively, tribal terms is another matter. In addition to being analytically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sloppy</ENAMEX>, it can become a self-fulfilling prophecy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huntington</ENAMEX> notes, as evidence
of tribalism, that foreign investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> encounters more hostility when
it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> than when it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>. Regrettably, this is true. But one
reason it's true is because <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Huntington</ENAMEX> and other tribalism aficionados spend so
much time talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other "civilizations," as if they lived on
another planet. Turns out they don't.

         
      
   
