
   
   
      
         
            Take <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Simple Test</ENAMEX>

            Here's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-question quiz
to determine how rational you are. This will work best if you stop and answer
each question before going on to the next.

            Imagine
that each of your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fabulously</ENAMEX> wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> offers you a choice of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> gifts. In each case, choose the one you'd prefer.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousin Snip</ENAMEX> offers you a choice of:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. $1</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in cash.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> A lottery ticket. The
ticket gives you a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-percent</NUMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>, an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX>-percent
chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>, and a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1-percent</NUMEX> chance of winning nothing at
all.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousin Snap</ENAMEX> offers you a choice of:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> A
lottery ticket that gives you an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> A lottery ticket that
gives you a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-percent</NUMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousin Snurr</ENAMEX> offers you a choice of:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. $1</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in cash.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. A</ENAMEX>
lottery ticket that gives you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/11</NUMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>.

            Now that you've made your choices, you can read on to
discover whether you're a rational <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>. "Rational" does not mean
"risk-neutral." A risk-neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is one who is indifferent when given a
choice <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 50 cents</NUMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-50</NUMEX> chance of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>. A risk-neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would
choose B in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> cases. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Snip</ENAMEX>'s offer, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX>) plus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$890,000</NUMEX>) equals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.39 million</NUMEX>, which
trumps <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Snap</ENAMEX>'s offer, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX>) trumps
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110,000</NUMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s offer, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/11</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.55 million</NUMEX>, which trumps <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>.

            But it's
equally rational to avoid risk or to seek it out. The insurance and gambling
industries are based on these proclivities. Even so, rationality does imply
some logical consistency in your choices about risk. It would be embarrassing
if a lot of 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> failed this test, so I'm going to make
it easy by adopting a very broad definition of rationality. As long as you
satisfy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> simple criteria, I'm willing to call you rational.

            
Here's my first criterion: If you prefer A to
B, then you should prefer a chance of winning A to an (equally large)
chance of winning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. And</ENAMEX> here's the test to see whether you've met that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criterion</ENAMEX>: Your answers to Questions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX> should be the same. That's because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap</ENAMEX>'s choice A is an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> shot at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> bucks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s choice A
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> bucks. Therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap</ENAMEX>'s A is an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> shot at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr's A.</ENAMEX>
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap</ENAMEX>'s choice B amounts to an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> shot at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s choice B.
(Do the math: A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-percent</NUMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> is the same as an
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a 10/11</NUMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.11 x 10/11</NUMEX>
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.10</NUMEX>) So, if you prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s A to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr's</ENAMEX> B, you should prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Snap</ENAMEX>'s A to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX>

            Here's my
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> criterion of rationality: If you're choosing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX> with
identical chances to win, then your preference should be unaffected if I throw
in a consolation prize that you get if you lose in either case. You pass that
test if your answers to Questions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 3</NUMEX> are the same. This is why:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snip</ENAMEX>'s choice A is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. Another way to say <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>--weird, but bear with me--is "an
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> chance to win <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>, with a consolation prize of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> for
losing." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s choice A is also <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snip</ENAMEX>'s A is an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> shot
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s A with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1-million</NUMEX> consolation prize.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snip</ENAMEX>'s
choice B is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-percent</NUMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> plus a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1-percent</NUMEX> chance
of winning nothing plus <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an 89-percent</TIMEX> chance of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>. The first
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> items, taken together, amount to an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> chance of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a 10/11</NUMEX> chance of
winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> item means you get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> if that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-percent
chance doesn't come through. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s choice B is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/11</NUMEX> chance to win <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snip</ENAMEX>'s choice B is therefore an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> shot at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s choice B
with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1-million</NUMEX> consolation prize.

            So if you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prefer Snip</ENAMEX>'s A to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snip's</ENAMEX> B, you should prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s A to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>'s
B-- if you're rational.

            To sum up, if you are even minimally rational, your answers
to Questions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 2</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX> should all be the same. But they probably aren't.
According to survey data collected by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Allais</ENAMEX>--and
duplicated by several subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>--most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> answer A to Question
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and B to Question <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. There is no way to reconcile that combination of answers
with the most rudimentary theory of rationality, no matter how you answer
Question <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prefer the cash over the lottery ticket--to
an extent that rational risk aversion can't explain.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX>
have variously viewed the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allais</ENAMEX> Paradox" as a warning, a trifle, an
opportunity, and a challenge. If you're looking to explain all human behavior
on the basis of a few simple axioms, it's a warning. If you don't believe that
casual answers to abstract survey questions constitute an important part of
human behavior, it's a trifle. If the survey responses mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
less rational than they ought to be, it's an opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> to
teach better decision-making skills. If you conclude that there's a critical
element missing from our theory of rationality, it's a challenge to identify
that element.

            
One missing element is regret . When you
choose a lottery instead of a sure thing (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Question 1</ENAMEX>), you risk not just
losing the lottery but also feeling regretful about your recklessness. But when
you choose between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX> (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Question 2</ENAMEX>), you can always reconcile
yourself to a loss by thinking, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I'd probably have lost no matter
what I chose." Maybe that's why most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go for the sure thing in
Question <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX> but are willing to go for the slightly riskier of the two bets in
Question <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for an experiment that could test this hypothesis.)

            Here's another
thought-experiment that indicates the importance of avoiding regret. Suppose
you belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, of whom one must be chosen for the
distasteful task of executing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>. Which of the following do you prefer?
A) One <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> is selected at random to shoot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>? Or B) all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> fire at once, without knowing which one of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> has been issued live
ammunition? Either way, you'd have a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-percent</NUMEX> chance of being the
executioner, so simple theories of rationality suggest that you should be
indifferent when asked to choose between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> options. Yet most people
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prefer B</ENAMEX>), because in case B) you never know whether you've been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unlucky</ENAMEX>.

            The
analogy between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allais</ENAMEX> survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> is imperfect;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who choose method B) are trying to avoid regret over bad luck,
while the survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> are, perhaps, trying to avoid regret over bad
decisions. But in either case, ignoring the human impulse toward
regret-avoidance might give a social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> cause for regret.

            
               Note to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>: A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> after this article was posted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX> clarified the "simple
test." Read his addendum in "E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>."
            

         
      
   
