
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Shadow Boxing</ENAMEX>

            The good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the fastest-growing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the
world, is that the Internet is a place where a smart young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can become a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tycoon overnight</TIMEX>. The bad news for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky Dayton</ENAMEX> is that the Internet is a place
where anyone with a home computer, a modem, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">animus</ENAMEX> can make your life
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miserable</ENAMEX>, and perhaps do real damage to your business. The bad news for the
rest of us is the larger moral of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>'s story: The famously "egalitarian"
properties of the Net have a creepy and oppressive flip side.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX> founded an Internet access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EarthLink</ENAMEX> (not to be confused
with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Earthling</ENAMEX>," the name of this column). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EarthLink</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> has grown from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to 400</TIMEX>, its annual revenue to more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX>, and its customer base to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140,000</NUMEX>. If you research Internet access
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>, you'll discover why: No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that matches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EarthLink</ENAMEX>'s network of
nationwide access points beats its price. But if you do your research on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>, you'll probably discover something else, too: a Web page
ominously titled "earthlink.net and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientology</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Links</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subtitle</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Scientology Training</ENAMEX>."

            With EarthLink preparing for its first public stock
offering, this is not good publicity. On the Net, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of Scientology</ENAMEX> is
the antichrist. It slaps lawsuits on church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who post quotes from
copyrighted church documents, sometimes getting federal marshals to search
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> and seize computer disks. There's no evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> currently
uses extralegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> against online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--pries into their e-mail, say.
Still, among the desirable qualities of an Internet access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> whose computers all your e-mail and cyberwanderings pass
through--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of Scientology</ENAMEX> affiliated" does not rank high.

            
               Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EarthLink Church of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientology</ENAMEX> affiliated? Apparently not, but we'll get to that later. First,
note that this isn't just another case of accusations speeding across the Net,
hopping from newsgroup to newsgroup (e.g., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s rumor that Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fields</ENAMEX>
had supplied free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>'s acquittal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>). There's a
subtler dynamic at work here, a property not of the Net at large but of the Web
in particular. This dynamic will affect more of us as the Web grows and more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s reputations are mediated there. On the Web, anyone can construct a
kind of "shadow identity" for anyone else--not just an unkind characterization,
but an unkind characterization that sticks to your cyber-identity like
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX>.

            Suppose,
for example, that some business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heavyweight</ENAMEX> is pondering a business deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky Dayton</ENAMEX>--or is just curious about him, having met him at a cocktail party.
She revs up a Web search engine--say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alta Vista</ENAMEX>--and types in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sky Dayton</ENAMEX>" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EarthLink</ENAMEX>." And there it is, on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of listings: "earthlink.net and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientology</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Links</ENAMEX>." As long as this shadow page contains key words that
are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>'s home page and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EarthLink</ENAMEX>'s home page, it will be seen by almost
everyone who finds either of those pages through a search engine. This is the
cyberspace equivalent of hanging a sign around someone's neck saying
"Scientologist"--or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molester," "bedwetter," whatever. Except that in the
physical world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> can remove the sign. Shadow pages, in contrast, are
indelible.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky Dayton</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of an oft-applauded trend.
As copying and transmitting data get cheaper, the distribution of power grows
more equal. After publishing technology evolved from its scribbling-monks phase
to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gutenberg</ENAMEX> phase, a form of power once dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popes</ENAMEX> and other big
shots was diffused, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX> happened. Now the power over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reputations</ENAMEX> is passing from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, and so on to--well, to
everybody.

            It can be fun watching the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davids</ENAMEX> take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goliaths</ENAMEX>--the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kmart sucks</ENAMEX>" web page, for example, authored
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who ran <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kmart</ENAMEX>'s own web page until <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kmart</ENAMEX> fired him. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mistake</ENAMEX>.) But
remember: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX> could be you. (You may doubt that someday you'll have a Web
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, but you may also have doubted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> that someday you'd need
e-mail.) Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyber-tormentor</ENAMEX> could be a nutcase former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, an envious
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, an aggrieved ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> or ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>. Their technological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">empowerment</ENAMEX> may take some of the thrill out of your own empowerment. On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--and every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> Gennifer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>. (Note to
gender <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>: You know what I mean.)

            Of course
you can always shadow your shadow identity with a rebuttal, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
see the charges against you also see your reply. When I mentioned this to a
legal-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar friend</ENAMEX>, he joyously declared cyberspace a "perfectly efficient
information market." His apparent assumption--that bringing all relevant
information to bear on an issue fixes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> in the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>--reflects
a touchingly pre-postmodern view of human objectivity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the news from
evolutionary psychology is less touching. Natural selection did not, in fact,
design our brains to apprehend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>. Our moral evaluations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are often
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subordinate</ENAMEX>, by design, to our social agendas, and as a result, our whole
machinery for appraising other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is gunked up with unconscious bias.

            Anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky Dayton</ENAMEX> faces something more elusive than lies.
It's true that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientologist</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chick Corea</ENAMEX>, etc.). "I
practice my personal right to choose my own beliefs," he says. Some of the
shadow page's other specific claims also are true. But there's no evidence
that, as the shadow page intimates, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EarthLink</ENAMEX> is an arm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Baptist</ENAMEX>, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief financial officer</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientology</ENAMEX> "is a large religion," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>. "If I were to ask you
if, because you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>,
everybody would laugh at me."

            In a way, truthful shadow
pages are the scariest of all. As many have noted, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, much of your
"private" life is vulnerable to intrusion. E-mail is less secure than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX>
mail or a phone call. Most financial transactions don't involve cash, and are,
thus, recorded. Your wanderings on the Web leave more footprints than you may
realize.

            Much of this vulnerability
may eventually be neutralized by encryption and other tricks. But until then,
technology will in some ways be pushing us backward in time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX>, though
celebrated as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libertarian institution</ENAMEX>, can also be the opposite. It can be a
bit like a claustrophobic small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, where your private life is part of the
public dialogue. Winesburg, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, like cyberspace, was a "perfectly efficient
information market."

         
      
   
