
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two hundred years ago</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Blackstone</ENAMEX> said it's better for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go
free than for one innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to suffer. And for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX>, legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> have considered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackstone</ENAMEX>'s pronouncement a profound statement of
principle. Apparently, none of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> has thought to ask the obvious
follow-up question, namely, why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>? Why wasn't it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 or eight</NUMEX>? The answer, of
course, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackstone</ENAMEX> invented a number out of thin air. That kind of
flippancy amounts to a defiant refusal to think seriously about the trade-offs
involved in designing a criminal justice system. But for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years</TIMEX>, legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> have cited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackstone</ENAMEX>'s refusal to think and mistaken it for an
example of a thought.

            There's
nothing profound about recognizing a trade-off between convicting the innocent
and acquitting the guilty. The hard part is deciding how many false acquittals
you're willing to accept to avoid a false conviction. That number matters. It
matters whether it is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 or 12 or eight</TIMEX>, because every time we rewrite a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> statute or modify the rules of evidence, we are adjusting the terms of
the trade-off. So it's got to be worth it to think about what terms we want to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aim</ENAMEX> for.

            Here's one approach: Imagine how a guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> going free or
a free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> getting convicted might affect your life. (Or, so we don't get too
deeply sidetracked into your personal idiosyncrasies, how the guilty going free
or the free getting convicted might affect the lives of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>.) On the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> risk being falsely accused and convicted. On the other
hand, they risk being victimized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who have been falsely acquitted
(or by others who were emboldened to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> because of the frequency
of false acquittals). In principle, the cost of either disaster can be measured
in dollars. In practice, we can approximate those measures by making a
reasonable guess as to how much your typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> would be willing to pay
to avoid a year in jail or to avoid being robbed on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work.

            After
estimating the costs of being either an imprisoned innocent or a crime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, we can estimate the probability that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> will actually
face each of these problems. But once we know the cost and the probability
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with a given risk, we can infer a lot about how undesirable that
risk is. We can do this, for example, by observing the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> behave in
insurance markets. Suppose you want to know just how unpleasant it is to face a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> chance of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> loss. Then all you have to do is look at those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who face a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> chance of losing their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in a fire and
see how much they are willing to pay for fire insurance.

            
If you don't like insurance markets, you can
look at labor markets: How much extra must you pay a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> to get him to take
a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> risk of, say, losing an arm? If we believe for independent reasons
that the value of an arm is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> (no, I don't mean to say that is
the value of an arm; this is a hypothetical example), then we have another way
to put a dollar value on the unpleasantness of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> risk of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>
loss.

            Or you
can use data from financial markets: How much more interest must you offer an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> to get him to accept a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> risk of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> financial loss?
That's relatively easy to observe, and it gives yet another measure of how much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dislike this particular level of risk.

            False acquittals and false convictions are each associated
with certain levels and probabilities of risk. By examining behavior in
insurance markets, labor markets, and financial markets, we can make some
reasonable guesses about how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dislike each of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX>, and
also the extent to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are willing to trade off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind of risk for
the other. That will give an indication of whether we ought to be expanding or
restricting the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>.

            It would take quite a bit of
work to complete that project, and at the end all you'd have is a rough
estimate. Your final number would be suspect in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> ways. For example,
the data from insurance and labor markets tell a pretty consistent story about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s aversion to risk, but the data from financial markets make the degree
of risk aversion appear much higher. There might be no entirely satisfactory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to resolve such inconsistencies. But until you've done some kind of
analysis, quoting a number such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10</ENAMEX>" is both dishonest and disreputable.

         
      
   
