
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Story</ENAMEX>

            I wish to issue a forceful
denial of sexual relations with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. I never told
anyone to lie about it. Any intimation that our relationship was improper will
be a source of deep distress to me, to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, and to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            While I
have met with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> on occasion, I did so only to
discuss matters relating to family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>, teen-age pregnancy, and social
consequences. Any elation or dishevelment observed in me upon leaving those
meetings was strictly professional. I just have that kind of hair. All the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> faxes, memos, and other messages I have in my possession deal with
subjects such as I detail above.

            Ihave examined the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> copies of the poetry of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibran</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and find no inscription from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> in any of them. All items of underwear in my possession were purchased
either by me or by my widowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. While items of my clothing are currently
at the cleaners, I can provide explanations for all the spots.

            My recent orthopedic
difficulties were in no way related to any unwillingness on my part to discuss
these or any other matters with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.

            I deny any implication that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Cranston</ENAMEX> in my still-to-be-published novel, Secondary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX> , was based upon my intimate knowledge of any real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX>
can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for themselves.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> relations: Domenika
Flack at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Howlton</ENAMEX>; phone: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">888-3737</TIMEX>; fax: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">888-3738</TIMEX>. (Photos
available upon request.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford Clark</ENAMEX>, at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pudge & Pose</ENAMEX>; phone: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">899-0679</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
