
   
   
      
         
            Judge Not

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiroshi Fujisaki</ENAMEX> has
instructed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> civil trial to ignore everything that
happened in the criminal trial. This makes him the judicial equivalent of the
automatic-elevator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> who will not allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to press the
buttons. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> started pressing their own buttons, there would be fewer
jobs for elevator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>; if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> started gathering their own information,
there would be fewer jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>.

            Economic
theory predicts that special-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> will try to manipulate the rules
of the workplace to make themselves indispensable. Everybody knows about union
featherbedding, and everybody knows about complex legislation--written by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>--that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> can interpret. But it seems to have escaped popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have developed the arcane rules of evidence that keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
in demand.

            Judicial featherbedding explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> insist on
filtering everything the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> hear. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> case in particular, a lot
of interesting arguments have been made, and not all of them have been made in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fujisaki</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>. Why would we want to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> from perfectly good
reasoning just because it happens to arise not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> but in an
editorial or over the dinner table?

            The
standard response, of course, is that we want to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> from bad
reasoning. But, if we trust these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to sort out wrongheaded analysis from
sound reasoning in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>, how can we not trust them to do the same with
the editorial page?

            
In fact, the entire system of shielding jurors
from "irrelevant" information (like past convictions, in criminal trials)
betrays a disturbing inconsistency. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> who is capable of sorting through
conflicting claims from dueling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> surely is capable of judging the
informational content of a past conviction.

            
Nevertheless, we allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to exclude evidence even though, once evidence
has been introduced, we trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> to decide how much weight it should
receive. In other words, we believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> are perfectly competent to
decide whether a given piece of evidence should be given a weight of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>, but not whether that same piece of evidence should
be given a weight of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0 percent</NUMEX>. I can think of no set of beliefs about the
limits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>' competence that would recommend such a policy.

            Either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> are capable of deciding how much weight to
assign a given bit of evidence or they're not. If they are capable, then by all
means show them all the evidence and let them ignore what they think is
irrelevant. If they are not capable, then why do we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? Either we have a very muddled view of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> can accomplish,
or the system has been devised to serve the interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who
thrive on confusion.

            I'm not
talking about things like the exclusionary rule, which prohibits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> from
seeing evidence that was gathered illegally. The exclusionary rule serves a
clear purpose by discouraging overzealous police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from inappropriate
behavior. Whether that benefit is worth its cost in terms of false acquittals
is arguable, but at least there is a clear benefit. By contrast, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admissibility</ENAMEX> of legally acquired evidence serves no apparent
purpose, except to generate motions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, rulings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, and grounds
for appeals.

            
You might think that without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to
carefully control the flow of evidence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> would drown in a sea of
irrelevant information--and trials would go on forever. But that problem is
solved most efficiently by having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> pay (in cash) for excessive use of
courtroom time, not by the long and costly process of motions and appeals.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>-selection process
is another good example of judicial make-work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> of the court go to
enormous lengths to choose unbiased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>. But what is so desirable about the
absence of bias--and of the informed speculation that might have led to that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX>? At election time, we are not urged to avoid the media so as to remain
unbiased until we get to the voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX>. Isn't it inconsistent to prefer both
a well-informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> and an ignorant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>?

            
(Sometimes, apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> are chosen not just for specific ignorance of
the case but for general ignorance of the world around them. I have a friend
who was excluded from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> because he answered "yes" to the question, "Do you
think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's been arrested is more likely to be guilty than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
hasn't been arrested<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" Presumably his place was taken by another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> who
really believes that the police arrest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> completely at random.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jurors</ENAMEX> are kept off-balance--and in need of additional
guidance from the bench--by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, who instructs them to convict if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> is guilty "beyond a reasonable doubt," without telling them whether a
"reasonable doubt" consists of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> risk of error, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> risk of
error, or a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> risk of error. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> scoff at the notion that doubt
can be quantified so precisely. Their scoffing is justified, but it's also
irrelevant. It is true that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> can be sure whether his or her doubt is
more or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 5 percent</NUMEX>, but it is equally true that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> can be sure
whether his or her doubt is more or less than "reasonable." With a quantified
target, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> would at least know what to aim for, even if they can't be sure
of hitting it.

            It's crazy to think that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> who are unsure about two criteria (what is a reasonable doubt,
and does my own doubt exceed that level?) will be more accurate than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> who
are unsure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about only one</NUMEX> criterion (does my doubt exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>?).
And quantified standards have the added advantage of flexibility--they can be
adjusted to different levels for different crimes. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, whose jobs
depend on judicial procedures being impenetrable, convoluted, and
self-contradictory, systematically conceal what they are thinking of when they
use the phrase "reasonable doubt."

            The entire
purpose of legal tradition and precedent is to make outcomes predictable. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have both the motive and the opportunity to contort tradition and
precedent in ways that render outcomes illogical and un predictable.
Respect for the law is enshrined in our culture, but it should not blind us to
the possibility that the law can be corrupted to serve sordid ends.

         
      
   
