
   
   
      
         
            More Sex Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safer</ENAMEX> Sex 

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1102</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 5</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 12</TIMEX>)
            

            It's true: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>'s awful retribution for our tolerance of immoderate and socially
irresponsible sexual behavior. The epidemic is the price of our permissive
attitudes toward monogamy, chastity, and other forms of sexual
conservatism.

            You've
read elsewhere about the sin of promiscuity. Let me tell you about the sin of
self-restraint.

            Suppose you walk into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> potential sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> are highly promiscuous; the others venture out only once a year.
The promiscuous ones are, of course, more likely to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive. That gives
you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-50</NUMEX> chance of finding a relatively safe match.

            But suppose all
once-a-year <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revelers</ENAMEX> could be transformed into twice-a-year <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revelers</ENAMEX>. Then, on
any given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, you'd run into twice as many of them. Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> promiscuous
bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> would be outnumbered by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of their more cautious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. Your
odds of a relatively safe match just went up from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-50 to four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>.

            That's why increased
activity by sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> can slow down the rate of infection and reduce
the prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. In fact, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kremer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>'s
economics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> could plausibly be retarded
if everyone with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than about 2.25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> per year were to take
additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> more frequently. That covers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterosexuals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of 18 and 45</TIMEX>. (Much of this column is inspired
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kremer</ENAMEX>'s
research.

            If
multiple partnerships save lives, then monogamy can be deadly. Imagine a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are monogamous, while all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> demand <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> per year. Under those conditions, a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> end up servicing
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Before long, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> are infected; they pass the disease
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> bring it home to their monogamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. But if each of
those monogamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> was willing to take on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> extramarital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, the
market for prostitution would die out, and the virus, unable to spread fast
enough to maintain itself, might die out along with it.

            Or consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>, who attended a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> where she ought to
have met the charming and healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately Fate, through its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX>, intervened. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> of the
party, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> ran across one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>-sponsored subway ads touting the
virtues of abstinence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chastened</ENAMEX>, he decided to stay home. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s absence,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> hooked up with the equally charming but considerably less prudent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> got <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. Abstinence can be even deadlier than monogamy.

            If those subway ads are
more effective against the cautious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Martins</ENAMEX> than against the reckless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwells</ENAMEX>,
then they are a threat to the hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joans</ENAMEX>. This is especially so when they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">displace Calvin Klein</ENAMEX> ads, which might have put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> in a more socially
beneficent mood.

            You
might object that even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> had dallied with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>, he would only have
freed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX> to prey on another equally innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. To this there are two
replies. First, we don't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX> would have found another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>:
Without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>, he might have struck out that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, reducing the rate of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> transmission is in any event not the only social goal worth pursuing: If it
were, we'd outlaw sex entirely. What we really want is to minimize the number
of infections resulting from any given number of sexual encounters; the flip
side of this observation is that it is desirable to maximize the number of
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">consensual</NUMEX>) sexual encounters leading up to any given number of infections.
Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> had failed to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX> a conquest <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX>, and thus
failed to slow the epidemic, he
could at least have made someone happy.

            To an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>, it's clear why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with limited sexual
pasts choose to supply too little sex in the present: Their services are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underpriced</ENAMEX>. If sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> could effectively advertise their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">histories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-conscious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitors</ENAMEX> would compete to lavish them with attention.
But that doesn't happen, because such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are hard to identify.
Insufficiently rewarded for relaxing their standards, they relax their
standards insufficiently.

            So a socially valuable
service is under-rewarded and therefore under-supplied. This is a problem we've
experienced before. We face it whenever a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> fails to safeguard the
environment.

            Extrapolating from their
usual response to environmental issues, I assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> will want to
attack the problem of excessive sexual restraint through coercive regulation.
As a devotee of the price system, I'd prefer to encourage good behavior through
an appropriate system of subsidies.

            The question is: How do we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subsidize Martin</ENAMEX>'s sexual awakening without simultaneously subsidizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>'s ongoing predations? Just paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have sex won't work--not
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX> around to reap the bulk of the rewards. The key is to subsidize
something that is used in conjunction with sex and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> values more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>.

            Quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plausibly</ENAMEX>, that something is condoms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell</ENAMEX> knows that he is more likely than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> to be infected already, and hence probably values condoms less than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> does. Subsidized condoms could be just the ticket for luring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> out
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX> without stirring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX> to a new frenzy of activity.

            As it happens, there is another reason to subsidize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condoms</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condom</ENAMEX> use itself is under-rewarded. When you use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, you are
protecting both yourself and your future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, but you are rewarded (with a
lower chance of infection) only for protecting yourself. Your future partners
don't know about your past condom use and therefore can't reward it with
extravagant courtship. That means you fail to capture the benefits you're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conferring</ENAMEX>, and as a result, condoms are underused.

            It is often argued that
subsidized (or free) condoms have an upside and a downside: The upside is that
they reduce the risk from a given encounter, and the downside is that they
encourage more encounters. But it's plausible that in reality, that's not an
upside and a downside--it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> upsides. Without the subsidies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't
use enough condoms, and the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who most value condoms don't have
enough sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>.

            All these problems--along
with the case for subsidies--would vanish if our sexual pasts could somehow be
made visible, so that future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> could reward past prudence and thereby
provide appropriate incentives. Perhaps technology can ultimately make that
solution feasible. (I envision the pornography of the future: "Her skirt slid
to the floor and his gaze came to rest on her thigh, where the imbedded monitor
read, 'This site has been accessed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">314</NUMEX> times.' ") But until then, the best we
can do is to make condoms inexpensive--and get rid of those subway ads.

         
      
   
