
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monopoly Shopping</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is paying me to
write this column. Does that affect my objectivity? I don't think so, but I
might be wrong. Fortunately, it doesn't matter. I'm not asking for your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>.
I'm going to lay out a simple logical argument that you can check for yourself.
The argument stands or falls on its own merits.

            In other
words, I aim to occupy the same high ground claimed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> in his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> debate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen A. Douglas</ENAMEX>:

            If you have ever studied
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">geometry</ENAMEX>, you remember that by a course of reasoning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euclid</ENAMEX> proves that all the
angles in a triangle are equal to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> right angles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euclid</ENAMEX> has shown you how to
work it out. Now, if you were to undertake to disprove that proposition, would
you prove it to be false by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Euclid</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>?

            I am
prepared to go <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> one better and to assert that you could not prove
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euclid</ENAMEX>'s proposition to be false even by calling him a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>.

            Now, then, let's talk about Web browsers. More
specifically, let's talk about what will happen if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> extends its
operating system monopoly into the browser market as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>
claims it is trying to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> denies that intention, claiming it bundles
browsers with operating systems only to take advantage of technical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synergies</ENAMEX>.

            Who's
right about that one? I have no idea. Well, OK, I have some ideas, but they're
probably no better informed than yours. Instead, I want to ask a related
question, one that is central to this whole affair but has been almost entirely
ignored in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of op-ed pieces that have cropped up over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple</TIMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. Namely: Would a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> browser monopoly be good or bad for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>?

            
Well--good or bad compared with what? What is
the alternative to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> browser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>? There are several scenarios
you might envision. One is an eternal competition between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and
Netscape, each striving to capture market share through innovation. The upside
of that scenario is that browsers would get better; the downside is that
innovation uses a lot of resources that might be better employed elsewhere.
It's not clear whether the benefits of that competition would outweigh the
costs, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>versa.

            Another
alternative to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> monopoly is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Netscape</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>. Which of
those would be better for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>? Your gut response to that question
is likely to depend pretty heavily on whose software has caused you the most
recent frustration. For the record, my own level of frustration with
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' products is so high that I don't run Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape Communicator</ENAMEX>. But let's you and I try putting aside our
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peeves</ENAMEX> and recasting the question at a more abstract level. Assume,
for the sake of argument, that there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> browser and that its
quality will be the same regardless of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> supplies
it. Then should you, the consumer, care who supplies it?

            Under those assumptions, there's an unambiguous answer: You
should root for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. Give me a few paragraphs, and I'll explain why.

            Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>
costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $90</NUMEX> at my local computer superstore. Why doesn't it cost more?
Because, despite its monopoly power, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> remains subject to the laws of
the marketplace. At a higher price, too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> would walk away. (If you
doubt a small price increase would significantly affect the sales of Windows
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95</TIMEX>, you must conclude <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is undercharging out of either foolishness or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generosity</ENAMEX>--neither of which is terribly consistent with the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at large think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.)

            
In fact, every time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> raises the price
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95</ENAMEX>, it gets punished twice. First, it loses sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, with each of those lost sales, it loses a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> of Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>. For example, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the browser market, then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>
lost Windows sales imply <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>. (This assumes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX> won't need a browser.)

            You might
ask why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is "punished" by the loss of an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>, given
that Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> can be downloaded free. The answer, of course, is that
in the long run, it won't be free. Even when it comes packaged "free"
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 98</ENAMEX>, you'll really be paying a combined price for the operating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> and the browser, which will surely be higher than the price <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
would charge for an operating system alone.

            Now think what would happen if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> had a monopoly in
the browser market. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> punishment would be doubled--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> lost Windows
sales would mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> lost Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> sales, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>. That's good
news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> a monopoly on browsers, and you'll intensify
the downward pressure on the price of its operating systems.

            In fact,
the same kind of pressure works to lower browser prices too. Just as a doubly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monopolistic Microsoft</ENAMEX> would be reluctant to raise the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95</ENAMEX> for
fear of losing Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, it would be equally reluctant to raise
the price of Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> for fear of losing Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> (who might
not be willing to invest in a computer at all if the price of browsers is too
high). Of course prices will still rise and fall in response to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX>--but they will never rise as high under a dual monopoly as they would
under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX>.

            
That doesn't prove that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> monopoly
beats any alternative. But it does prove a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> monopoly beats a
Netscape monopoly, assuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> provide products of comparable
quality.

            I promised to make an
argument that would stand or fall on its own merits, and I claim to have
fulfilled that promise. You can judge the argument for itself, and it doesn't
matter who else has endorsed it. But I do want to mention for the record that
it has a lot of endorsements. In economics textbooks, it is commonplace to
observe that vertical integration of monopolies tends to reduce consumer
prices--for essentially the same reasons I've given in this column. That
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX> wasn't always commonplace, but it has been for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years now</TIMEX>--ever since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H. Bork</ENAMEX> forcefully called it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>'
attention. (In my own textbook, the discussion of this issue is peppered with
quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>.) In his recent public statements, he has skirted this issue
entirely. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> pays him a lot more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> pays me.

         
      
   
