
   
   
      
         
            Be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fruitful and Multiply</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> you were born, you
brought both costs and benefits into this world. The costs include the demands
you made (and continue to make) on the world's resources. The benefits include
your ongoing contributions to the world's stock of ideas, love, friendship, and
diversity.

            Do the costs outweigh the
benefits, or vice versa? In other words: Should the rest of us consider your
birth (or any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s birth) a blessing or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>?

            Let's not try to
settle this by listing all the costs and benefits of sharing the world with
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> stuck in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> traffic, you'll remember that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in front of you imposed a cost, but you might forget that the guy
who invented your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s air conditioner conferred a benefit. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>
remember to complain about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>, but sometimes forget that without the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> would be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cedar Rapids</ENAMEX>.

            Instead
of making a list, let's think about the decision your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> faced when they
were considering whether to conceive a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. Is it more likely that they
undercounted costs or that they undercounted benefits?

            I'll start with benefits. The clearest benefit of your
birth is that it gave your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to love; they certainly counted that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. But the other benefits are spread far and wide. If you build a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mousetrap</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> will be in your debt. If all you do is smile, you'll still
brighten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. We don't know how to list those benefits, but we do
know that many of them fall on total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>. That makes it unlikely that
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> took them fully into account.

            Now let's look at costs. The
costs of your existence fall into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories. First, you consume privately
owned resources like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and land. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, you might consume resources to
which you have no clear property right--for example, you might open a factory
that pollutes the air I breathe, or you might become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">burglar</ENAMEX> who steals my
stereo system.

            (You might
imagine that there are also costs associated with your competing in the
marketplace, bidding some prices up and others down, applying for the job I
wanted, and so forth. But each of those costs has an offsetting benefit. If you
bid up the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> will gain as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> lose. If you
prove a stronger job <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> than I do, my loss is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s gain.)

            
Stealing and polluting clearly impose costs on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strangers</ENAMEX>. But if you're at all typical, your consumption of staples like food
and land will far exceed your consumption of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s air and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s property. In other words, for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> category of costs
is the big one. So let's concentrate on that.

            Where do you get all those
resources you own and consume? Some you create; those don't cost anybody
anything. Some you trade for; again, those don't cost anybody anything. The
rest you inherit; and those come from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX>' share. That means your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">siblings</ENAMEX>--not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>--bear most of the costs of your birth.

            That's a
point that's often missed. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think about overcrowding or
overpopulation, they typically imagine that if, for example, I had not been
born, everyone else would have a slightly bigger share of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>. But that's
not right. If I had not been born, both my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> would have substantially
bigger shares of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>, and everybody else's share would be exactly what it
is now.

            So when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are deciding whether to have a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, they are generally more conscious of the costs than of
the benefits. Most of the costs are imposed on their other beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
while many of the benefits are dispersed among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>.

            When a decision-maker is more
conscious of costs than of benefits, he tends to make decisions that are overly
conservative. That almost surely means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> than is
socially desirable, and that therefore, the population grows too slowly. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, which makes me part of the problem.

            Somewhere
there is a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> whose life has been impoverished by my failure to sire
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who would someday sweep her off her feet. If I cared as much about that
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> as I do about my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, I'd have produced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. But
because I selfishly acted as if other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are less important than
my own, I stopped reproducing too soon.

            
Population growth is like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> in reverse.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of a polluting steel mill weighs all its benefits (that is, his
profits) against only a portion of its costs (he counts his expenses, but not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>' health). Therefore, he overproduces. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> weigh all--or at
least most--of the costs of an additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> (resources diverted from their
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>) against only a portion of the benefits (they count their own
love for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but not others' love for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>). Therefore,
they under produce.

            This argument seems to
suggest that I should have had more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for the sake of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>. A
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, completely separate argument says I should have had more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for
the sake of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> themselves. Presumably they'd have been grateful for
the gift of life. I'm not sure how far to push that argument. There's obviously
nothing close to a consensus on how to assign rights to the unborn, so we can
hardly hope for a consensus on how to assign rights to the unconceived. But the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> argument does tend to buttress the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

            Personally, I ignored both
arguments when I selfishly limited the size of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. I understand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selfishness</ENAMEX>. But I can't understand encouraging others to be selfish,
which is the entire purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zero Population Growth</ENAMEX>.
Instead, we should look for ways to subsidize reproduction. A world with many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> offers more potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who share our interests, more small acts
of kindness between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>, and a better chance of finding love. That's the
kind of world we owe our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
