
   
   
      
         
            Abortion Apostate

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> love an apostate,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> is the apostate of the moment. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1995</TIMEX>, at the
start of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' battle over so-called "partial-birth abortions,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX>, the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Coalition of Abortion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Providers</ENAMEX>, went on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> to argue against a ban. Even ardent
pro-choicers concede the grisliness of the procedure--in which delivery is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">induced</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>' skull is crushed, and its brains are suctioned. So,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> now says, he deliberately underestimated how often the procedure is
performed and claimed incorrectly that most such operations were necessary for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s health.

            But last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> came clean. "I lied through my teeth," he said in an interview
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical News</ENAMEX> . This became front-page news and revived
the partial-birth-abortion issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> failed to override <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s veto of a ban <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>. But there is speculation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will
change his position now that the truth has been revealed.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX>' confession have been
stirring. First, there was the critical moment of moral doubt: The day after
appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> says, he felt "physically ill. ... I
told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, 'I can't do this again.' " Next, heroic outrage: He stepped
forward when he could no longer watch the debate be "engulfed by spins and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-truths." Finally, redemption: accolades from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, declared in his
conscience-of-the-nation mode: "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> did the honorable thing."

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are being as
credulous about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX>' new story as they were about his old one. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">starters</ENAMEX>, why did it take him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 months</TIMEX> to retract lies he claims to have
immediately regretted?

            Then
there's the underplayed fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX>' mendacity could not possibly
have influenced the national debate, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> of the
Nightline interview in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> says he lied through his teeth
never aired!

            
Quite apart from the melodrama of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recantation</ENAMEX> and confession, moreover, there is nothing new about what he
"revealed" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX>, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen Record</ENAMEX> ran front-page stories asserting that pro-choice groups
underestimate the number of "intact dilation and extraction" (IDE) procedures,
to use the medical term, that are performed. In a piece that pro-life groups
circulated all over the place, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen Record</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Padawer</ENAMEX> showed
that one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Englewood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, had performed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDEs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. That is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> more than pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> claimed had been performed in the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. After interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who perform the procedure, both papers
concluded that only in very few instances was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDE</ENAMEX> actually necessary to
protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s health. Most of them were performed on poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who could
not muster the money to pay for abortions earlier in their pregnancies.

            Abortion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> have publicly admitted the same for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Haskell</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who developed the procedure, asserted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> paper that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX>
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> choose it because it is safer and more convenient than the
alternatives. There was no medical necessity. The other leading late-term
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abortionist</ENAMEX>, the now-deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James McMahon</ENAMEX>, presented similar statistics
before a congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> together
performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500 late-term</TIMEX> abortions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>, and there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least eight</NUMEX>
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who administer it--obviously, this adds up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 500</NUMEX> IDEs
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> nationwide.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> now endorses the pro-life movement's figure of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>. But that figure is as unreliable as the pro-choice movement's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>. None
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that provides reliable statistics about abortion tallies up the
total numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDEs</ENAMEX>. Consequently, there's much improvisation and sleight of
hand involved when anyone throws around numbers. Both sides claim to have
derived their figures from interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who perform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDEs</ENAMEX>, but
different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> use different definitions of the procedure and, in many
cases, they probably make only rough estimates of their own caseloads. Whether
the correct figure is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearer 500</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5,000</NUMEX>, it is a minuscule percentage of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 million</NUMEX> abortions performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            You might think, from the
attention paid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX>' recantation, that he was a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in
the abortion debate. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who cover abortion--to say nothing of
pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>--say they had never heard of him. "This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> came out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blue</ENAMEX>," says an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. At best, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> is
a B-league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, a trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>, represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">220</NUMEX> clinics
(but not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planned Parenthood</ENAMEX>, the largest abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>). While it aims to protect abortion rights, its agenda is mostly more
mundane. Right now, its biggest task is negotiating contracts with
pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> (who isn't giving any interviews now) offers no new statistics to
back up his current claim that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> IDEs are performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. And most
newspaper accounts fail to point out that, in spite of his confession,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> continues to oppose a ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDEs</ENAMEX>.

            
There is little doubt about the pro-choice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>'s unquestioning acceptance of the faulty pro-choice statistics. Editorial
boards at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> took the
position that a ban on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-term</TIMEX> abortions is bad because it affects only women
carrying badly deformed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> who have no other alternative. Perhaps the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncritical reportage of Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> can be explained by pangs of
guilt about the uncritical reportage of his old one.

            Pro-choicers have muddled
the debate over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-term</TIMEX> abortions, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> affair is their
disingenuous strategy coming back to bite them. Instead of categorically
defending a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s right to an abortion, they have chosen to challenge
pro-lifers on the pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifers</ENAMEX>' turf. They squabble over the details of late-term
abortions. But these details are their weakest points. Abortion is necessarily
an ugly business, and it doesn't do them any good to debate the extent of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ugliness</ENAMEX>. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> agrees to regulate one sort of abortion because it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gruesome</ENAMEX>, the pro-lifers will immediately turn to another form of abortion and
insist that it, too, be regulated, because it, too, is gruesome.

            If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is a fully human
life, then all abortion is murder and the debate over any particular procedure
is beside the point. But the pro-life movement recognizes it has lost the
larger debate, and has therefore adopted a step-by-step strategy. If abortion
is not wrong--irrespective of the circumstances--then the issue becomes a
tradeoff among unpleasant alternatives. And the question is not which of these
alternatives is more unpleasant, but whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should be making
the decision.

         
      
   
