
   
   
      
         
            Child <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Abuse: Threat or Menace</ENAMEX>?

            With a new government-funded
study in hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services Donna Shalala</ENAMEX> diagnosed a
rising epidemic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. She reported that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and
neglect nearly doubled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1986 and 1993</TIMEX>"--and that
was only the beginning of the ugly news. The number of "serious" cases had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quadrupled</ENAMEX>, and the percentage of cases being investigated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
had actually declined by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX>, trends that she called "shameful
and startling."

            Is
Shalala right? Is an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">unheeded child-abuse</ENAMEX> epidemic raging in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>? Or, as I
think is more likely, is the methodology behind the study and the
interpretation of its numbers flawed? And if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalala</ENAMEX> overstated the child-abuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peril</ENAMEX>, is she undermining public interest in the problem by making it appear
too big and difficult to fix at a reasonable cost?

            

               A Look at the Numbers
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> drew her
was conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westat Inc.</ENAMEX>, a consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that conducted similar studies
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980 and 1986</TIMEX>. In the new study, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, a representative
sample, were asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westat</ENAMEX> whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they had served appeared to
have suffered specified harms or to be living under specified conditions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westat</ENAMEX> then determined if the reported "harms" and "conditions" met the study's
definitions of "abuse" and "neglect," and generated estimates of incidence.

            The odd
thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalala</ENAMEX>'s claim that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> abused and neglected
doubled from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.4 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.8 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> is that no other signs
point to such a dramatic increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and neglect. Fatalities
arising from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse have held roughly steady, ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,014</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,216</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> to Prevent Child
Abuse.

            
Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4 million</NUMEX> additional cases reported,
almost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> fall into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> categories. (Anywhere from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.8 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> suffered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> type of abuse
or neglect. Unfortunately, the study did not "unduplicate" these reports.
Nevertheless, the proportions I describe below provide a general picture of
what is happening.)

            
               
                  Endangered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
                account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX> of the increase. These are cases where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was not actually harmed by parental abuse or neglect, but was "in
danger of being harmed according to the views of community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> or
child-protective service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>" [emphasis added]. (See Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.)

            
               
                  Emotional
abuse
                and neglect account for another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of the increase. The
great majority of emotional-abuse cases, according to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westat</ENAMEX> study,
involved "verbal assaults," and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of the emotional-neglect cases
involved "the refusal or delay of psychological care."

            

               
                  Educational neglect
               --the chronic failure to send a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to
school--added another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> to the total of new cases.

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Definitional Creep</ENAMEX>"?
            

            All these cases warrant
attention, but the explosion of numbers may be caused by the growing
reportorial sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, that is, "definitional creep."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professionals</ENAMEX> who become more sensitive to possible abuse, or more adept at
noticing it, would make more reports to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westat</ENAMEX>--even if the actual incidence
had not risen. In endangerment cases, at least, the study seems to accept this
explanation.

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalala</ENAMEX>, the number of "serious" cases increased <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1986 and 1993</TIMEX> from
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 143,000</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 570,000</NUMEX>." Her comments left the impression that the
cases involved life-threatening assaults, but the study defines "serious" cases
as any in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> suffered "long-term impairment of physical, mental,
or emotional capacities, or required professional treatment aimed at preventing
such long-term impairment." Emotional maltreatment accounted for fully half of
the increase in serious cases. (See Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.)

            

               I ><ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">n</ENAMEX> cases labeled as serious physical abuse, the reported injury
could be mental or emotional.

            Even in these "serious"
cases, the study seems affected by definitional creep. For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
categories (sexual abuse, physical neglect, and emotional neglect), the number
of cases described as "moderate" declined even as the number of "serious" ones
increased--strongly suggesting that cases once viewed as only moderately
threatening have now been "upgraded" to the most dire category.

            

               Uninvestigated Cases?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalala</ENAMEX>'s assertion that
investigations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and neglect cases have dropped by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX>
deserves closer scrutiny. In producing the number of uninvestigated cases, the
study compared the number of cases identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> with those known
to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Of the cases not investigated, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> involved
educational neglect. (See Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.)

            The main flaw here is that
most educational-neglect cases are handled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>; reports are made to
protective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> only when all else fails.

            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Another 30 percent</NUMEX> of
uninvestigated cases involved emotional abuse and neglect. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-protective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> usually avoid these cases because they tend to involve subjective
judgments, and there is little that a quasi-law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> can do about
them.

            
Definitional creep is clearly at play here, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professionals</ENAMEX> who are
increasingly willing to identify situations as harmful aren't necessarily ready
to equate them with the sort of abuse and neglect they are legally obliged to
report. And even if they did report these instances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-protective agencies
would still be expected to screen them out.

            

               Does <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shalala Believe Her Own Hype</ENAMEX>?
            

            Probably not. Radical action
would be required if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalala</ENAMEX>'s figures were even roughly correct. But instead
of proposing radical action when she released the report, she outlined modest
steps that had long been planned and budgeted.

            Having worked in the field
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>, I can testify firsthand that the problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and
neglect is real. But however well meant, exaggerating the severity of abuse
endangers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX>, for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was told that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">375,000</NUMEX> drug-exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> were born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> were
immobilized by estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of billions of dollars</NUMEX> were needed to
protect these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. In fact, the true number was closer to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX>, and a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has yet to mount a meaningful program for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Overstatement</ENAMEX> may also
obscure genuinely worrisome findings. Some of the increases in sexual abuse,
physical abuse, and physical neglect uncovered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westat</ENAMEX> may well reflect a
true deterioration of conditions in disorganized, poverty-stricken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalala</ENAMEX> paid scant attention to this possibility.

            And to claim recklessly that
too few cases are investigated is to play with fire. Child-protective agencies
are already overwhelmed investigating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2 million</NUMEX> reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of which are dismissed as unfounded or inappropriate. For many in
the field, the most pressing need is to discourage inappropriate reporting--not
to blithely call for more.

            
               Figures
for specific types of maltreatment exclude endangerment cases. Percentages
total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 100</NUMEX> because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> counted under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> type of
abuse.
            

            

               Percentages total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 100</NUMEX> because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> counted under more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of abuse.
            

            
               These
exclude cases of endangerment.
            

         
      
   
