
   
   
      
         
            Know Maass

            When I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> moved to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, a neighbor approached me in the corridor of my apartment
building.

            "Are you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maass</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>?"

            Though I have heard this
question many times over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, I still don't know the correct response.
Yes, I am; no, I am not. Both are accurate. Unfortunately, I offered my
neighbor a reply that raised more questions than it answered.

            "Yes, I am, but there are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us."

             

            He looked at me oddly and adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those
don't-mess-with-me expressions that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> are born with. If an
opportunity for amity had existed between us, it seemed to have vanished. He
slipped into the elevator, I slipped into my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, and I imagine he rolled
his eyes to the ceiling and thought, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great</ENAMEX>, another nut case in the
building."

            If only he knew the
truth.

            I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>--a very good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, according to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. I worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a decade</TIMEX>, and I have written a book about my experiences covering the
war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. It was published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and got positive reviews. It even won
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of</TIMEX> awards. So when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ask whether I am <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maass</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, I
should feel good, I should feel triumphant, I should feel like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the
literary universe receiving the adulation he so rightly deserves, and I should
reply in a voice of elegant humility, "Yes, I am."

            But I
don't. I can't.

            
My problem is this: Although I am <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maass</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, I am not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX>--one "s," not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>--has
a career's worth of books under his belt, and he's famous. Serpico
famous. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Valachi Papers famous</ENAMEX>. This has created a great deal of
confusion. I've received letters intended for him, phone calls intended for
him, compliments intended for him, a publishing solicitation intended for him,
even a job offer intended for him (which I turned down).

            I have never met the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>.

            Until
recently, I enjoyed the confusion. There's something flattering about people
thinking I was capable of writing a best seller about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> when I was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, or that I could write one book after another in my
20s, while at the same time reporting one newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> after another. I had
a great laugh when I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and someone
congratulated me on my phenomenal output. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>!

            Circumstances have changed. I now have my own literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oeuvre</ENAMEX> . This entitles me to certain privileges, such as employing
foreign words in my writings (see previous sentence) and living on the Upper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Side</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. Also, I should be able to revel in praise rather than
worry about it. But in my case, praise from a stranger is like a glass of water
served at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX>: You drink it warily, if at all, fearing it
may be tainted. Even if the water tastes pure and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious</ENAMEX>, you cannot enjoy
it as much as you should. There's nothing more pleasant than being
congratulated for your literary skills, but there's nothing less pleasant than
realizing the congratulations are intended for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who writes about the
mob.

            I had
hoped that my book would end the confusion, that I would emerge as the
one-and-only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maass</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maas</ENAMEX>), though I suspected this was unlikely. At
the least, I hoped the confusion would turn to my favor. Shortly before my book
was published, I wrote a piece about my identity crisis suggesting that if an
admirer who thought I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX> asked for my signature, I would scribble
away and confide that my "newest" opus was far better than "my" previous ones.
If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> bought my book by mistake, I would not complain.

            
Yet I miscalculated. No sooner did my book
start getting some attention than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX> released a book that turned into a
best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX>. It's about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvatore "Sammy</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gravano</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> who
turned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s evidence against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gotti</ENAMEX>. From what I hear about the
book--and I hear quite a bit--it's not bad, and that's unfortunate, at least
for me.

            I went to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> recently to do a reading. There was a sign
at the entrance announcing the event, and my name was spelled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX>." I
thought little of it until a beefy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience member</ENAMEX> walked out shortly after I
started talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. I am pretty sure he wanted to hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX>. It's not that I can't drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> away from my readings, but it
usually takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than 35 seconds</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ignominy</ENAMEX> has many forms. Once, after I signed a pile of
books at a bookstore, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> told me not to leave because there were more
copies in back. He returned with a stack of books by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX>. I was tempted
to sign them, and nobody would have been the wiser, but something held me back.
Integrity? Honesty? No--try jealousy. Signed books sell much better than
unsigned ones.

            I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> not long
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> to attend a book festival. A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lined up for my book signing,
and I was very pleased until some of them pulled out copies of his
books. It was a bit embarrassing, especially as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was sitting next to
me at the time.

            Could it
get worse?

            
After a lull, a middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> approached
me, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had my book. My book. I introduced him to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
and I explained how amusing it was that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX>
and wanted me to sign his books. A distraught look emerged on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s
face and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> stared coldly at him. "I told you!" she sneered.

            There was an awkward
silence. I quickly wrote a personal inscription in the book--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best</ENAMEX> regards from
the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maass</ENAMEX>"--and he smiled and thanked me. I would like to
think my inscription soothed the pain for him, cheered him up, and naturally
this was my intention. It was only later, of course, that I realized my
inscription made it impossible for him to get a refund.

         
      
   
