
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tocqueville Missed</ENAMEX>

            Nostalgia is rampant among
public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as they look for some critical juncture when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
democracy was flourishing more than it seems to be now, hoping to draw
inspiration and lessons for what might be done to revive our apparently ailing
civic life.

            Those who still admit to
being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> usually locate the golden era of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> democracy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> and
1940s, when, it is thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Delano Roosevelt</ENAMEX> provided bold,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progressive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. Those of conservative or center-right proclivities
characteristically look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s past through the eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis de</ENAMEX>
Tocqueville, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aristocrat</ENAMEX> who toured the fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1830s</NUMEX>, gathering observations and ideas that were, in due course, published
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tocqueville</ENAMEX>'s opus has become one of the modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s most influential political ethnographies--that is, a set of densely
descriptive observations of another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, written to influence political
debates back in one's own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            That message-to-home aspect
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tocqueville</ENAMEX>'s work is important in understanding its limitations. Alarmed by
the simultaneous expansion of democracy and an ever-more-centralized
bureaucratic administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in post-revolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, he used his
explorations of early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to make the case to his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX>
that they should encourage voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> in civic society as a new
buffer against state centralization.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of all ages, all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX> in life, and all types of dispositions are forever forming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tocqueville</ENAMEX> reported in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, oft-quoted passage. This happy
situation was possible, he felt, because extralocal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> seemed barely
present. "Nothing strikes a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> more," wrote
Tocqueville, "than the absence of what we would call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or
administration. ... There is nothing centralized or hierarchic in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constitution of American</ENAMEX> administrative power."

            Given
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tocqueville</ENAMEX>'s anti-statist purposes, it is not surprising that contemporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> federal government celebrate the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX>'s stress
on voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> (understood as functioning in opposition to
bureaucratic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state power</ENAMEX>). Still, before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> plunge forward on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">errand</ENAMEX>, we might want to notice that the best historical social science
challenges the claims of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and centrists about when, how, and why
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> civic engagement has flourished in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolution</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of the requisite
size for commercialization and urbanization had already emerged, but without a
vibrant set of voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1800s</TIMEX>, however, the
emergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> in both smaller and larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> was
outstripping commercial and demographic change. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> emphasizes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX>, political struggles over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>, and deepening popular participation in national, state,
and local elections served to spur associational life. So did religious and
cultural ideals about self-improvement, and growing awareness of extralocal
commercial and public affairs through widespread newspaper reading.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tocqueville</ENAMEX> himself was well aware of many of these extralocal influences.
Present-day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> often overlook how much he stressed political
participation, marveling at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> country in the world
which, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day in, day</TIMEX> out, makes use of an unlimited freedom of political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX>," which, in turn, encouraged a more general "taste for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX>."

            
In retrospect, it is obvious that what social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Mary P. Ryan</ENAMEX> has dubbed the pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> "era of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>," from
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1820s</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1840s</TIMEX>, coincided with the spread of adult male suffrage and
the emergence of competitive, mass-mobilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> the Jacksonian
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whigs</ENAMEX>, and finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Soilers</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            

               Democracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> took note of early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, too.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspapers</ENAMEX> make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>," Tocqueville
wrote. "Thus, of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> on earth, it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that one finds both
the most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and the most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>." Yet, blinded by his negative
passions about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state power</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tocqueville</ENAMEX> failed to grasp what his
observations meant about the early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard John</ENAMEX> cleverly points out in
Spreading the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News: The American Postal System From Franklin to Morse</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tocqueville</ENAMEX> traveled by stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> in the "hinterland of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>," remarking on the "astonishing circulation of letters and newspapers
among these savage woods." Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX>'s travels might not have been
possible if many stage-coach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had not been subsidized--through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--so that mail could be carried, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> travel home, to
remote districts.

            A
well-known quip has it that early modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prussia</ENAMEX> wasn't so much a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with an
army, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Similarly, the early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> may have been
not so much a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> that gave popular
reality to a fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> points out that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1828</TIMEX>, only 36 years
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Post Office Act of 1792</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> postal system
had almost twice as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> as the postal system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX> and over
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> as the postal system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1830s</TIMEX> and
1840s, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three-quarters</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.

            
Obviously, the institutional structure of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had everything to do with the spread of the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislative system</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and (above all) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> a strong interest in subsidizing communication and
transportation links into even the remotest areas of the growing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
Special postal rates made mailing newspapers cheap and allowed small newspapers
to pick up copy from bigger ones.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> system was even more important for civil society and democratic politics
than for commerce. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could use it to communicate freely with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens</ENAMEX>, even in the remotest hamlets, could readily communicate with one
another, monitoring the doings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.
Voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> soon learned to put out their message in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">formats</ENAMEX>, to take advantage of the mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergent</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksonian America</ENAMEX> were intertwined with the federal postal system. Party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> were often newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and postmasters, and postmasterships
quickly became a staple of party patronage.

            In short, the early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> civic vitality that so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entranced Alexis de Tocqueville</ENAMEX> was closely tied up with the representative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and centrally directed activity of a very distinctive national
state. The non-zero-sum nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> governmental and associational expansion
becomes even more apparent when we consider that most of the big voluntary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">associations</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX> prospered well into the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> , often building toward membership peaks reached only in the
1960s or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1970s</ENAMEX> and in full symbiosis with public social provision.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Army</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> spread in the wake of state and national benefits for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> veterans
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, for example. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraternal Order of Eagles</ENAMEX> was so active in
promoting state and federal old-age pensions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Eagle</ENAMEX> himself
received an official pen when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Social Security Act of 1935</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> women's federations of the early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> were champions
of local, state, and federal regulations, services, and benefits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. New Deal laws and administrative interventions were vital aids
for nascent industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Legion</ENAMEX> sponsored the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI Bill of</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>.

            
               Lessons for
Today
            

            
Maybe the problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
quite rightly, no longer feel they can effectively band together to get things
done either through, or in relationship to, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The problem may not be
a big, bureaucratic federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--after all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national government
still has proportionately less revenue-raising capacity and administrative heft
than virtually any other advanced national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The issue may be recent
shifts in society and styles of politics that make it less inviting and far
harder for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to participate efficaciously in civic life, except locally
or on very narrow issues.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> do
show an explosion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>-based advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> between the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1960s and the early 1980s</TIMEX>. But apart from a few on the right--notably the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Right to Life Committee</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>, and the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rifle Association</ENAMEX>--the few new big voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> that have been
founded have been structured like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of smaller ones: They are
staff-led, mailing-list <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>.

            Obviously, societal conditions so propitious for
encompassing voluntary federations have changed a lot. Higher-educated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of many such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>--now have nationally oriented
careers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cosmopolitan centers</ENAMEX>. Indeed, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> developed a very large professional-managerial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> that was, arguably,
more oriented to giving money to staff-led national advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> than
to climbing the local-state-national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> ladders of traditional
voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> are rarely
contacted directly by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> may not care much
about them at all if they aren't relatively well-off or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of targeted
"swing" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. This has happened in electoral politics at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> that all our mailboxes are full of computer-generated mailings from
single-issue advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> seeking to raise money from paper
"memberships."

            Were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis de Tocqueville</ENAMEX> to
return to the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for another visit, he
would be just as worried about these national trends as about possible declines
in purely local or small<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-group</ENAMEX> associationalism. After all, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> 's insights was that vital democratic participation served as a
kind of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>," where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> learned how to build social and civic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> of all sorts. He would also surely be surprised that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are using his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to justify a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">depoliticized</ENAMEX> and romantic localism as an improbable remedy for the larger ills
of national politics.

         
      
   
