
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uninsured-Motorist Fun</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years ago</TIMEX>, an economics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Wright</ENAMEX> resigned from his job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX> and drove his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Daytona Turbo</ENAMEX> down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> to begin teaching at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> found out how much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphians</ENAMEX> pay to
insure their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, he gave up driving.

            If you
live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, your auto insurance probably costs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> times what
it would in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>--and more than twice what it would in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>.
Philadelphians have traditionally paid more for insurance than their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, despite much higher theft
rates in those other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. This led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> to ask a question that ultimately
became the provocative title for an article in the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> : "Why is automobile insurance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> so damn
expensive?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Areasonable</ENAMEX> first guess is that the answer has little to do
with economics and much to do with the behavior of state regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
But the facts don't support that guess. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> is in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> could have insured his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> for less than
half the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> price, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>'s theft rate was then more
than double <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s rate. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> provide equally striking
contrasts: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, is much cheaper than neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksonville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, is much cheaper than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>, is much
cheaper than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>

            While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> was puzzling over these discrepancies, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate student</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Smith</ENAMEX> was involved in an auto accident. The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> was at fault, but
he had few assets and no insurance, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> had to collect from his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX>. That unpleasant experience gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> the insight that led
to a new theory of insurance pricing.

            
In brief, the theory is that uninsured drivers
cause high premiums, and high premiums cause uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. In somewhat
more detail, a plethora of uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> increases the chance that, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, you'll have to collect from your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX> even when you're not at
fault. To compensate for that risk, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> charge higher premiums. But when
premiums are high, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> opt against buying insurance, thereby creating
the plethora of uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and completing the vicious circle. Once a
city enters that vicious circle, it can't escape.

            In other
words, insurance rates are driven by self-fulfilling prophecies. If everyone
expects a lot of uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> charge high premiums and then many
drivers choose to be uninsured. Conversely, if everyone expects most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> to
be insured, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> charge low premiums and then most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> choose to be
insured. Either outcome is self-reinforcing. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that falls into either
category (for whatever random reasons) remains there indefinitely.

            So it's possible that modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphians</ENAMEX> are paying an
exorbitant price for a brief outbreak of pessimism among their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>.
If, for just one brief moment--and contrary to all past
evidence--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philadelphians</ENAMEX> could believe that insurance rates will fall and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insured</ENAMEX>, that belief alone could cause insurance rates to
fall and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> to become insured. And then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever after</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s insurance market might look like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>'s.

            It's not certain that
a burst of optimism would be so richly rewarded; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>-style outcome
will be undermined if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> is home to enough of the "hard-core
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uninsured</ENAMEX>," who are unwilling to insure themselves even at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> prices.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith-Wright</ENAMEX> theory predicts that some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, but not all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, have the
potential to maintain low insurance premiums in the long run.

            But in
cases where that potential exists, it would be nice to see it realized. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way
to accomplish that is by enforcing mandatory-insurance laws. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright</ENAMEX>
point out that enacting a mandatory-insurance law, which a majority of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have already done, is not the same as enforcing a
mandatory-insurance law, which is nearly unheard of. Moreover, even where the
laws are enforced, minimum liability limits are typically very low, and
probably too low to make much difference.)

            
In theory, mandatory insurance could make life
better for everyone , including those who currently prefer to be
uninsured. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Philadelphians</ENAMEX> who are unwilling to buy insurance for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> might
welcome the opportunity to buy insurance for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>. So if mandatory insurance
yields a dramatic drop in premiums, then both the previously insured and the
newly insured can benefit. (In practice, there will probably be a small segment
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>-- presumably at the low end of the income distribution--who
will be unhappy about having to buy insurance even at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>. But income-based
insurance subsidies would allow even the poorest of the poor to share the
benefits of lower premiums.)

            For ideological
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">free-marketeers</ENAMEX> (like myself), theories like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s can be
intellectually jarring. We are accustomed to defending free markets as the
guarantors of both liberty and prosperity, but here's a case where liberty and
prosperity are at odds: By forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to act against their own
self-interest in the short run, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> can make everybody more
prosperous in the long run. (Though some diehard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> will object that
the prosperity is an illusion, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> that have been empowered to
make us more prosperous will inevitably abuse that power to our detriment.)

            Is it worth sacrificing a
small amount of freedom for cheaper auto insurance? I am inclined to believe
that the answer is yes, but the question makes me squirm a bit.

         
      
   
