
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me on Me</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garrison</ENAMEX> Keillor

            

               
                  (Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrison Keillor</ENAMEX>'s new book, Me by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Boy</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valente</ENAMEX> as Told to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garrison Keillor</ENAMEX> , was published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The publisher
describes it as "an uproarious political satire about a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX>
who's elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.")
               
            

            
               What have you got
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrison Keillor</ENAMEX>?
            

            Me:
Nothing.

            
               Come on, you're talking
to me.
            

            Me:
Nothing, really. Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> (this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before I was a second-tier
public radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>) I went to see his show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech College</ENAMEX>, caught
him out in the corridor, and lied to him about how much I liked his show
(really, he talks so slow it makes me nervous, plus all that lip noise
indicating introspection being released into the atmosphere) and, silly boy,
launched into how I was doing a live <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> radio show from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">greasy spoon</ENAMEX> and
all, and he looked at me and said, "Do you know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> is?" I did,
having just been there. But I vowed on the spot that, should I ever be in a
position to be accosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, or faux <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>, wanting to tell me
about their life, I would always have something more constructive to say.

            
               Unless you really have
to pee.
            

            Me:
True. But I try to emulate country music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>--they may be assholes, but
they're great to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>.

            
               Working on the asshole
part?
            

            Me: You
should talk.

            
               Right. So what besides
that?
            

            Me:
Nothing. Well, in every press interview I've ever had that goes over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> words,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them are "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrison</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keillor</ENAMEX>." That gets to you pretty quick. They
all want to talk about what we have in common, as if I'm doing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">standup</ENAMEX>. I told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Scene in Biloxi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, that I was up
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.67</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keillor Units</ENAMEX>, but that was just bravado and doesn't include royalties,
speaking fees, catalog sales, ancillary rights, etc. Now this well-timed new
book should put him way ahead. You could probably get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> of me for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garrison</ENAMEX> now.

            
               And a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> to be
named later. So it's the shadow thing?
            

            Me:
Yeah. Either he's getting bigger or the sun is setting.

            
               On the other hand, he's
got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Twain</ENAMEX> between him and daylight.
            

            Me:
That would account for the occasional white suit.

            
               And he's got to get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">past Ring Lardner</ENAMEX> first.
            

            Me:
True. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benchley</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.J. Perelman</ENAMEX> ...

            
               ... can rest in
peace.
            

            Me: You
said it .

            
               Who wins a Jesse "The
Body" vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kitty Boutique</ENAMEX>" grudge match?
            

            Me: My
money's on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garrison</ENAMEX>, as long as it stays out of the parking lot.

            
               Yeah, in a parking lot
he's dead, bent over the trunk of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trans Am</ENAMEX>, face smeared against the rear
window.
            

            Me:
Brains all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Oakley Thermonuclear Protection</ENAMEX> decal.

            
               Yeah. For messing with
the best.
            

            Me:
Hooyah! But if it's strictly hyperbole, with the ring strung with verbal barbed
wire, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garrison</ENAMEX> will helicopter him on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> finger so Jesse pees outside the
ring.

            
               Read the new book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me: Worse</ENAMEX>, I took it on
vacation. Fortunately, I had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s short stories. White <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> drinking
the same. Anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX> is kind of a comic book, very heavy on graphics
like you used to find in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> catalogs, and rife with bold print
emphasizing nothing in particular:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fairbanks White Blaze Vanderbilt Used Rambler Alcan Highway</ENAMEX> The post
office The cogs simply do not mesh As a bear would say goodbye to a leg
trap
            

            
               That's not bad. I kind
of like that.
            

            Me:
Sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Green</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>.

            
               So you pretty much
liked the book then?
            

            Me: No.
It's pretty hard to parody a parody.

            
               But it's "a political
satire."
            

            Me:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Farm</ENAMEX> was a political satire. "A Modest Proposal," was a political
satire. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrison</ENAMEX> has written is a parody. Look it up. And why do we call
him by his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name, anyway? What is he, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam"</ENAMEX>?

            
               Anything else you liked
about the book?
            

            Me: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> looking at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> spread "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Women</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>." Now that's funny.

         
      
   
