
   
   
      
         
            The Wimps Are Winning

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s advocacy of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX> bombing pause in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict was
getting much attention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of
Madrid both led with it, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welt</ENAMEX> reported progress in negotiations about it, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said on its front page that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were
"seriously considering" it. The idea, proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo D'Alema</ENAMEX>, is that the bombing should stop as soon as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security</ENAMEX>
Council resolution on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> settlement is drafted (rather than approved) so
as to avoid a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> veto. The airstrikes would stop before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> withdrew any of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--perhaps even before he
formally agreed to do so.

            It
seemed like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> for the wimps, but other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers--including the
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>--highlighted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> plan. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Independent</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> will "oppose fiercely"
any plan for a pause in the air war. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> also reported tension
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> led its front page with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> clash
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>." This was based on some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> press reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> in an "unusually difficult" telephone conversation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that he must
"get control" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spreading the impression that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them are not
getting on. There have been a number of articles in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> about supposed differences between them, especially over the issue of
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.

            The
other most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> angle in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was the first large-scale
desertions by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. This received front-page treatment in Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, but the
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> tempered the excitement with a big headline saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is "as strong as ever." Quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the
Times said that despite reports of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> deserting,
"the size of the military presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> remains at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40,000</NUMEX>, the same
as when the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> began." It saw this as a blow for those within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
who hope that the fight will have gone out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX>.

            There
was, however, a rare suggestion by an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> that the
air war might actually be working. Preparing to eat humble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>, military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian John Keegan</ENAMEX>, writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , of which he is
defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, said the desertions and reports of anti-war protests in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> are "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> indication that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s hold
over his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may be loosening." He said the "strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>" on both
sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> may have been wrong in relying on historical precedent to
pooh-pooh the idea of victory by air power alone. They may also have underrated
the new technology because "no self-standing air campaign has ever before been
mounted with precision <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keegan</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s main mistake may have
been to send barely trained teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conscripts</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, since their morale
is especially vulnerable. "Yet those who direct the war, if it comes right,
will still not have a proper reason to congratulate themselves," he wrote. "If
it is emerging that this is a war of morale--that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conscripts</ENAMEX>'
willingness to bear fear versus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s patience with apparent lack
of results--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> should now accept that
they have paid insufficient attention to supporting the morale of their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electorates</ENAMEX> and have been insufficiently calculating in attacking that of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>."

            For
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> developments paled in significance beside a
feared revival of home-grown terrorism. All the main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led on the
murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo D'Antona</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>,
who was shot outside his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in jeans and
denim jackets. A document purporting to come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Brigades</ENAMEX>, a guerrilla
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> thought to have been eliminated, later claimed responsibility for the
killing. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gloomily</ENAMEX> recalled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Brigades</ENAMEX>' bomb
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outrages</ENAMEX> and assassinations of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> said in a
front-page comment that there is an important difference now. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has a new
ruling class and a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has leadership," it said.

            In an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>, thanked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> for showing him the way to his election victory.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> got the [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> when that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was in a similar
situation to the [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> said. "He told me that the
accepted premise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was that they must lose elections. They lost for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX> and got used to it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> insisted on finding out why they really
lost, and in this way arrived at a victorious campaign."

         
      
   
