
   
   
      
         
            A Racist <STRONG><EM>Slate</EM></STRONG>?

            On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> debated a proposed resolution condemning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Conservative Citizens</ENAMEX>, a racist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> has come under fire for addressing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts Jr.</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> pre-empted consideration of the bill by introducing an alternative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> denouncing all forms of racism and bigotry without mentioning the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> specifically. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reps.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Canaday</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coyners</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> substitute (which failed to get the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>
vote required for passage), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> answered them from the floor:

            
               ... I would
just say to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, the gentleman from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, that it is an amazing thing
to me that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 4 years</TIMEX> when I have been attacked, when I have had
racist comments made about me, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> never came to the floor
and spoke up. The gentleman from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, when I have had racist attacks made
against me by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democrat Party</ENAMEX> back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, 
                     Slate
                   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>,
which is a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, no one ran to the floor to condemn
that.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Gottlieb</ENAMEX> of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to ask what he thought

                  Slate
                had done that constituted a racist attack.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Pryor</ENAMEX> pointed to a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Bedfellow"</ENAMEX> column that
I wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May, 1998</TIMEX>, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Football Caucus</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX> then forwarded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> by e-mail and asked what in it <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> found racist.

            
               From : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pryor</ENAMEX>

            
               Sent :
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25, 1999</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:16 PM</TIMEX>

            

               To : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Gottlieb</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>, the part in the story that says, "But despite
his go-along, get-along ... (through) if he weren't black," is the part we find
offensive in particular. Doubtful you would have said that about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>.

            And if you did, many
voices would have risen against you ...

            I then replied:

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>

            
               Sent:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26, 1999</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:45 PM</TIMEX>

            

               To: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Pryor</ENAMEX>

            Dear
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pryor</ENAMEX>,

            I can understand how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> might be annoyed by
my article, and how any number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might disagree with it for a variety
of reasons. But on what basis did he go onto the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and call

                  Slate
               , and by implication me, "racist"?

            You cite this passage: "But despite his go-along,
get-along affability, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> is unlikely to accomplish much in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. The
problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> would never be given a leading role in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> if he
weren't black."

            I can only guess at what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> might have
found offensive here. The phrase "go-along to get-along" has no racial
implication that I'm aware of. It's a standard description of party loyalty,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> most often in my experience to white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            Next we come to the phrase, "unlikely to to
accomplish much in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>." This is my prediction based on my assessment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>' record thus far and my opinion of his abilities. I might be wrong
in this forecast. But either way, it's got nothing to do with the fact that
he's black. Indeed, I say nearly the same thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> elsewhere in
the same article.

            The final sentence in the passage you cite contends
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> has been elevated within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> in part because
of his race. In other words, I think that affirmative action has played a role
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>' rapid ascent within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. Do you actually dispute this? Would you
seriously maintain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> would have been chosen to give the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> immediately after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> election
and to speak at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Convention</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>--to name only a few of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">honors</ENAMEX> and distinctions--if he happened to be white? But again, whether or not
I'm correct in my analysis, there's nothing racist about arguing that a member
of a minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>--whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>--has benefited from a
desire for diversity.

            Supportive of the party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> ... not especially
capable ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of affirmative action. I most certainly would say any
of these things about a black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> to whom they applied. In fact, I did say
them in a column about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Herman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months earlier</TIMEX>. No one accused me of
bigotry. And if someone had, I would have been just as offended as I am
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.

            Unless I'm missing
something here, I really think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> owes 
                  Slate
               ,
and me, an apology.

            Yours
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sincerely</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Weisberg</ENAMEX>

            To date, we have received no answer from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>
or his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. 's a link to my original article. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> can make up their own
minds about whether it constitutes a racist attack.

         
      
   
