
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Early
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Developers</ENAMEX>
            

            I always enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> but wanted to correct the impression from "" that teen movies began in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>. While it is true that films such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackboard Jungle</ENAMEX> , The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wild One</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East of Eden</ENAMEX> , and Rebel Without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cause</ENAMEX> tapped into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, the teen demographic was identified at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX> with the popular films starring the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead End Kids</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayer</ENAMEX> produced the bourgeois <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, the obscenely successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>
Hardy series starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Rooney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Garland</ENAMEX>, later teamed in the
archetypal teen pix <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Babes in Arms and Babes</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> made a likewise profitable series with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deanna Durbin</ENAMEX>, and over at RKO
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s</TIMEX>, the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shirley Temple</ENAMEX> starred in movies like The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bachelor</ENAMEX> 
               and 
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby-Soxer</ENAMEX> . It is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> that the
echt misunderstood teen film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knock on Any Door</ENAMEX> was made, starring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Derek</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misfit</ENAMEX> who wanted to "live fast, die young, and leave a
beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rickey</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>

            
               Leak
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> missed a
clear <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> spin in his "" item on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bakaly</ENAMEX>'s investigation and
resignation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bakaly</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wolves</ENAMEX> for leaking to deflect
attention from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s own leaks in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late January and early February of 1998</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bakaly</ENAMEX>'s disclosure would not violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rule 6</ENAMEX>(e), as it is more a legal
conclusion than evidence. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bakaly</ENAMEX> suffers little and can be the whipping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> for all leaks.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Rudman</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            

               Gunplay
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s "middle ground" on gun control
(see his "") seems to be that only untrained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. That
would be like the "untrained" 6-year-old who gets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glock</ENAMEX> down from the
closet shelf, or the drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> who gets out his old service revolver and
goes over to ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, or your convicted-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> neighborhood drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> who bought his streetsweeper from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who, it turns out, bought <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> of them at a gun show. See, it wasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>' fault--it was the
goshdarned untrained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>! If everybody just took NRA gun safety courses none
of this would've happened!

            Come on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>. It's
really cool to be postmodern and hip; but you have to pick your targets a bit
more judiciously.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J.</ENAMEX>
Berla
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               Beating Around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s "" takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> to task
for coyly sidestepping stands on significant issues. But the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> primary is a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> away, and the general election a year and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> away. It's already crazy
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have to run shadow campaigns for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and then form
exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> before formally announcing their candidacies. I suppose
in the election cycle for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> (which, by my calendar, starts in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>) potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will first announce plans to pick a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to
determine if the potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> should form an exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to
determine if they should run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            The absurdity here for
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> is that we don't want to hear a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>'
positions repeated ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nauseum</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 or 18 months</TIMEX>. Take the spotlight
off of them until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> lights come down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>. If TV
lights aren't there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will be forced to do something practical to
bide their time. And potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> won't have to be concerned about
establishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> to determine if they should throw out their televisions
and delete their bookmarks to e-zines until a more reasonable time next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Clark</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wife</ENAMEX>'s
Defense
            

            There is a curious symmetry between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who would like to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX>,
remain in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> forever. In "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> presents his own damning opinions on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX> case as if they were fact, in much the same way that these government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> accuse my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> of crimes for which he was never
indicted.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> did not commit, was not charged
with, and was not convicted of the outrageous charges now being hurled at him
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. There is no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> to the latest pack of lies proffered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , nor to the charges invented by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               . Moreover, no evidence to support any of these
false charges was presented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years ago</TIMEX> when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> entered into a plea
agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In other words, these charges are very
recent fabrications that have suddenly surfaced in the press to serve political
ends. Based on the evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> presented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX> was indicted on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> count only--passing classified information to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. He was not charged with intending to harm the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. He
was not charged with treason.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> count of passing classified information to
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX> was charged with usually carries a sentence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 to 4</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. No one in the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has ever received a life
sentence for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>--no one but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX>. As a result of a last
minute secret submission to the sentencing judge by then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casper Weinberger</ENAMEX>--which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> have never in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX> been
given the opportunity to challenge--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ignored the plea agreement and
meted out a life sentence without parole. Who plea bargains for a life
sentence?

            The "new" crimes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> is now being
accused of in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were, in fact, committed by a host of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> spies
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boone</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Pelton</ENAMEX>. But that has not
stopped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from continuing to publicly blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX>--and
by extension, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--for the damage done by these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy agents</ENAMEX>, nor has it
stopped irresponsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> from parroting these unsubstantiated lies.
What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> did do is warn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> had amassed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-approved and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-financed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction, which he
intended to use to scorch the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX> deeply regrets that he
broke the law in order to warn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> about this threat to her existence. He
had tried everything in his power to get the information released to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
through legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> but was thwarted every step of the way, right up to the
top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. It would appear that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>--Casper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Ray Inman</ENAMEX>, and others--were more concerned with the
world finding out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was arming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> at that time, than they were
about covertly violating their information-sharing agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. It
was in desperation that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> acted on his fear for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and
finally sought out the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> to warn them about this betrayal.

            Contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s contention, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX> has
expressed his remorse repeatedly--privately and publicly--and in various
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mediums</ENAMEX>. He deeply regrets not finding a legal means to act on his concerns for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> threat.

            There is still enormous embarrassment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s arming of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and the ongoing threat from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Madman of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>." The release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> would bring this shameful episode to
the forefront. For that reason fearful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> hurl false charges at him in
the media--never in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--to try to keep him in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX> and to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> forget about how he blew the whistle on a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tilt</ENAMEX>, long before it became public knowledge.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is doing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> just what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan-Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> did with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. For political and
economic reasons, a blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> has been turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> espionage in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is now armed with nuclear munitions
that could pose a major threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, just
like its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to look the other way, so it can downplay
the story in the media and give implausible explanations for why a top level
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> who provided nuclear munitions information to a hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should be
fired from his job instead of being brought to trial!

            Interestingly enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> don't
see fit to utter a peep of protest about the mishandling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>
case. Mindlessly they swallow whole what they read in the press and continue to
focus their hostility and anger on the wrong target. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> stole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
information on nuclear warheads for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and was fired. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> gave
information to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, about a threat to that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s survival and
he got life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proportional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> or political vengeance? Why is it that the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who are so relentless and vociferous in their condemnation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> are so utterly silent about all the other recent
spy cases where the charges were far more serious and the damage was
measurable?

            By mangling the truth
and presenting uninformed opinion as if it were fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> and

                  Slate
                have done a great disservice not only to the case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> but to the ongoing battle he is waging to restore the
principle of equal justice for all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX>
Pollard
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>
replies: I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Pollard</ENAMEX> on one crucial point: The fact that
the most damning allegations against her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> were never made
publicly--though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollard</ENAMEX> himself did see them--has muddied his case. No matter
how credible the allegations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX> piece are--and they are
extremely credible--they are unverifiable and irrefutable as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' damage assessment remains secret. This secrecy allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Pollard</ENAMEX> to
make bold claims about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s innocence and to dismiss these damning
allegations as the malevolent fabrications of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pollard</ENAMEX>-haters.
            

            
               But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> who
aren't married to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX> are left with a choice: Do we trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX>,
an admitted, unapologetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>, who told lie after lie after lie in the course
of stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> secrets, when he says he didn't take anything serious? Or do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Intelligence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committees</ENAMEX>, all of whom know exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollard</ENAMEX> did, and all of whom are
adamant he should be kept locked up?
            

            
               To <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Whine Own</ENAMEX>
Self
            

            In "" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sandel</ENAMEX> makes the lovely point that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewsinky</ENAMEX> might be guilty of a betrayal of herself. He notes that being
merely honest or truthful may not be the end-all of integrity, that integrity
is based on an identity, not primarily moral but ethical, the identity of and
with one's life-narrative. For <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> to be guilty of such a betrayal, though,
she would need to have a life-narrative, an explicit or implicit
understanding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> she would like to be. She clearly doesn't.

            The given complexity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">desires</ENAMEX> and adaptations that make up the ego suffice. "Be true to yourself" has
been reinterpreted to mean either "Getting what you want" or, more
aggressively, "Express yourself (don't repress yourself)."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
Feeney
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
