
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intellectuals Go</ENAMEX>
to War
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s intervention in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> has made strange bedfellows among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Pinter</ENAMEX> has pronounced the
bombing "misjudged, miscalculated, disastrous," and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niall Ferguson</ENAMEX> scoffs at the campaign's inadequacy in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">op-ed</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Bleeding Hearts and Bloody Messes</ENAMEX>"). Elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the
bombing include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germaine Greer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Bourdieu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christa Wolf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regis Debray</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noam Chomsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Magnus Enzensberger</ENAMEX>, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> arming the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>, begs to differ: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> themselves are not merely
capable of intervening [in this conflict], we are morally obligated to do so."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novelist Günter Grass</ENAMEX> supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> campaign and regrets only that it did
not come sooner, and he is seconded by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slovenian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavoj Zizek</ENAMEX>, who
denounces the hypocrisy he sees in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> demonstrations against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
bombs. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>," he writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are defiantly dancing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
while <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 kilometers</NUMEX> to the south, a genocide of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> proportions is taking
place." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleksa Djilas</ENAMEX> told
the Financial Times that although he would never have fought with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, if drafted now, "I would probably not resist."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> has proposed community service as a requirement for graduating from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University at</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monterey Bay</ENAMEX> already gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> course credit for performing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two semesters</TIMEX>
of mandatory public service. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to require community
service from its high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, following the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
emphasis on public service in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>. Who could object to such
civic-mindedness? In response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' objections, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayn Rand Institute</ENAMEX>
offers an internship of its own: Participating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> earn their community
service credit by working against volunteerism.

            
               This Class Is
Rated "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>"
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arizona</ENAMEX>
student who enrolled in a class called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Women in Literature</ENAMEX>" was dismayed to
discover that the class addressed gay and lesbian issues. As a result, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> is now considering warning labels for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> with
potentially "objectionable" content. Says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Regents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>
Gignac, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and they are paying to be taught. They
need to know in advance what it is they're paying for." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of such
course labels have suggested classes be rated like TV programs--but, Gignac
points out, "that might increase enrollment in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>" with particularly
racy ratings.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kitschy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Holocaust</ENAMEX>
            

            Is there a difference
between denying the value of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> scholarship and denying the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>
itself? One might think so. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary Senior</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> published scathing attacks on the kitschiness and
obscurity of contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> scholarship in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commentary</ENAMEX> and in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , he found out otherwise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Feinstein</ENAMEX>, acting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust and Genocide Studies</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Minnesota</ENAMEX>, wrote on an e-mail discussion list that Schoenfeld
"has done as much damage as deniers." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Littell</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> studies conference, accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> of "subtle denial." In
response, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Littell</ENAMEX> is not merely using vicious rhetoric
against a detractor, but engaging in behavior that itself undermines the cause
of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust remembrance</ENAMEX>."

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>
Revolution
            

anniversary of the liberation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>, we often refer to that event
in shorthand as the "fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX>." But should we refer instead to
"the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> round-table negotiations"? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> thinks so, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 9</TIMEX>, it gathered an array of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> to make the case. Most of the conference
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attendees</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Michnik</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Kwasniewski</ENAMEX>,
participated in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> talks that led to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. At the
conference, they defended their activities against numerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> denied they made too many compromises; priests
denied they had been co-opted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> denied they had
committed treason. "We were not servile to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>'s
last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, "we were helpless before that huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>."
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> had planned to protest the conference, upset
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> was paying to put former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> up in fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>. In fact, the protests did not occur.

            
               "I'd Like To Thank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>"
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Academia</ENAMEX>'s most popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-year fellowship</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>, has been awarded to dozens of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Harris</ENAMEX>, who will research the history of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> building, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams College</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Stamelman</ENAMEX>,
who will study the literature and culture of perfume. Meanwhile, the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library</ENAMEX>'s brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Scholars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers</ENAMEX> unveiled its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fellows</ENAMEX>, each of whom will receive a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> stipend and an office in the
venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. Chosen under the auspices of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Peter Gay</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> include cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berman</ENAMEX>, at work
on a literary and political history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan</ENAMEX> revolution; technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Gregory Dreicer</ENAMEX>, who will study the architecture of racial
segregation; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Kaplan</ENAMEX>, who studies the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>.

            
               For Whom the Calls
Toll
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Mason University</ENAMEX>
has dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star runners</ENAMEX> from the track <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for the wrongful use of
campus phones--and fired their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s track <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Gordon</ENAMEX>. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Showers</ENAMEX> allowed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> members
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMU</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s track <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>--all of whom hail from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>--to make
long-distance personal calls from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. After a routine audit of the
departmental phone bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMU</ENAMEX> discovered the calls and found them to be in
violation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> rules intended to curb recruitment abuses. Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX>
allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> to regain their eligibility by reimbursing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMU</ENAMEX>'s athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> has decided they will not run with the team this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">semester</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nazistudent</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wofford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spartanburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, staged a protest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX> against one of their
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis Wolfgang Hawke</ENAMEX>, a Web-savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX> who
runs a neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> from his dorm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawke</ENAMEX> is also double-majoring
in history and--sensibly enough--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>. While his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">banding</ENAMEX> to his racist <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Poverty Law Center</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawke</ENAMEX>
has garnered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful adherents</ENAMEX>, most of whom are linked to him
through his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knights</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX> Web site. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal-Constitution</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wofford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> don't feel they can do
much about the situation because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> rights, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> says, "There is no
feeling here that we just say it's free speech and go the other way. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> has the obligation to speak out forcefully against speech that is
offensive."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honk</ENAMEX> if You Love
Honkies
            

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> psychology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glayde Whitney</ENAMEX> has given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX> his
scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX>. In a foreword to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s latest book, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX>-page autobiography judged by hate group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> to
be the most naked statement yet of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand wizard</ENAMEX>'s racist views,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> a "seeker of truth," comparing him to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enlightenment</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philosopher Voltaire</ENAMEX> and declaring his vision of racially segregated societies
to be based on "good science." The endorsement--along with the revelation that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> has quietly pursued race-based research for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>--has provoked a
furor at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSU</ENAMEX>, which has the second-highest number of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. At a town meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy D'Alemberte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">declared Whitney</ENAMEX>'s beliefs "obnoxious" but defended the tenured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s
right to publish them.

            
               Look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
Label
            

            Abetted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> outreach
campaigns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are mobilizing in the name of labor on college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent State</ENAMEX> spoke out on
labor issues ranging from graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> unionization, academic stipends, and
teaching loads to sweatshop abuses. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, the protest was organized by the
Graduate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Students Organization</ENAMEX>, which is fighting for recognition from
university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>. Turning out to support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GESO</ENAMEX> and its recent study
claiming that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of undergraduate instruction at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is
performed by poorly compensated graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and adjuncts were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> student
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> and labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, including an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and
Nation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnist Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
Employment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relations Board</ENAMEX> has ruled in favor of allowing union elections at
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> campuses by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the semester</TIMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabbi</ENAMEX>
Went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gay Bar</ENAMEX>
            

            Confronted by an increasingly vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> of
rabbinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> rabbis, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Theological Seminary</ENAMEX> may be
forced to reconsider its ban on admitting homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. According to a
recent article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forward</ENAMEX> , the matter is expected to spark heated debate at the
late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>'s religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabbinical Assembly.</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>
prohibitions on homosexual acts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Committee on Law</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards</ENAMEX> declared a ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> within the rabbinate. A backlash against
the ruling has been growing ever since. At the very least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Gordon Tucker</ENAMEX>,
a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theological Seminary</ENAMEX> told the Forward that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabbinical Assembly</ENAMEX> should provide "assurances to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> ... that their
sexual orientation will not be a factor in limiting their options in furthering
their careers."

         
      
   
