
   
   
      
         
            I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have Read the Future</ENAMEX>

            Since the launch of 
                  Slate
                nearly
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>, we've joked about how you'd know when online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> were
ready for mass consumption. It would be when you could take them, like print
magazines, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>. Well, I'm here to tell you: I've read

                  Slate
                on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">john</ENAMEX>.

            Among the other places I
have been reading 
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>, an electronic version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , and the e-texts of various novels and short
stories, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of weeks</TIMEX>:

            

               Aloud to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>

               In a taxi, again at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>

               While brushing my teeth

               On a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> without an overhead light

               Standing on the subway

               In bed

               While eating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> with chopsticks

            

            These are situations in which reading is ordinarily
either awkward or impossible. They present no challenge, however, to my new
favorite gizmo, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Rocket eBook</ENAMEX>. I'm not what you would call an early adopter
when it comes to consumer electronics. I don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DVD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, an MP3
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">player, or a Palm Pilot</ENAMEX>. But I'm ready to blow <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$499</NUMEX> on a Rocket as soon as I
have to send my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">demo model</ENAMEX> back. This chunky little device, which weighs just
under a pound and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half</TIMEX>, actually deserves that overused epithet
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX>," because it has the power to change something as basic to human
civilization as the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> read.

            A lot has happened since
I wrote about  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>. You can now actually buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different models.
One is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softbook</ENAMEX>, which at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$299</NUMEX> appears less expensive than the Rocket but
actually costs more because you must commit to spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$479</NUMEX> on books over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> as part of the package. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softbook</ENAMEX> is a writing-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tablet</NUMEX>-size screen with
a leather cover that gives off what someone must have imagined to be the musty
scent of an old book (but is actually the smell of a new shoe). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softbook</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big advantage is that you don't need a PC to use it. You buy books directly
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softbook</ENAMEX> and download them into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> via a phone line. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softbook</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big disadvantages. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that it's poorly designed. The
screen is hard to read, navigating text is clumsy, and the whole device has an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unbalanced</ENAMEX> feel. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> drawback is it doesn't work. After reading a bit of
preloaded text-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack London</ENAMEX>--I couldn't download
anything else, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softbook</ENAMEX> soon purged its preloaded content as well. The
only other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> I know who has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softbook</ENAMEX> reports a similar failure.

            By contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket</ENAMEX>, which is made by a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>
start-up called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NuvoMedia</ENAMEX>, is ergonomically sound, with the pleasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heft</ENAMEX> of a
folded-over paperback. The screen is superb, and you get a choice of large or
small print as well as a variety of lighting settings. You can orient the text
horizontally or vertically and position the grip for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-</ENAMEX> or right-handed use.
And because it doesn't need to be held open, you can read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-handed. In fact, you can even prop it up and read no-handed if you're
eating something greasy or shaving. All you need is one clean finger to click
the "forward" and "back" buttons that move the text a page at a time. The
battery lasts for some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 hours</TIMEX> before needing to be recharged.

            And while the process of
getting stuff to read on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket</ENAMEX> is a bit involved, it actually works
remarkably well. First, you load the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rocket</ENAMEX> software onto your PC. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, you
register your eBook and get an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID</ENAMEX> and a password. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Noble</ENAMEX> Web site, which is (but won't be for long) the exclusive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distributor of Rocket</ENAMEX>-formatted content, and make your e-purchase. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> sends you an e-mail message with a Web link that allows you
to download what you've purchased into the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rocket Library</ENAMEX>" on your PC. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fifth</NUMEX>,
you transfer your book from your PC's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket Library</ENAMEX> to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocket</ENAMEX>, which has
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 mb</TIMEX> of memory (enough to hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> medium-length novels). The only hitch I
encountered in this procedure was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> to
e-mail the link I needed to download books I bought. (I understand that this is
not an uncommon problem.) Instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gratification</ENAMEX> is an important part of the
appeal of e-books, and I found this delay slightly maddening.

            There are other drawbacks of the sort you would expect from
any infant technology. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> stocks only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">524</NUMEX> eBook titles at
present, an unfortunately large number of them in the business and self-help
categories. You can buy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Endless Referrals: Network Your Everyday Contacts</ENAMEX>
Into Sales and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> Without Stress: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Far Eastern Antidote</ENAMEX> to Tension
and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Anxiety</ENAMEX> (which would seem to cancel each other out) but not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncovering Clinton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ground Beneath Her Feet</ENAMEX> . Recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> are gratuitously overpriced. The discount price of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashes</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.40</NUMEX> in paperback, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.50</NUMEX> in hardcover, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> for the eBook
edition.

            This makes no sense when
you consider that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> has eliminated such expenses as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>,
printing, binding, warehousing, distribution, and "returns." Another advantage
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> is that because a book is encrypted for a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>, it can't
be copied, forwarded, or resold. So, why are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> setting e-book list
prices so high? Because they fear e-books, even as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>, including a
sizable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, embrace them. When you think about it,
though, their positions might well be reversed. If e-books become a real
alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX>-books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> stand to gain by eliminating most of their
fixed costs and by being able to keep everything in print forever. They might
even envision cutting out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX>, namely the bookstore. If I retailed
books, I'd be worried. This, however, is only one scenario. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Eberhard</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NuvoMedia</ENAMEX>, thinks booksellers will remain part of the process.
"When's the last time you went shopping for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX> book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" he
asks. And it might be established <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> who would try to do an end run around
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX>. "It's not clear who gets disintermediated," he says.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> he really good news is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can disintermediate
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> and booksellers and get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> free.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocket</ENAMEX> released a beta version of software that lets anyone
upload texts to its site, creating a kind of open-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source library</ENAMEX>. The site
offers <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Art of War</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aesop's Fables</ENAMEX>, among
other titles. But more significantly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">eBook</ENAMEX> lets you download any
text-based content from the Web or your hard drive. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rocket</ENAMEX> software, I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downloaded Daisy Miller</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Mutual Friend</ENAMEX>, and some other
fiction in the public domain from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Gutenberg</ENAMEX> Web site before a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcontinental</ENAMEX> flight. Another feature I love is that you can find remembered
passages by word-searching these texts. You can also highlight words and look
them up in the pre-installed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Dictionary</ENAMEX>, though it didn't have
"arras," which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX> used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Nabokov</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               's"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club"</ENAMEX> (it means "tapestry"). And I figured out how
to download the full <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> text of 
                  Slate
                in one go by converting
the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Word file to the HTML
format. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Late</TIMEX>-model word processors allow you to use the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Save As</ENAMEX>" function to
save documents in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTML</ENAMEX>.)

            E-books are going to evolve. They will get lighter,
their screens will get more legible, and their batteries will last longer.
Soon, they may do what a related device called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Audible</ENAMEX> can do, and actually
read to you, either via sound files or text-to-voice software. E-books may
converge with other handheld devices. You can use the newest palm-sized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> as talking books or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>--though you wouldn't want to read a
novel on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, at least not yet. Most important, e-books will get cheaper. They
may even be given away, or sold at a token price with content purchase
agreements or subscriptions, on the model of cell phones. But I have no doubt
that they're coming. And when they truly arrive, I predict that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket</ENAMEX> will
be remembered as a landmark: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> demonstration that reading a "book"
didn't require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, ink, or even an overhead light.

         
      
   
