
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Calling</ENAMEX>

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">distinguished American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> complain that it's nearly impossible to get
their plays produced, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dramatist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX> has opened no fewer than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 12 months</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last spring</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s play about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judas Kiss</ENAMEX> , came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. It was followed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX> by his adaptation
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Room</ENAMEX> , which made the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> on the backside,
as it were, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX>. At the moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX> occupies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stages in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">View</ENAMEX> , starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judi Dench</ENAMEX>, is playing to full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel Barrymore Theatre</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hare</ENAMEX> himself is performing a monologue about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX> , at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Booth Theatre</ENAMEX>.

            It shouldn't come as any
surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> have a taste for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> drama. Stage envy is
a well-trod Anglophilic path, which has in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> widened into a
mostly one-way superhighway stretching from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West End</ENAMEX> to the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater District</ENAMEX>. Current productions that have breezed down it include The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX> , by the young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conor McPherson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Closer</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Marber</ENAMEX>. Lately, we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> even seem more interested in our own
playwrights when we see them reflected back at us by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX>. Revivals of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Williams</ENAMEX>' early work Not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightingales</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Neill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Iceman Cometh</ENAMEX> , starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX>, are both <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
imports. In a recent discussion in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts & Leisure</ENAMEX>" section,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> drama <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> discussed this phenomenon. Basically,
they all concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> is better.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hare</ENAMEX>, who now dominates <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> in a way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX>
never has, may illustrate a somewhat different phenomenon. There is, of course,
an element of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglomania</ENAMEX> in his success here. But I think it may also speak to
something more interesting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX> feeds an appetite for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> engaged with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, which our domestic dramatic economy isn't satisfying at the moment. He
is in almost every way an old-fashioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>, who uses dramatic form to
amplify questions of politics, religion, society, and relations between the
sexes. And while I think that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hare</ENAMEX>'s best work falls short of greatness,
the combination of his seriousness and his success bode well for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> as a
form on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s early work has the
reputation for being left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agitprop</ENAMEX>. In fact, while less skillful than his
later efforts, his early plays are not mere polemics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s first produced
play, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slag</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>), is a kind of dystopian fantasy about radical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminism</ENAMEX>, in which the attempt to run a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> dissolves into absurd
infighting. It is true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> socialism originally took
the not-very-novel form of negative portrayals of establishment institutions
and the residue of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> imperialism. But what soon began to distinguish him
from a lot of his like-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> were a low-key wit and an ability
to write memorable roles for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s first play to open at the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> (and currently being revived there) was
Plenty , later made into a film with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX> plays the role
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Traherne</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who works undercover in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
and subsequently finds herself unable to cope with postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> life.
Despite her craziness, we see that she has a point.

            His radicalism mellowed with time and success. Where once
he proposed a debate between between socialism and capitalism, between the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> World and the First as in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Map of the World</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s later
plays posit a subtler conflict over personal and political values. The first
time he really demonstrated this maturity was in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret</ENAMEX> Rapture
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), a work <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hare</ENAMEX> himself has pointed to as an important departure. It's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> who have to deal with the messy legacy of their departed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. One is generous and impractical. The other is ruthless and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-interested</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thatcherite</ENAMEX> vein but nonetheless sympathetic in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>, then the lead drama <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , who liked
the play when it debuted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, wrote a harsh review of the New York
production and especially of the performance by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s then-girlfriend
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair Brown</ENAMEX>. An embittered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hare</ENAMEX> pledged not to bring another play to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX> stopped reviewing.

            In following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, Hare
became more interested in the soul of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> under Thatcherism. In the early
1990s, he wrote a trilogy of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">State of the Nation" plays: Racing Demon</ENAMEX> ,
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murmuring Judges</ENAMEX> , about the legal system,
and The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Absence of War</ENAMEX> , about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX>. All opened to acclaim at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Theatre</ENAMEX> and provoked national debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. Racing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demon</ENAMEX>, a play about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, even came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> moved
on. Why, you have to ask, is it so seldom that important-seeming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> plays
address societal issues such as these? You might start with the fact that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, has no centralized national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, either
literally or figuratively. What occurs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> doesn't resonate
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, or even down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> corridor to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. And you
might add that the political interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwrights</ENAMEX> tend to revolve
more around issues of identity and less around national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>.

            We also have a different kind of theatrical tradition,
which is less talky and intellectualized than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> one. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>
whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hare</ENAMEX> harks back to most directly is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>. Though his wit is
not of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shavian</ENAMEX> sharpness, his plays are in another sense more sophisticated.
Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> tend to represent views pitted against each other,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s cannot resist becoming genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--contradictory, quirky, and
imperfect both as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>. The play where one sees this most
clearly is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skylight</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), for my money his most successful work. It's
the classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX> setup, a collision between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who see life differently
but are nonetheless connected: a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>-era <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> and his
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East End</ENAMEX>. You know where Hare
comes down in the debate between their values. But the play does not exist for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s worldview to vanquish the other's. Both are by turns
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuasive</ENAMEX>, flawed, and poignant.

            The recent offerings on
Broadway show not only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s gift for the exposition of issues but also his
limitations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Room</ENAMEX> , which I saw in its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> production last
fall, was probably the weakest of the bunch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schnitzler</ENAMEX>'s original play,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Ronde</ENAMEX> , was a scandalous-for-its-time depiction of empty sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promiscuity</ENAMEX>--so scandalous it wasn't meant to be performed. But with the shock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">value</ENAMEX> lost, the play needed something more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s topical amendments
added. His adaptation didn't provide much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for thought, which is unusual
for him. A bit of hackwork, it suggested that he might be spreading himself too
thin.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V ia Dolorosa</ENAMEX> , which I also saw in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, is more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulating</ENAMEX> (intellectually), but only a bit. Based on a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, it's
journalism by other means of the sort that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Deveare Smith</ENAMEX> has done so
brilliantly. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hare</ENAMEX> is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>. His performance adds little to his script,
and his script adds little to the subject, arriving mostly at familiar
platitudes about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, one has to admire his guts for trying to
entertain an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> single-handedly with a talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> politics,
no less. And the work is somewhat interesting despite its inherent limitations.
We see how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX> can turn even a monologue into a kind of dialogue of
perspectives, as he pits the passionate commitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>
against the humanism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">culturati</ENAMEX>. "Are we where we live or what we
think?" he asks at the end of the play. "What matters? <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stones or Ideas?</ENAMEX>"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">View</ENAMEX> , the best of the recent works
to show up here, is a more familiar and successful exercise. It is a play with
clear imperfections, such as an excessively shrill <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> act. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> forgives
such flaws because of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hare</ENAMEX> draws his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> into the play's issues.
Here the debate he sets up is a three-way among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>. Esme, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judi Dench</ENAMEX>, is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who lives for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s ethereal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> a little too good for
this world, lives for love. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominic</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX> who
lives only for himself.

            Within this conflict of values is a clash about
art. Dominic, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of exploitative films and television, contends that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> is a dead form. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esme</ENAMEX> stands in for the continued vitality of the
stage. The final act finds her having lost everything--her home, her financial
independence, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>--but performing brilliantly in a new play that
she describes as "sincere." We see her failings redeemed through commitment to
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. The same might justly be said of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who wrote the play.

         
      
   
