
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawkish Doves</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dovish Hawks</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, you may remember, opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> on the grounds that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s conquest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> was just one "nasty little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> invad[ing] a
littler, but just as nasty, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." So what does <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> think of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> intervention to stop nasty little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s invasion of littler,
but almost as nasty, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>? He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>.

            Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> declared before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, "If a small, heavily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militarized</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> can stand up to a global blockade [and] the opprobrium of
the entire world ... and still emerge intact and in possession of the fruits of
its aggression, the message to every other potential aggressor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> will
be clear: There are no rules in the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War world</ENAMEX>."

            So what's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX>'s view of the small, heavily
militarized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> that is standing up to a global blockade and the
opprobrium of the entire world? He would leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> intact and in
possession of the fruits of its aggression. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is performing a zoological alchemy on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s foreign policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawks</ENAMEX> have mysteriously become doves, doves
have inexplicably become <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> has upset the traditional taxonomy and
replaced it with what appears to be chaos.

            But it's not chaos.
Here's who is where on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and how they got there.

            
               Doves Into
Hawks
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The
Europeanists
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Biden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>, is the stellar example
of this category, which includes other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> who opposed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europeanists</ENAMEX> are pragmatic rather than moralistic about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX> opposed intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>. But he's
hawkish on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> because it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Africa</ENAMEX>, is a vital <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interest. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX> likes to say, is
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> power." (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europeanists</ENAMEX> are also NATOists. They say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will be
ruined if it doesn't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must support the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europeanists</ENAMEX>' claims
are somewhat disingenuous: It's hard to argue that benighted, bankrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
is a more vital <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interest than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>-rich, centrally located <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>. So
there is another, unspoken, reason why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeanists</ENAMEX> favor intervention: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humanitarians</ENAMEX> (a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red-Tailed Hawks</ENAMEX>)
            

            Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europeanists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Liberal</ENAMEX> Humanitarians
have turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> for moral reasons. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have opposed every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grenada</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Wellstone</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> is a pre-eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Humanitarian</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> opposed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, and the control of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX>
oil was not a cause worth dying for. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wellstone</ENAMEX> favors <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> intervention
to stop the "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>-like atrocities" occurring there.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Liberal Humanitarians</ENAMEX> are a product of the
post<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-Cold War</ENAMEX> peace. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> shunned military
intervention--even humanitarian military intervention--because such adventurism
could provoke conflict with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> and tended to buttress thuggish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">right-wingers</ENAMEX>. The end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> has freed them to pursue humanitarian
ends: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> now can be the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>, so it
should be.

            (A special place in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Humanitarian pantheon</ENAMEX> belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX>. Click to read why.)

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third</ENAMEX>
Worlders
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> of this small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> but has since
favored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Worlders</ENAMEX>
share most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Liberal</ENAMEX> Humanitarians but are particularly
hawkish about helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> traditionally shunned by the West, notably
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. In this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> avidly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muslim Kosovars</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. The Credibility
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fanatics</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> is the
intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Credibility Fanatics</ENAMEX>. They are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who
fundamentally detest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and have little interest in the
morality of the issue. They don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is important enough to fight
for, they wish we had never gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX>, and they think it will be a
horrible, ugly conflict. But while their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> instincts are dovish, they are
Real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX> (pronounced "ray-all"): Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has committed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, we must win. If we don't, the credibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> will be shattered. Unsurprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Hagel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Credibility Fanatics</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Caspar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Weinberger</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX>, a kind of
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europeanists</ENAMEX>, deserves his own category. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger Doctrine</ENAMEX>, which precludes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action except in absolutely
vital cases of national security, would seem to bar any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> intervention.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX> has declared that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> are a vital national
interest because they "were at the heart of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> world wars." Hence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> should intervene--and with overwhelming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawks Into</ENAMEX>
Doves
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The
Neo-Isolationists
            

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> belong in this category,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> were hawks,
believing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should intervene promiscuously to reverse communism
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> Doctrine"). Now that there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil Empire</ENAMEX>, they
believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> shouldn't intervene militarily unless national
security is really at stake.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neos</ENAMEX> cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> reasons for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dovishness</ENAMEX>. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is not a vital <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interest: It has no
commercial or strategic value. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX> rout of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is a civil war, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should not involve
itself in civil wars. We leave sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> alone. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, and more
preposterously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Inhofe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> claims that interceding on behalf
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovars</ENAMEX> demonstrates a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European-American</ENAMEX>" bias in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy.
Why don't we help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwandans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> fits in the
neo-isolationist category, but not perfectly. Click for why.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neo</ENAMEX>-Isolationists
are not entirely insincere: They really do believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is too
irrelevant to national security to risk <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lives. But there's also
another major reason they have turned dovish: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and they side against him reflexively.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The
Paleo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isolationists</ENAMEX> (a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtledoves</ENAMEX>)
            

            They are the mirror image
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Humanitarians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neos</ENAMEX>,
they are <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> burnouts. They were ferocious <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cold Warriors</ENAMEX>, but they favored
military action only to defeat the communist menace, not for any greater moral
purpose. Now that there is no menace, they have withdrawn into their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shells</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Paleos</ENAMEX> believe almost nothing justifies intervention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> on the grounds that it was irrelevant to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s vital
interests. (Any oil price increase caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s takeover, he claimed, would
help the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.) If the invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
didn't qualify as a vital interest, then a civil war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> certainly
doesn't. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neos</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paleos</ENAMEX> are not against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> bombing for
partisan reasons: They would oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> involvement even if a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
Analogists
            

            This is less a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> than
an undercurrent. No one has explicitly adopted this position: The closest there
is to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 
               Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> have exploited the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war by likening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">viciousness</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> cruelty toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analogists</ENAMEX> would turn that comparison around. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX>, for instance, opposes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> bombing partly because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation</ENAMEX>
Army are morally equivalent in their brutishness. Just as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> conflict is more complicated than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> cartoon
of it, so too the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> war is subtler than it seems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> even
tacitly compares <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are as likely to give up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
willingly because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> want it as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> are to give up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> want it." (The subtext: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> has as much right to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> does to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>--namely, a lot.)

            
Not all hawks and doves have changed places.
Consider:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The
Conservative Moralists
            

            This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeane Kirkpatrick</ENAMEX>, and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neoconservatives</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Reaganites</ENAMEX> who did not give up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX>, moralistic vision when the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> ended. They don't believe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">communism</ENAMEX>'s defeat ended <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s global obligations: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should
still strike boldly against authoritarian oppressors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative</ENAMEX>
Moralists are less concerned with the national interest than with what's right.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , for example, editorializes that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should support
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> action unless they want to become "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of callous indifference to
human suffering."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old-School</ENAMEX>
Lefties
            

            The rest of the left may have turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, but a few die-hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doves</ENAMEX> remain. The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , for example,
has written extensively against the war. A recent cover story argued that the
bombing was dubious because a) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was just as brutal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are now; b) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> ignores similarly horrific ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cleansings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, etc.; and c) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy is being driven by
corporate interests. It's reassuring to know that some things, indeed, never
change.

         
      
   
