
   
   
      
         
            What Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Permissiveness</ENAMEX>?

            It's
not easy to tell from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is heading on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. There
seems to be a consensus around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Fitchett</ENAMEX>'s statement in the lead
story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18</TIMEX>, the date
of a summit between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, is a "make-or-break date for
the air war to produce a political solution." If no breakthrough occurs by
then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitchett</ENAMEX> explained, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will have to choose between ground action and an
admission that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> has won, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s central war
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aim</ENAMEX> of getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> home will have become unachievable. But
beyond that, there is no clarity on who stands where on what, especially on the
controversial issue of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.

            The
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, for example, on an agreement between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to use ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> "to drive the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>" in either a "permissive" or "non-permissive" environment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is
"ready to go in fighting," it said. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , in its lead story
reporting a doubling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s land <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>, said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX> has "secured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s backing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to
enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>'s approval as soon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> begins
withdrawing."

            
However the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , leading on the same thing, reported "a difference
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> could be sent into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>'s agreement." It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> as contradicting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s "significant" statement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> are being prepared for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deployment</ENAMEX> into a "non-permissive environment." She was quoted as saying,
"Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> are going to go in a permissive way." Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> clash again on when to send in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> had "flatly contradicted" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>. In an editorial, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Independent</ENAMEX> presented the agreed build-up of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> as a triumph
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> after his "surprising and apparently
reckless absolutism in his conduct of the war" by ruling out any "exit
strategy" except total victory. "Even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellor</ENAMEX>
Schröder were at their most flaky <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, he blithely insisted there could
be no compromise and that all options, including the use of land <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>,
remained open," it said. Now he has what he wanted.

            A
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> editorial described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualty</ENAMEX> of the war. It
said it has made his "essential task" of putting some distance between himself
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> much harder. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cannot do anything other than support the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s conduct of the conflict," it explained. "He is therefore tied to an
enterprise that has, so far, reflected Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s political weaknesses. He
has never felt comfortable with his role as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>, and neither has
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> led on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> that he is continuing with the airstrikes but not ruling out
"other options." It called this "a semi-threat of ground intervention."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX>
highlighted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s remark that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> are
"<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99 per cent</NUMEX> totally agreed" on their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> strategy, although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> are among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> declared their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> opposition to
the use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> led on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s supposed satisfaction
with its achievements so far--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> bombs having destroyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s
heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">weaponry</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a report that a "fascist clique" is responsible for a plot to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assassinate Sonia Gandhi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajiv Gandhi</ENAMEX>, who was himself assassinated. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Party</ENAMEX>, of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Gandhi</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> until she recently resigned
in a huff when her "foreign birth" was criticized, warned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atal Bihari Vajpayee</ENAMEX> that the same "clique" that murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahatma Gandhi</ENAMEX> more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51 years ago</TIMEX> was behind it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> has already
been warned of "certain plots" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Gandhi</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> intelligence
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> and has increased the security around her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>
she said that she too feared she would be murdered and had therefore decided to
stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> rather than return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to fight a conviction for
corruption.

         
      
   
