
   
   
      
         
            

             

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe DiMaggio</ENAMEX>
died of complications from lung cancer surgery. News accounts recited
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumé</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> championships, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> All-Star
games, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American League Most Valuable Player</ENAMEX> awards--but focused on
his record <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> game hitting steak in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>, which still stands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. While
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> compared his greatness on the field to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lou Gehrig</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> traced his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> to his courteous, humble,
all-American, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants personality</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> represented
the grace and dignity of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">good old days</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty Cobb</ENAMEX> represented the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pugnacity</ENAMEX> and decadence of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">good old days</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> was the exception.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/8/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, announced he is forming a presidential campaign
exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. Though he won't officially declare his candidacy until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, he paraded notable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> such as former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts Jr.</ENAMEX>, before the press. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> also listed
scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> who are backing him. Everyone
agrees his strategy is to create an air of inevitability and suffocate his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. The spins against him: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He's inexperienced in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
He's inexperienced in national politics. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) He has no base. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) He lacks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> in early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) He's had it too easy and is due for a fall. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)
His expectations are too high. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s entry into the race will
kill his momentum. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> don't know what he stands for. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) He
doesn't know what he stands for. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/8/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Film director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> died . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obituaries</ENAMEX> recalled his movies' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Awards, focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangelove</ENAMEX> , A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clockwork Orange</ENAMEX> , and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Odyssey</ENAMEX> , also mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lolita and The</ENAMEX>
Shining . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> debated the significance of the bleak fantasies in
which he portrayed human recklessness, madness, brutality, murder, and nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">holocaust</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-cynical spin: He hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and portrayed them as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savages</ENAMEX>. The completely cynical spin: He hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and portrayed them as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savages</ENAMEX> because they deserved it. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/8/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> aired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> . The biggest news that
wasn't leaked prior to the broadcast: Between trysts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had
another affair leading to an abortion. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy million</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> watched the
interview. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> had forbidden <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to
talk about him in the interview, she bashed him separately in her book, which
is outside his jurisdiction. Pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) She's a
fool for love. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) She's smarter than we thought. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) She's still loyal to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She's vain. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) She's amoral. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) She's a savvy,
pernicious temptress. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) She's shameless. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) She makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> look moral by
comparison. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) She reflects our decadence. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) She reflects our empty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sentimentality</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) She reflects our tasteless commercialism. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" analysis of the interview, and for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culturebox</ENAMEX>" take.)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
A court-martial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> acquitted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">U.S. Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ashby</ENAMEX> of involuntary homicide
and manslaughter in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> ski lift accident. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashby</ENAMEX>'s jet severed the
lift's cables, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skiers</ENAMEX> . He still faces trial on a
charge that he obstructed justice by ditching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s videotape of the
accident. Evidence in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trial indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was flying too
fast and too low but that incomplete <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military maps, poor training,
inadequate communications, and a possibly faulty altimeter may also have
contributed to the accident. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> are outraged. The naive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> spin:
There is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> spin: To get justice
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> we'll have to file a lawsuit. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Blackmun</ENAMEX> died . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obituaries</ENAMEX> fulfilled his prediction
that he would always be associated with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> opinion in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> . The conservative spin on his career: He snookered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and
undermined justice by evolving from a law-and-order moderate into a flaming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackmun</ENAMEX>'s spin: He remained a moderate but seemed increasingly
liberal by comparison as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> took over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The liberal spin:
He served justice by evolving from a law-and-order moderate into a flaming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan Hutu</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels abducted</ENAMEX> and murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> , including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealanders</ENAMEX>. The selection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> was evidently deliberate. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, with
help from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, are tracking down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">culprits</ENAMEX> and vow to
bring them in dead or alive. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
adequately warn the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> of danger? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX> government
adequately warn the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) If the lives of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are so important, why haven't we paid more attention to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX>
Africans similarly massacred in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX> civil war? (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/3/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
