
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">197</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;A Man Has Needs&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Press</ENAMEX> assesses the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX>-to-be-announced
presidential bid of his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playmate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. "He is
convinced that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> stumbles, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.W.</ENAMEX> stumbles, in a field of
pygmies, he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>. This is not just a need for ____________ on his
part."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 196</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Go":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     
                        
                           <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has already got rid of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66,000</NUMEX>, and by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year's end</TIMEX> will remove <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 800,000</NUMEX>.
What?
                        
                     
                  
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoners</ENAMEX>' kidneys."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foreskins</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> calendar, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year of the Rabbi</ENAMEX>. Or was that
a typo?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Cornog</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Daughters</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tullis</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nell Scovell</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter Miller</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb Stavin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rickey</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Spencer</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

               "Pesky
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollars that rightfully belong in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaign coffers. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Multiply</ENAMEX>
all figures by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Welty</ENAMEX>
               

               "God, I
hope it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientologists</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX>
               

                

               Click
for more answers.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> were a radio
panel show--a sort of What's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Line / I've Got a Secret with Larry</ENAMEX>
Amaros as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennet Cerf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene Francis</ENAMEX>, or perhaps the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> around, whatever they like--the great advantage (beyond the chance to hear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX> being audibly disdainful) would be posing several questions a day.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A dozen</NUMEX> per program would form an interesting outline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, but choosing
just one is tough. Excellent topics are lost. For instance, in an effort to
counter its image as an occupying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> brutalizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police department</ENAMEX> plans to recruit more actual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> to its ranks.
The heart of the plan will be an ad campaign with a snappy slogan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Safir</ENAMEX> says he wants "Be all you can be, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> wants
you, or something like that." Too militaristic? Just militaristic enough.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited, in the privacy of their own thoughts, to devise an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NYPD</ENAMEX> recruiting slogan. It's my anniversary gift to you. Isn't it better than
something impersonal like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>?

            
               What's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mine Is Your</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is clearing land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> along its border with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.

            In other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> news, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> has destroyed its entire stock of anti-personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
before the deadline set by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ottawa Convention</ENAMEX>. This treaty, banning land
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mines</ENAMEX>, has been signed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
among them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Committee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> estimates that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>
kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and maim <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 1,200</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>.

            For
more information, write to:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Campaign To Ban</ENAMEX> Landmines
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Wareham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans of America Foundation</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> S <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suite</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">740</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC 20009</ENAMEX>
E-mail: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">mary@vi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>'s
Anniversary Extra
            

            Please indulge me as I revisit some of the moments
that have made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> so very special to me over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. Sadly,

                  Slate
                offers no soft-focus or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RealAudio</ENAMEX> function, but feel free
to smear a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaseline</ENAMEX> on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> and hum an evocative tune to yourself as you reminisce with me.

            

               Strolling on the beach with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lerangis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter Miller</ENAMEX>,
picking up sea shells and admiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>'s superior sand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> building
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technique</ENAMEX>, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Galbraith</ENAMEX> suddenly appeared and stamped the delicate
structure to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX>.

               Sitting quietly in a dark <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb Stavin</ENAMEX>, exchanging favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schopenhauer</ENAMEX> quotes ("There is no doubt that life is given us, not to be
enjoyed, but to be overcome") until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Galbraith</ENAMEX> flicked on a harsh
fluorescent lamp and blasted the stereo.

               Enduring a tense dinner out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX>--a meal marked by painful silences and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> running sobbing from the
table every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">few minutes</TIMEX>, and thankfully interrupted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Galbraith</ENAMEX> calling
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Department</ENAMEX> and having the joint shut down.

               Enjoying this wonderful Web site featuring the extraordinary work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>, though knowing at any moment <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Galbraith</ENAMEX> could hack my gratuitous
plug to smithereens.

            

            Music up, fade to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pink</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Female infanticide.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
