
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Loeb</ENAMEX>
Blow
            

            I am pained by the of me in

                  Slate
                for writing an essay on personal finance that ran
in a special advertising section in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . Much or
all of the criticism is based on a false assumption: that I was paid by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for this assignment.

            In fact, I did not receive payment from
anybody--not <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one penny</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> did offer to pay me a fee, size
unspecified. I declined. But I suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> might want to make a
contribution to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> of which I am an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recording for the Blind & Dyslexic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , of course, was pleased to
do so. I do not know the size of this contribution. My name will in no way be
attached to it. I certainly will not receive a tax deduction for it. I will
receive no credit for it in any way. To reiterate as emphatically as I can: I
was not paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , not paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Inc.</ENAMEX>, not paid by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, not paid by anybody in any way. This a key point that I should
have clarified and corrected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>.

            So why did I accept the writing assignment? I did
it because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> offers a magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, because I frankly don't
mind the limelight, and because I believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and cautions I have
to offer about personal finance may be useful to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            This is also a good time
for me to reiterate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX> was, is, and
always will be independent, tough-minded, fair, and impartial in all its
judgments.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Loeb</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX> replies: When I interviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loeb</ENAMEX>, he said, according to my notes, "I am paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Inc.</ENAMEX>" He did not tell
me that the payment had been made to charity and not to him personally. He now
says he does not remember whether the decision to give it to charity was made
before or after my item appeared. He also says that payment for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advertorials</ENAMEX> went to his book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> and that he also did not profit
directly or indirectly. This is something else he did not mention in our
interview. It seems clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loeb</ENAMEX> has not personally profited from writing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advertorials</ENAMEX>. I think my misunderstanding on this point is understandable, but
I apologize for suggesting otherwise. I still think it is wrong from someone in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loeb</ENAMEX>'s position to be writing advertorials, even for free.
            

            
               Game Over (and
Over)
            

            Your discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> as it relates
to online auctions (see "") overlooked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very important point: the multiplier
effect that comes from the power of the Internet to reduce transaction
costs.

            Let's take video games as an example. Over the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> I have bought one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new video games a year, ones that seemed so
great that they were worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the $50</NUMEX>. The main reason I only bought one or two
was I knew that after playing them I would generally be stuck with them. Sure,
I might be able to sell them to a used software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, but I wouldn't be able
to get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $5</NUMEX> or so because those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> must mark them up so
substantially to cover their own costs. Now, thanks to Internet auctions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>
being my personal favorite) I can do most of my game shopping online. When I
was interested in picking up the new smash hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unreal</ENAMEX> , I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>
and saw that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past month</TIMEX> some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70 or so</NUMEX> copies of that game had been
auctioned for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $22</NUMEX> each. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following week</TIMEX> or so I tracked the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> auctions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unreal</ENAMEX> that were going on, and I eventually won a copy
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18.50</NUMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> shipping. The game arrived, I played it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>, and
then I put it back up for auction right there on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> and made back almost all
of my money.

            Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> know that there is a fluid
aftermarket for video games, they are more likely to go into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and buy
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these games for full price on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> it comes out. They know that they
can play it and auction it off right away online when its value is still quite
high. The net result is not only far more transactions at much lower costs but
also a sharp increase in market participation, thanks to the price
discrimination seen over time. (If you're not willing to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22</NUMEX> wait a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> until the online market is only going for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX>.)

            In addition, any effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> are
offset by the fact that "losing" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> become "winning" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> when they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-auction products. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> can therefore be said not to exist for
products that we buy, enjoy, and resell without using up their inherent
value.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> may be
pervasive in auctions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie Babies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faye Dunaway</ENAMEX>'s eye mask, but that
is in large part because those items have such little inherent value, and they
can lose their public appeal <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. Even there, though, the magic of the
Internet auction helps out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last time: He who has overpaid for Faye
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunaway</ENAMEX>'s eye mask can enjoy it for a bit and then put it right back up for
auction.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Epstein</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlottesville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> by Any
Other Name
            

            Just a point of
clarification--these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovars</ENAMEX>, not "ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>"
as much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> keep singing. If they are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovars</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>
is an "ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> is an "ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Wiesenthal</ENAMEX>
is an "ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>," and so on. Please label things correctly. Calling the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> "ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>" makes it sound as if they are really <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>,
though they have lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 500 years</TIMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX>
Hamod, Ph.D.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clearing</ENAMEX>
Up
            

            "" asked, "Why did the weather prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> from
hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> forces purging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, when it didn't seem to hamper
the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>? ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have shed little light on how poor
weather can impede various missions."

            Here's the answer:
Bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, or other fixed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> with known coordinates, can
be accomplished by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Positioning System</ENAMEX>, a satellite navigation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">service</ENAMEX>)-guided <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tomahawk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. It is not necessary to be
able to see the target. Bombing mobile targets, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> performing
ethnic cleansing, requires the use of laser-guided <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Because we don't
know in advance where these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> will be, we can't use GPS-guided <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>,
and laser-guided weapons require clear weather to operate.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cmdr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chesapeake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
