
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do You Mean by &quot;Violence&quot</ENAMEX>;?

            At his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> summit on youth violence this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> summed up the prevailing wisdom about entertainment and
its connection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, murders. "We cannot pretend that there
is no impact on our culture and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that is adverse if there is too
much violence coming out of what they see and experience," he said. In other
words, the issue is the quantity of violence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> absorb from
television, video games, and movies. Countless academic studies frame the
problem this way. They seek--and usually find--a correlation between how much
violent entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> consume and how aggressively they behave.

            This view isn't wrong, it's just way too crude.
Asking whether violence on screen foments violence in life is like asking
whether drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquids</ENAMEX> leads to car accidents. In a dumb way, the answer is
yes. But you're not going to get anywhere until you distinguish between
alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverages</ENAMEX> and nonalcoholic ones.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> prefer
to address this issue at this level of generality because it lets them off the
hook. "If you're looking for violence, what about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geffen</ENAMEX> asked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> just before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
conference. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>; it's on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. It's not a
movie, it's real." If the problem is merely the quantity of violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> see,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geffen</ENAMEX> is right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teen-agers</ENAMEX> can get plenty of gore without ever renting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slasher</ENAMEX> film. But we all know from personal experience that different sorts of
screen violence have drastically varying emotional effects. Some depictions
whet our appetites for brutality, while others do just the opposite. These
all-important distinctions are not ones that epidemiologists or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologists</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> can measure very effectively, because they involve a strong
subjective element. But until we begin to distinguish among the different ways
violence is portrayed, we can't begin to understand what those portrayals may
do. Here are some categories that may be helpful in thinking about the
issue:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> ragic 
               Violence: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Needless</ENAMEX> to say,
tragedy is often very violent. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Branagh</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-hour</TIMEX> film version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamlet</ENAMEX> . Having punctured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laertes</ENAMEX> and launched him over a balcony,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamlet</ENAMEX>, in the climactic scene, impales <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claudius</ENAMEX> with a flying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>, brains
him with a swinging chandelier, and force-feeds him poison. (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">View</ENAMEX> the scene
above.) A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> watching this sequence in isolation might say that the
violence is "cool," in a low-tech sort of way. But how does this violence make
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult viewer</ENAMEX> feel? In the context of the play, the most prominent emotions
it arouses are the ones <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX> identified as the essence of tragedy: pity
and fear. We pity a tragic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hamlet</ENAMEX> because his misfortune is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undeserved</ENAMEX>, and we tremble at the realization that he is like us. Tragedy
doesn't stir violent urges but rather inhibits them. That is why war films like
All Quiet on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Front</ENAMEX> are often described as "pacifistic." The
tragic context of the violence sensitizes us to its horror and makes us revile
it.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Righteous Violence</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotelian</ENAMEX> opposite of the pity and
fear is righteous indignation. This is the feeling we get when we see bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> flourish. It is stoked when we see them get their just deserts. That's
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> movies are all about. Typical of this type of drama is the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Enforcer</ENAMEX> , a sequel to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Harry</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> pursues
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie terrorists</ENAMEX> who murder assorted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX> and kill his female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in a shootout. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX> remedy the situation with a handheld mortar
above.) The way you feel watching this act of violence is very different from
the way you feel at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> . You experience satisfaction and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glee</ENAMEX>, not pity and fear. You want to exclaim "Yes!" instead of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>!" In this
category are most war movies as well as the oeuvres of Arnold
Schwarzenegger, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Bronson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Seagal</ENAMEX>. In such films, the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
become increasingly subhuman and thus deserving of more and more grotesque
forms of torture and dismemberment. In this sense, the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hays Office</ENAMEX>
production code, which required that films teach a moral lesson by having
evildoers punished, had it backward. If you want to discourage violence, you
should show the innocent suffering, not the guilty.

            G raphic 
               Violence: Is a more
realistic depiction of gore, in which someone's head is chopped off, affording
a glimpse of severed tendons and gushing arteries, worse in terms of inuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to violence than generic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mayhem</ENAMEX>, in which the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> fall over dead?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body-counters</ENAMEX> tend to assume that graphic violence is worse. But more
realistic depictions may prevent violence from becoming an abstract idea. Once
again, the context is what matters. In a tragic story, graphic violence makes
horror more horrible. A retributive context makes extreme gore less horrible.
If I were a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX>, I'd try to keep them away from Marked for
Death but not from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> , even though the latter is
far more vividly gruesome.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pornographic Violence</ENAMEX>: In horror films such as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
               , the issue of whether anyone deserves torture and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dismemberment</ENAMEX> is immaterial. The deliciousness of the violence is the whole
point. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> a clip from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scream , in which Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX> gets stabbed
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX> and dragged about her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> by a masked serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> above.) If
you're squeamish, you may cover your eyes when seeing this in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. But
the horror is undeniably thrilling, in a sexual way. There's an obvious
parallel between the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-splatter climaxes in horror movies and the "money
shots" in sex-porno. Indeed, the only difference between this kind of slasher
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> and snuff films is that no <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are harmed in the making of the
former.

            I ronic 
               Violence: There
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who will tell you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scream</ENAMEX> and the meta-horror subgenre
that developed from it are not crudely sexualized violent films. They're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-conscious</ENAMEX>, postmodern comments on crudely sexualized violent films.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of violent entertainment tend to hate this defense. It doesn't matter,
they say, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are butchered ironically in films such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Natural Born Killers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>'s Reservoir
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dogs</ENAMEX> . Here, I think the difference between the response of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> and
that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> becomes crucial. (Check out the torture-dungeon scene from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarantino</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp Fiction</ENAMEX> , in which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsellus</ENAMEX> promises sweet
revenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has just raped him, above.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX>, or at least most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, recognize this as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of black comedy, albeit one that expresses
a real sadism on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. But to immature minds, the message
may be simply that brutality is cool and funny. In other words, ironic violence
may be desensitizing and stimulating to the young in the same way that
pornographic violence is.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartoon Violence</ENAMEX>: What of films such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , in which the violence is not quite ironic but rather so hyperbolic and
unreal that it becomes a cartoon? Or, for that matter, what of cartoons
themselves, which are filled with calamities without consequences? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch Wile</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Coyote</ENAMEX> blown up, reconstituted, flattened, and reinflated above.) You might
think that such portrayals teach the false lesson that violence doesn't have
real effects. Perhaps for those too young to distinguish fantasy from reality,
that's the case. But there's not much basis for thinking that this confusion
persists. By the time a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is old enough to borrow his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> (say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>),
he understands that cartoons and comics don't describe the real capacities of
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>.

            S chool 
               Violence: Since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> killings, there's been a special focus on depictions of
adolescents committing mayhem in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> films cited most often are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heathers , in which Christian Slater</ENAMEX> is foiled in an attempt to detonate
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Basketball Diaries</ENAMEX> , in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>
fantasizes about gunning down his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terminator</ENAMEX> -style while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> cheer. (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">View</ENAMEX> a clip from the movie,
above.) This scene is now the centerpiece of a lawsuit by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paduchah</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, who say the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> who killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> was motivated by
the movie.

            Of course, it is always possible that an unbalanced
individual will misunderstand something in a crazy way, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hinckley</ENAMEX> did
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver</ENAMEX> . But you can't protect yourself against the criminally
insane by cutting off their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of possible inspiration, which are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limitless</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sane adolescents</ENAMEX> seeing either of these films would understand that
it is the violent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who are supposed to be deranged--in the case of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basketball Diaries</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. I'd worry more about The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage : Carrie 2</ENAMEX> , which mixes righteous indignation with pornographic
violence in a school setting. The issue isn't how much violence. It's what
kind.

         
      
   
