
   
   
      
         
            Divide and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
Daily said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in an editorial that behind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s "barbaric air
strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>" lies a plan to divide <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and dominate the
world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' secret strategic objective is to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> apart, it said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> are trying to get closer together and eventually might unite to
compete with it in international trade. "The most urgent strategic task for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to contain <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and prevent it from becoming
powerful enough to threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hegemony in the world," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. Then
it will try to deepen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis with a view to destroying its
nuclear capability. If this works, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> might then target <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to
eliminate its nuclear capability.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> and foreign trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to lobby for an end to airstrikes. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> is exploiting
its status as an aggrieved party to weaken the unity of what it calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>
war machine," the paper quoted an unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> as saying. It also said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> foreign trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
that dissociate themselves from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s "hawkish" policies will stand the
best chance of reaping benefits from the vast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> market. Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
has signaled its willingness to separate politics and business by instructing
the media to cool their anti-U.S. rhetoric. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have been told that
criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should be confined to the specific issues of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> wants to contain popular
hostility even against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and products," a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rexhep Meidani</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> will visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> for talks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis,
despite the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, was attacked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, apparently
because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> is considered an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>.

            
Despite editorials around the world expressing alarm about the deteriorating
political situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> (including an especially strong one in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun of Tokyo</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX>
Chirac declaring after talks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> that he doesn't believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
will withdraw from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peace process and that he expects the next few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to show "that things are moving in the right direction, that of peace."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> led on the deal struck at a stormy meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Party</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, by which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> is permitted to hold to its existing war policy.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers were dominated by the election of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo Azeglio Ciampi</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 78</TIMEX>. The easy
victory of this former wartime partisan and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX> was welcomed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> in a front-page comment as "a fine moment for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> politics and for
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> was replaced on the front pages of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> by the start of a new campaign by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> to put
an ambivalent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> at "the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>," and by the threat of huge
disruption to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s secret intelligence services by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> on
various Web sites of a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , in its main front-page lead, said that frantic
government efforts to purge the Web of this sensitive information are "doomed
to failure."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> of "dereliction of duty" for failing to
investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s theft of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half-century</TIMEX>'s worth of nuclear secrets from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>, "the most damaging case of spying against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosenbergs</ENAMEX> passed along the atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>." It said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX> that
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as 1995</TIMEX> they suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> had stolen the design of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' most advanced nuclear warhead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>. Yet it looks as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> chose
not to investigate all this "on the old principle: 'if something smells bad,
why put your nose in it?' When that something is the theft of the development
codes for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>, however, such discretion shades into
dereliction of duty of the worst kind. It must now receive the fullest and most
open inquiry--and any resistance to such investigation will unavoidably look
like evidence of guilt."

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> nanny convicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> of killing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">-month-old Matthew Eappen</ENAMEX>, have been arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> over fraud
allegations relating to a trust fund set up to pay their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s defense
costs. Sue and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Woodward</ENAMEX>, who have separated, have been released on bail
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> gave
front-page treatment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to the death in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 7-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> who
had been put in a clothes drier by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, who thought she was
being helpful when he woke up crying with a soiled diaper. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> 's front page reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> have the worst
record for sexual disease, pregnancy, and abortions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
