
   
   
      
         
            The Killers

            The comedy Analyze
This requires little analysis: It plays like a slapstick fever dream. It
boasts, essentially, a single joke, the one about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingpin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niro</ENAMEX>) who goes to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Freudian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystal</ENAMEX>) to cure his panic
attacks. The introspection that this process entails flies in the face of
everything we know and cherish about gangster movies. Hotheaded crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scarface</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Caesar</ENAMEX> are attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> for our fantasies
because they don't think through the moral consequences of what they do. They
want, they take. They get mad, they get even. Most of us enjoy seeing their
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">real-world</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> stripped of their ill-gotten gains; at the movies,
however, we're shameless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX>: We love the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX>'s vitality, his
charismatic demonstration that, with big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and even bigger balls, everything
is permissible. So what's the point of psychoanalyzing the id?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laughs</ENAMEX>, of course--big
ones. The juxtaposition of macho bloodletting with touchy-feely explorations of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-doubt</ENAMEX>. The incongruity of watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Vitti</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gotti</ENAMEX>-like mob
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX>, being counseled to phone a rival gangster (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chazz Palminteri</ENAMEX>) who has
tried to have him whacked and communicate his feelings ("I feel anger") for the
sake of "closure." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX>, of course, is hardly touchy-feely, but Analyze
This is funny enough to be forgiven its muddling of therapeutic modes. The
script, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ramis</ENAMEX> (also the able <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Tolan</ENAMEX>, and the
brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Lonergan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Is Our Youth</ENAMEX> ), must have
been a tag-team effort. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> is repetitive, but each scene begins with
a joyous blast of comic energy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hooligans</ENAMEX> continually disrupt
the personal life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Sobel</ENAMEX>, who's on the verge of
marrying a straitlaced TV newswoman (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Kudrow</ENAMEX>). They track him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>, where he's plucked from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> to treat
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s sudden impotence. They kidnap him from his wedding ceremony on
pain of death. Each impromptu session ends with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s exclamations of
relief--"You got a gift, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>! Yes you do! A load is off my shoulders!
You're good!"--followed, a short time later, by the return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX>'s
anxiety and another forced appointment: "You did nothing for me!"

            For all its comic exaggeration (almost no gangster or
Freudian cliché is left unparodied), Analyze This ends up affirming the
efficacy of psychoanalysis more than any picture since Spellbound
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>). It turns out that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sobel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitti</ENAMEX> are staggering under the legacy
of powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> in their fields of psychoanalysis and racketeering,
respectively. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sobel</ENAMEX> has to fire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitti</ENAMEX> has to get in touch with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blubbery</ENAMEX> inner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>--shticks that sound more offensively pat than they play,
largely because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX>'s handling of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX>'s bawling like a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX> seem like sensible therapies for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX>'s high-profile hosting chores have made his hunger for approval
seem too sweatily transparent. Playing the straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> becomes him, and when
he finally has a chance to cut loose--in a climactic speech before a meeting of
the crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, where he's forced to pose as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitti</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consigliere</ENAMEX> --his macho vamping jumbled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX> stammers had me
laughing so hard that I almost needed supplemental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Niro</ENAMEX> is borderline
appalling. Once the most unaffected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>--the most
magnetically self-contained--he has evolved into the movies' most shameless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ham</ENAMEX>. To every part he brings an all-purpose dyspepsia. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monster</ENAMEX>, his sour expression was so ingrained that you had to conclude that the
mad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> had misaligned his intestines, resulting in a steady stream of acid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reflux</ENAMEX>. His grimacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Expectations</ENAMEX> seemed less in need
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and shelter than of a swig of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maalox</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vitti in Analyze This</ENAMEX>
has the dodgiest gastrointestinal tract of all. At the best of times he winces,
in repose appearing ulcerous; in the throes of a panic attack, he might be
struggling with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alien</ENAMEX> -like parasite about to burst through his chest.
The miraculous thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX> still has his timing. I've never met a
psychiatrist clumsy enough to use the words "Oedipal conflict" with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>,
let alone to explain it by invoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophocles</ENAMEX>, but this dumb bit is worth it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">watch De Niro</ENAMEX> blanch, shake his head in disgust at the thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipus</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, and exclaim, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuckin</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>."

            It's a testament to the hilarity of Analyze This
that it's going to survive comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX>, the rich and
exuberantly tragicomic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> series. Working from some of the same impulses as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Chase</ENAMEX> has fashioned an elegy to a vanishing
world of "family-oriented" crime--and an exploration of the dislocation that
its passing evokes in sometime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Soprano</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Gandolfini</ENAMEX>). Loping
around his overdecorated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> manse in an open bathrobe, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gandolfini</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soprano</ENAMEX> is part muscle and part flab, with no connecting sinews. He carries his
tension in his shoulders, so that even when he's sweet he suggests a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the
verge of snapping. Arrested between thought and action, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gandolfini</ENAMEX> still bears
traces of childlike befuddlement in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doughy</ENAMEX> face; he can't begin to figure
out why the foundations of his world have become so illusory. Analyze
This is a hoot, but <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> really sings.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stock & Two Smoking Barrels</ENAMEX> is
the laborious title of an even more laborious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockney</ENAMEX> action movie that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s pajamas crossbred with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bee</ENAMEX>'s knees. It combines
the music video syntax of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trainspotting</ENAMEX> with the jokey nihilist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bloodletting of Pulp Fiction</ENAMEX> . You're supposed to root for the hapless
amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX> over the platoons of murderous professional ones, and to watch
as, with farcical precision, the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> end up accidentally blowing one
another away. As someone who has written <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Feydeauesque</ENAMEX> farce, I can tell you
that it's no easy feat. But the real trick isn't bringing disparate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into slapstick alignment, it's figuring out what to do with them once
they're all assembled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Ritchie</ENAMEX>, doesn't need to bother
with sorting them out at the end, because there's nothing left but piles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corpses</ENAMEX>. Now, why didn't I think of such an easy way out?

         
      
   
