
   
   
      
         
             <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>?

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter of 1981-82</TIMEX> was a
grim one for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. After a nasty recession in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, there had been
a brief, hopeful period of recovery--but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1982</TIMEX> it was clear that a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, even worse recession was underway. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late that year</TIMEX> the unemployment
rate would rise above <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> (and so far only) time since the
1930s. So bleak was the prospect that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine ran a long article (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Stein</ENAMEX>) titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"A Scenario</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Depression?</ENAMEX>" which suggested that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has arrived at a new spot on the
economic map where the old remedies--or what we thought were remedies--have
lost their power and the economic wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have lost their magic." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> and
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> worried that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a decade</TIMEX> of disappointing performance,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy might simply fail to respond to monetary and fiscal policies,
that a self-reinforcing downward spiral of pessimism and financial collapse
might already be out of control.

            Fortunately, however, it
turned out that the old remedies were just as powerful, the nostrums of the
economic wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> just as magical, as always. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX>, which
had been following a strict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monetarist</ENAMEX> rule, reversed course in mid-summer and
opened up the monetary taps. Interest rates came down, the stock market rose,
and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1983</TIMEX> the economy was unmistakably on the mend. Indeed, as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> left idle by the slump went back to work, output soared:
Real GDP grew <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 7 percent</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">in 1984 Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was
triumphantly re-elected under the slogan "It's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." It wasn't:
Once the slack had been taken up, growth slowed again, and over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> as a
whole the economy actually grew a bit less than it had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. But the
surge in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> was a spectacular demonstration of the way that a sufficiently
expansionary monetary policy can reverse a depressed economy's fortunes.

            The biggest single question now facing the world economy is
whether the same magic can work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.

            In some important ways,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> today bears a strong resemblance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in that frightening
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 1982</TIMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> then, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has some serious long-term
problems: a slowdown in productivity growth, an ossified management culture, a
troubled financial sector (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s article talked at length about the looming
problems of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> industry). But overlaid on these long-term
difficulties is a severe recession. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s unemployment statistics notoriously
understate the true extent of joblessness, but even so the current <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.4 percent</NUMEX>
rate is the highest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 45 years</TIMEX> the number has been published. Depending on
whose estimates you believe, the economy is operating anywhere from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 10 percent</NUMEX> below its capacity. That means that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s "output
gap" is probably comparable to that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years ago</TIMEX>. So if
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> can somehow persuade its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to start
spending again, there is room for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of rapid growth--even if the
"structural" problems remain unsolved.

            There is, however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> then
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> now. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> can no longer use conventional monetary and fiscal
policies to get the economy moving. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interest rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1982</TIMEX>
were in double digits--and could therefore be sharply reduced--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
short-term interest rates have been below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, apparently
leaving little room for further cuts. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is already deeply
in debt, already running huge deficits. The experience of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>
(in which the prospect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would have to sell vast quantities
of bonds to finance its deficits temporarily led to a tripling of long-term
interest rates) suggests that any attempt to stimulate the economy with even
bigger deficit spending will do more harm than good. So it might appear that
there are no easy answers, that nothing short of a total restructuring of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy can turn it around.

            But over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> a
growing chorus of Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> has argued against this fatalistic view.
On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side, they have worried that unless something dramatic is done to
increase demand <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> may go into a deflationary tailspin; that the expectation
of falling prices will make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> even less willing to
spend, worsening the slump and driving prices down all the faster. On the other
side, they have argued that radical, unconventional monetary policy can
still be effective--that even if short-term interest rates are near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>,
massive monetary expansion can still push up demand. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>--namely,
yours truly--have even argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> should try to get out of its
deflationary trap by creating expectations of inflation .

            Until very recently, these arguments seemed too outlandish
to receive support from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than</NUMEX> a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. But the
events of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few weeks</TIMEX> suggest that there has been a sea change of
opinion inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Japan</ENAMEX>--a change similar to, but even more striking
than, the abandonment of monetarism at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. After years of
warning about the risks of inflation and the importance of sound policy, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOJ</ENAMEX> has suddenly begun flooding the market with liquidity. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> rate
at which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> lend to each other--the equivalent of our "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> funds" rate--has
been driven down literally to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> now charge each other only for the
administrative costs of making the loan. And still the expansion continues.
It's still a bit hard to believe, but it looks as if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> has
been radicalized--that is, it has finally seen the light, has finally
understood that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s current state adhering to conventional notions of
monetary prudence is actually dangerous folly, and only monetary policy that
would normally be regarded as irresponsible can save the economy.

            There are, of course, big risks in any such radical
policy departure. My own view is that the biggest risk is that the new policy
will not be radical enough, for it is a characteristic of deflation-fighting
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-measures get you nowhere. Suppose, for example, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> were to try to convince the public that the future will bring inflation,
not deflation. But that the target inflation rate is too low, so that even if
everyone believed that target would be achieved, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy would
remain seriously depressed. Then deflation would continue--and the policy would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ignominiously</ENAMEX> fail.

            But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOJ</ENAMEX> is determined enough--and if people
like me have analyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s plight correctly--then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> or a year from
now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> may be on the road to an economic recovery more dramatic than anyone
would now dare to forecast. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime next year</TIMEX>, the Land of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rising Sun</ENAMEX>
may, at least for a while, live up to its billing. You heard it here <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
