
   
   
      
         
            Tepid <EM><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tea</ENAMEX></EM>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tea With Mussolini</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). This story
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a group of English and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> living in 1930s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>--sort of
an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enchanted Fascist April"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> )--receives tepid reviews. Surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> is the highlight of the
movie and holds her own among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily Tomlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judi Dench</ENAMEX>, and a gaggle of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> actresses: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> is terrific here doing what she does best: Wearing
heavy makeup and being flamboyant"(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). Aside from
her performance, though, the film isn't much more than "a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sub-Merchant</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX> mix of eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and enchanting scenery" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
Ebert, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). (Check out this collection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> photos through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX>.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>).
More negative responses: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are resentful about the fact that the film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will</ENAMEX> rake in money despite their reviews. A few, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX>, defend the film: "If it were the first "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars</ENAMEX>" movie,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX>' would be hailed as a visionary breakthrough. ... How
quickly do we grow accustomed to wonders." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podhoretz</ENAMEX> also praises the film, saying "it will strike a chord with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>
for the same reason that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> did: It is earnest, well-meaning, and
delightfully free of irony. ... The jokes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> are broad
and childish in a way that may displease sophisticates but will be endearing to
everyone else." The more high-flown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are flush with Schadenfreude
at what they see as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lucas</ENAMEX>' fall from glory. Some even take jabs
at the gullibility of eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX> writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> :
"It is, of course, profoundly gratifying that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace"</ENAMEX> should
emerge as a work of almost unrelieved awfulness. It means, for one thing, that
the laugh is on all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dweebs</ENAMEX> who have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX> camped out on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX> beside movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theatres</ENAMEX>, waiting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the big day</TIMEX>." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s take on the film in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Turn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Andersen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>).
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX> magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Spy co-founder</ENAMEX>, and current
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Andersen</ENAMEX>'s satire of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-'90s</TIMEX> culture wins good
reviews, but many carp about its weaknesses. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The irony is laid on too thick:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX> is "so arch you could almost drive through him" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Okrent</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Turn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> is not a novel with a plot so much
as a collection of riffs, observations, and set pieces on subjects such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>. Although it "bristles with
sharply observed detail" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ), the book runs into
trouble in terms of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and maintaining any sort of pacing or
momentum. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" about the novel;
click here to read an excerpt [requires free registration].)

            

               
                  Close <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Range: Wyoming Stories</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Proulx</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scribner</ENAMEX>). The words "bleak," "harsh," and "tough" show up in almost every
review of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Proulx</ENAMEX>'s collection of stories set in her
adopted state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. The word "powerful" shows up frequently, too.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>, ranch hands, and the unforgiving nature of life out west are her main
subjects, and by all accounts she handles them with extraordinary skill and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> can't say enough about her tight, honed prose: She gets
the speech patterns just right ("a stunningly authentic voice," declares
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Knight</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ), she writes "sentences whose
specific gravity mysteriously exceeds their size" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ), and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have an "absolute authenticity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Lehmann-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haupt</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (Listen to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBC</ENAMEX> interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proulx</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Why We Buy
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paco Underhill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say this exploration of what factors affect a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopper</ENAMEX>'s behavior within
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> is interesting, but several grouse that at times it reads as if the
"book is really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> long advertisement for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Envirosell</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Marchetti</ENAMEX>,
Sales & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marketing Management</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underhill</ENAMEX>'s consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. If
the subject sounds familiar, it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> reported
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underhill</ENAMEX>'s findings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Throckmorton Zakaria</ENAMEX>). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are fascinated by the sociological
details of retail shopping--things like the "butt brush factor" (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> often
won't buy something if another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> accidentally brushes her behind while
she's shopping) or how the positions of signs and chairs in a store affect a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shopper</ENAMEX>'s likelihood of actually purchasing an item. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Music
            

            
               
                  Take Your
Shoes Off
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Cray</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> soul-blues
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">singer</ENAMEX> and guitarist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cray</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11 th</NUMEX> album: "A sheer blast of rocking
good times" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Linden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ). It may not break any new ground, but
it nevertheless impresses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Rosenthal</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX>
writes that it is "a slow-burning soul record--and one of the most focused
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">album's</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cray</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 year</TIMEX> career."

         
      
   
