
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bombing Kosovo To Save It</ENAMEX>

            After much previous
controversy, there was surprising unanimity in the western <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> over the necessity of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> air war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. There were a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissenting</ENAMEX> voices. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, one of its former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Jenkins</ENAMEX>,
wrote in his op-ed column that Western meddling in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s separatist struggle
"has now brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> possibly and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> certainly to a catastrophe." He
asked, "Why does a bloodstained shroud only have to wave over a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Balkan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>
for otherwise intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to take leave of their senses<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" An op-ed
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Buchan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> stressed the threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, which is "likely to go into the deep freeze." He
concluded, "Over the longer term, the argument with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> may cast a pall over
further enlargement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>--'collateral damage' of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> before it started."

            But most editorials in
the papers of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were almost unanimous in
supporting the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the conservative tabloid the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> "to strike relentlessly and hard"; the
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> should "be prepared to conduct an
extended bombing campaign to be followed, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, by the introduction of
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>"; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> said it was essential for "all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> involved--including
the notoriously short-sighted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>--to recognise that they
must now commit themselves to the long haul, ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and all."

            In the main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> papers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis ranked <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
to the main story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>--the enforced leave taken because of a
sex-and-money scandal by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roland Dumas</ENAMEX> as head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. Libération saw this as a
welcome blow to the traditional arrogance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> ruling class. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
evening paper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soir</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumas</ENAMEX> should have
resigned properly instead of taking an "illegal" temporary leave, which
logically nullified all future decisions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional Council</ENAMEX>, "the
essential guarantor of the good functioning of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> said in a front-page
commentary on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> will overcome its history only when it is able
to preserve peace across the whole continent without the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> summit on security policy and the
coordination of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> diplomatic and military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> is overdue.
Melancholy reflections on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> weakness and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> also dominated the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> press. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vittorio Zucconi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>,
highlighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remark that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> history is
largely the history of massacres carried out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>, and said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is "once again forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to take up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> and die for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> whose names they don't even know."

            In another front-page commentary in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paolo Garimberti</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "merciless" in drawing attention to the truth
that even now <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> can't curb its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> regimes without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s help,
and he added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> "dramatically underscores the
inadequacy of the political and military instruments of which the European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> disposes." On the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gianni Riotta</ENAMEX> heralded
the return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> that won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> without firing a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> is now mobilized against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> often consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, culture, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>," he said, adding that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> would
certainly exploit this situation to strengthen his uncertain power at home.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, an editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> took
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> to task for justifying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s opposition to the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> by
citing the example of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basque</ENAMEX> separatism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> aren't bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>
"because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Basque</ENAMEX> problem hasn't been resolved," he said. This is a "very
crude comparison," the paper commented: The case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Basque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, with
its advanced political autonomy, has nothing in common with "an open war and
'ethnic cleansing' against <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>."

            An editorial in the
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> headlined "This war, at least, is silly and unnecessary" referred to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> exports of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> that were fed a bovine growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>. The
Independent supported <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s position on this, but an op-ed piece in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> strongly supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
in the "banana war," which, it said, might "do irreparable damage" to the World
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Organization</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> carried a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX> is "a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> funded by
dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, including drug money." It said the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of three
western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are separately investigating growing evidence that
some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>'s money comes from drug trafficking. "Should the West back a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrilla</ENAMEX> army that appears to be partly financed by organised crime?" the
paper asked. "Could the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>'s need for funds be fuelling the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> trade
across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>?"

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eAlbaniai</ENAMEX> blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s alleged involvement
in organized crime for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s recent decision to freeze aid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX>, trafficking in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has increased rather than diminished, the
paper said. "Moreover, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> that visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tirana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> ago
said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> had evidence proving that high-ranking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> were involved," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>, another
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">iKoha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonei</ENAMEX> , published some impressive statistics about
corruption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Attributing its facts to a report by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Audit Commission</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43,000</NUMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had
been found to have abused their positions for illegal financial gain. The
guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> of public economy and privatization,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, justice, employment, and immigration, as well as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and in
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX> and tax <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. It added that, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Ministry of Social Affairs</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57,306</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> had paid no taxes at all
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> eGazeta <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shqiptarei</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> might become the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world to be wholly privatized,
its ruined economy could only be revived by the privatization of all its
national assets.

             

         
      
   
