
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Here's the Pitch&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fill in the blank. After creating the highest-rated movie ever made for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Weideman</ENAMEX> is about to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sequels, but the project was a
tough sale. "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> eyes would glaze over as soon as I said the words,
'____________.' "
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 214</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nutkin":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               You give the brief lead; I give the headline from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s
Independent : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Letter Reveals Nutkin Was a Savage Squirrel</ENAMEX>"
            

            "My
God! <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Mad Cow disease</ENAMEX> has mutated! Run for the hills!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> "Why, Yes, I'd
Love Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wasabi</ENAMEX> Polenta" Carvell
            

            
"Despite revelations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> still stands by his campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Bell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ha</ENAMEX>!
That got your attention. Now, back to the tariff implications of EMU
membership."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "Fergie
wins <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Anagram</ENAMEX> contest for her positively bitchy entry: 'Queen wears rags
at rave; rants like evil slut.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squirrel Nutkin</ENAMEX> was a bitter, resentful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recluse</ENAMEX> who secretly despised
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twinkleberry</ENAMEX> and goaded Old Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> into violence, according to a collection
of correspondence published by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> coverage of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> teaches this lesson: It's futile to
read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. Salient details are always concealed, key decisions are
always made in private, and the ink gets all over your hands. Review the
dailies from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942 or 1929 or 1863</TIMEX>, and you'll come away with a similar
impressively false sense of the great events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. So why persist in
newspaper reading? For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, it lets you participate in the ongoing
conversation that is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s culture. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> doesn't wish to stand silently by
while others merrily exchange misinformation about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>, and
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">viruses</ENAMEX>. (That's why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of decent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Shoot</ENAMEX>
Me : It'll be the talk of the schoolyard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. Surely not because it is,
in any meaningful sense, good.) For another thing, the news provides a myth
system for a secular age, giving us figures of good and evil, around whom we
can construct tales of ... well, OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of evil and more evil. But perhaps
the utility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>--their ability to provide truth and understanding--is
beside the point. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> buys them for other reasons: for powerful photographs,
now often in color, of underwear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>; for a chance encounter with an
embarrassing detail about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>; and perhaps most of all, for that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lovable Marmaduke</ENAMEX> cartoon. At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 cents</NUMEX>, it's a bargain!

            
               Squirrelicious
Answer
            

            "A letter in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrix Potter</ENAMEX> reveals that one
of her best-loved fictional creations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squirrel Nutkin</ENAMEX>, was based on a pet
squirrel with behavioural problems is expected to fetch <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to £15,000</NUMEX> at
auction," reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Marks</ENAMEX>.

            Writing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> before the publication
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tale of Squirrel Nutkin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> notes: "I bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> squirrels,
but the one called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nutkin</ENAMEX>--who was much the handsomest--was so very savage I
was obliged to take him back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. So I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> now, called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twinkleberry</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary Franklin</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">letter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, learned its value when she took it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Television</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiques Roadshow</ENAMEX> .

            
               Scrupulous
Extra
            

            Some corrections from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> :

            

               It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX>.

               He is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>.

               He was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>, not a lieutenant.

               It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silbury Hill</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avebury</ENAMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninos Con Bombas</ENAMEX>, not Todos
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">los Manos</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bullwinkle</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
