
   
   
      
         

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borislav</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has no plans for acts of terrorism in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> but that "if the war gets worse, I don't know what will happen." In
the interview, he cited the example of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that has struck
outside its borders when attacked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borislav Milosevic</ENAMEX> said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> will
never surrender and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> might well give in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. "We can count not only
on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> but also, in the long term, on Western public
opinion," he said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> ones, put the main
emphasis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> on peace initiatives, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> reporting "a notable rapprochement" between the positions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also said that former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romano Prodi</ENAMEX>,
now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designate</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, was called by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar Qaddafi</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> with peace proposals which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prodi</ENAMEX> urged him to pursue.

            Opinion polls published
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> showed public support rising for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> attacks on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, despite civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>. A Gallup Poll conducted for the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> showed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72 percent</NUMEX> in favor of the war, compared
with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> led on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>
hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bulgarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sofia</ENAMEX>. On this theme, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>
published a cartoon showing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX> asking a
smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, "What's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>?" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bomb replying</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sofia</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
led on intensified security at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> after death threats against senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> by telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> claiming to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
responsible for the murder <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Dando</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most
popular TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX>.

            In an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Papandreou</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> opposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
bombardment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, said that sending in ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> before a peace
agreement would have terrible consequences for the coexistence of the peoples
of the region. He also criticized proposals to strengthen the economic embargo
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. "That could have been a good idea at the beginning, but today
it's more a historical than a practical question. Now, we have to look for a
solution," he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Papandreou</ENAMEX> expressed mild optimism about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> peace
initiatives. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are now saying yes to an implementation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>--not
armed, certainly--but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> think there are various possibilities," he
said. "On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> side, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points are important: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, the inviolability of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frontiers</ENAMEX> has been forcibly reaffirmed--in other words, there won't be a
partition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, after having talked of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> 'under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command</ENAMEX>,' they are now talking about a force directed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
'with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> kernel.' This new flexibility doesn't mean there will be a
solution <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, but perhaps soon."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the weekly
Far <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Economic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executioner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> has become a born-again <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and is willing to face an
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kang Kek Ieu</ENAMEX> has admitted to being "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duch</ENAMEX>," the director
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuol Sleng</ENAMEX> detention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phnom Penh</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 16,000</NUMEX> people
were executed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975-79</TIMEX> "killing fields" reign of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terror</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> said. Duch, who disappeared into the jungle after
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> captured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phnom Penh</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> and has long been presumed dead,
was found living in the western part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>.

            Opinion polls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> papers showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> would defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> by
around <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>'s general election. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>
Poll, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maariv</ENAMEX> , gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> against <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dahaf Institute</ENAMEX>'s poll, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> , put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> at
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX>. In both polls, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center Party</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Mordechai</ENAMEX> is slipping: He gets <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dahaf</ENAMEX> although--paradoxically and theoretically--he would still
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beat Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round.

            The current clamor in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> to be put on trial for crimes against
humanity should be used to demand the prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> for atrocities
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Arab War</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammad al-Az</ENAMEX>'ar in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab al-Hayat</ENAMEX> . In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, the semi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Ahram</ENAMEX> published an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salaheddin Hafez</ENAMEX>
warning that what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is doing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> could be replicated against one
or more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world has good cause to be deeply apprehensive
about the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has taken to posing as the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> and projecting
its power beyond its borders in a nondefensive role, he wrote. "Even the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s sole superpower, with its unique responsibilities, is increasingly
seeing violence and the use of overwhelming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> as an easy option for
achieving its ends as the most violent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century in human</TIMEX> history draws to a
close."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> split over a point of grammar in a bill to abolish its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hereditary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The issue is whether to say "a hereditary peer" or "an
hereditary peer." The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> version appears in the bill but was disputed in a
debate by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> hereditary peer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Ferrers</ENAMEX>, who moved an amendment to
change "a" to "an." He pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fowler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern English Usage</ENAMEX>
cites "an hereditary title" as a correct example. But a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> spokesman
responded with a quotation from a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> edition of the same reference book: "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'An</ENAMEX>' was formerly usual before an unaccented syllable beginning with 'h' and is
still often seen and heard (an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, an hereditary title). But now that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'h'</ENAMEX> in such words is pronounced, the distinction has become anomalous and
will no doubt disappear in time." Their lordships voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63-31</NUMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrers</ENAMEX>' amendment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Laud</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX>, has been made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of foxhounds. He told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that his appointment
as joint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the 210-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Forest Foxhounds</ENAMEX> has nothing to do with
the color of his skin. "We don't want to put distance between us and anyone
that wants to participate in this sport. It doesn't matter if they are a woman
or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, gay or straight." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the hunt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laud</ENAMEX> was chosen
because "he's just a bloody nice bloke."

             

         
      
   
