
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX>
            

            The cover story predicts that the disappearance of privacy
will bring about "one of the greatest social changes of modern times."
Technology is destroying privacy that we took for granted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, but the
corresponding benefits--better government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>, cheaper products, less
crime--may outweigh that loss. ... An editorial sighs that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s firing of his most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal aide</ENAMEX> bodes poorly for a compromise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war. ... The
magazine slams the recent spate of millenially inspired "best"
books lists and recommends 
                  Slate
               's very own instead.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>
            

            The cover story describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>' shriveling
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> and corrupt political system. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> now level their anger at
their own rotten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> as well as at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. (Intifada-era graffiti has
been painted over with phrases such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confront corruption and patronage</ENAMEX>!")
Some right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> factions aspire to replace the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with
a theocracy similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>'s. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Jonah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s crimes are "different from those
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX> only in scale." He also argues that an allied victory could
stimulate a postwar democratic transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> similar to that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2</TIMEX>
            

            The cover story contends
that eliminating affirmative action does not devastate equal opportunity in
higher education. Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, and graduate
programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> suffered losses in minority enrollment
following affirmative-action bans. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>
"cascading" to less prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> but caused university
heads to adopt more "holistic" admissions criteria--e.g., giving more weight to
nonacademic achievements--to bolster minority enrollment. ... A profile
condemns the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>-choking (and uncoachable) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX> for crushing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> championship hopes: His nihilism and selfishness have
sapped his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>' will to win. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX> essay riffs on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis, concluding that it is a just war to deter "radical evil" and
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> will fail if they don't oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3</TIMEX>
            

            The newsweeklies
reconstruct the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> massacre and solicit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> opinions on why it
happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> kill when pre-existing biological flaws
are exacerbated by poor nurturing. Biological warning signs: low heart rates
and swollen brain <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX>. Other post-massacre advice: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               recommends that high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> provide counseling to "help
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bullies</ENAMEX> deal with frustration," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> should vet their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>' comments ("Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> gave me a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>, and I could just kill her for that.") for homicidal
tendencies.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> print blueprints for a ground war in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               inventories the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, time, casualties, and money necessary
to carry out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different plans, from limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-3 weeks</ENAMEX>
of prep time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> dead, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX>) to full-on occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-6 months</TIMEX> of prep time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> dead, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 billion</NUMEX>).
A retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> tells 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> could retake <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in a
brief ground attack (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-3 months</TIMEX> of prep, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>

               reports that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> are shunning white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for
black ones. Among the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> courting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rookies</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puffy Combs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Johnnie Cochran</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3</TIMEX>
            

            The cover
story details the disturbing behavior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> killers
before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s massacre. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> knew about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trenchcoat Mafia</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> were unaware of its existence. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sidebar</ENAMEX> stresses the dangers of bullying, which causes 8
percent of school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to miss "a day of class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>" and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> to fear
using school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX>. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> goes inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> surveillance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>
currently searching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>. Despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>' detection
techniques, sometimes "you don't know if it's some civilian driving to the
grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, or a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>," says an intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. ...
A piece calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd Wright</ENAMEX> an awful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpiece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fallingwater</ENAMEX>, has been girded by steel scaffolding to prevent it
from crumbling.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3</TIMEX>
            

            An editorial warns that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> may lose both the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and his strong popular support if
he continues to dither over the use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. ... Another
editorial defends the "incrementalist" positions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> have taken on abortion. Their hesitantly pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> are
useful token gestures "of occasional conformity with the governing [pro-choice]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>." (For 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s take on this
topic, see the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17</TIMEX> ".")

         
      
   
