
   
   
      
         
            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nukes Make Good Neighbors</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Asian</ENAMEX> papers gave
extensive coverage to the goodwill journey of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vajpayee</ENAMEX>, who crossed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> border on a bus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> to meet
with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> emphasized that nuclearization had given rise to new challenges and
opportunities by bringing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to "a defining moment."

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two day</TIMEX> summit
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">culminated in the Lahore Declaration</ENAMEX>, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> resolved to
intensify efforts to solve the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> issue through ministerial talks and
agreed to a series of "confidence-building measures." These measures include
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' respective unilateral moratoriums on nuclear testing. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> plan to ease travel restrictions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sharif</ENAMEX> is expected to take a
trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> called the visit "a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of amity in
Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> relations," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> pointed toward organized protests in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lahore</ENAMEX> as evidence that the "commitment to neighborly amity is still less than
total."

            The papers highlighted the symbolism of the event. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Vajpayee</ENAMEX>
is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 10 years</TIMEX>. His
visit marked the opening of the first regular bus route between the quarrelling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> since their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madras</ENAMEX> quotes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vajpayee</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that "the running of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
symbolizes the desire of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to improve relations." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> quotes
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>'s assertion that "in a situation where people
don't even make gestures, this is a powerful sign." Nevertheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
papers differed in their assessment of the summit's outcome. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
commented that "this modest outcome was on expected lines and while it provided
a framework for a new beginning, a lot would depend on the follow-up," whereas
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> wrote that the "bold steps" in the memorandum of
understanding "set the tone for a shared vision of peace and stability."

            The coverage in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>
papers was tepid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lahore</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> reported that the visit took place "amidst
feeling of both apprehension and optimism." By contrast, the coverage of
the visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan of China</ENAMEX>'s defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> was
glowing.

            Headlines throughout the world were also dominated by the
stalled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peace talks. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine hours</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> deadline for a deal on
returning autonomy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> had passed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> announced that the deadline had been extended by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>, thus
forestalling the airstrikes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> had threatened. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> placed
the blame for the deadlock on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intransigent</ENAMEX> refusal to countenance a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-led force as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX>, despite
the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> were holding out for a referendum on
independence once the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year</TIMEX> interim period covered by the proposed
settlement expired. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brinksmanship</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times of London</ENAMEX> commented that the stalemate evinced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s weak hand in forcing a settlement.

            In a story
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> fails to win right to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> commented
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>' refusal to unilaterally sign on to the
settlement frustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attempts to corner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> with the choice of
accepting the peace package or facing airstrikes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> remarked that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>' refusal to assent makes it more likely that the talks will
end in "a fudged compromise."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have had some success in sartorial sleuthing. A computerized database of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">footprints</ENAMEX> found at crime scenes reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok Classics</ENAMEX> recently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">displaced Nike Air Max</ENAMEX> as the favorite footwear of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. In one
case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> used a shoe print to link an unlucky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> other
crimes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> cannot use sneaker stereotyping
to arrest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> are told to watch out for suspicious shoes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX>
beware of choice of footwear when in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> without a bill of rights!

             

         
      
   
