
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Thirds&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               He's done it twice, and he announced on the radio that if it were legal
to do it again he would. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> say this desire indicates "a strange
psychological <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>." Who wants to do what?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 198</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chat and Argue Choo Choo":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next month</TIMEX>, hoping to
re-establish cordial relations, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 140</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> will board a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chartered Amtrak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> bound for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX> What will they do when they get
there?
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               

               "The
same thing everyone does after getting off an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>: attempt to wash
that vague uriney smell out of their clothes."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
               

               "Let
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Gerber</ENAMEX>
               

               "I'm
not sure, but if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> is going, I'll bet he doesn't touch any 'Special
Dark' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich Harrington</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hershey</ENAMEX>? Train? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressmen</ENAMEX>? Is it just me, or is it a little homoerotic in
here?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Schnur</ENAMEX>
               

               "Bang
on drums and try to get the talking stick away from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weepy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
DeLay."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Gabel</ENAMEX>
               

                

               Click
for more answers.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Beyond a preschool visit to a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy</ENAMEX>, my first
assembly line was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>, and it was
perfect--incredibly loud and with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocoa</ENAMEX> aroma as thick as a fist. There were
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">items</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy bars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kisses</ENAMEX>--in infinite multiples, and ordinary
objects in gigantic versions--mixing bowls, ladles, boxes. But you'll never see
it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX> no longer runs a factory tour. Instead it
has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">visitors center</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candytown</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Chocolate Work Shoppe or Fattyland</ENAMEX>,
something like that--pathetic, fake, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Disneyfied</ENAMEX>. It's the same at most
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>. Fear of lawsuits has superseded pride in the product.

            One delightful exception, should you like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
to see something made, and an easy drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mack Truck</ENAMEX> in
Macungie, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX> While it's an assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, not a manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, they do
start with a pile of parts in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and roll <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of those big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> out the
door by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>. You get to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> building something that's not
idiotic, a great treat for one who's worked in television.

            It's interesting that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dem-Rep</ENAMEX> safari is at the site of a pseudoexperience rather than the real thing.
But if you're trying to inspire artificial amity, that's not such a bad
choice.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Recantation
            

            Several of you chided me
for calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>," omitting the women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>.
Quite right. My mistake.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Touchy Feely</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            They're going to pretend that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Waterston</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>.

            As they did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> are
attending a retreat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are expected, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dennis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX>. Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Kearns</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hume</ENAMEX> who, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>, won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for his work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. Waterston, supported by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, will present selections from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Emancipator</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pew Charitable Trust</ENAMEX>
is providing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> to underwrite the event.

            
               Month of Junk
Extra
            

            I received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> unsolicited e-mails in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, not a
huge number, but it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short month</TIMEX>, and I use a local Internet service
provider. Most of this trash, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> pieces, proffered business
opportunities--dubious investments, credit card schemes, home employment.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> involved retail sales (dental care, computers, divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, online
auctions); <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> announced some sort of performance; one was an ancient chain
letter scam.

            Each investment scheme began with a lie. Ask to be
removed from the list, and you learn that the return address is bogus. I
suppose I'll never get my money back. Or earn enough to buy that solid gold
hat.

            A few highlights:

            From: clinical14b@gmc.edu

            Subject: CBSNews:1st <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aphrodisac Drug Apr</ENAMEX>

            "The announcement of this scientific breakthrough
has set off a media fire-storm."

            If this is an investment
opportunity, it's unconvincing. If it's a personal suggestion, it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impertinent</ENAMEX>--like I'm not doing fine with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyquil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kahlúa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cocktails</ENAMEX>.

            From: marketwatchernow1999sb@he.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.br

            Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>: "STRONG BUY" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HI-TECH MEDICAL</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDCID</ENAMEX> has announced priority production of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">proprietary Hypo-Sterile 2000</ENAMEX> which render medical contaminants harmless."

            Tempting. But my money's
tied up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rumplestiltskin</ENAMEX>'s process, which renders <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>.

            From: aoolw@<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigy</ENAMEX>.net

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Subject: Earn 2-</ENAMEX>4k <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Per Week from Home</ENAMEX>!!

            "What have you done with your dreams<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            My dreams rarely involve
becoming a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, but they frequently include an enormous cartoon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">swan</ENAMEX>.

            From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cwix</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Com</ENAMEX>

            Subject: Next Networking
Events@<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheetah</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limelight</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After work Networking Events For Young</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professionals</ENAMEX>."

            It's difficult to decide
which word in the above phrase is the least attractive.

            From: BrwBier1@aol.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            Subject<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: A Bit About Your Family's History</ENAMEX>

            "Do you know WHO your ancestors are and WHAT they
did?"

            I already employ a system
for addressing these questions; it's called psychotherapy.

            
               Common
Denominators
            

            The dangers of an underfunded rail system.

            The joys of erotically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> chocolate.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
