
   
   
      
         
            

            
Update on the
bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> captured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
who were patrolling the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Macedonian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> border. There is a dispute over
which side of the border they were on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> reportedly plan to
court-martial the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' capture
"illegal" and said it will hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> responsible for their safety. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) A
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim Rugova</ENAMEX>, was shown on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> television asking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to halt the bombing and meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>
to sign a document urging a "political" solution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> are questioning whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rugova</ENAMEX> has sold out or has been coerced and
whether the meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was actually videotaped before the bombing.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Reports indicate that the bombing has begun to inconvenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and to cause shortages of supplies to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
The new endgame under consideration is to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> until their
capacity to fight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is so impaired that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> can easily recapture
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and set up an ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> enclave under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> protection.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/2/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> white
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> were arrested on charges of second-degree
murder for firing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou Diallo</ENAMEX>, an unarmed black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He
died of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> bullet wounds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> pleaded not guilty, and their attorneys
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> had fired their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in the "reasonable belief" that they
were in danger. The case has triggered protests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, passionate
defenses of law enforcement from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>,
and a national debate over police tactics in black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> neighborhoods.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie Cochran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX> are preparing a civil suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> once the criminal trial ends. The high-minded spin: It's a conflict
between public safety and civil liberties. The cynical spin: It's a conflict
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/2/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is
tracking down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Melissa</ENAMEX> computer virus . The virus,
which replicates itself in e-mail messages it automatically transmits from
computers it has penetrated, infected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100,000</NUMEX> computers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>,
causing significant problems throughout the Internet. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> have now
confiscated a computer in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, that may contain clues to the virus's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, and they have secured a court order to obtain apparently confidential
information from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX>, since an AOL account seems to have been used
to launch the virus onto the Internet. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/2/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> industrial average closed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above 10,000</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time.
This marked a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> rise in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300 percent</NUMEX> rise
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> wheeled out prepackaged articles boasting about the
breadth of stock ownership among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and the growing dominance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the world economy. The pessimistic spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> are still a mess; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock valuations are completely out of whack;
the Internet investment mania will burst <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> will
collapse. The optimistic spin: That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pessimists</ENAMEX> have been saying for a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/1/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> won its first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s basketball championship . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UConn</ENAMEX>
beat the consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>, with outstanding defense and hot shooting.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> agreed it was one of the best-played finals in recent
memory, the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> fell to a record low. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sportswriters</ENAMEX> credited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UConn</ENAMEX>'s
victory to its refusal to be intimidated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s reputation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s defeat demonstrates the price of arrogance. The
counterspin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UConn</ENAMEX>'s victory demonstrates the power of arrogance.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/1/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are sorting out an interracial embryo mix-up . A white woman
and a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> went to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> for in vitro fertilization. The black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> didn't get pregnant, but the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> gave birth to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black, who are now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months old</TIMEX>. Once the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parentage</ENAMEX> was ascertained, the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, the
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> relinquished the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
What is in vitro fertilization doing to our concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">parenthood</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Would the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> be making such a fuss over this story if all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were
the same color? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Would the mix-up have been discovered if all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were the same color? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) How often do these mix-ups go unnoticed?
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/1/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>

               Kevorkian was convicted of second-degree murder . He faces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> to
life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The shallow analysis: The case was open and shut, since
Kevorkian taped the incident (in which he administered a lethal injection to a
terminally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s consent) and had the tape aired on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> . The sophisticated analysis: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> tried to make the trial a
political debate over assisted suicide, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> refused to go
along. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX>'s spin: He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> for the assisted suicide movement. The
conservative spin: His conviction proves that assisted suicide is murder. The
dull liberal spin: He's an embarrassment to the assisted suicide movement and
good riddance to him. The clever liberal spin: His conviction shows that if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't get assisted suicide legally, they'll turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/29/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">navigator</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> jet involved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> ski lift accident, Capt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Schweitzer</ENAMEX>, is pleading guilty to obstruction and conspiracy
charges. The charges relate to his alleged destruction of an on-board videotape
that recorded the accident. The interesting question now is whether the plea
deal means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">navigator</ENAMEX> will testify against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> (who was acquitted
of manslaughter in the incident by a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks ago</TIMEX>) on
similar obstruction and conspiracy charges. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/29/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
An <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has
banned the use of cell phones while driving . The ordinance allows
exceptions if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is in "park" or if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> keeps both hands on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wheel</ENAMEX> (e.g., by using a speakerphone). It was prompted by an accident caused by
a cell phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> who wasn't paying attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. This is believed to
be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such ordinance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Similar legislation has reportedly
been considered in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/29/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               For more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> coverage, click .
            

         
      
   
