
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two of this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
Prizes were awarded for wit: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Edson</ENAMEX>'s play of that name, about
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> poetry facing ovarian <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and
another for the quality most evident in the writing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnist Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>. Newspaper commentary, a dying art (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
on its last great), is nowadays dominated by sententiousness, not satire. On
the flat, windy landscape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s opinion pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> stands out for
her sharp one-liners and her brisk aperçus . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s recent movies
are versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Catcher in the Rye Bread</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Albert"</ENAMEX>)
"grew up as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>'s version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eloise</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plaza</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter
is "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> scandal with product placement." "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> has turned politics into
a TV series that nobody has the power to pull." And let's not omit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incisive</ENAMEX> summary of the moral and constitutional crux of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex
scandal, almost worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>: "These are not grounds for impeachment;
these are grounds for divorce."

            Like anyone who tries to
be funny, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> sometimes strains for effect and falls flat: She posed a choice
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX> as one
between "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> who cracks down on crime and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> whose crime was
crack." At other times, her glibness gets in the way of her insight:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historians</ENAMEX> will long ponder how Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> came in as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and
left as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>." They will? Like anyone who must produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> words of
headline-based observation twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>, she appears on occasion to phone
in her copy, as when she imagined a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history documentaries
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail Adams</ENAMEX> is really <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX>.") And
she could set a welcome example for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> everywhere if she took a solemn,
public oath never to write another word about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> . Still,
occasional lapses aside, no other regular newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> matches her
gimlet eye, her sense of phrase, or her unpredictability.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s importance is that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
profess to despise her seem to read her religiously--and to recycle her jokes
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Another is that she is subject to frequent, sometimes scathing,
criticism in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> of every ideological stripe and market niche. Her
unalloyed contempt for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> managed to infuriate even as lukewarm a
Clintonite as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>, who wrote, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>,
that "any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> must be super strenuous to take the vileness award from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s disgust with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s persecutors and her
merciless flaying of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, including the famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 23</TIMEX> column of last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> that began, "He couldn't stop thinking about the thong underwear," earned
her some brickbats from the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX>
called her "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of relentless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>," by which of course it meant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal orthodoxy</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s politics are
nearly impossible to glean from her columns. Most of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> on the
Times op-ed page represent an identifiable and more or less consistent
position: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas L. Friedman</ENAMEX> is the voice of liberal internationalism, Russell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> was the voice of New Deal liberalism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Herbert</ENAMEX> is the voice of liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> is the voice of libertarian conservatism, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> is the voice of sheer ranting lunacy. Dowd, in contrast, plays her
ideological cards close to the vest. Her published views on matters of policy
would scarcely fill a chapbook: She favors gun control, hates the tobacco
industry, and welcomes the prospect of peace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>.

            These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> are hardly evidence, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> era, of
a heterodox temperament. They are as likely, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, to be held by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> as by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. But it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s views that irritate her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> so much as her style and her attitude. The case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>, taken up
lately by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wolff</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> ("she is derisive, mocking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hyperbolic</ENAMEX>, bitchy") and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Kennedy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston Phoenix</ENAMEX> ("Call her
our most celebrated bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>") was most cogently laid out in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> piece
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Boo</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Monthly</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">At the time, Dowd</ENAMEX> was still
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, following the presidential campaign after having covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Houses</ENAMEX>. (She was anointed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quindlen</ENAMEX> in what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' "liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s seat.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boo</ENAMEX>'s brief boils down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main charges: that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s breezy,
sardonic style has inspired a flood of stilted, self-conscious imitators; and
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dowd</ENAMEX> crowd" contributed to the erosion of political discourse by
placing style and personality above seriousness and substance.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> charge is
easily dismissed. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> with a strong and original voice will always
influence lesser talents: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imitation</ENAMEX> is the tribute mediocrity pays to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>.
You might as well blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monkees</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Groening</ENAMEX> for The
Family <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy</ENAMEX> . But the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> accusation is both more interesting and more
complicated, especially because the trivialization of politics has long been
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s obsessions. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>, the
celebrity culture and the political culture have become indistinguishable.

            But the merger of politics and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> was one Dowd
herself helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX>. Or, to switch metaphors, she is simultaneously a
brilliant diagnostician of the political disease of our time and a symptom of
it. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>, after all, who wrote the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s alleged
affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>, as chronicled in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX>'s biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>,
on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . (Dowd protests that the piece
was an assignment and, quite rightly, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, decide what
goes on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>.)

            And it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> who last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> wrote a hilarious column called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Of Frogs and Newts</ENAMEX>," which linked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed speaker</ENAMEX> with, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> who speculates about what kind
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> would make, and who calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> "the Saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> of presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>"--meaning that the aura of
inevitability that surrounds him now may turn out to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. (Does
this make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> ?)

            The politics of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> is also a politics of
personality--of confession and "healing," of narcissism disguised as empathy.
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s (but kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s moments of self-revelation
are carefully rationed and, therefore, unusually effective. She recently wrote
a powerful piece about the shooting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou Diallo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> that
began with an account of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>, killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, in a defense of the concept of sexual harassment, she
recalled her own humiliation, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years before</TIMEX>, by a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> she had gone
to see about a job. And in a remarkable (and notorious) column from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, she detailed her encounter, at a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> herself, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> had mercilessly cast as a fat, insecure,
bubble-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. ("You can take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>, but
you can't take <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.") "Do you mind if I ask you
something?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>, "Why do you write such scathing articles
about me?"

            The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> was
struck dumb by this question has been used against her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> sees it as proof of her "utter disengagement" and her "detachment from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> she writes about." But we wouldn't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s failure to
muster a response, or about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s poise and forthrightness, unless Dowd
herself had chosen to tell us. And while perhaps an explicit admission that
she'd been unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> would have been sporting, the column as written
is at once more artful and more honest.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last October</TIMEX>, in a column that featured selections from
some of the predictably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misogynist</ENAMEX> hate mail she has received from both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> permitted herself to fantasize about a
parallel universe in which she could be "a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in love
with a neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cognac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>. Or an archaeologist in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yucatan</ENAMEX> who flies
her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> and owns a supper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fuzzy Slipper</ENAMEX>." "Anything," she
concluded "as long as I am not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> in the era of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, covering this horrible grudge match between the right
and the left that has been building since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>."

            Don't believe a word of
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> on her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s op-ed page fully in tune with the
political and cultural moment. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> beam their opinions at us as
through a time warp, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the hazy days</TIMEX> of past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX>
is stuck in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX> (though he tries to convince us that he's stuck
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to the end, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>
recalls the glorious presidency of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene McCarthy</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> is, mutatis
mutandis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.L. Mencken</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> era--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s symbiotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scourge</ENAMEX>. He may have the numbers of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> alone has his.

            Like the rest of his most loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and his most
intractable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> (and she has been, uniquely, both), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> is part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> boom generation. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Historians</ENAMEX> will record," she has written, elaborating on
something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Weiseltier</ENAMEX> once wrote about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s
contribution was to be the generation that worried about its contribution."
Another feature of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s passage through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture--shared
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, cynics and true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> herself--is a misty sense of some better, earlier
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> before they came along and screwed everything up.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s work as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, and in
particular the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> pieces that won her the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>, is one of the most
brilliant examples yet of boomer self-castigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency is,
of course, another example. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> worries a bit about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> will do when
it ends. She has been practicing for this inevitable terrible event lately,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">scoring</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nurse Ratched</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Flew Over the Cuckoo's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nest</ENAMEX> , admitting to a fondness for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, and having great fun at the
expense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">scions</ENAMEX> likely to fight it out in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. But while she will no doubt be splendid on their millennial campaign,
it's hard to see how her intemperate wit will find adequate targets in either a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Jr.</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            Is it too selfish of us to ask for a repeal of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> nd <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX>--for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four more years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million for Ken Starr</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
