
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Death Sentence</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Under pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX> will
add a single sentence to each print ad for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winston</ENAMEX>. Saying what?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 201</ENAMEX>)--
                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No-Stick Finish":</ENAMEX>
               

            

            

               
                  Fill in the blank. Ending her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, Secretary
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> was disappointed with that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s position on
human rights but has few ways to alter it, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lardy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carrot</ENAMEX>--that is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">_____________</ENAMEX>."
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baywatch</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mott</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
sentence with which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudians</ENAMEX> will have a field day."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>
Vuitton handbags and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> cashmere sweaters ... oops, wait, not
anymore."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Hoo-hoo! There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'Lardy</ENAMEX>' at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>! Lardy-butt, lardy-butt,
cannot get the bathroom door shut! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> "Cruel things were done to my
name in childhood" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uh ...</ENAMEX>
Dammit! Did anyone remember to tape <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20/20</NUMEX> for me last
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">night?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Goodman</ENAMEX>-Malamuth
            

            Click
for more answers. 

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            What have we got that
others envy? What are the crowning accomplishments of our society the world
yearns for? Cheap consumer goods, crappy fast food, and bland mass
entertainment! That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> cite. And, incidentally, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> announces his candidacy, I believe that that will be his official
slogan. Can't fit it on a bumper sticker? You can if the bumper's on a big
enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SUV</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven miles</NUMEX> to the gallon and it'll crush anything in its path,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comrade</ENAMEX>! Want one?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flies With Honey</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carrot</ENAMEX>--that is
permanent trade status ."

            Weary of facing an annual
vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> wants to be enshrined as a "most favored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>" with
the same economic rights as the major trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
This might induce the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> to take action on human rights and is even more
likely to urge them toward membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>. Joining
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> believe, would lead to lowered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> tariffs
and increased adherence to international trading laws, such as copyright.

            
               CCC
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Witherspoon</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that he was severing his
ties to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Conservative Citizens</ENAMEX>: "I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>. I am a
conservative. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing I am not is a racist." (One thing he will remain is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> voluntarily known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy</ENAMEX>.")

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, he had refused to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
saying it was not racist but merely an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for causes such as displaying
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Confederate</ENAMEX> battle flag and playing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dixie</ENAMEX>" at public events.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Poverty Law Center</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> is "the
reincarnation of the racist white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens Councils</ENAMEX>" that battled integration
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>.

            Decide for yourself by
visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> Web site.
Some highlights from the table of contents on its home page:

            
               OUR
WAR
            

            A multi-part exegesis of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX>'s ideology. "The Northern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> have been waging a religious war
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> all this time: secular humanism is intent upon
stamping out Christianity."--I believe we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> church attendance
down to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> and representation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to a meager <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX>.

            
               VIEWS
            

            Various opinion pieces,
including "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Troops Don't Belong</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Schlafly</ENAMEX>.--I
thought she was kept pretty busy writing for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Animals Attack</ENAMEX> .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LINCOLN</ENAMEX>
            

            Including astonishingly
nutty anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> links.--These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are going to be so upset when they find
out he's dead.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KING</ENAMEX>
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of durable
fascination to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> article: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liar</ENAMEX>? Sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Addict</ENAMEX>?
Fellow-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>?"--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Buddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy</ENAMEX> ...

            

               MILLARD
            

            An endless river of
goofball theories from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX>'s most prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Millard</ENAMEX>, including:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Betty Crocker Gets Blended</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'I Am</ENAMEX> Not A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hater Of Southern Whites'</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Vanishing American White In Search of White Identity for the Next</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Growth in Anti-Whitism</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stupid Race Panel Bashes Whites</ENAMEX>.
Surprised?"--It's about time someone had the guts to take on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence</ENAMEX>
Page.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The comedy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">literalism</ENAMEX>.

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
