
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">239</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Terror Train&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "We're not being
motivated by what's to come, but a fear of being left out as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> is
pulling away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, with some exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in mind." Who said this
about what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 238</ENAMEX>)--"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meta-4</ENAMEX>":
            

            
               "The so-called
low-hanging <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> has all been picked."
            

            
               "All of the cards
have fallen the wrong way at the same time."
            

            
               "If all you do is
fix the watch, nobody ever builds a better watch."
            

            
               "Everyone's in
deep yogurt."
            

            

               These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> lines have something in common. What?
            

            "Every
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> knows this one! They are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sentences you always insert
in plagiarized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> to throw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> off track."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX>
Shuger
            

            "Promo
lines for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoplait</ENAMEX>'s new 'playing card and watch parts on the bottom'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yogurt</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX>
            

            "They
are all quotations from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Testament Book of Aunt Ruth</ENAMEX>."-- Adrianne
Tolsch
            

            "OK.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> haiku translated and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 16</NUMEX> more to go for my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> final."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mays</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Awkwardly translated, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> signs held by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reasons To</ENAMEX>
Read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX> Wrap-Up
            

            Many cultures have a great epic filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> who personify the culture's values and vices. That function is now
provided by our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, which offer a kind of ongoing myth, related to
but not a literal rendering of any actual events, much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX>
account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark</ENAMEX> may allude to an actual flood, but it doesn't really
matter. (A more simplistic version of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Mythology</ENAMEX> is provided by TV
news--the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Classics Comic</ENAMEX> version, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cliff Notes</ENAMEX>.) This serialized myth
presents a roster of stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--among them, the erotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dynamo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>; the
erotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dynamo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX>; the sexless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, male only; the sexless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workaholic</ENAMEX>,
female only; the amiable doofus--to nobly embody or disgracefully lack the
qualities we prize.

            If you follow our <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ongoing Epic</ENAMEX>, you become familiar
with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, handy for making metaphors or making conversation with
your fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX>. This theory also gets at the proliferating
sections of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily papers</ENAMEX>, devoted to so much that is clearly not
news--developments in TV sitcoms, personal lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX>. These
aspects of life provide additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character types</ENAMEX>, imps and demigods, nymphs
and satyrs, to further populate our great saga. If we lived in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>,
we'd sprinkle our conversations with references to gods and goddesses; instead
we refer to those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titans</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

            The particularly loopy
metaphors in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question inspired many of you to suggest the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for the role of amiable doofus in our national drama, a sort of Loki
figure if that clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trickster</ENAMEX> were just a little less, well, clever. See
below.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Code Blue</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            Each was said by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> worried about cuts in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> payments to teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>.

            The particular mission of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>--training new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, developing new methods, treating the
poor--is paid for not by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> fees but by federal funds, and cuts have been
severe. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> cuts alone will cost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> will be laid off. Entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> will be closed
down.

            

               "The low hanging fruit" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Skinner</ENAMEX>) refers to the most easily made
budget cuts.

               "The cards" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr. Stuart Altman</ENAMEX>) are the lamentable combination of
increasing expenses and decreasing funds.

               "The watch" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Roper</ENAMEX>) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>; "fixing" it is curing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>; "building a better watch" is developing new medical techniques if you
really torture the metaphor. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, damn it, not an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>.
Well, OK, he is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, but he's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep yogurt</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell Rabkin</ENAMEX>) is a coy metaphor for deep
trouble.

            

            
               Does Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctor</ENAMEX>'s
Size Count Extra
            

            An ad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers</ENAMEX> runs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> under the banner: "When it comes
to ... PENILE ENLARGEMENT ... there is a difference" (ellipses theirs). Below,
some all too infrequently asked questions with answers gleaned from the ad and
the Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">barron</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Is there an illustration with the ad?
A: Yes. The famous statue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">discus thrower</ENAMEX>. I'd never noticed this before,
but he appears to be embarrassed by his unusually small penis.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> been seen on television?
A: Yes. (I'm not sure where I first heard about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, but it may have
been on Everybody <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loves Raymond Despite His Unusually Small Penis</ENAMEX> .)

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Does penis size matter?
A: Duh! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney S. Barron</ENAMEX>'s answer is more articulate, more elegant,
more--what's the word?--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincolnesque</ENAMEX>: "Size matters to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all
of the time and to all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> some of the time, but not to all of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all of the time." And then he didn't go on to add: "Is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emancipation Proclamation</ENAMEX> in your pocket, or are you just glad to see me?"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: But surely there is nothing known to medical science that could possibly
give me a lovelier scrotum, that could make a silk purse out of my, er,
wait--is that my phone ringing?
A: "Yes, there is. It's possible to do a fat transfer to the scrotal sac, which
results in a larger and fuller looking scrotum."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Is there some sort of hoity-toity name you could give the procedure to
make is sound kind of--I don't know--not stupid?
A: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scrotum Enhancement</ENAMEX>."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: How do I know where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">penis</ENAMEX> fits in? No, wait, let me rephrase
that.
A: Don't worry. I'm writing in the voice of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. A chart on our Web site
shows the percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that has various sizes of erect penis
from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3.75 to 9 inches</NUMEX>, broken down in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">quarter-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">increments</ENAMEX>. And it shows
erect girth from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 to 6.75 inches</NUMEX>. (You understand, that's the size of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">penises</ENAMEX>. We're not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-inches</NUMEX> tall. Now that would be
funny. Little <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. Can you imagine! Is that my phone?)

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Does the site have lots of before-and-after pictures of penises dangling
next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>?
A: Indeed it does. They'll put you in mind of a rather odd fishing trip.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Isn't there some way you could cash in on the insecurities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as
well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>?
A: Would you like to rephrase that?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Isn't there some way you could use your medical training to help women
as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>?
A: In addition to penis stretching, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barron Centers</ENAMEX> offer liposuction. And
not just to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. If you can afford it, we'll happily suck the fat out of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">poodle</ENAMEX> or a peach cobbler. In accordance with medical ethics, of course.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: What's all this going to cost me? Not me, but one of those small penis
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> or the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gals</ENAMEX>.
A: "The simple truth is that the procedures range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $4,900</NUMEX> to slightly
over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,900</NUMEX>, depending on which procedure or combination of procedures you
select. All fees include the procedures you've selected, all <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> costs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anesthesiology</ENAMEX> charges, and aftercare-follow-up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barron</ENAMEX>. There are no
'optional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX>.' "

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: So, I suppose that rules out some kind of blinking red light?
A: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical</ENAMEX> science is in its infancy.

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
