
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I'm wondering if I
am nuts. I am considering marrying again. (If you're thinking <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> marriage,
keep going.) I am no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>--and think my steady is the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. He
wishes to tie the knot, while I am on the fence. What say you?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blushing Bride</ENAMEX> ... Maybe
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Blush</ENAMEX>,

            Well, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">52</TIMEX> you do not need to marry in order to
have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. (Please don't anyone write me about petrie dishes.) And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX>
did die from an overdose of wedlock.

            On the other hand,
Prudie, herself, was never a bridesmaid but always a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>. It all boils down
to what feels right for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved. Do not let the heroic numbers
stand in your way. And if you do choose to walk down the aisle <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> wishes you mazel ton, which of course is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of luck.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, matrimonially

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I just wanted to ask a quick question. I went
wedding ring shopping with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. We have lived together for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and we really love each other. The whole time, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have never
said anything about me. And they refuse to pay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the wedding</TIMEX>, as they do not
approve of me. Apparently, I am a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> (read: not a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>). It's
a real strain on our relationship to have her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and grandparents letting
her know that they think I am unworthy.
            

            
               I'm in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and have always treated
her well. We split the rent right now, but when I get my degree I intend to pay
for rent and let her handle the money. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> want me to quit school and
"get a job." I wrote them and told them that the job I can get with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.A.</ENAMEX> is
likely to pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> as much as the job I can get with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX>, but they
don't seem to care.
            

            
               This is all very distressing. They have now cut
off all financial aid to her and refuse to pay for her wedding unless we have
it at their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. (I'd rather wed in hell, and so would she.) Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did,
however, have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> wedding for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, and then bought them a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> after they got married. Now they are claiming they have no money and
can't afford a wedding.
            

            
               Would it be
considered rude to shoot her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>?
            

            

               --Bummed Out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Bum</ENAMEX>,

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has the fondest feelings for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, she has a hunch you are a fine young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, your little firearms joke
notwithstanding. Because you state that you and your beloved are in agreement,
the sad but best thing to do is deep-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> the relationship with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
They sound controlling and manipulative and demonstrably unfriendly.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> recommends that
you end the discussion about a parent-sponsored wedding and do something simple
and meaningful ... and inexpensive. Purse strings can be strangling, so make
your own way and revel in the freedom.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, independently

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I write regarding your response to "" who did
not want to complain about the misdated baby blanket. What is it with people
who always complain about gifts? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> are wilted, the can is dented, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blouse</ENAMEX> has no sleeves, or my personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, told to me when I sent special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bagels</ENAMEX> and varied <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream cheeses</ENAMEX>, "I prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">margarine</ENAMEX>."
            

            
               Is something else going on? I like my friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue</ENAMEX>'s advice: Say you love it, then hide it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>. Anyway, keep up your
wonderful work.
            

            
               Sign me,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tired</ENAMEX> of Being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Complaint Department</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Ti</ENAMEX>,

            Feel better now? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is always here for people
who need to vent. As for something possibly underlying seemingly trivial
complaints, there need not necessarily be a repressed anything. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
just graceless.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes, by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, that the recipient of the bagels and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream cheese</ENAMEX> is not also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sue's</ENAMEX>, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream cheese</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> would be a disaster.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, olfactorally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have noticed a recent rambling of rhetoric
regarding "personal responsibility." Missing from all the talk is exactly what
personal responsibility is, and what it means to "accept personal
responsibility."
            

            
               It seems to me that, as of late, one can hide
from fallout by stating, early on, "I accept personal responsibility."
Period.
            

            
               Does personal responsibility mean I am
responsible for myself and thus immune from criticism? I am afraid that if I go
on I will become more befuddled.
            

            
               Sign me,
            

            

               --Personally Responsible in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Pers</ENAMEX>,

            Personal responsibility in some cultures means
falling on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>, either by resigning or ... by falling on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees with you that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> announce that they are
"responsible," then expect the subject to be closed. This is a little like
rapping oneself on the knuckles and then continuing on with business as usual.
Like much behavior-babble, certain phrases and concepts have become empty of
meaning.

            You clearly are inclined
to evaluate things philosophically, an approach for which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has
admiration.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, responsibly

         
      
   
