
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Method-ology
            

            As a miffed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, I wish to register my
protestations about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>'s "." Your Intdis Index is an accounting
system; it has nothing to do with the scientific method. The scientific method
is about hypothesis testing and experimentation. Simply giving things numerical
values is not science.

            I can understand your
wanting to shame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> with some semblance of
mathematical rigor, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> knows we poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have to defend ourselves
against enough nonsense posing as science ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, how can that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> study show us anything about bears when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> told me he never saw a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> in his life?").

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Personal Non
Grata
            

            "" wonders if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal investigator</ENAMEX> for the research project on the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s work
on young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who reported the story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , themselves, have
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and worked outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
lead story was about another research finding (air pollution in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>), and we did not learn whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
involved live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Newspapers</ENAMEX> continually report on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research or heart
disease without telling us if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> ever had those diseases, or if they
or any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of their immediate family is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">albino lab rat</ENAMEX>, and so on.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Haaga</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bethesda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               Does He or Doesn't
She?
            

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> (see "")
has no explicit gender, how do you know that the handbag, tutu, and so on
aren't veiled signals that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinky</ENAMEX> is female?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Wright</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>
replies: I didn't say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> have no gender, because they do. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> are
ostensibly male (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dipsy</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are ostensibly female (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Laa</ENAMEX> Laa
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX>). I said they have no intended sexual orientation.
            

            
               Choose and
Lose
            

            I adore intellectual parlor games as much as the
next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "" seems to be offered up as genuine critical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> rather than as the "cocktail chatter" it is. Like all dichotomies,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollonian</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionysian</ENAMEX> is limited as a means of ordering the world. It's like
putting a filter over a camera lens: Some colors are heightened, but others are
completely obscured, and the final result may bear no resemblance to reality.
Labeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> a "cool, calm, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern European</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> as a "hot,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">temperamental Spaniard"</ENAMEX> is that kind of distortion (not to mention ethnic
stereotyping of the most trivial and annoying sort). Do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s "blue period"
paintings really strike one as "hot" and "temperamental"?

            Do the terms apply to a work's form or its content?
I was especially amused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson/Whitman</ENAMEX> dichotomy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>'s poetry
is simply too weird, and yes, sexual (talk about images of "ecstatic release"),
to fit comfortably into a category whose hallmarks are deemed to be "measure,
reason, and control." Yes, you can sing just about every one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poems</ENAMEX> to the tune of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I'd Like To Teach the World To Sing"</ENAMEX> (try it, it's fun),
but that kind of surface-level orderliness is undermined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s
disconcerting propensity to topple into the abyss, whether prompted by union
with God, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with the beloved, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with death. If a work is "about"
"abandon, irrationality, and ecstatic release," but its execution displays
"measure, reason, and control" --one might place any number of baroque operas
in this category, for instance, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nathaniel Hawthorne</ENAMEX>, for that matter.

            Equally annoying is the
assertion that we are all either <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Matisse or Picasso</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stones</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles people</ENAMEX>. Many of my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquaintances</ENAMEX> have little tolerance for
any of them, while I would never be able to make a "desert <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>"
choice between them--really. Besides, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sympathy for the Devil</ENAMEX>" only seems
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">darker</ENAMEX> and more subterranean than "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O'Connell</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
