
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">222</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Zanimax&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farsi</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>") and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Mira</ENAMEX>"?) are in trouble for
similar offenses. What?
            

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 221</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Carrying On":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    Fill in the
blank on this comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Wiggins</ENAMEX>, jubilant over the voting on
a new proposal: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Missourians</ENAMEX> do not want __________ carried into football games
and bars and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>."
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "To be.
We like it at home."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scantily</ENAMEX> clad state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Footballs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>, and textbooks. What? Really? Well there goes my
re-election!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Chihuahuas ... or was it hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>? No: Chihuahuas with handguns!"-- Tam
Doey
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifeless bodies</ENAMEX> of our vanquished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael Roche</ENAMEX>
            

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most
exhausting lessons of adolescence is discovering that just because you've
settled an issue in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>--i.e., racism is bad; my history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> is such
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>--does not mean it is settled in the actual world. Racism persists and
you must still write your report on the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> frontier. One
of the most exhausting lessons of adulthood is discovering that just because
you've settled an issue in the actual world--i.e., abortion is legal; my
computer is fixed--doesn't mean you won't have to keep settling it again and
again. History is not a synonym for progress. No issue is ever settled. No case
is ever closed. And so, even after the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse James</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> must vote on the same policies over and over. But at least I won't
have to write an essay about it on my balky computer, and that's progress. Or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decrepitude</ENAMEX>.

            
               Unconcealed
Answer
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Missourians</ENAMEX> do not want <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> carried into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> games and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, despite a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> campaign by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> voted down an
attempt to lift the ban on concealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Forty-three <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> currently
permit concealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>'s Inside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry Extra</ENAMEX>: M*A*S*H
               
            

            I'm told that every now
and then a memo would arrive from above, demanding a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> -type
precis for the next episode. Since the episode might well not have been written
yet, they had a stockpile of generic descriptions: "It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4077</TIMEX>,
and all hell breaks loose in the OR" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One week</TIMEX>, hearing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> had begun
developing a new show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trapper John</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX> starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pernell Roberts</ENAMEX>, they
sent in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawkeye</ENAMEX> receives word from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trapper John</ENAMEX> is dead." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> didn't
see the humor in this.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultradull Weekend</ENAMEX>
Bonus Question
            

            A big <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-of-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a</NUMEX>-page ad on the op-ed page of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> criticizing military procurement policies was
placed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sensible Priorities</ENAMEX>, perhaps the most boring name ever devised
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. Separately, each of these words is dense with tedium, but
collectively ... Sorry ... where was I? Must have dozed off.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited
to create an even more torpid name for an even more lackluster
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Books--so illiterate are those illiterate
Midwesterners, they're just illiterate.

         
      
   
