
   
   
      
         
            Blundering Blurbers

            
               Duked
Out
Citing long-standing unresolved ethics and safety violations, federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> suspended human experimentation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University Medical Center</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. The experiments ranged from drug tests to research on
psychological reactions to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>. Among the alleged violations: "insufficient
training" of review <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, "potential financial conflicts of interest
with some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>," and inadequate supervision of informed-consent
procedures. (Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> also uncovered an incident in which a
space-walk experiment volunteer briefly lost consciousness.) The ban was lifted
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX> agreed to overhaul its procedures for protecting human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. The
government also warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New York</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Sinai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX> to clean up their safety
procedures or face shutdowns of their federally financed human research.

            
               Legal
Omertà
               
            

            

               Closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Lazarus</ENAMEX>' behind-the-scenes exposé of political
wrangling at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, continues to generate controversy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazarus</ENAMEX>, who clerked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Blackmun</ENAMEX>, earned the
opprobrium of legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> for making
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> in his book, published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
Kronman, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX> who blurbed the hardcover edition of the
book as "well-researched and wonderfully written," has formally apologized to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> and sent a letter of explanation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>.
Declaring that his initial enthusiasm for the book constituted a "real lapse"
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment, Kronman</ENAMEX> said he believes former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> are bound to silence about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s nonpublic discussions and activities. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kronman</ENAMEX>'s blurb will not appear on the paperback edition of the book
due out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>.

            
               Little Big
Man
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review of Books</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Powers</ENAMEX> stands accused of ignorance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incompetence</ENAMEX>, and racial stereotyping by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> studies scholars
for his review of several books about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who has written about spycraft and the atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, drew the ire of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Hilden</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Krupat</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Lawrence College</ENAMEX>, who wrote that he had
"little or no detailed knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> scholarship" and that he
reproduced tired clichés about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> and traditions. "We are
quite certain that no one of us would be asked to review books in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fields</ENAMEX>," the signatories declared in a letter in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX> issue. Powers
expressed bafflement at the charges, concluding that the letter "amounts to an
attempt to intimidate ... me from writing about 'their field.' " The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> concurred: "It is hard to take seriously <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> who
condemn an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> without making a single substantive criticism of
his work."

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academics</ENAMEX>
Strike Back
            

            

               Star Wars hoopla visits academia, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning</ENAMEX>
News . Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> view the original Star Wars film as a simplistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> allegory that helped to legitimize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> as an "evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>" and to build popular support for a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">star wars</ENAMEX>"
missile defense. Others reverse the movie's ideological lenses, arguing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaker George Lucas</ENAMEX> based his "evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth</ENAMEX>
Vader on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>. Finally, others charge that Star Wars
represents a covert remake of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birth of the Nation</ENAMEX> . "The narrative
homologies between <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birth of a Nation and Star Wars</ENAMEX> click beyond
the possibility of accident," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Taylor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufts University</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Darth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vader</ENAMEX> (dark invader?) is the upstart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of 'black' political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>,
threatening a weakened, but spiritual, refined, and honor-bound version of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'South</ENAMEX>.' ... [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">R2-D2</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-3PO</ENAMEX>] take the place of those sassy, back-talking
darky house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>, of equally mechanical loyalty to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">betters</ENAMEX>." Whatever
their differences, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> agree on Star Wars ' enduring impact on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture.

            
               Eyes on the
Prize
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bancroft Prize</ENAMEX>, given to honor the best works of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
history, was awarded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books on slavery and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the (hostile)
relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>. The books are Many
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone: The First Two Centuries of Slavery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ira Berlin; Slave Counterpoint: Black Culture in</ENAMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eighteenth-Century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chesapeake & Lowcountry</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip D. Morgan</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">The Name of War</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Origins of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Identity</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Lepore</ENAMEX>.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Side of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow</ENAMEX>
            

            
Affirmative action is good for you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, for one, cites statistical evidence to argue that affirmative
action benefits not only minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> but all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who
attend a "diverse" college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> are more likely to work in integrated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">settings</ENAMEX> and to display ambition, confidence, and other worthy traits, the
school attests. "Diversity enhances learning," says university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bollinger</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> offers a rosy portrait
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> after the abolition of affirmative action. Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who
once might have been admitted to the system's best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are now finding
places at lower-tier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. More important, the new dispensation has
encouraged state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> to step up their efforts to recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from
low-performing high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, often with positive results.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">businesschool</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
            

            Junk
bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Milken</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> are partnering in an online business school
venture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> has just announced a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNEXT</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, an online
education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> partly funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milken</ENAMEX> and headed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustee</ENAMEX>.
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> anticipate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> in revenues just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty members</ENAMEX> are concerned about conflicts of interest, not only
on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trustee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Rosenfield</ENAMEX>, but also because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNEXT</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Becker</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merton Miller</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Fischel</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fischel</ENAMEX> is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Payback: The Conspiracy To Destroy Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Milken and His Financial Revolution</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrators</ENAMEX> protest that they are
only keeping pace with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNEXT</ENAMEX> has already signed on with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> are
considering commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> for their own online programs.

            
               UC-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> Folds
...
            

            A
monthlong protest by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>'s ethnic studies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, marked by a hunger strike and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">129</NUMEX> arrests, ended in near complete capitulation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, which promised
more tenure-track faculty and a research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. The "Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation</ENAMEX>
Front" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> argued that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> had neglected
its ethnic studies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, failing to fill positions in fields such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> studies. The agreement calls for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty members</ENAMEX> to design a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> plan to guide the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s hiring strategy.

            
               ... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And So Does</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX>
            

            
Protests by anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villanova University</ENAMEX> convinced former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX> to bow out as a commencement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. The
best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> would have been the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> member of her family to receive
an honorary degree from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>. Quindlen, a
plans to discuss abortion in her address--"I would have talked about the sheer
pleasure of living," she told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Inquirer</ENAMEX> . She added that
she didn't want to divert attention from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> on their graduation day.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX>-mollified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quindlen</ENAMEX>'s gesture: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Collegians for Life</ENAMEX> regrets that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> did not revoke the
invitation <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yo Queerio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
            

            Under
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Missionary Positions</ENAMEX>" theme, the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano Studies</ENAMEX> met in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, to focus on sexuality, a topic long considered taboo in the
Latino <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reports, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>
gathered to hear papers on subjects that ranged from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Latina rage</ENAMEX>" to "joto"
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">queer</NUMEX>) scholarship to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano</ENAMEX> rap music and machismo. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alicia</ENAMEX>
declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano</ENAMEX> studies has "finally been won by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
gender studies." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Lutheran University</ENAMEX>
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, predicted a "backlash" in a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Academics</ENAMEX> are no more enlightened than anyone else."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas Shrugs</ENAMEX> at No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
            

            At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of April</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> posted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lists of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nonfiction titles of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>--one
as judged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Library</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caleb Carr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Pagels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Gould</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Krakauer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX>, among others) and the
other as judged by the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>," or basically anyone who voted for his or her
favorite book on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Library</ENAMEX> Web site. Topping the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>" list is The
Education of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Adams</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Adams</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>" gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayn Rand</ENAMEX> four
titles in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, including the top slot. In response, the feisty journal
Philosophy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Literature</ENAMEX> has inaugurated a different kind of discussion
on its listserv . Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are posting their votes for the
worst books. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rand</ENAMEX> has proved to be a listserv favorite, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinbeck</ENAMEX>'s Cannery Row and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>' The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX> have
also garnered mentions.

         
      
   
