
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;A and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Q&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               I give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s answer; you give the question from his rare
and recent press conference: "I think it's very important. And I think that
what young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will learn from my experience is that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> have to
do that, and that there are consequences when you don't."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 210</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let Us Now Praise Famous Me</ENAMEX>":
               

               

                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You like me</ENAMEX>! You really like me!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Field</ENAMEX>
                  
               

               

                  "I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the world and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">lord of Monkey Island</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cameron</ENAMEX>
                  
               

               
                  Every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Awards broadcast yields <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> perfect remark. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to predict
the comment from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> that will be most quoted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
papers.
               

               

                  ( Topic courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>. )
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fernanda Montenegro</ENAMEX>: 'Why is the sickly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> holding my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX>?' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Benigni</ENAMEX>: 'Yes I'm look nuts, but I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. I want to thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX>
for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 mics</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>. I am a lacto-vegetarian. You can give me <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spinach</ENAMEX>. I like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and radish. Now I am biting the moon.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall</ENAMEX>
Efron
               

               " 'Oh
God! Someone just shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Rivers</ENAMEX>!' (or was that 'THANK God'?)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
Petrosky
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coburn</ENAMEX>: 'And I especially want to thank my life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>; this one's for you, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Vance</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Hiller</ENAMEX>: 'I'm terribly, terribly sorry.' (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rescinding</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pesci</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marisa Tomei, Goldie Hawn</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
Costner, and reassigning them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Bacall</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX>.) 'Also,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiller</ENAMEX> added, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Al Pacino's Oscar</ENAMEX> is no longer for
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scent of a Woman but for The Godfather</ENAMEX> . That is all.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">They Don't Have the Met Here, but They Do Have Back to the Future: The Ride</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Counts for Something</ENAMEX>" Carvell
               

                

                

                

                

                

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

            

            I no longer watch the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX>. They're neither good enough to take straight--the choices convey no
aesthetic authority; the performances make no earthly sense--nor consistently
awful enough to enjoy as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. (Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> was claptrap, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare in Love</ENAMEX> was indeed wonderful.) Or perhaps I've simply lost
my taste for cleavage and greed. There's a relentless evolution in this sort of
event, from genuinely interesting, to ludicrously bad, to soporifically bland.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal stage</ENAMEX>, having achieved the tone of a shopping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mall</ENAMEX>, a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> event, frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cajun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each March</TIMEX>,
instead or watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>, I rent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All About Eve</TIMEX> and heave a
smoke <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. And the best thing about my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX>: It's Whoopi-free.

            
               Politics and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poetry</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Poets</ENAMEX> have announced major changes. A comparison.

            
               Most Apparent
Change:
            

            AAP: More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of color on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chancellors</ENAMEX>.

            
               NR : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More</NUMEX> color photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>.

            
               What the Changes
Mean:
            

            AAP: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the many
things going on in poetry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Galassi</ENAMEX>.

            
               NR : "It's going to be fresh and frisky," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">publisher Will Lippincott</ENAMEX>.

            
               Will it Be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuddy-Duddy</ENAMEX>?:
            

            AAP: No official position.

            
               NR : "It's not going to be fuddy-duddy,"
insists Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lippincott</ENAMEX>.

            
               Biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prize</ENAMEX>
Offered:
            

            AAP: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> Tanning <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prize</ENAMEX>.

            
               NR : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winner</ENAMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> sweepstakes
gets to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> editorial meeting; loser forced to attend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> edi ...
oh, you know how this one goes.

            
               Possible Impetus
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Change</ENAMEX>:
            

            AAP: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxine Kumin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Kizer</ENAMEX> resign from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> in protest.

            
               NR : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX> dragged from office in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handcuffs</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Means of Avoiding</ENAMEX>
Stasis:
            

            AAP: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rotation</ENAMEX> system instituted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chancellors</ENAMEX>.

            
               NR : Frequent firings and resignations
instituted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> in chief.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Means of Avoiding</ENAMEX>
Pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Bias</ENAMEX>:
            

            
               NR : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Peretz</ENAMEX>'s public pledge to do
less boosting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.

            AAP: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Galassi</ENAMEX>'s
implicit pledge to discourage erotic sonnets about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
