
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">194</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Unaffordable&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               After a call from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Motors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Bradsher</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Archives</ENAMEX>
said, "You have to think in terms of corporate memories. There is probably no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> around who knows anything about this stuff." What stuff does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> need help
remembering?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 193</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>":
               

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poitras Report</ENAMEX>,
recently released in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>, describes an inept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that routinely
broke the law, lacked ethics and professionalism, and embraced a code of
silence that thwarted whistle-blowers. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>?
               

               

                  ( Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>.)
                  
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Cohen</ENAMEX>'s old girlfriends."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
               

               
"Whoever it is, it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of Scientology</ENAMEX>. Now please give me back my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>. But I'd like to see ya come down here and release
that report, tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
               

               "Sounds
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX>, but any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that could find hookers
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> seems far from inept to me."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara Williams</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Reid</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie Haskins</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

               "Who
cares? It's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ballard</ENAMEX> )

               Click
for more answers.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unguarded</ENAMEX> Wrap-Up
            

            According to the old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> clichés, a diet of back <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX> and access to excellent health care lead
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Young</ENAMEX> boring everyone silly by singing about hockey in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> languages.
The new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> cliché, judging by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> responses, is just hockey, and
it's now broadcast on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>. It's a different sort of coverage from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Puck</ENAMEX> appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between periods</TIMEX> to explain the game to us unsophisticated
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. That animated black rubber cylinder provided a surprisingly lucid
exegesis of offside, icing, and the undesirability of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> separatism, along
with some disturbing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX> sex techniques. But I may be misremembering. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> we played without helmets, and I was regularly high-sticked in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>. Hey hey, hi hi.

            
               Answer
Québecois
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Sûreté du Québec.</ENAMEX>

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,100</NUMEX> member provincial police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, more a
sort of regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> than state troopers, accepted the scathing criticism
delivered by a public inquiry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> and will undertake sweeping reforms,
reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monique Beaudin</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montreal Gazette</ENAMEX> . "We are taking this
very seriously," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SQ chief Florent Gagné</ENAMEX>.

            The investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> headed by former Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Poitras</ENAMEX> was set up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> to look into allegations of
cover-ups and threats after a botched drug investigation.

            "They have been notorious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>," adds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>.

            
               Augmented
Quotations Extra
            

            Each final sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.

            

               "I think it's absolutely ludicrous to completely
wipe out something so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are in favor of. Just like with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sorority</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Coup</ENAMEX> detests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth</ENAMEX>'s plan to eliminate
single-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fraternities</ENAMEX> and sororities.

               "It would be much nicer to have real ones. My dad
said he was disappointed too. You need the noise and the smell. It's as
disappointing as those robot lap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny Chang</ENAMEX> hates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX> firecrackers.

               "I've got so much real work to do, I can't do this
very often. After lunch, I launch myself into a low <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> orbit to battle giant
space monkeys from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neptune</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawyer Johnnie Cochran</ENAMEX> sets aside time from his
busy schedule to appear on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Guiding Light</ENAMEX> .

               "We're getting the speed of light so low we can
almost send a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> into the system, go for a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and return in time
to see the light come out. We can also see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX> making up gags about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lene Vestergaard Hau</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> have devised
a way to slow light from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">186,00 miles</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">120 feet an hour</NUMEX>.

               "We do not know where he is. He made us all close
our eyes, spin around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times, and count backwards from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>."--Taliban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diplomat Abdul Hakeem Musjahid</ENAMEX> has looked everywhere for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>, but
just can't find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hockey</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
