
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, and I have
a problem with geographically challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who confuse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
(just a part of the whole) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, and are constantly sending
mail addressed to me in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>--instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Should I make a pest
of myself and keep telling my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that I live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, or
should I just shrug it off?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adopted Welshman</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Ad</ENAMEX>,

            Ah yes, a gray matter issue. But you have come to
the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. A geographically challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, that is. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks
she was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> when other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> learned these things in grade
school.)

            In any case, speaking as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who would be on the receiving end of your "pestering," by all means offer
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>education. Sending mail--and wanting it to arrive--makes your little
lesson one with actual value. If, however, you find yourself having to tell the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> more than once, then shrug it off ... and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you
will be compassionate.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, geographically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Just a quick note of support for your reply to
"" regarding forms of address. I think your first instinct, that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
should address <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in the manner in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> ask to be addressed,"
is absolutely dead on.
            

            
               Not only as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, but even now--well into my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulthood</ENAMEX>--this rule has served me well. Not only do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> appreciate my
respect for their preferences, but I also don't have to choose to whom to cater
in mixed situations. It is one of those rare cases in which I can please
everyone. Best of all, though, I avoid the hubris of pushing my ideas of
appropriate formality on others, even those who agree with me.
            

            
               Now I just wish more
forms would allow me to omit Mr. from my name ...
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accommodating</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Ac</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thanks you for the
vote of confidence, and doubly so because she was taken to task by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
who disagreed. We are kindred in another way, as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> just likes to use
her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and last name and would happily ditch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> or the Mrs. or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Miss.</ENAMEX>

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, gratefully

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Does a bridesmaid
have to give the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> a gift for every shower given?
            

            

               --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professor</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Prof</ENAMEX>,

            Certainly not. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brides</ENAMEX> have so many people
entertaining for them that it would seem to be constantly "raining" luncheons
and teas--and etiquette calls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> to be invited to every such
event.

            The bridesmaids may skip
giving shower presents, unless they simply feel they'd like to. Or a token gift
would be appropriate. And since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, a small
addendum about those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brides</ENAMEX> who've previously been up at bat. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Post</ENAMEX> wrote
this: "Those who attended a shower for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> before she was married the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time should not be invited to a second shower unless they are very close
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> or very dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who would want to be present."

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, graciously

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               We got to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, with
whom we had much in common. We shared tools, went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> together,
cared for each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> while away on trips. They borrowed a bottle of wine
while we were gone, and they were doing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> thing for us. It was not a wine
that was known to them (i.e., they didn't know if it was a gift, or special in
some other way). But they took it anyway, drank it, and told us about it as
soon as we returned. It was not, in fact, a special or expensive bottle of wine
but, not to belabor the point, they didn't know that. They also didn't replace
it in a timely fashion. When we let them know we weren't happy with the whole
thing, they were offended and have since completely severed the
friendship.
            

            
               What do you think about taking something like
this from someone's home while you're doing them a favor? If it had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> from the fridge we wouldn't have given it a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought. But a bottle
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> that may have been irreplaceable?
            

            
               Thanks,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sad</ENAMEX> in Philly
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dear Sad</ENAMEX>,

            First, they told you, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, they failed to
replace it. This suggests they view things differently than you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, and their
idea of correct behavior is different from yours. There is a chance that, by
their lights, they assumed that had you been home you would have "lent" them
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees with you that this was not first-rate
behavior. It could be, though, that they just didn't know any better. Should
you feel generous and lonesome for the friendship, you might make the first
move and say you wish to let bygones be bygones because the relationship was
important to you. I mean, you all went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> together!

            Their severing ties
bespeaks their embarrassment at having made a social misstep and perhaps anger
that you wouldn't cut them some slack. So ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> recommends that you patch
it up if you wish the whole thing had never happened. And she is certain
if relations are repaired that the neighbs will never again help themselves to
anything in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, soothingly

         
      
   
