
   
   
      
         
            The Out-of-Towners

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> toys
with a run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat, the main charge leveled
against her has nothing to do with her conventional liberal views, her status
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, or her smarmy New Age morality. Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> blast
her status as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbagger</ENAMEX>--an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinoisan</ENAMEX>, by way of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, who would exploit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s lax residency requirements for personal
glory. So how come no one cares that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>?

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> grew
up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Still, the point is that in our highly mobile society,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carpetbagging</ENAMEX> is as common a political sin as taking soft money or committing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adultery</ENAMEX>. According to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> tally by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roll Call</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--were born outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> they
represented. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Byrd</ENAMEX>, known for bringing federal pork to his West
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>, hails from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>. And his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior colleague</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, isn't a native either. Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX>, hoping to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capture New Hampshire</ENAMEX>'s critical primary as a native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trenton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX> Yet the charge of carpetbagging remains a favorite campaign-season
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accusation</ENAMEX>.

            Where does the term come from? Southerners pinned the label
on both the opportunistic and idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Northerners</ENAMEX> who packed their worldly
possessions into "carpetbags" during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX> to enter
politics. A term of opprobrium, the word came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX>' perception
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> represented the dregs of society, seeking nothing but easy
political gain. In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX> were scorned for capitalizing on
the freed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>' newly granted right to vote. Testifying before a
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William M. Lowe</ENAMEX> explained, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carpetbagger</ENAMEX> is generally understood to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who comes here for office
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sake</ENAMEX>, of an ignorant or bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, and who seeks to array the negroes
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>."

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> won the
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1870s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
"redeemers" (as they were admiringly called) got the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to
withdraw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> that were safeguarding the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile,
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacists</ENAMEX> regained control of state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> through fraud and
violence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX>, who wrote the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of histories of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>, portrayed slavery as a benign, paternalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> (for more on
this topic, see "") and painted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX> as venal and corrupt
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interlopers</ENAMEX>.

            Hardly a pack of jackals feeding off the crippled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX> came from various backgrounds and acted from a range of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> tell us. Most were well educated, and included former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, newspapermen, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">postwar Freedmen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>.

            The opportunism of some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX> was more economic than political: The war-ravaged and
economically stagnant <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> direly needed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to spur the kind
of dynamic industrial and commercial growth that was transforming the rest of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Others, of a religious bent, followed what one called "a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mission</ENAMEX>
with a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>" to help former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>. Still others simply warmed to the
region's climate, the way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would later flock to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. "Maybe I
will locate in the sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> wrote to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX>. "What think you of roses blooming in open air in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, and the
gardens glorious with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>." As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Current</ENAMEX> noted, the phrase
"Go <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" supplanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Greeley</ENAMEX>'s famous exhortation to head
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>.

            While the behavior of a few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX> is,
according to Current, "rather difficult to defend," most were not unusually
corrupt. Committed to rebuilding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, they advocated strong public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX>, labor reform, and progressive taxation. As
for disturbing race relations, of course many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX> did so--that was
the whole idea. In a society drenched in white supremacism, race relations had
to be disturbed. Few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would question their virtue on that score.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX>'
reputation has improved, but the word's negative connotations have spread to
cover all ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX>. The proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX>, then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">automobile</ENAMEX>, and later the airplane made this a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile</ENAMEX>, ambitious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-20 th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX> made up the
majority in the West. Yet, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> dating back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis de Tocqueville</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1835</TIMEX> have noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> take pride in their local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wherever</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transience</ENAMEX> and provincialism collide, the charge of carpetbagging still
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stings</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> went to court to try to force him off the ballot,
arguing he hadn't lived in the district long enough. (They lost.) In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Flynn</ENAMEX>--a lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX>--leased an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Boston</ENAMEX> apartment to qualify for an open
congressional seat. (He lost, too.) Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynn</ENAMEX> was merely imitating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>, who ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX> by using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> as his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">11 th District</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>." (He won.) A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> rival placed a
mocking newspaper ad: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Congress Seat for Sale</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Experience Necessary</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Applicant Must Live</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s easy residency requirements--you only
need to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> at the time of the election--and its political prominence
make it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbagger</ENAMEX> magnet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detractors</ENAMEX> assailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX> for his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> bid; even the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Keating</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Buckley</ENAMEX> suffered
similar charges en route to winning the seat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> have accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
of carpetbagging in other high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> races: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lautenberg</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Huffington</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Sarbanes</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Brock</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, also in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'94</TIMEX>. It
didn't help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s case that he had already served as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>--from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>.

            For all its currency, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbagger</ENAMEX> charge only
carries these days in parochial places and when it plays into other, more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">potent</ENAMEX>, liabilities: the naked ambition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huffington</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-insider image of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>. Solid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFK</ENAMEX> (or HRC),
weather the charges. And for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>,
living in an adopted home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to matter at all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>
requires only that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> "when elected, be an inhabitant of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for
which he shall be chosen." Having rehabilitated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX>, we might as
well give them back their good name.

         
      
   
