
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Go
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Star Pictures</ENAMEX>). A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> adore the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>--"the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> truly thrilling movie I've seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> )--but most say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Liman</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swingers</ENAMEX> ) does well but misses greatness. Biggest complaint: The film
is overly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarantinoesque</ENAMEX>. Some say the results are good: Sure, it's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiction Jr.</ENAMEX>," but "the intoxicating brashness of youth--and not graphic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gore</ENAMEX>, language and violence--is what keeps Go moving" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). The highlights of the film are young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Polley</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taye Diggs</ENAMEX>, as well as the breakneck pace of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> intertwining plot lines,
each full of vigorous thrill-seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>. On the down side,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX> writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clever</ENAMEX> as parts are, Go doesn't
add up to much," and several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rainer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> says, "There's nothing much to this movie except a lot of
funky attitude"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> likes the film: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>]erivative as it is,
Go has a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> of its own. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liman</ENAMEX>] does not merely
appropriate the familiar, he takes it by storm." (This <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Polley</ENAMEX> fan
site has pictures, information, and links to other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dreamlife of Angels</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX>-throttle raves
for this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> feature film for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erick Zonca</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, intimate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">touching</ENAMEX>, with an emotional immediacy that is killing" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ); "brilliant" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ).
The film follows the trajectory of an intense friendship that develops between
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who meet at a sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leads, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Élodie Bouchez</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natacha Régnier</ENAMEX>, were widely honored in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. (They shared <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Actress at</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cannes</ENAMEX> and each won a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">César</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> concur with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
enthusiasm: Maslin calls it a "beautifully acted drama, as raw and immediate as
it is heartfelt" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> calls it
"completely absorbing, almost rudely poignant" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ). (For
a biography, filmography, and news on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bouchez</ENAMEX>, click here.)

            
               
                  Never Been
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kissed</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> agree that the plot
(a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> goes back to high school undercover) is trite but say the dreamy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX> makes it all worthwhile: The "screenplay is contrived. ... but
Barrymore illuminates it with sunniness and creates a lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. I
think this is what's known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> power" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). A few are immune to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barrymore charm: The New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX> calls it "the latest and dumbest in the deluge of
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> comedies," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrymore</ENAMEX> is trapped in "goofy oopsadaisy behavior that does justice
neither to her talents nor to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>." But this is a minority view. Most find
her irresistible, sometimes to the point of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-sharing: "You just want to
wipe away the tears from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cheeks</ENAMEX> and give snookums a big old hug"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX> is one of those smitten: "It's worth seeing, it demands to be seen,
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX>, who is at once the dizziest and most magically poised
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comedienne</ENAMEX> in movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." Read the rest of his review .)

            

               
                  Metroland
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Gate Films</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for this
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> film about a suburban family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who looks back wistfully at his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">footloose days</TIMEX> after a wild 'n' crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
Contrary to expectation, the film ends up celebrating his marriage; it's a
"no-fuss movie that casts a rich, tranquil spell" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman, Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ). High marks go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Watson</ENAMEX> in the role of the staid but smart
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who manages to make humdrum domesticity appealing. "The odd aspect of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> is that, though we quickly realize we have seen this story before, it's
being done so intelligently that we're enjoying it" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kauffmann</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> ). Those who aren't caught up in the story call it bland; some find
the ending forced. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX> writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> is such a diabolical minx that
she makes the prospect of a life amid those metros and under those gray skies
more seductive than an endless luau." Read the rest of his review .)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ground</ENAMEX>
Beneath <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Feet</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Holt</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX>'s latest, a sprawling tale of rock 'n' roll mixed with ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mythology</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX> to task for what they see as his
sloppiness: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> calls the novel a "loose, baggy monster" and "a
decidedly disappointing performance" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX>
writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> that it is "a very bad novel about rock and roll."
Some are not put off by the mishmash: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wood</ENAMEX>'s windy positive review in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> is nothing more than a long plot
description with a single sentence of critical response: He calls it "exuberant
and elegiac ... his best since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midnight's Children</ENAMEX> ." Interesting tidbit:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carla Power</ENAMEX> notes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rushdie</ENAMEX> got an eye lift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Marzorati</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX> the book in 
                  Slate
               , and this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> has an
impressive listing of links to articles on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX>'s books, life, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fatwa</ENAMEX> .)

             

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The Iceman
Cometh
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene O'Neill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks Atkinson Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
City). Raves for this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> import, directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Davies</ENAMEX> and starring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' only complaints are about the play itself, which they
call heavy-handed and overlong. Spacey as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickey</ENAMEX>, the slick-talking salesman
who punctures the pipe dreams of a pack of sad sack rummies in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Hope</ENAMEX>'s
bar, "gives the performance of his life," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Zoglin</ENAMEX>:
"A potentially grueling <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> becomes a breathtaking experience." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kroll</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> : "Never have these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hours</TIMEX> in hell raced by
with such Einsteinish speed." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Isherwood</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> :
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>]akes a startling case for the reexamination of this landmark play ... a
magnificent achievement." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
that the play "manages to entertain even at its darkest and preachiest."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strangest</ENAMEX> line in a review: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Spacey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
writes, "On the move, he is a panther in pants; when still, a coiled cobra."
(This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> has
photos, cast bios, and ticket information.)

            Find a
movie playing near you on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX>
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>
               

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Things I Hate About You</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Walk on the Moon</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie- - <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Out-of-Towners</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Financier</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strouse</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Life and My Life With the</ENAMEX>

                  Times , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Frankel</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mod Squad</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EdTV</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dates</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Futurama</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- All Too Human: A Political Education</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief of Unbearable Urges</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englander</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  True Crime ;

               
                  Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> and I ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces of Nature</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renewal</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  
                     Movie--
                  
                  The
Deep End of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corruptor</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage: Carrie</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  Wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Death-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  Black <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hawk Down</ENAMEX>: A
Story of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Modern War</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Bowden</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
