
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China Loves America</ENAMEX>'s Bombs

            
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the "minimum requirements" of even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politburo</ENAMEX> are that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> issue a full apology for
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> a bigger role in resolving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict. But hard-liners,
who include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Liberation Army</ENAMEX>, are calling for an
overall scaling down of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relations unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> agrees to stop its
offensive against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. In a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> on
emergency <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> meetings of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadres</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> noted that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLA</ENAMEX>'s Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xiong Guangkai</ENAMEX> insisted that the embassy
strike had been a deliberate attempt by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to trample on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
sovereignty. Noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has reserved the right to take
"further action," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> said "they would do their best if that 'action'
contained a military component." Quoting "a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said,
"government-organized protests would continue at least through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>." It
also predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shi Guangsheng</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX> will now reverse some of the concessions they granted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX>.

            
According to a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in the Straits Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China's Liberation Army Daily</ENAMEX> , the mouthpiece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLA</ENAMEX>, had
been much impressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s bombing methods in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX> strike. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only last week</TIMEX>, it urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to change its defense strategy
so as to master <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> precision-bombing techniques. In an article published last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Army Daily</ENAMEX> said, "We have to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis
to raise the alarm, and work towards high-technology warfare, create new
warfare techniques and training methods." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has not
done enough research on long-distance precision missile strikes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkan</ENAMEX>
crisis will accelerate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s military modernization drive, it said. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straits Times</ENAMEX> said that, because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' promise of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">theatre-</ENAMEX>missile defense system for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLA</ENAMEX> is
expected to intensify the development of intermediate or long-range <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>
and military communications technology.

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> expressed its "stalwart moral support for the
protests that are blazing across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>-directed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">atrocity</ENAMEX>." Insisting that the attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> was deliberate, the
editorial said it was "too smart to be explained as a 'mistake in target
identification' or a technical error." It asked, "Then what is the reason that
can convincingly explain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>'s provocation? ... Is it because of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
persistent opposition to their barbarity<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" In its editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX>
deplored the "blind arrogance" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> in believing it can drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> to capitulate through airstrikes alone, and it
said that the orchestrated protests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> are "understandable." But it also
said that claims that the bombing was no accident are "simply ludicrous," since
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nato</ENAMEX> stood only to lose by its action." Calling on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
to "undertake a damage-limitation exercise in earnest," it said the most
important thing is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to make "a proper and public apology.
Not words of sadness, but a formal expression of apology."

            The
papers in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> generally agreed that the bombing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> was the worst thing that could have happened. They widely
credited it with having destroyed all hope for the peace principles agreed in
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. There was bitter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mockery</ENAMEX>, too, of reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> was using old maps of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> was built. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> published a headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> reading
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> failed to check phone book" and a map with an arrow pointing at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> and the words "Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deligradska Ulica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11000</NUMEX>." Having been the most hawkish in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> throughout the war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
press has started to show small signs of defeatism. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, for example, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Observer</ENAMEX> , which previously supported the bombing as a
prelude to a successful ground campaign, called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> for it to be scaled
down, deciding that a land war is no longer a practical possibility. "Without
it, compromise may allow us to achieve most of what we want," it concluded
hopefully.

            But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
Times urged "escalating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s attacks to maximum pitch, redoubling its
efforts to avoid civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, pushing ahead with plans for the use of land
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX>, and keeping the diplomatic pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to agree to terms." It
even said that "the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing has focused the attention of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN Security Council</ENAMEX> may be no bad thing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> also urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to intensify the war effort, saying that "the problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s conduct
of the war is not that it is employing too much force. It is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has not
used enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to behave in accordance with the
minimum of humanity." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accusing NATO</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of pusillanimity, it
said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s equation seems to be simple: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovars</ENAMEX> are not
worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>."

            The
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> took the same line, criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
for his "studied ambivalence" during his visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and saying that it
"suggests that he is still looking for a settlement on the basis of bombing
alone." Describing the attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> as "a crass mistake," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said it made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s aim harder to achieve than before, with
the result that "the air campaign will be prolonged as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is emptied of
ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and the support of Western public opinion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX> action
wanes. In such a quandary does the fear of taking casualties land you." Unlike
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , which seem to have given up hope of
a land invasion, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> reaction to the embassy
bombing showed that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interests are intimately bound up with the speedy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis." "Speed cannot now mean more bombs," it said.
"Speedy resolution could denote ... greater willingness by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to act
on the ground."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, Le Monde
warned in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that because of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s attitude a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> might no longer even have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> "core" if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukrainian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presences</ENAMEX> in it were too strong. Deploring this prospect, it said the essential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aim</ENAMEX> of getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> back to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> could only be achieved
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> have confidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. "Its composition mustn't seem to
them like a compromise favorable to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> , " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said, for
"if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> chased from their land cannot return
there freely to reconstruct their future, the allied forces will have lost the
war."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo Sunday</ENAMEX> described
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Solana</ENAMEX> and allied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX> as
"total incompetents." And it said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> who appointed
them "have taken on a grave responsibility by making themselves accomplices of
their imbecilic 'smart bombs,' thus delegitimizing the noble aims with which
this intervention was undertaken." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s founding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugenio Scalfari</ENAMEX>, wrote, "We wanted an 'intelligent' military
intervention, but we have had the stupidest intervention imaginable," and he
proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should definitively stop describing its war aims as
"humanitarian" so as to protect itself from ridicule. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalfari</ENAMEX> described
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> as "unconscious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>" who
were militating against peace as effectively as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatah</ENAMEX>. "The latter are clear-headed, the former probably unaware, which is
almost worse."

         
      
   
