
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">God Said</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Ugh&quot</ENAMEX>;

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Kevin Walker</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">screenwriter of Seven</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) and of the new snuff-film thriller
8MM , must have grown up watching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of kinky detective
shows. My guess is that they left him aroused but essentially ungratified.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> has made his fortune by packing in all the maggoty, sadistic details
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Commish</ENAMEX> left to the
imagination and that even such coolly clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> series as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The X-Files</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homicide</ENAMEX> have opted to leaven with reminders of the fundamental
beneficence of humankind. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX>'s clean-cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective heroes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8MM</TIMEX> ) embark on odysseys into the nether
region, where they view atrocity after atrocity before arriving at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>:
an evil that is pure, unrepentant, and infectious. You can lop off its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>,
but the skull goes on grinning, serenely confident that it has passed on its
disease to its slayer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Fincher</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> thrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX>'s worldview into your viscera; I can still recall
that film's gun battle, set in a long corridor, with its slingshot angles and
bullets that seemed to explode beside your head, and the ghastly sight, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">riveting</ENAMEX> and repellent, of a partially flayed, obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>, its milky white
blubber framing intestines that looked like blue balloons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Schumacher</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8MM</TIMEX> , has none of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fincher</ENAMEX>'s graphic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">originality</ENAMEX>, but the
material still carries a lurid charge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Welles</ENAMEX>, an earnest,
professionally polite private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> summoned to the manse of a recently
deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly widow</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myra Carter</ENAMEX>) has discovered in a safe an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millimeter</ENAMEX> film that appears to document the murder of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. The
appalled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> needs to know if the killing is real or simulated and hands
Welles the financial resources he needs to ferret out the filmmakers and their
possibly unfortunate leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>.

            Leaving his harried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Keener</ENAMEX>) and infant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in wintry <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> travels from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> to the subterranean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S/M</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parlors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> to a production office
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> market of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. What he sees twists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>'s hitherto poker
face into an increasingly Eastwoodesque grimace. His eyes bulge. His monotone
verges on the point of exploding into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of hysterical semitones. He
stops taking calls from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (always clutching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>) on his cell phone.
A wisecracking porn shop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Joaquin Phoenix</ENAMEX>), whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX> has hired as a
tour guide, delivers the film's thematic warning: "There are things that you
see that you can't un-see, that get into your head. ... Before you know it
you're in it, deep in it. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance</ENAMEX> with the devil and the devil don't change,
the devil changes you." I won't spell out where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">8MM</ENAMEX> leads but, trust me,
there are no surprises. As in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> , there are devils and they dance and
everyone gets down. And down. And down.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Robin</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), a one-time costume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> and art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, usually
exhibits the aesthetic of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior decorator</ENAMEX>, his pictures boasting the most
cluttered mise en scènes I've ever mise en seen. I'm impressed
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8MM</TIMEX> he has managed to muzzle his fruitier impulses and work in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chill</ENAMEX>, stripped-down style, reverting to form only in the black leather porno
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">basements</ENAMEX> and his characteristically semicoherent action scenes. The ambience
isn't as clammy as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fincher's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> , but it's dank enough, with eerie
intimations of a demon lying in wait. The score by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mychael Danna</ENAMEX> features
faraway muezzin wails--calls that could be emanating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flickering</ENAMEX> movie who's about to be slain. She stares doe-eyed into the camera,
like the naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edvard Munch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puberty</ENAMEX> , who seems just at that
instant to realize her true vulnerability.

            It gets to you, this movie--gets you titillated, then
spooked, then suffused with righteous fury. Murderous fury. It's only after the
picture ends that you realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX> hasn't really danced with the
devil, at least not by the standards of vigilante movies. He doesn't get a
sexual charge out of the brutality, nor does he develop a penchant for
torturing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX>. Apart from his stricken expressions and a couple of nasty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wounds</ENAMEX>, there's nothing even to suggest that he's damned by taking justice into
his own hands. If ever bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> deserved to be executed, it's the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in
8MM . They promise they're going to torture and kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, they cast aspersions on his masculinity, they sneer at the
notion that anyone would care about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. It's up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX> to say, "I
care"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- BLAM</ENAMEX>! What's to feel guilty about?

            Movies like 8MM
make me appreciate what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schrader</ENAMEX> tried to do when he chose to bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Banks</ENAMEX>' novel Affliction to the screen. Having written <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1976) and Hardcore</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>) and other vigilante pictures in
which the underlying motives of the avenger are called into question, Schrader
embraced the story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vigilante</ENAMEX> who turns out to be dead wrong, driven mad by
an increasing sense of his own impotence in a world that has left him behind.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX> worked with similar themes in the poorly thought through Falling
Down (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX> has a spell of road rage and doesn't
cool off. Next to these films, the moral contortions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8MM</TIMEX> seem
especially bogus, a sadomasochistic peep show <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> pretending to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confessional</ENAMEX>.

            The test of a piece of storytelling is whether its audience
can forget that it's listening to a history--something in the past tense--and
enter the living present. That doesn't happen in God <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ha</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX>'s film of her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">one-woman</ENAMEX> show. The subject is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX>'s late
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brother's</ENAMEX> and then her own. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> stands in the middle of the stage and tells
the off-screen (but audible) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> how her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> got sick and took up
residence in her small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and how her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> moved down from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, and threw her life into an uproar. She comes off as extremely
smart and likable--and she looks better than she did on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night</ENAMEX>
Live , with the soft face and sensuous blue eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth McGovern</ENAMEX>. Her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monologue</ENAMEX> has some funny, dislocating observations: the unsophisticated ways of
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> juxtaposed against her newly acquired yuppie tastes, her need to
sneak around like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> comes to stay and, especially,
her dislocation when, after taking her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for
chemotherapy, she finds herself suddenly playing his part, as if, she says,
she's at a square dance.

            But God <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ha</ENAMEX>!"--which has won praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX>'s artistry and candor--is the sort
of work that gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">one-person</ENAMEX> shows their bad rap. Few of the good bits flow
together; nothing builds. It's mostly one thing after another: I went here,
then I went there, then I went to a bookstore and cut a big fart and someone I
didn't remember from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groundlings</ENAMEX> recognized me, then I tossed a cigarette I
wasn't supposed to be smoking out the car window and then noticed that the back
seat was on fire, and then ... Occasionally, she turns to look into
another camera--a move that unintentionally evokes the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend</ENAMEX>
Update" shtick--but the movie is otherwise static, and the lines sound as if
she has said them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> times before.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX> tells instead of shows, declining to haul out the
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>--her immense comic gifts--to put her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> across. I have a
feeling she must think it would be vulgar to get too showbizzy, too gonzo, too
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> -ish with this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>, given that it's about (hush)
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. But then why do it? What's the point of going out in front of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with a tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> if she's not going to bring all her imaginative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to bear on it--to transform it into something that transcends its
relatively routine particulars and gives us something to hold onto when our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for tragedy comes?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Sweeney</ENAMEX> chose to take the story of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> and hers to the stage and then the screen; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX> made
no such decision, which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushmore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Anderson</ENAMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> account of visiting the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> seemed
an unseemly invasion of privacy. After writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s piece in , I
sent a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York T</ENAMEX>
               imes , which printed it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.
Click to read my letter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s response, and my annotations.

         
      
   
