
   
   
      
         
            Go E-Mail Yourself

            
               
                  Slate
                is pleased to
announce a new feature: E-mail This <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article</ENAMEX>. Just click on the words "E-mail
This <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article</ENAMEX>" at the top of each article. That's all there is to it.

            Well, obviously, there's more to it than that. If
that was all there was to it, we would have made it something like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Give Me a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Million Dollars"</ENAMEX> or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Send Milosevic to Hell" or "Have a Nice Day</ENAMEX>."

            But clicking on the words E-Mail This
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article</ENAMEX> is all you have to do. 
                  Slate
                Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX> and his crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> take it from there. Your click
sets off an alarm in their lair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX> kicks awake his nearest dozing acolyte,
and he or she will personally retype the 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in
question and e-mail it to anyone you choose. Or so they've explained it to me.
You can even e-mail it to several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at once, thanks to the miracle of
carbon paper, or something. What gets e-mailed is not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>
address) and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTML</ENAMEX> page, which some e-mail programs can't handle, but a
plain text version of the article itself.

            Who should you e-mail

                  Slate
                articles to? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> (thanks!) ... the possibilities are
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX>! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> option you should not overlook is e-mailing to yourself. Why would
you wish to do that? After all, 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are all much too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX>, successful, and psychologically secure to send themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> or
any such thing. You are not the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who need to artificially inflate
your in-boxes, thank you very much. But consider:

            

               E-mailing yourself an article is a way of putting it aside to read
later.

               Reading e-mail at your desk looks more like working than reading

                     Slate
                  's elegantly designed Web pages. (Caution: this should not
be interpreted as an attempt by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX> to collude with you to
deprive your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> of your services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solitaire</ENAMEX> is for that.)

               If you download your e-mail, you can read 
                     Slate
                   articles
without going online.

               You can print out the e-mail using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer</NUMEX> pages than printing out directly
from the Web.

               If you finally think of someone else to e-mail the article to, you can do
that.

            

            Do remember that spamming is bad form, and avoid
e-mailing 
                  Slate
                articles to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wouldn't want to get them.
Unless, of course, in your opinion the article is so insightful and brilliant
that it must be forced upon the ignorant and wrongheaded. In that case, e-mail
away.

         
      
   
