
   
   
      
         
             Hold That Martyrdom

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 7</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> (and probably last) trial of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hiatt Steele</ENAMEX> for lying and obstruction of justice ended with a hung <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>.
The low-key coverage of the event reflected several pre-established media
themes: a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> is a "peripheral" figure hounded by a vindictive special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>; b) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> trial is a pathetic coda to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s
now-finished symphony ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Gasps</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ); and c) the sole
remaining function of the case is to help determine the credibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
Willey, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialite</ENAMEX> who accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of crudely
groping her near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.

            All wrong, I'd argue.
What follows is a short primer on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> case for those who,
understandably, have been paying more attention to the wars, tornadoes, mass
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">murders</ENAMEX>, and nuclear espionage that constitute the rest of the news:

            
               Who is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey's</ENAMEX>. The issue is
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> provided the truth to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s grand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>
told her about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s supposed grope. Steele, it's been alleged, has at
various times offered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different stories:

            Story No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> of a
presidential pass <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very day</TIMEX> it occurred, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1993</TIMEX>--and that
it was a sexual advance that left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> "humiliated, scared, embarrassed."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> told this story to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1997</TIMEX>
(according to his book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncovering Clinton</ENAMEX> ) after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had suggested to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> that he could check out the grope story with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>.

            Story No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> only told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> "about
the incident <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after it happened, saying only that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had made a
pass at her," not necessarily an unwelcome pass. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, Steele
told this version to him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1997</TIMEX>, just as he was preparing to
write up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> story for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . Steele at that time said that
Story No. 1 was a lie she had told him at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s request. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isikoff</ENAMEX> reported
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s initial story and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story No. 2</ENAMEX> in his first piece on the Willey
episode, published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1997</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> has reported that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story No. 2</ENAMEX> to him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as early 1998</TIMEX>, and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s
trial, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> said she told them something like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Story No. 2</ENAMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> even appeared on the scene.

            Story No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: That Willey
"never told [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Steele</ENAMEX>] of any sexual advances made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," even
welcome sexual advances, and that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> heard about any such thing
was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> called her and asked her to lie to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> took
this position in an affidavit she signed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
scandal broke. It is the story she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and claims today is the truth.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> also denies that in recanting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story No. 1</ENAMEX> she confirmed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had told her about any pass. In effect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> says she never
told Story No. 2.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s story, which he repeated under oath to
a grand jury, is that he never made any sort of pass at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> (i.e., it jibes
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steele's Story No. 3</ENAMEX>). Willey, in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> trial testimony, stuck to the
story that she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> of an unwanted pass <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> it happened (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story No.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), although she said that she only knows she told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> immediately because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> once reminded her of it!

            The prevailing
perception, of course, is that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Steele</ENAMEX> stories, one
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Willey</ENAMEX>, one anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Willey</ENAMEX>. Press accounts--even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s account in his
book--tend to omit <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story No. 2</ENAMEX>, presumably for simplicity's sake. But Story No.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> seem rational.

            
               So why has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pursued Steele</ENAMEX>?
            

            The basic press take is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is pursuing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> to vindicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>. That's doubtful. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> might
like to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s story was bolstered more than undermined
by the testimony at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s trial. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to find out why.) Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
story has serious problems, quite apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Steele</ENAMEX>, as a recent, endless
analysis in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> makes clear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is much more
likely to be interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Steele</ENAMEX> herself and in why she changed her story.

            This is where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steele's Story No. 2</ENAMEX> becomes important. The
key thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story No. 2</ENAMEX> is that while it helped clear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of the charge
of making an aggressive, unwanted sexual overture, it still contradicted
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp's official line, which was (and is) that there was no
sexual overture at all , not even a welcome one. Story No. 2 was only
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">semi-exculpatory.</ENAMEX>

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> really changed
her story a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time, to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story No. 3</ENAMEX>, that might suggest she was trying to
fall in line with the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> account, which in turn suggests that
someone from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s side somehow "got" to her. That, at least, is what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> seems to believe. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s goal--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Shapiro</ENAMEX>, in a perceptive
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Salon</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> , recognizes--is most likely not to vindicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> but
to unravel a presidential cover-up conspiracy.

            
How? By <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convicting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> of lying and then
getting her to "flip" and finger in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp got to her to change her
story to version No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s theory may be a bit florid in its <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>, but
it's not crazy, given what we already know about current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
operations. Significantly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> could have pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> to
falsely switch to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story No. 3</ENAMEX> even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> is lying about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s grope,
and even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> at some point asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> to lie to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> for her.

            
               What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure Steele</ENAMEX> lied?
            

            He's got evidence. At the
trial, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s contradicted her account. One said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> told
him she'd heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Willey</ENAMEX>'s account long before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> said she'd
actually told them something like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Story No. 2</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. All this is quite
apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s testimony and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s reporting.

            
               But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX>'s still a
peripheral figure, right?
            

            She is now, but she
wouldn't be if she flipped and finked. Security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christoph Meili</ENAMEX> was an
extremely peripheral figure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss Holocaust</ENAMEX> banking scandal until he
blew the whistle on the destruction of bank records. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Detective</ENAMEX> would have been
a peripheral figure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> trial if the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> hadn't made a
big fuss over whether he was or was not telling the truth about his use of a
racial epithet.

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y et Steele</ENAMEX> had no obvious, sufficient motive for lying
...
            

            Right, but that's the
point. If she did in fact lie, what made her do it? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> may be wrong in
thinking the reason was intimidation by a Clintonite conspiracy. But there's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> clear way left for him to try to find out.

            
               At least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s a
sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> is a divorced
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>) who has had to set up a Web site to solicit
money for her "defense fund." On the other hand, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are representing
her pro bono. And of all the "peripheral" figures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> has been among the most industrious at marketing herself. Indeed, Steele
seems to have followed <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Strout's Law</ENAMEX>, which summarizes the advice of legendary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Strout</ENAMEX> to "sell every story <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times." Long before she
was threatened with prosecution, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> sold a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,000</NUMEX>. (At the same time, she also met with an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enquirer reporter</ENAMEX>.) Then she was paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> for sitting down with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Gooding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> to see what else she might have to sell.
Then, most surprisingly, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal broke she was paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for more on why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is .)

             

            B ut didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> threaten to take away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX>'s adopted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>?
            

            As even Steele-philes
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Rosen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> acknowledge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was trying to
find out whether someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> might have somehow threatened
to take away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX>'s adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, and thereby gotten her to change
her story. So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> asked questions about the legality of the adoption.
Whether in asking these questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> himself was pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>--and
whether that constitutes a "vicious attempt to threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s adoption"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shapiro</ENAMEX>) in "genuine Gestapo fashion" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> in the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> )--is a question the current criminal proceeding will not
answer.

            
               So 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX>
               as the evidence at trial
enough to prove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> guilty "beyond a reasonable doubt"?
            

            After reading the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcript</ENAMEX>, I'd say probably not. But that's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, mindful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
Department guidelines discouraging compelled testimony from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, never
even tried to get the testimony of his best potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, . Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> could not be called by the prosecution, thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX>,
and did not testify in her own defense. (Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> rested their case without
presenting any evidence of their own.) Only a criminal justice system as
sophisticated as ours could hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s trial without hearing testimony from
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.

             

            
               In other words, Steele
won and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> lost?
            

            After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> deadlocked, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Steele</ENAMEX> proclaimed
victory--and victimhood. ("It's time to start my life again," she said.) But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Steele</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>--unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in the recent trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>, with
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s trial is often twinned--did not acquit her of any of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> charges against her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jurors</ENAMEX> didn't say which way they were split and vowed
not to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> (though it came out that one thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s skirt
was too short). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> could seek to retry the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> case. He hasn't announced
whether he will.

            Pssst! If you do, call
Isikoff this time!

            F ull 
               disclosure: I worked for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of 1998</TIMEX> and am still listed on the masthead
as a contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. I'm also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> is suing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, claiming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> broke an "off-the-record"
promise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> denies making any such promise. I suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX>'s suit is
groundless, but whether it is or is not, it has had the effect of more or less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">silencing Newsweek</ENAMEX> on the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s trial that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> was ready to
testify that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> said "the lawsuit was filed to shut [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>] up." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> did not allow the testimony.

         
      
   
