
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underpaid Soldiers</ENAMEX>?

            To justify a new increase in military pay, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> are citing a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> "pay gap" between the salaries
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> and their civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. Ignoring for a moment whether a
dramatic increase in military pay is needed, the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> figure is bogus.
Even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> debunked the statistic in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>,
several military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> continue to cite it in congressional
testimony.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> "pay gap" represents the difference
in the growth of military versus civilian wages since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>--that is,
civilian wages have grown <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> faster. This does not mean that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> earn less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, because it does not take into account the
pay differential from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. If my wages have increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' have increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 50 percent</NUMEX>, this
does not mean that I am earning <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, since he was
making more to begin with.

            Moreover, even as a
measure of relative wage growth, the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> figure fails. First, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>
starting point--as opposed to some other year--makes the gap look especially
big, since there was a substantial military pay increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. Even worse,
the comparison does not account for the fact that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are younger and less educated than civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. This is important
because in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> the wages of college-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have grown much
faster than the wages of high-school-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The better comparison
would be between the wage growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> of comparable age
and education.

            So forget about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> argument. Is there any pay gap?
A rough study by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> found that enlisted service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">members</ENAMEX> earned
higher wages than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> high-school graduates
of the same age, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> earn higher wages than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-quarters of</TIMEX>
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of the same age. By that measure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> earn more than
their civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAND</ENAMEX> study has found essentially similar
results.

            Military service offers many
advantages--self-improvement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX>, travel, patriotism, the esteem of
one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX>--as the services tout. It also has severe disadvantages, such
as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX>, harsh discipline, isolation from loved ones, and the risk of
injury or death. It may be a good idea to attract better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airmen</ENAMEX> with huge salary increases, but military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> is so different from
civilian work that most wage comparisons are extremely suspect.

         
      
   
