
   
   
      
         
            Family Plots 

            The term "black comedy" has
become so elastic in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> that it now extends to entertainments
as various as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Is Beautiful</ENAMEX> , in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaplinesque</ENAMEX> sentimentality is
juxtaposed with concentration-camp horror, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX>, Stock & <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> Smoking
Barrels , in which flyspeck louts machine-gun other flyspeck louts with
farcical haplessness. Somewhere in the middle comes my ideal black comedy, in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> are base but their emotions have weight, and the human condition,
while irremediable, is leavened by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s cheery sleight of hand. A great
black comedy should be palatable but hard to digest, slipping easily down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gullet</ENAMEX> and then sticking in the gut. The form is currently represented by an
unheralded, low-budget jewel called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Six Ways</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> from a script he wrote with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Gerald</ENAMEX>. Its young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Reedus</ENAMEX>), a fry-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> in the postindustrial wasteland that is
Youngstown, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, lives with a shut-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Harry</ENAMEX>), who has
contrived to keep him in a state of sexual ignorance. A breathy ex-prostitute
now going to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>, she bathes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, controls the light in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and warns
him off relations with "sluts" while hovering <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> from his face in low-cut
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nighties</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s a walking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freudian</ENAMEX> time bomb.

            Invited by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrien Brody</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">garish rapper affectations</ENAMEX>, to help
collect a debt for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> of a sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> finds
himself bombarded by images of topless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and unable to keep from whaling on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they came only to threaten. "I hope I killed him," he says, when pulled
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s bloody, broken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. And then: "I hope I didn't kill him."
Seasoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> love to exploit such youthful intensity, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> is soon
adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Abie "The Bug</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Appel</ENAMEX>) and then by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Varga</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adler</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> in search of a more dependable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully boy</ENAMEX> than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chaotic Arnie</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bringing Harry</ENAMEX> along means teaching him how to dress and spend
money ("Having money and not flashing it is strictly for gentiles," they
explain); treating him to a whore (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Thompson</ENAMEX>), whom he reluctantly accepts
and then pays not to have sex with ("Do I seem normal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sexually?</ENAMEX>" he
asks); and presenting him with a huge switchblade, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> is shortly
expected to plunge into the heart of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> he has never met.

            S ix 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> is freely based on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> novel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait of a Young Man Drowning</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Perry</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> who died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> before completing
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> book. Set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>'s novel (which features white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>)
is bleaker than the film, less archly distant, with a nastier ending. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX> have made it their own. The movie's slapstick and brutality inhabit
the same psychological landscape, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s acts of violence are viewed in
stroboscopic flashes, held long enough to convey their garishness but so
fleetingly that you might giggle at your own uncertainty: Did he really do
what I think he did? I hesitate to use the word "offbeat," which has come
to describe a metronomical quirkiness that's as predictable as anything on the
beat, but here the surreal touches are sprung without overture, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX> that
just happen to be hopping across the screen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> is dogged by a phantom
slickster, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madden</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holter Graham</ENAMEX>), who leers at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and then demonstrates how
to molest them. Is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madden</ENAMEX> who's attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varga</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iris</ENAMEX> (Elina
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowensohn</ENAMEX>), or is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madden</ENAMEX> a stand-in for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iris</ENAMEX> is a tiny yet imposing
thing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowensohn</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Almereyda</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nadja</ENAMEX> ) with a game leg; it was her "affliction," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, later, that
was the source of his attraction. "That's why I was attracted to you ,"
she replies, prompting a look of puzzlement. Here, as elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reedus</ENAMEX> is
remarkable, his face both masklike and porous, so that you never consciously
register the ways in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> is dissolving before your eyes--but you're not
in the least surprised when he does.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Harry</ENAMEX> is no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>--her speaking voice is as dead as her singing voice is glassy. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
is meant to be zonked and zombielike, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mummy Dearest</ENAMEX>, and this bedraggled
ghost of a glamorous icon is startlingly potent. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheekbones</ENAMEX> seem to
stretch from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the screen to other--they hold up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s features,
which might otherwise collapse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> underlines the tension between her
past and present by using the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blondie song "Sunday Girl</ENAMEX>" in a tender encounter
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iris</ENAMEX> in a diner. At first I questioned the wisdom of that--it
seemed a little cheap. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> has brought off a coup, making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> a
literal presence in that scene and reinforcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Harry</ENAMEX>'s stature. It's
even a coup that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is played by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>--the incestuousness extending
to their very names.

            My <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> professional movie reviews were written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> at
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Phoenix</ENAMEX> under the tutelage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Schiff</ENAMEX>, then a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magisterial</ENAMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> as well as an exacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. Presented with a
sentence containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> adjectives in succession ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Tiddlywinks</ENAMEX> gives a
funky, severe performance"), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiff</ENAMEX> would say, "Choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>." "Well, gee, I
dunno, the performance is funky but also kinda severe so you kinda need both."
"Choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>," he would repeat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squirming</ENAMEX>, I would direct him to eliminate an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adjective and then Schiff</ENAMEX>, after a respectful beat, would strike the other.
Where adjectives are concerned, there's no substitute for tough love.

            Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiff</ENAMEX> has
become a big-deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> (his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lolita</ENAMEX> generated scads of ink and
his adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">True Crime</ENAMEX> , directed by and starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>,
opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>), it's as if those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 17 years</TIMEX> didn't happen. I'm sitting
here trying to choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or another adjective for his newest script, The
Deep End of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX> --an exhausting task because I'm genuinely of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
minds about the picture. I want to say it's subtle, but I also want to say it's
heavy-handed. I want to say it's incisive, but I have too many problems with
its psychological elisions to let it off the hook. Based on a novel--one of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> best sellers--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacquelyn Mitchard</ENAMEX>, it's the story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Cappadora</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>), whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> vanishes in a hotel
lobby. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> section of the film dramatizes the apparent kidnapping and its
agonizing aftermath. Then, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treat Williams</ENAMEX>), achieve a queasy normalcy with their remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan Merriman</ENAMEX>) shows up at their door offering to cut their
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">lawn</ENAMEX> for money. Is it? Could it be? (I hope I'm not spoiling anything--all this
is in the film's coming attractions.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Deep End of the Ocean</ENAMEX> is
powerful all right but, given this kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>, that isn't much of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>. And I'm not sure what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX> is doing there as a lesbian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> with about as much verisimilitude as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s 500-year-old alien
bartender on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek: The Next Generation</ENAMEX> . But in the nebulous middle
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>, the movie develops layers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulu Grosbard</ENAMEX>
achieve something extraordinary: They dramatize the undramatized--the latent.
When an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX> presents a blank face to the camera,
it's really blank, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>'s blankness can make you seasick with its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sloshing</ENAMEX>, stormy underpinnings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> gives off glints of suppressed
violence and, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Jackson</ENAMEX> has a queer
affectlessness that signals something roiling underneath. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s fake
equilibrium creates a tension that's nearly unbearable, and when the front door
swung open and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> stood there it was all I could do to keep from jumping
out of my seat.

            But the movie grows
increasingly frustrating. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, we learn, was taken by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> crazy with
the loss of her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and then raised, after her suicide, by a big-hearted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kapelos</ENAMEX>), who had no knowledge of his adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s
true origins. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cappadoras</ENAMEX>' elation at the return of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is
gradually eroded by the realization that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> still thinks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> as
his real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. But how are we to take the evident inability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
even to address the subject of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> with another couple or
their bland expectation that he'll nestle himself into the family bosom as if
he'd never left? Are they supposed to be so shallow, so uncurious, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dim</ENAMEX>? It's hard to tell, since so much has been left off-screen--including a
climactic discussion between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and his stepfather that triggers the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s absurd ending.

            There's another aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchard</ENAMEX>'s narrative that bugs
me, although here my reasons are entirely personal. As someone born to a mother
in her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year of medical school and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, I was--with
great regret--placed in the care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first years</TIMEX> of my life
and later reclaimed before my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> birthday. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX>
in psychiatric bills <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, I can speak about this with limited objectivity;
the point is that, although very young when taken from my primary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caregivers</ENAMEX>--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>--I recall both the joy of my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> with them and
the hellish trauma of separation more vividly than much of what happened to me
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. I risk boring you with my autobiography to buttress my contention
that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Deep End of the Ocean</ENAMEX> is fundamentally bogus. I don't buy that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>, in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> year at the time of his snatching, would, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a decade</TIMEX>
later, have no recollection of the parents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> with whom he'd spent
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, and that only the aroma of a cedar chest would rekindle faint
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> of his warm life among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cappadoras</ENAMEX>. I find it absurd that he could
ever have settled into life with his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (especially a certifiably crazy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>) with no scars, growing into a happy, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">snub-nosed</ENAMEX>, uncomplicated
adolescent instead of, say, the delusional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">momma</ENAMEX>'s-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy assassin</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways</ENAMEX>
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> --or, for that matter, a vaguely unstable wannabe movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> differ, of course, and there might be ways to account for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s
surprising evolution, but they're not in the novel and they're certainly not in
the movie.

         
      
   
