
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallwell</ENAMEX>'s That
Ends Well
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> in "" is missing the point about the
reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>'s outing of the "gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubby</ENAMEX>." While Tinky Winky
may be queer and proud, and while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> might be your best fantasy and
your worst nightmare, that's not the why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are shaking their heads.

            Personally, I couldn't
care less if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> is gay. What does offend me is that
bigots such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> feel the need to
"save" our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from supposedly evil influences, such as gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX>.
If a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubby</ENAMEX> teaches tolerance and acceptance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, that's a good
thing. What we should be afraid of are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falwellian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bigots</ENAMEX> who preach hate and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Green</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  Real
Numbers
            

            I am writing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> where the statements by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arminio Fraga in the to "Don't Blame It on Rio ... Or</ENAMEX>
Brasilia Either" have been front-page news for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. While I am pleased that
you have published to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s note, I am distressed to see that

                  Slate
                has not taken responsibility for its actions in the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> has. 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> must take a large measure
of responsibility for this "bagunça "--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> for mess. As Krugman
notes in his apologies, he is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. Given the
seriousness of the charges--trading inside information for the gain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraga</ENAMEX>'s
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>--shouldn't 
                  Slate
                offer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraga</ENAMEX> an apology as well?
Leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> to take all the heat of a very angry <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is not

                  Slate
               's finest demonstration of journalistic ethics.

            The greatest tragedy of
this episode is that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> situation is one of the most positive and
accurate I have seen during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six months</TIMEX>. He makes clear what few have
been able to--the vicious cycle of lack of confidence and interest rates. I
wish the public discussion of his article had focused on solutions to the
dilemma he posed rather than on an extraneous appendage.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>

            
               War, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blockades</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX>
            

            Broadly speaking, I agree with the points <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> makes in "." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has the sole power to declare war, and a bipartisan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> have cheerfully ignored that clear constitutional
fact. But I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> may be mistaken in saying the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> bombing
needed authorization. As I understand it, the war between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, has not yet ended. The shooting war of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> ended with a
cease-fire, not peace. Indeed, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> following, we have enforced a
blockade on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Blockades have always been regarded as acts of war. And the
cease-fire is conditional: if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> permits inspections, doesn't fly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> in certain areas, and doesn't threaten our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, then we will
hold our fire. So, if the war was constitutional in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-92</TIMEX>, the war is still
constitutional now--nothing in the resolution specified a time limit.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has
not made this case. Whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> claimed (quite rightly) that arms inspections
were a violation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> sovereignty, we could and should have responded,
"Bugger your sovereignty--this is war." Somehow, I can't imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> saying
that.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
Solovay
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belmont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary of a Mad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>
            

            I must say that the "" by
the anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant professor</ENAMEX> portrays the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> stresses and
anxieties of academic life through the eyes of a shockingly irresponsible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instructor</ENAMEX>. The way in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> views both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and undergraduate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> reveals unhealthy personal insecurity. Teaching is a profoundly
ethical vocation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> entrust their emotional and intellectual well-being
to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, and those who command such authority must recognize their
responsibilities to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The stresses of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> are truly
heavy, but why should it be different from any other profession? Does the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> think that teaching in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> involves a lighter load than
working for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>? Why? Furthermore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is fortunate enough to
have a job when so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humanities scholars</ENAMEX> are without
employment.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack W. Chen</ENAMEX>
            

            Somerville, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
