
   
   
      
         
            

            
               The Vast
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conspiracy That Cried Wolf</ENAMEX>
            

            As usual, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> put it best. "Do we really
want to ask or answer all these irrelevant questions about what someone may or
may not have done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 or 30 years ago</TIMEX>? Quite frankly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>," he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> recently. "And quite frankly, it's not
that important. What's important is who you are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, what you're going to
do."

            Quite right. What does
it matter if, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> forced himself on Juanita Broaddrick
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>? Whom a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> may have raped in the privacy of her hotel room
when he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> has nothing to do with his ability to
lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>. If an elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> is
doing a good job, how he relaxes during his free time is not a legitimate
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> denies the accusation, and there are good reasons
not to believe it (see ""). But it would have been better if he had said, with
simple dignity, "none of your business." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, are winning press plaudits for refusing to answer press
questions about past private peccadilloes. Exhausted by the Year of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, we
have all decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' private lives should stay private.

            Some might demur that
rape is not a peccadillo. It is, among other things, illegal. But so are pot
smoking and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine snorting</ENAMEX>, which are high on the list of private behavior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are getting little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> for refusing to discuss. Is rape a
worse crime than using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>? Well, many might think so, but you wouldn't know
it from the way most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. In declining to talk about
his own drug experience, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> made the interesting point that he didn't
want to give young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the unfortunate (though accurate) impression
that you could do whatever he did when young and still end up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. Certainly this argument applies in the case of alleged rape by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> even more currently popular than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.

            It is obvious why the liberal perverts and druggies of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> favor a curtain being drawn on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' private lives. But
how did <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>--pure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>--get into this
position? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way is by repeating the mantra "it's not about sex" just once or
twice too often. They thought they had him by the legalities on perjury and
obstruction of justice, and in attempting to win converts to their cause they
may have been more dismissive than they intended about the sex thing. Too late,
too late.

            Then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> voices, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> and the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page, remained steadfast in their
hysterical disapproval of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s private sexual behavior, and remained
adamant that it is a legitimate public issue. But even they--like all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> of both parties, almost all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, and most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizenry</ENAMEX>--were hysterical and adamant that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> should not be allowed
to draw public attention to the private sexual behavior of anyone else. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> even insisted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> should be prosecuted for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blackmail</ENAMEX>.)

            Why? If a category of information is legitimately useful in
judging an elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public official</ENAMEX>, how can it be illegitimate and outrageous
to gather and publish such information? Maybe they decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was a
good place to stop. When your side has launched an offensive, been driven back,
and nervously awaits a counteroffensive, it's not a bad time for an armistice.
That would be hypocritical of course. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have the right to practice
hypocrisy in the privacy of their own editorial pages.

            But did the Vast
Right-Wing Conspiracy tragically call for a cease-fire just as the ultimate
weapon was about to be delivered into their hands? Did they dig a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> to
within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> of freedom from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> imprisonment when they gave up?
Did they finally have an accusation that would shock a seemingly unshockable
public? Rape! Those few elements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VRWC</ENAMEX> that haven't been drained of
fight--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>, for example--are flogging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX> story with at
least a bit of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> and are puzzled that even this hasn't worked.

            It is puzzling. The evidence is flaky--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has both
confirmed and denied the story, corroborators with their own reasons to
lie--but major scandals have been built on less. Yes, we're all suffering from
scandal fatigue, but rape?

            The explanation is
partly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frog</ENAMEX>-in-hot-water phenomenon (he'll jump out if you drop him in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">boiling water</ENAMEX>, but not if you put him in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and slowly heat it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boiling</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has faced an escalating series of serious
accusations--serious in the sense that they were all plausible and some were
true. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> or another of them might have stuck, but each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> inured the public
to the next. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> skillfully augmented this process by pacing any
admissions he has been forced to make, so that each new one was just a small
accretion on a large pile of old news.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, though, has also faced a continuing barrage of
unserious allegations--implausible and untrue. He's been accused of , among
other things. The effect of these stories from the nether regions of the Vast
Right-Wing Conspiracy has been like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crying wolf</ENAMEX>. When you've heard the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president preposterously</ENAMEX> accused of murder so often, you just yawn when he's
accused of rape.

            So now we are living in the world everyone has long
claimed to want: where we judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> based only on the issues and their
public records of governance. Some might feel that healthy indifference to what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> do in their private lives has gone too far when it covers
allegations of rape. But they'll get used to it.

         
      
   
