
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">245</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Dis Sent&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
Vollmer-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heurer</ENAMEX> has a plan, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Adol</ENAMEX> hates it. "It is cheap, it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">degrading</ENAMEX>, it is smelly," says Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adol</ENAMEX>, who has a plan of his own. "What I
propose is something clean, useful and solid." What is the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>'s disagreement?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 244</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When IRS Eyes Are Smiling":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        Fill in the blank on this tax tip from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> collection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. "If you don't want to pay your taxes
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> all you have to do is say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> magic words: _________
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">_________</ENAMEX>."
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whale</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Fein</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin H. Murphy</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mommy</ENAMEX>, please."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Scheft</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
commute! (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New York Metropolitan-</ENAMEX>area answer.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
Silow-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carroll</ENAMEX>
            

            "I'm
sorry. (No, wait, that's how you get out of accidentally bombing somebody's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zach Hooker</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform</ENAMEX>
Wrap-Up
            

            One criticism of our tax system is its use not
merely to raise revenue but to encourage social policy, as in the deduction for
mortgage interest or charitable contributions. I'd like to suggest that the tax
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> should go much, much farther down this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, particularly the sales tax.
Under my plan, sales taxes would only be not eliminated on certain socially
desirable purchases, but also good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> would receive an anti-tax, a bonus
for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beneficent</ENAMEX> purchases.

            For example, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> you're charged an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1/4 percent</NUMEX> tax when you buy a book. I propose that when you buy a really good
book--say, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick O'Brian</ENAMEX>, he's marvelous!--you'd be paid a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>
bonus: Buy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> book; receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.

            Buy a TV set and you should pay a tax: Your
purchase will make you fat and stupid. Buy a TV set that operates only when you
pedal a bicycle-powered generator, and you receive a bonus: Your purchase will
make you thin and stupid.

            Rent a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Samurai</ENAMEX> , a fine movie,
and you get the bonus. Rent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Three Ninjas</ENAMEX> and you pay a tax, but you can
check a box that allocates your money to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to beat the hell out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Valenti</ENAMEX>.

            The question, of course,
is who decides which items are taxed and which earn the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> a bonus. I do. By
making these decisions a matter of narrow self-interest, my reform remains
within the historical context of the present system, where tax rates are set to
benefit the rich and powerful. My system would differ only in benefiting a
different self. And what's good for me would no doubt be good for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bracket Creep</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "If you don't want to pay your taxes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> all you
have to do is say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> magic words: installment agreement ."

            "You just say you want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and even if the terms
you propose are ridiculous--like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> when you owe <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>--collection stops while your proposal goes up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 days later</TIMEX> you are told no. Then you need to say another
magic word--harassment--and because of this new law, the collection process
stops while your complaint gets reviewed."

            This new law is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' way to bully the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> into acting nicer. As a result, seizures of
property in lieu of back taxes are down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Other attempts to
get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to pay what they owe are also way down. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say the
drop stems from their fear of running afoul of the new niceness laws and
getting fired.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>'s
Cool <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Bible</ENAMEX> Follow-Up
            

            There is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> game based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX>.

            Some details:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 to 3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>.

               Units represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magog</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>), the Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">empires</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West</ENAMEX> gets a piece representing the antichrist.

               When you throw the die to resolve a battle and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> comes up, an
"apocalyptic event"--<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euphrates</ENAMEX> dries up, sky turns blood red interfering with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, etc.--occurs.

            

            The game is published by
the Microgame
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co-op</ENAMEX>, a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> run by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry Anderson</ENAMEX>. Its raison
d'être is to publish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> games by unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> or on "niche" subjects
(they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> game depicting the struggle between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sendero Luminoso</ENAMEX>). Check it out.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Sestinas are for sissies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
are still encouraged to attempt this far more demanding verse form:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> lines, each with the same number of words; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
suggested, but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>'s choice.

               The words in each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> must originally appear adjacent to each other in a
newspaper headline.

               The headlines must all come from a single
edition of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>.

            

            Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lyrical</ENAMEX> examples:

            Through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot</ENAMEX>
Metaphor
A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX> of Missteps
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pay Gets</ENAMEX>
Terms <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard To Swallow</ENAMEX>

            
               Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18, 1999</TIMEX>

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather</ENAMEX>
Harmon
            

            Quiet Jubilation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman Mounts</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloody Gloves</ENAMEX>
To Sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drugs</ENAMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The rich and the dead.

         
      
   
