
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unproven Pay Parity</ENAMEX>

            
               Pay
Check
            

            I was rather
dissatisfied with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Chait</ENAMEX>'s "" regarding the "pay gap" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX>.
He states:

            
               The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> "pay gap" represents the
difference in the growth of military versus civilian wages since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>--that is, civilian wages have grown <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> faster. This does
not mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> earn less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, because it does not
take into account the pay differential from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. If my wages have increased by
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' have increased by
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 50 percent</NUMEX>, this does not mean that I am earning <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, since he was making more to begin with.
            

            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chait</ENAMEX> really mean to imply that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">servicemen</ENAMEX> made a lot more money in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> than their civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>? The
only evidence he offers for this position is that military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> got a big
raise in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. However, if memory serves me, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> raise was designed to
provide a "catch up" to bring military pay back to parity with civilian wages
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> of lagging pay increases. It seems to me that military and
civilian pay in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> should have been comparable. If this is true, the military
may have since lost ground, because some of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> raises since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'82</TIMEX> have
lagged the inflation rate.

            He also cites studies from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAND Corp.</ENAMEX> that indicate that "enlisted service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>" make
more money than their civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. I can't speak about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> study,
but I've seen the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAND</ENAMEX>, and its conclusions are more complicated than
he suggests--that junior enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> are overpaid compared to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian counterparts</ENAMEX>, senior enlisted are slightly underpaid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior officers</ENAMEX>
moderately underpaid, and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> seriously underpaid. So, does Chait
advocate pay table reform rather than an across-the-board increase in pay?

            The bottom line is that
after reading this article, I'm no smarter than I was before about whether
there really is a pay gap, since no evidence was offered that addressed the
actual salaries of either the military or civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. A little more
research would have been helpful here.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geri Peters</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chesapeake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               Fiddling With
History
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> writes, "the hallmarks of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lapham</ENAMEX>'s style are a magnificent contempt for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>'s folly and an apparent
conviction that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is reenacting the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>." And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> cites <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lapham</ENAMEX>'s mention of "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> familiar with the expensive
claques traipsing after the magnificence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nero</ENAMEX>."

            Nero was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.D.</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, there
were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four emperors</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nero, Otho, Galba</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vespasian</ENAMEX>), and the secret of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman Empire</ENAMEX>--that in a time of turmoil, a provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> with an army
could march on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>--was revealed, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>'s decline was a
long way off. The situation stabilized with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vespasian</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.D.</ENAMEX> is often considered the golden age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibbon</ENAMEX> himself says that
the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Aurelius</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late second century</TIMEX>--was the best time to live of
all in history). Around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> split between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and west. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>
in the west finally collapsed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">476</TIMEX>. In the east, it lasted until the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 th century</TIMEX>.

            So, if these times in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are like the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nero</ENAMEX>, we have (by analogy) at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, including <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another century</TIMEX> of greatness, and perhaps another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX>. This is not a criticism of your amusing article on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lapham</ENAMEX>, but of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lapham</ENAMEX>'s apparently poor grasp of actual ancient history.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Margolies
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Wrong
Turns
            

            I thought it might be worth attempting to correct
some misstatements and mistakes made in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Chapman</ENAMEX>'s "." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> writes,
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insurance Institute for Highway Safety</ENAMEX> reports that after the repeal of
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55-mph</NUMEX> speed limits, fatalities rose by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> on interstate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> where
the limit was raised."

            Hopefully <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> is aware that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIHS</ENAMEX> is an
industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> directly benefit from the imposition of a national
speed limit. Further exploration would have turned up studies by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> (if memory serves) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Automobile Association</ENAMEX> showing
either no increase or decrease in fatalities on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> where the speed limit was
increased. Looking state by state, the same lack of a pattern emerges: There
simply is no good data, counterintuitive though it may seem, to link "speeding"
with accidents. Although deaths per passenger mile did indeed decline when the
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55-mph</NUMEX> limit was imposed, they have declined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year since</TIMEX> statistics have
been kept and are continuing to decline in the wake of the revocation of the
national speed limit.

            Another innocent mistake is comparing
"speed-related" deaths to "alcohol-related deaths." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> writes, "But speed
comes in a very respectable <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>." The
national database in which this information is kept allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> at the
scene to code multiple reasons for an accident; they do, indeed, tend to cite
"excessive speed for conditions" as a contributing factor quite frequently.
However, if you were to pull the number of accidents where speed was the sole
factor cited, the number declines precipitously. Keep in mind, again, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> are not good to begin with; this is simply the opinion of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who
arrived on the scene after the fact.

            The radar <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> was invented to allow civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>
to determine "<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">85 th percentile</NUMEX> speed," or that speed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> will maintain on a given piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. In more sensible times,
that's how speed limits were set: Build the road, time traffic on it, determine
the speed most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are comfortable driving at, and post that as the limit to
encourage uniform speeds, which, unsurprisingly, minimizes accidents. A
national speed limit, by being completely separated from local conditions,
actually encourages unsafe behavior, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will vary in their speed
significantly. On many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, driving at or below the limit puts you well below
the speed of most traffic, thereby greatly increasing the chances of an
accident.

            So, no; rigid enforcement of a national speed limit
with draconian penalties for violating it will not save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of lives. Nor
would repealing the freedom of the airwaves act (the federal legislation that
permits radar detectors and any other listening-only devices) be a good idea
merely to protect the various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipalities</ENAMEX>' right to collect revenues from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorists</ENAMEX>. It may not be sexy or simple, but setting speed limits on a
case-by-case basis at sensible speeds would do much more to reduce speeding and
accidents than any of the measures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> proposes. Since even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> estimates that better than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> speed, it
might make more sense to look at why, rather than simply demanding that they
all stop.

            Or maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> thinks
the current "war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>" is a good idea, too.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
            

            
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Chicago</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schooled</ENAMEX> in the
Past
            

            While it is always good to have some historical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> on modern trends, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Greenberg</ENAMEX> misses a couple of subtle
distinctions in his piece on the violence of schoolkids in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years past</TIMEX> (see "").
Let's stipulate that high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> of yesteryear were a rowdy,
school-stoning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage-tipping</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>-beating, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-whipping,
liquor-soaked bunch of devolved maniacs. That is, after all, about the deepest
level to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>'s analysis descends, and having once reached it he
turns and angles for the bright sky of the story he wants to tell.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, murdered their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. They found a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> weeping under a table,
shouted "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peekaboo</ENAMEX>," and killed her. At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close</NUMEX> range. And they apparently enjoyed
it. "Look at this black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s brain! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Awesome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>!" is what one was reported to
have exclaimed. They stood in front of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, asked her if she believed
in God, and shot her in the head when she answered yes. They had no goal; no
end in mind beyond destruction. They weren't trying to restrict a rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>,
enforce a political ideal, or overthrow authority. They appeared to revel in
death and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and hate for its own sake alone.

            So, I ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>: Would you be comfortable
lacing up the old athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> breeches, rubbing a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pine tar</ENAMEX> on your
trusty ball bat, and heading down to P.S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX> with a few of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to
teach these ruffians a lesson?

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> can't
detect the differences in these situations, then he is part of the problem. I
too read a lot of history, but unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> I think you have to go back a
bit farther to find truly analogous behavior. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark Ages</TIMEX> should prove
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fruitful</ENAMEX>. And by the way, it's misleading to place the sentence "occasionally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were put to death" at the end of a list of the things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> did to
keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in line. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> mean to suggest this was the tool of last
resort? He is referring to the fact that some teen-aged "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>" were
occasionally executed for crimes (the crime of murder in the period to which he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">refers</ENAMEX>, or perhaps for stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hare</ENAMEX> from the king's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> times).
Not laudable, but definitely irrelevant to his argument. Just a bit later in
the piece he makes the point himself that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> were considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in
the time he is examining. Or were we executing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-olds</TIMEX> back then?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Betz</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parsippany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Lies</ENAMEX>
            

            I enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
writings on art, but in his review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The American Century</ENAMEX>" show
(see "") he conflates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s most controversial shows. The buttons
saying, "I can't ever imagine wanting to be white," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Martinez</ENAMEX>,
were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1993 Biennial</ENAMEX>--not, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> writes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Male show</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX>
Cembalest
            

            Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>,
ARTnews
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>
replies: I stand corrected.
            

         
      
   
