
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Balloon Smugglers</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               This is an odd
question to ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>--but at least you are objective, seeing as how we
don't know each other. I am undecided about whether or not to get breast
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">implants</ENAMEX>. I have convinced myself that they are not dangerous. The issue, now,
is the correctness of having such a procedure. I do not mean political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correctness</ENAMEX>; I mean how important should it be for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) oneself, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) one's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">onlookers</ENAMEX>," and whatever ethical-philosophical considerations come into play.
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, by the way, says the decision is mine. (P.S.: I am not
particularly flat-chested.)
            

            

               --To D or Not To D
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear To</ENAMEX>,

            This is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>, who has never been
asked before to decide about someone's chest enhancement.

            Only you know the
reasons for considering implants. Are you built like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>? Do you think a pair
of remarkable hooters will change your life for the better? Do you think
drawing attention to your chest is a good thing? In general, there do not seem
to be "ethical-philosophical considerations" attached to breasts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
personal view is that implants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (they often do not feel
genuine to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>) and really, what is the point? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> wishes she could
attribute the phrase to the proper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, but some clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> named the
bearers of implants "the balloon smugglers." That pretty much expresses
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s thoughts on the matter.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, naturally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Could it be that ,who so disliked the use of
the expression "there you go," has confused that phrase with "off you go?" I'm
not sure whether the latter has any currency in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
it is often uttered in a pleasant--and perhaps patronizing tone of voice in
instances such as, say, insisting to a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> that he march off
and do his homework. By actually describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">addressee</ENAMEX>'s future act of
leaving the presence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, the "off you go" indicates a request for
departure.
            

            
               I think the reason
"there you go" has no such unpleasant connotations is that it describes, in the
retail context, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> finds him- or herself after
successful completion of the purchase. (See also the rather <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Jamesian</ENAMEX>
"there you are.") In other words, it functions as a polite observation
naturally terminating the transaction.
            

            
               --Yours
pedantically,
            

            

               Amitavo from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Am</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thanks you for
your internationalist input on the issue of "there you go." She found it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enlightening</ENAMEX> and thoughtful. Whoever named your part of the world "down under"
surely was not referring to the educational level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, internationally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Having just marked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>, here is my problem. I am married to a lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a charming
family. He has no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, and I am the only daughter-in-law. For as long as
anyone can remember, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> always forgot my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s
birthday, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>, etc. Although she clearly loves a fuss, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> produce not a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>, a card, a flower, or a gift. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX>, I realized
everyone expected me to attend to these details, which I had previously
neglected to do. I am happy to celebrate her occasions in a way she would
enjoy, but I resent being expected to handle this task for everyone just
because I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Should I put feminist principles aside and do my familial
duty because it's the nicer thing to do, or should I leave it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to
wise up?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dutiful Daughter-in-law</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Duti</ENAMEX>,

            Let's make a list. On
the plus side is "a lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a charming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." On the minus side,
these male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't seem to get it together to do anything about occasions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels certain feminism wasn't addressing itself to this issue and hopes
you will lose the resentment factor. Do the thoughtful thing for your lovely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and the charming others, because on the Richter Scale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family Chores</ENAMEX>,
this ranks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about .05</NUMEX>. You can only reap the appreciation of your male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and who knows? In time you might have trained them by example, without
their even knowing it.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, generously

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               What is the most
polite--but effective--way to handle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> who do not know when to leave a
party? My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of his to a brunch I gave recently. Not only
did these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have too much to drink, but they actually stayed later than
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. I resorted to time-honored tricks such as washing the dishes, then
announcing I had a headache--and yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> stayed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another hour</TIMEX>! Of
course I will never invite these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> again, but was there a more
direct, yet still polite, way I could have induced them to leave?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tired Host</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Ti</ENAMEX>,

            You say you will never
invite these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> again. My dear, you didn't invite them the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> recommends, however, for those invited or not, a direct approach
once a hint is ignored. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granted</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who aren't sober can be rather slow on
the uptake.) Simply say the festivities are over and you hope they had a good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. If they wore wraps, hand them to them. If the weather is too warm, thank
them for coming and walk with them to the door. Do not take no for an answer.
The socially inept are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>-glove <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, directly

         
      
   
