
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitchens Bites Clinton</ENAMEX>

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Music</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moe Asch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folkways Records</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter D. Goldsmith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX>). A book about the extraordinary, if messy,
career of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folkways Records</ENAMEX> wins polite reviews, but it's no
masterpiece of biography. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moe Asch</ENAMEX> created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folkways</ENAMEX> and ran it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38 years</TIMEX>,
until his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, releasing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,200</NUMEX> records, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> by Leadbelly
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Guthrie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> from all over the globe playing everything from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s music to jazz. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asch</ENAMEX>'s tale is compelling, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldsmith</ENAMEX> concentrates
too much on the business story, writes the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dallas Morning News ' Stanley</ENAMEX>
Trachtenberg: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]ometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making People's Music</ENAMEX> reads like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discography</ENAMEX>." Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Nicholson</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ) dislikes
the book's sometimes clotted prose and odd lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>: "The real
problem is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asch</ENAMEX> himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Variously</ENAMEX> described as a 'very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely man</ENAMEX>' and lacking
'much of an interior life,' he is--for all the aforementioned
complexity--strangely absent here. Names, dates, and facts abound, but Asch
remains elusive." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for a dictionary of folk music terms.)

            

               
                  No <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Left To Lie To: The Triangulations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verso</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX>' jeremiad
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s personal life is part and
parcel with his political one. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX> ... directs his argument at his fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leftists</ENAMEX>, those turtlenecked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worrywarts</ENAMEX> who hate welfare reform and the bond
market and still get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hoppin</ENAMEX>' mad about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanzetti</ENAMEX>," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> . Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Drew</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times : "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX> obviously loathes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, finds him a lying, ruthless,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">low-life</ENAMEX>. But in this compelling, disturbing, entertaining, necessary book, he
raises questions that cannot be ignored." What worries <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> is the
relentless negativity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> portrait. Writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Lehrman</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "What's good about a well-done polemic is that
everything fits neatly into place. What's bad about a well-done polemic is that
everything fits neatly into place." (To read more by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX> and to purchase
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">memorabilia</ENAMEX>, visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> Web .)

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Besieged
                (Fine Line Features). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are mostly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">respectful of Bernardo Bertolucci</ENAMEX>'s sparse romantic tale about a wealthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX>. "From the start of ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Besieged</ENAMEX> , a film that combines a stunning sensuality with a rigorous
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, you know that you're in the hands of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> who trusts in the
storytelling power of the camera," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . "Besieged is a thrilling reminder of what moving, personal
art the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Conformist and The Last</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> can make
when inspired by the right material," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>. Most don't even mind the ending, which is invariably described as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O. Henry</ENAMEX>-esque. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Naysayers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX> ("[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]here's ... a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">portentousness</ENAMEX> in the silence that's distancing and annoying, especially since
it leads to a too perfectly ironic ending.") and an irritated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whose Derek Kelly</ENAMEX> lashes out at everything he can: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> is spread pretty
thinly over the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>. ... [It's] structured in a rambling manner, often
borderline risible in its dialogue."). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review
in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirteenth Floor</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>). The Thirteenth
Floor is the latest alternative-universe special-effects extravaganza,
following <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dark City</ENAMEX> , eXistenZ , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Matrix</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of
virtual-reality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> operates in an alternative universe, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree that the movie suffers when the initially interesting
conception falls apart. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> calls it
"a virtual reality thriller so caught up in its time and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> confusions
that it takes the entire movie to explain it." Some don't even think the basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise</ENAMEX> is all that hot. "When a movie quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Descartes</ENAMEX>'s 'I think, therefore I
am' right at the beginning, you should probably consider yourself warned,"
writes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> cite solid
performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent D'Onofrio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armin Mueller-Stahl</ENAMEX>, and nearly all
admire the film's production design (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk M. Petruccelli</ENAMEX>) and camera work
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wedigo von Schultzendorff</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to try an "immersive simulation" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Book
            

            
               
                  Bone by
Bone
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Matthiessen</ENAMEX>. Mixed takes on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> volume of a
grisly Everglades trilogy. "This dense, mesmerizing novel will leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
stunned, as if waking from a horrific sunburnt daydream," pronounces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flynn of Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> . Says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Skow</ENAMEX> of the
"quirky trilogy": "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> might conclude: brilliant, obsessive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">panoramic</ENAMEX>--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> novels too many."

         
      
   
