
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">253</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Pesca Milagrosa&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "It is terrible
that something so frightening should be given the name of something so pure and
beautiful," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luz Marlene Sierra Mayorga</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogotá</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>, referring to
"miraculous fishing"--which is what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 252</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Euphemism?</ENAMEX>":
            

            
               "We want to be
able to land in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">grandma</TIMEX>'s backyard at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, in thick fog, without hitting the
clothesline," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Allison</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> on the project. What
project?
            

            

               
                  (This question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Pope</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eww</ENAMEX>.
Just eww."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            "An
improved smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, now with added <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bleach</ENAMEX> and a touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lemon</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
Considine
            

            
"Getting grandpa back home after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shriners</ENAMEX>' parade."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Mason</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
very ambitious 'meals-on-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX>' program."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Terns</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX>
this another one of those commercials to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> they can drive sport
utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>? 'Cause, like, I want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miata</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
responses, here's what we know about the world: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is dangerously inept, as
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amtrack</ENAMEX>, as is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>, as are the elderly when attempting to
sustain an erotic life. And incompetence is funny. Something falls on someone's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. The hose doesn't work, then it does, then it squirts somebody in the
face. Someone tries to build something, and it collapses in a heap of rubble.
It's the myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sisyphus</ENAMEX> played for laughs: When the rock rolls back down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hill</ENAMEX>, it crushes that poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bastard</ENAMEX>'s toes. Of course it all depends on whose
toe we're talking about. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> observed, if you break your back, that's
comedy; if I break a nail, that's tragedy; if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> breaks his back,
that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. I paraphrase, of course, and no doubt incompetently.

            
               Futurific
Answer
            

            It's that flying car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular Science</ENAMEX> has
been putting on the cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year since 1939</TIMEX>, only this time it's really,
really about to happen, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>.

            "Earlier flying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were simply conventional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> with wings bolted on top, which had to be dismantled before they could
run on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Moller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skycar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M400</ENAMEX> operates with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pairs of engines
with power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> that simply lift the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> into the air.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moller</ENAMEX>, a former engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at Davis</ENAMEX>, has been working on the technology for a
flying car since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moller International</ENAMEX>, has spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$</NUMEX>100m
developing the flying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, which he calls a volantor.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> would have to take off from what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moller</ENAMEX>
calls a vertiport. Noise levels and safety risks make it impractical to take
off in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, but he believes that in the future vertiports
could be as common as corner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M400</ENAMEX> will not be cheap. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> models will
cost up to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1m</NUMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moller</ENAMEX> believes that a mass-produced <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> could cost as
little as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX>. And the flying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is not easy on petrol either. It does
only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8km</NUMEX> per liter."

            Next up:
superintelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> that farm the ocean floor ... on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neptune</ENAMEX>!

            
               Entrepreneurial
Extra
            

            When I need <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shampoo</ENAMEX> or a stereo or a piece of heavy
industrial equipment, I can read up or ask a professional, but what I really
wonder is: What sort of earthmover do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> recommend?

            That's the idea behind endorsement.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, a Web site
that would list the product preferences of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Click
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenna Elfman</ENAMEX> (kooky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of television's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX> ), scroll
through her categories--health and beauty aids, home electronics, medical and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dental</ENAMEX>, non-ferrous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metals</ENAMEX>--click heavy equipment , click earth moving
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">machinery ,</ENAMEX> click <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">backhoe</ENAMEX> , and discover that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenna</ENAMEX> is nuts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>, I've got some pretty savvy advice. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenna</ENAMEX>? For each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who seeks her advice she's paid a modest fee, let's say <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>. Not much, is
it? But with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenna</ENAMEX>'s tips on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of purchases,
she's going to become one wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity endorser</ENAMEX>.

            Why should a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> gamble <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> endorsement deal when they can't be sure how influential he
really is, particularly in retirement? What if he goes nuts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and slaps
the hell out an orphan, or even better, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>? Just goes after him with a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-by-4</NUMEX>. That might discourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from seeking his advice on refreshing
noncarbontated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverages</ENAMEX> or inexpensive long-distance services. But with
endorsement.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> gets paid only when someone seeks his advice. It's
risk-free.

            And everyone is a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>. Many people
go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Rose</ENAMEX> for medical advice. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hint: She</ENAMEX> loves those new gel caps, so
easy to swallow!) If she were always available online instead of just in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Shabbat</TIMEX> services, she could help more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> an
endorsement, help herself.

            Interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> can
contact me through this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.

            
               This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Do for Me</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>, Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are still
welcome to offer a sentence from an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> that best conveys
ludicrously conspicuous consumption in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Submissions due by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7</TIMEX>.

            
               Headline
Haiku
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midlife</ENAMEX> hits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
Center
Hamptons feud and fret
and playing with pain
walk in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' shoes

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 1999</TIMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lois C.</ENAMEX>
Ambash
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
