
   
   
      
         
            

            
 <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> admitted that one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> bombed a caravan of ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, claiming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, called
it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> "atrocity." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> mistook the caravan for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said that such tragedies are
"inevitable" in war and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> must fight on to stop far worse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
atrocities. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is reportedly planning to call up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of reservists . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> changed their definition of victory. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
definition: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Driving</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. New definition: Shifting the
"balance of power" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>. The sunny
spin: Now we have a viable strategy. The cynical spin: Now we're allied with
vengeful, ethnic-separatist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Astronomers
found another solar system . It consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> huge planets
around a star <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">44 light-years</NUMEX> away. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) We are not alone! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) There
can't be life on these planets, because they're too big, too gaseous, and too
close to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Maybe they have moons capable of supporting life. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
Among the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 billion</NUMEX> sunlike stars in our galaxy, we're certain to find other
habitable solar systems. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hockey</ENAMEX> legend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Gretzky</ENAMEX> is retiring . Known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great One</ENAMEX>," he holds the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hockey League</ENAMEX> records for goals (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">894</ENAMEX>), assists (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,962</NUMEX>), and most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">valuable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> awards (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>). As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, his decision wasn't yet
official, but he indicated he would retire "unless a miracle happens between
now and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hockey pundits</ENAMEX> lauded him in terms reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>. The happy spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gretzky</ENAMEX> built hockey into a popular sport in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. The sad spin: He's going out on a low note because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Rangers</ENAMEX>, is mediocre. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/16/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was held in contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for lying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Webber Wright</ENAMEX> called his testimony about his relationship with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> "false, misleading and evasive" and "designed to obstruct the
judicial process." The judge ordered him to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> costs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' legal
expenses that were caused by his lying. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> agreed that materially the
ruling is just a slap on the wrist (and therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> won't appeal it) but
that symbolically it's a huge blow to his legacy, since he's the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to be held in contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> hailed the ruling as
history's verdict on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Liberal editorialists paired it with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">acquittal/</ENAMEX>mistrial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>, which they portrayed as a similar rebuke
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX> expressed satisfaction that each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is being repudiated without vindicating the other. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> testified against renewal of the independent counsel
law . He argued that it had failed in its stated purpose, which is to assure
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> that investigations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would be nonpartisan.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> for discrediting the law by injecting politics
into his investigations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> replied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> had repeatedly rejected
assertions that he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> had "conducted ourselves inappropriately."
Elite opinion is divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> law; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) against both; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> (as a bad
example) but in favor of the law. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s testimony, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> took
a break from their quarreling to make fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> for being the only advocate
of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> position--against the law but in favor of himself.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
Kevorkian was sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 to 25 years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for injecting lethal
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> into a terminally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s consent. The case was based on a
videotape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s death, which was brought to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> and aired
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> . He can't be paroled until he has served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s spin: The death was a victimless crime, the verdict
is an injustice, the sentence was too harsh, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> will starve himself
to death in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> forced the issue by taking
the tape to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s spin: The case wasn't about assisted suicide, it
was about a flagrant challenge to the rule of law. The new liberal spin:
Kevorkian was an embarrassment to the assisted suicide movement, and we're glad
he's out of the way. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX> avoided conviction in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> cover-up trial. She was
acquitted 
               of obstructing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s
investigation (by refusing to testify against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>) and got a
mistrial 
               on the remaining charges of 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> contempt
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was deadlocked. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX>'s spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> agreed that her
refusal to testify was based on a reasonable belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was trying to
get her to lie. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s spin: She escaped justice by putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> on
trial, but we'll try her again. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s spin: Go ahead, and we'll try
you again. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Jos√©
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar√≠a Olaz√</ENAMEX>°bal 
               won the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Masters golf</ENAMEX> tournament. The sentimental
spin: It's the heartwarming tale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfer</ENAMEX> who came back to win <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sport</ENAMEX>'s biggest prizes after being so seriously injured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> that he
couldn't walk. The counterspin: It's the heartbreaking tale of third-place
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">finisher Greg Norman</ENAMEX>, who, after blowing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-stroke lead in the tournament's
final round <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>, choked away his lead again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The
completely unsentimental spin: It's the tournament's worst winning score in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of
the 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beavers</ENAMEX> were captured . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park Service</ENAMEX>
suspects them of gnawing down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cherry <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>'s
scenic <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tidal Basin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agents</ENAMEX> are pursuing a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> beaver that is believed to be
still at large. The captured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beavers</ENAMEX> were given medical checkups and were then
released in a secret location to protect them from public scrutiny. According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> tried to determine the sex of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> beaver, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> did not seem to appreciate the prodding." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spins: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurray</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feds</ENAMEX> saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurray</ENAMEX>, they caught the beavers!
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boo</ENAMEX>, let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beavers</ENAMEX> eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) This is another attempt to distract
attention from the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
