
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Ain't No Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX>

            For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> started its offensive
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks ago</TIMEX>, hope for peace dominated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. With the exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>--the former all
leading on the election of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, and the latter on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s troubles in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corsica</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX> devoted their
main front-page headlines to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> peace plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> declared
"peace in sight" and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> said it was "finally possible to talk of hope;" but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press was much more wary. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
and the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> all demanded an intensification of the war.

            Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Give War a Chance</ENAMEX>," the
Times ' editorial said the "general principles" agreed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> "are not principles at all. ... At best, they may be
understood as diplomatic circumlocutions, designed to ease <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s political
dilemma in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> and thus avert further frictions with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>," it said.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX> is nearing the point where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have been so damaged that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> could be committed at acceptable risk. It has never been clearer
that the best prospect for a peace worthy of the name is to give war a chance."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> said the peace plan could be "a trap for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>" and
that the bombing campaign must continue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> continued to argue
for a land war "to capture <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and turn it into an international
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protectorate</ENAMEX>."

            In an op-ed article for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>
insisted that peace could be only on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s terms and that "the corrupt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictatorship</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> must be cast out," which is still not
officially an alliance war aim. He backed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX>'s statement earlier
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> that the only way the war would end would be "victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>,
defeat for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, and the reversal of ethnic cleansing."

            On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's
defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Keegan</ENAMEX>, called for the replacement
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Lacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX>'s "uncompromisingly soldierly manner," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> appears "to have
fallen under the spell of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>, which believes that a
combination of diplomatic formulae and the indirect application of military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> can achieve desired foreign policy results," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keegan</ENAMEX> wrote. He blamed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "for not appointing a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlord</ENAMEX>," and asked: "Are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> have
committed to this lacklustre war not entitled to ask for someone who can match
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> in single-mindedness and strength of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s motive in
freeing the moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim Rugova</ENAMEX>, who was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
for talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, generated much perplexity in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koha Jone</ENAMEX> described it
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> as "one of the most interesting developments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis
since the start of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> airstrikes" and part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "peace
offensive" for softening up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> might also be wanting to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strengthen Rugova</ENAMEX>'s international standing against the more militant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who have gained the upper hand since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX> agreement.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
welcomed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-brokered agreement on self-determination for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> but expressed doubts about the policing of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next August</TIMEX>'s referendum
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, "which invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, forcibly annexed the
territory, and has maintained a policy of brutal pacification" there. But the
paper saw hope in the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> was for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX> and international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> into the territory. If things do go
smoothly, it said in an editorial, "it will represent a victory for
commonsense, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of patient international diplomacy, but most of all for
the courage and determination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            In the run-up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> election, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> Poll published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> showed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is still slipping slightly against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Mordechai</ENAMEX> is continuing to
decline. The poll put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43.5 percent</NUMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mordechai</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX>. Following the dissolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>
after a political row over misprints in a new edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koran</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX>
daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Qabas</ENAMEX> , which is associated with the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>, said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that it reflects a growing "climate of religious terrorism" in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columnist Abdellatif al-Duaij</ENAMEX> wrote that many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> supported a no-confidence motion against a
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> on this matter "because they feared that otherwise they
would be accused of being insufficiently zealous about religious matters."
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Legislators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> alike felt obliged to make a huge fuss over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misprinted</ENAMEX> copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koran</ENAMEX> for fear of being accused of not being concerned
enough about God's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Book</ENAMEX>," he wrote. "Neither had the courage to say that
the matter was unimportant, though they all knew that what had occurred was
merely a printing error."

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> papers also pointed out that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> elections scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3</TIMEX> would take place in the height of summer
when temperatures would be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around 50 degrees Celsius</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">122 degrees Fahrenheit</NUMEX>)
and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emirate</ENAMEX>'s wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> would be abroad. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Hayat</ENAMEX> said this would create "real problems" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who
traditionally erect large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> in which to hold banquets for their electors.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Awsat</ENAMEX> noted that an election in high summer
meant these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> would have to be air-conditioned, incurring costs that could
deter some potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> from running. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caterers</ENAMEX> who
have been expecting a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> slump in business are now looking forward to a
boom, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            The front pages of most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> carried the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Fayed</ENAMEX>, the controversial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrods</ENAMEX> department store in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX>, who died with her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> car crash,
has had a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> application for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> turned down. According to
an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , "The decision is cause for
collective rejoicing among those who deplore Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fayed</ENAMEX>'s malevolent influence
on our public affairs, particularly his disgraceful claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> assassinated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
