
   
   
      
         
             Was Bob a God?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--at least those who own stock--have not
only endorsed the infallibility of the markets, they have also endorsed the
infallibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who watch over those markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> was long ago elevated to divinity. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>, who announced his resignation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, has joined
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">pantheon of Money Gods</ENAMEX>. (There are no atheists in bull
markets.)

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>, but especially since rumors
of his departure began circulating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has been bathing in media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slobber</ENAMEX>. He has been credited with eliminating the deficit, captaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> fat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, vanquishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial crisis,
transmuting base metals into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and generally doing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> impossible things
before breakfast.

            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> deserve this sanctification? Is there,
in fact, anything wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>?

            As with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s godliness rests on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of genuine accomplishment. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> was one of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> who urged deficit reduction rather
than economic stimulus. This tightfistedness set the table for the current
boom, leading to low interest rates, job growth, the Wall Street explosion,
etc. Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s cautious advice has helped ensure that the
administration did nothing to screw up the prosperity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rubin</ENAMEX> lobbied for NAFTA
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX>. His friendly relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>--a dramatic contrast to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s squabbling with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>--has soothed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. His deft manipulation of the debt ceiling during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1995-96</TIMEX>
government shutdown prevented a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> default and guaranteed that the political
war between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would not derail the
thriving economy.

            And as a conservative Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> brought market credibility to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, reassuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
would not go loopy on them. Perhaps the most compelling evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s
accomplishment may be, perversely, Wall Street's yawn at his resignation. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> points on the news, then gained most of it back
within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX>. This is testament to Wall Street's faith that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has been
so successful that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> won't dare change his pro-market
policies.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s deification
is not simply the result of having done a good job. Who hasn't done a
good job during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>? His reputation depends on style as much as
substance. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> would be another gray suit,
another dull rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> moonlighting as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has been blessed
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who make him look good by comparison. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
emotional, loud, chaotic, horny, and enveloped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> sleaze. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> is
ascetic, controlled, rational, quiet, and untouched by any of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">zillion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals. During <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> and since, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s chilliness has been a
welcome adult relief from the childish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            In a more democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s
wealth--estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125 million</NUMEX> or more--would have made him suspect. But
among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonians</ENAMEX>, it has burnished him. He seems the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cincinnatus of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: Unlike the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> around him, he has proved himself in
another arena. He doesn't need the power and prestige of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and feels
no compulsion to claw his way up. This is rare among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX>. Having been
assigned the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Amateur Politician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> seems pure next to the
sleazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX>. (He is not, of course, an amateur. Click for an example.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has another rare
quality. He does not seek press coverage, and when he is covered, he speaks
with blandness in order not to make news. This silence impresses those
who cover him: Compare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s worshipful treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> with its scorn
of publicity-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cuomo</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-designate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Summers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s reticence,
as well as his praise of underlings and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, has earned him an enormous,
though not fully deserved, reputation for humility. "This humility stuff is
nonsense," says a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s. "He does not need to
elbow others out of the way and brag, but it's not because he's humble. It's
because he is totally confident."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> subtly enhances his own reputation for perfection by
talking frequently about his imperfections. In interviews, he repeatedly
emphasizes the uncertainty of his job. He describes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> how he focuses
on weighing and reweighing percentages until he makes the best possible
decision in ambiguous circumstances. This is a fine way to make decisions, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has proved, but it is an equally good way to protect your image. If a
decision turns out well, it's because you calculated it would. If it turns out
badly, it's not your fault: You made the most rational choice you could.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> agnostics will be
glad to learn that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> weak spots in his record. He arrived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as a supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of the poor. He was expected to use his
position as head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Economic Council</ENAMEX> and later as treasury
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to redirect federal resources toward inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and the underclass.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s cautiousness has got the better of him. Although he strongly
disagreed with the welfare reform bill, he didn't battle hard to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from signing it. And instead of lobbying for large-scale anti-poverty
or urban revival programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rubin</ENAMEX> settled for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: small efforts to
prod <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to extend credit in troubled neighborhoods, micro-loan programs to
encourage entrepreneurship among the poor. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s defense, his stewardship
of the economy has done more to help the poor than any federal grant program
could have.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> has also been excessively obeisant to Wall
Street. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has bucked Wall Street by opposing a capital-gains tax
cut, he comes from Wall Street, and most of his closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>
are Wall Streeters, and he generally heeds the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. During the global
financial crisis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has halfheartedly warned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> not to invest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cavalierly</ENAMEX> in weak foreign economies, but anytime foolhardy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
have been threatened, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has rushed to save them. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> crises, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> constructed bailout deals that benefited outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> above all. He insists he was not trying to help Wall Street.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s logic, safeguarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in these troubled economies
prevents contagion from spreading. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> thought they were
going to lose the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> they had unwisely put in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, they might pull out
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>, or the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>.

            But many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, especially non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
complain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has been far too obliging toward his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and
indifferent to the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and bankrupted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX> damaged by his
decisions. (After all, when Wall Streeters say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> crisis is
"over," what they mean is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> exposure is over. The economies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
are still a mess.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s relief for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> has encouraged a "moral
hazard"--an inducement for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to speculate excessively because they know
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will rescue them.

            The regulatory capture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> by Wall Street has
not only benefited Wall Street, it has also polished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s reputation. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> makes decisions that aid Wall Street, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> reciprocate in
the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, telling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomberg</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, just how wise the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> is. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> himself probably does not
care about such back scratching, but it is a lesson that heir-apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summers</ENAMEX>,
an eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> hound, has surely absorbed. Be nice to Wall Street, and perhaps
you can be a money god, too.

         
      
   
