
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> Question

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been preparing to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. His stated reasons are
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>-dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, is waging war on the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> refuses to sign a peace plan to which
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> have grudgingly agreed. Persuading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
public to support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action abroad is always difficult because such
action poses risks to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, requires moral justification for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
aggression, and threatens to entangle us in commitments we will regret. To win
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is trying to turn those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> issues upside down.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Risk. This is the big buzzword
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the bombing. Speaking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> after his meeting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> used this word <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times
in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX>. Another favorite phrase in the anti-bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> is "rise to
the level." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s impeachment effort by
persuading the public that the charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't "rise to the
level" worthy of removing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are turning the tables,
arguing that the stakes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> don't "rise to the level" worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military action.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the bombing argue that the risk
can be minimized. But this is a losing game, since risk is always more than
zero. The better answer is to reframe the status quo as a parallel option with
risks of its own. "We must weigh those risks [of bombing] against the risks of
in action," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said at his press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. "If we don't
act, the war will spread. If it spreads, we will not be able to contain it
without far greater risk and cost. ... You have to ask yourself, what will be
the cost and the duration of involvement and the consequences if we do
not move? ... I'm convinced we'll be dragged into this thing under worse
circumstances at greater cost if we don't act."

            To put plausibility and
punch in this theoretical argument, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s past aggression
and invoked images of slaughtered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX>. Absent intervention, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> will produce "the same thing that happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>"--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>" and
"further atrocities." "I would hate to think that we'd have to see a lot of
other little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> die. ... I do not believe that we ought to have to have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> slaughtered and buried in open soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> before we do
something." To drive home his point that inaction, like action, requires
justification and bears consequences, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> distilled his frame job to a
brilliant sound bite: "In dealing with aggressors in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, hesitation is
a license to kill."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aggression</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of the bombing depict the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> as the aggressor and protest that we shouldn't intervene unless
provoked. "For us to initiate an action such as bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> is really an act
of war," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>, told reporters outside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. "I don't think that we should begin bombing unless and
until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> really begin a very significant massacre." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Bailey Hutchison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, urged her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> not to let
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "take an affirmative military action against a sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that
has not committed a security threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has responded by casting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aggressors</ENAMEX>. At his press conference, he replied, "I don't think it's accurate
to say we're acting <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. I think they have acted <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. They have massed
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, they have continued to take aggressive action, they have already
leveled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in the recent past and killed a lot of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." He
added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> had "stripped away" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s right to "self-government" a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade ago</TIMEX>. Above all, he argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have repeatedly violated a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> in which they pledged to limit their military presence and
action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. This, he maintained, is sufficient to "trigger" bombing: "The
threshold for their conduct has already been crossed." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Biden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>, agreed: "Everybody forgets we are operating in the
context of an agreement that [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>] signed. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> government
has flagrantly violated the limits stipulated in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> agreement."

            Together, these points
reverse the aggression argument in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. First, they turn the immorality of
aggression into an argument for punishing the aggressors, i.e., the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, they shift the burden of justification from the pro-bombing to the
anti-bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. The code word for this burden-shifting maneuver is
"impunity." As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> put it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, "We cannot allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to
continue the aggression with impunity."

            Much of the aggression debate revolves around the integrity
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> who oppose the bombing warn that it would pervert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> into
an "aggressive" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is a defensive alliance," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickles</ENAMEX> observed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor. "Never has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> [threatened] to go in to another
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that's not threatening neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, not threatening part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> ... to quell a civil war."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> of the bombing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interpret NATO</ENAMEX>'s mission more broadly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, they argue, rests on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deterrence</ENAMEX>, which rests on credibility in threatening the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, which
rests on the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> when challenged. This argument is weakened by its
abstraction but is bolstered by the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> challenge is in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s turf. After meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Leahy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>,
told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that "the question" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> was, "Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> relevant? Can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
stop massacres right in their own backyard? ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, if it's
going to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> relevant, has to show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Commitment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> invoke the specter
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> by warning against an unwise "commitment" to war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
can't dispute the principle of commitment, so he turns it on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. We've
already pledged to use force, he argues, and now we must keep our word.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ostensibly</ENAMEX>, this commitment was made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> voted
with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> to use air power if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> war
signed the peace plan and the other refused. After meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, told reporters, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is resolved. He's
going to keep the agreements made with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>."

            Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of
bombing use the word "impunity" to shift the burden of the aggression argument
to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, they likewise use the word "credibility" to shift the
burden of the "commitment" argument. Failure to make good on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
already-delivered threat would "undermine the credibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, on which
stability in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and our own credibility depend," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, agreed: "The credibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is on the line. The credibility
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> working with its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is on the
line." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Levin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, urged his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to "support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>" and
"not undermine [its] united effort."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is trying to reverse assumptions not merely about
what should happen but also about what will happen. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> mantra for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX> has been that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> faces a "stark choice":
Sign the peace plan or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will bomb you. The last thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> needs is a
genuine debate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> over whether we're serious about that
threat. To shortcut that debate, he is trying to lull <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> into assuming
that we're objectively as well as morally committed--that the bombing is
inevitable. He pulls off this trick by presenting bombing as the default course
with a momentum of its own. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> continues to choose
aggression over peace, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s military plans must continue to move forward,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> decreed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.

            The questions posed
before a war are always the same: Should we fight? Can we? Must we? Will we?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Philosophers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> try to answer these questions, but smart
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> rewrite them. That's not fair, you say? Neither is war.

            

               For more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> coverage, click .
            

         
      
   
