
   
   
      
         
            Autobiographical

            I rode
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX>.
Marble arms raised for joy in the garden,
a slush of sculpture salvaged from wrecked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>
around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don d'Carlo</ENAMEX>'s sandstone pen
carved from a boulder fallen from that cliff.

            When I
was a nude <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sicilian</ENAMEX> youth, and had been
lounging on the piazza for a good hour,
above the sea, I heard a cry from the beach
and ran. A seal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pup</ENAMEX> lay curled around
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>. Someone--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>?--had beat it

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">senseless</ENAMEX>, so I heaved the sack of fur
back to surf, the body cooling my body,
and swam some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yards</ENAMEX> until it sank to green.
Back up the steps, I dried on the wall
fell to sleep forgot the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> and grew

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">athletic</ENAMEX> and kept my tongue back of my head
obeyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> loved a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she climbed
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> beside the training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> to whisper
my secret names from the arbor. War grew
as we slept. I fled across the sea

            to
escape conjecture; I biked all over
to build a body of forgiveness, the wheels
wearing down a new world of old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>.
I rode across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX>, my spokes
speaking for me, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>:

            I swam in the sea there,
among the mangled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>.
A lost flotilla, the hemisphere
tapped in my ear, the ticking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX>
the warnings of sand. And when I drowned
I sank slowly and meant every fathom.

         
      
   
