
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">201</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TK&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> it happened to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's down
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX>, and a policy just announced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pediatrics</ENAMEX> is meant to make it happen even less. What?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 199</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thirds":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    He's done it twice, and
he announced on the radio that if it were legal to do it again he would.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> say this desire indicates "a strange psychological <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>." Who wants
to do what?
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>, own slaves."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Van Dussen</ENAMEX>, except more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Harveyian</ENAMEX>.)

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days in a row</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Clinton</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigerian President-elect Olusegun Obasanjo</ENAMEX>, fix an election just so he can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visit Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Gaffen</ENAMEX>
               

               "You're
telling me they passed a law to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> from directing? Well,
thank God!"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Smith</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos SaÃºl Menem</ENAMEX>, drive down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East 88 th Street</ENAMEX>
holding a can of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lerangis</ENAMEX>
               

                

               Click
for more answers.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Many of your suggestions
involved actions that, while amusing and cruel, are not illegal but merely
unlikely (Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would be too scared to lift it while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> was in the
room.), unappetizing (With a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">femur</ENAMEX>? Not in my copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> of
Cooking !), or in direct contradiction of the laws of physics (Sure, naked
and on the surface of the moon--but here on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>? I doubt it.). You know who
you are.

            
               Factory Tour
Follow-Up
            

            "As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> (the
last time I visited), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakdale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, offered
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tours</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Contreras</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
               Month of Junk
Follow-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Porges</ENAMEX> warn: "Never reply to the address that spam message says you should use
to be removed from the mailing list. This is one of the ways spammers verify
that the address is live and may result in even more spam."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>,
you received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> [pieces of junk mail] and not one was sex-related? You gotta
get on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
               Born To Run
Answer
            

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos SaÃ</ENAMEX>ºl
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menem</ENAMEX> said he'd like to seek re-election, but his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s constitution
forbids <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> consecutive terms. In addition, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> amendment specifically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prohibits Menem</ENAMEX> from running again. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RaÃºl AlfonsÃ</ENAMEX>­n thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menem</ENAMEX>
is just nuts, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menem</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AlfonsÃ</ENAMEX>­n should be ignored because "he couldn't
govern the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menem</ENAMEX> again
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reversed</ENAMEX> himself, announcing that he'd retire at the conclusion of his
term.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Edition Guest Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>, I'm always true to
you, darling, in my fashion, but sometimes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> needs to sow some wild
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BETH'S LITTLE BLACK BOOK OF ONLINE QUIZZES</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Online Quiz</ENAMEX>
            

            "Test yourself on your
knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>. If you get all the questions correct, you will
have the opportunity to be listed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Paine</ENAMEX>, me.

            
               Bat
Quiz
            

            "How much do you know about these flying, furry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>?"

            Not enough. Why do you think I stopped
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spelunking</ENAMEX>?

            
               Guess the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dictator/Sit-Com Character</ENAMEX>
            

            "Pretend to be your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> or television
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sit-com</ENAMEX> character, and I'll try to guess who you're supposed to be."

            Only if you promise to stay the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayer Aspirin Trivia</ENAMEX>
Game
            

            "No description available."

            Just the thing after a hard <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of beer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trivia</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alcatraz Trivia Contest</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alcatraz: The Warden Johnston Years</ENAMEX>."

            And you thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>'s ass was a hack
answer only at 
                  Slate
               .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership U</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible Literacy Quiz</ENAMEX>
            

            "Find out how much you really know about the
Bible."

            Moneylenders for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex.</ENAMEX>

            
               Miata
Trivia
            

            "An online quiz of basic information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miata</ENAMEX>."

            Never drive your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda Miata</ENAMEX> if you are:

            a) drunk

            b) uninsured

            c) sole support of your family

            d) all of the above

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Famous Cats Quiz</ENAMEX>
            

            Plus those nude photos of
Socks you've been hearing about!

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the insatiable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">campaigner</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
