
   
   
      
         
             Things <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fall Apart</ENAMEX>

            "All collapsed, and the great shroud of the sea
rolled on as it rolled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thousand years ago</TIMEX>." Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Melville</ENAMEX> was
not covering the removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Anderson</ENAMEX>'s breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">implants</ENAMEX> when he wrote
that line, but collapse is everywhere in the tabloid world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, from
celebrity lives, to health, to marriages, and even to body parts.

            Former sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Plato</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>, died
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> of what is being described as an accidental overdose of
prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> after declaring on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>'s radio show that
she had been sober for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> had been anticipating her death
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as a few months ago</TIMEX>. Hers
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood Babylon</ENAMEX> life with arrests for robbery and for forging
prescriptions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valium</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Newton</ENAMEX> bailed her out of jail on the
latter charge. Plato starred on the television show <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Diff'rent Strokes</ENAMEX> ,
which went off the air <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years ago</TIMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> say the show had a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX>'s two child
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-stars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Coleman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Bridges</ENAMEX>, have each found little work, but
trouble with the law, since the show ended.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> continues to assert its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medusa</ENAMEX>-in-reverse powers. In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
mythology, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mortals</ENAMEX> who looked upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medusa</ENAMEX>'s face were turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>. In the
case of the tabs, they put ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> on the cover in the apparent hope
of predicting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>'s imminent demise. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ,
former <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight</ENAMEX> show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX> is suffering from irreversible
lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and depression, which are complicating his recovery from a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carson</ENAMEX>'s former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">employer</ENAMEX>, is thoughtfully filming interviews with the TV legend's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. A
video get-well greeting? No, they're preparing his obit.

            In their coverage of a recent on-set mishap involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>, the tabs seem to be longing for another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX>--a young
star who dies at the height of his beauty and fame. While filming a scene on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> for his next movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Beach</ENAMEX> , in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, it seems that
the weather turned treacherous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> abandoned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, which promptly sank, for a rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>. But the
rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>'s engines malfunctioned and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and the others were told to
jump overboard and wait for yet another rescue vessel. Perhaps imagining the
tabloid coverage of the death by drowning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> was
what gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> the strength to keep his head above water until help arrived.

            While not in mortal
danger, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> seem to be having trouble staying conscious this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports that during a food fight scene on the set of
his latest movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX> slipped on mashed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>, whacked his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on a table, and was knocked senseless. Perhaps imagining the tabloid
coverage of such an ignominious demise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affleck</ENAMEX> recovered without incident. And
at his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX> rd birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> says, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Hefner</ENAMEX>,
while dancing with girlfriends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brande</ENAMEX>, collapsed and had to
be carried to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>. In this case, it's safe to assume that the aged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">playboy</ENAMEX> was able to make a quick recovery because he realized that when he
makes his final exit, he doesn't want to be carried to bed, he wants to be
there already.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Rourke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> were
taken to emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX> because he felt "unable to breathe" and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rourke</ENAMEX> because he was "dizzy," according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . The publication
does not report if these attacks were precipitated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> reviewing the
state of their careers. After sitting in the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cedars-Sinai</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rourke</ENAMEX> began to feel better. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX> blames the episode on
that old standby: "an allergic reaction to some cough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">syrup</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> was given
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tranquilizer</ENAMEX> and diagnosed with sleep apnea. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> also
alleges he has been distraught over rumors that he's a child molester. Perhaps
it's just a coincidence that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the preceding</TIMEX> issue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reported
on the friendship <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> has developed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, ages
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 and 11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> when he was visiting the country
and they asked for his autograph. Since then he's attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> mitzvah of
the elder and taken them both to a water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. In defending the relationship
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> offers the quote of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, "We're very protective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and if we had any suspicions about his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motives</ENAMEX>, we wouldn't be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with him. ... He is a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who is
so normal."

            Now that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX>
marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Agassi</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disintegrated</ENAMEX>, it's possible to look back and see the end was coming. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> she met "hunky <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotshot</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Henchy</ENAMEX>, a comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and
producer who wrote a comic speech for her to deliver in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . Soon afterward, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were violating taboo by taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tae Bo</ENAMEX>
classes together. But it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> that shows the marriage was doomed.
It reprints a letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agassi</ENAMEX> paid to have published in the program for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globe</ENAMEX> awards when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. He wrote, "It is wonderful just
to watch you when you don't even know that I'm looking, and to count how many
times you smile." How humiliating for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> to know that everyone who read
that thought in unison, "or watch as you scratch your private parts." He
miscalculated even more when he added, "In all of my excitement of growing old
with you, I will never forget this day." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre</ENAMEX>, no one in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is excited about growing old.

            Also over is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year</TIMEX> marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Ross</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> shipping magnate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arne Naess</ENAMEX>, who is "worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $700 million</NUMEX>,"
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . You know there's no hope of reconciliation when
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> blurts out the news of your impending divorce on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Evening</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> . And according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , the marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX> is kaput. But how would anyone know? The
publication reports that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have always maintained separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX> and
that "[f]or most of the marriage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nic</ENAMEX> was either off making a movie or off with
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>."

            Finally, the collapse of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX>--or is it? Yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Anderson</ENAMEX> has had her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36DD</NUMEX> breast implants removed, returning her to a
36C, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . They quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s reason for the
reduction of the asteroid-sized breasts: "I was getting self-conscious about
it." (But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX>, isn't having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stare at your chest the reason you get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">implants</ENAMEX> like that in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson</ENAMEX>
has deflated from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36D</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">34C</NUMEX> and says the reason for the reduction was that the
silicone sacs, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> says weighed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 1/2</NUMEX> pounds each, were
giving her back pain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> agrees the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> has gone from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36D</TIMEX> to
34C but reports that the implants weighed a pound each. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> also
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s assertion that she's all natural now is suspect. A
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX> got new implants called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'shapers</ENAMEX>.' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> had to do something because she had such big implants that
when they were removed, her breasts would have sagged."

            The attention caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s surgery has
supposedly inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny McCarthy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demi Moore</ENAMEX> to consider having their
implants removed, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ,
respectively. They may want to consult an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astrophysicist</ENAMEX> as well as a plastic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>. Such a sudden collapse of so much mammary matter could possibly result
in some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">black hole</ENAMEX>. Not everyone is deflating however.
Besides the widely reported increase in the bust-line of teen singing star
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britney Spears, Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> is planning an expansion, reports the
Star . The possible surgery was prompted by "fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> [comments]
on her lack of cleavage in her pink <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> dress." Gwyneth, there's a cheap,
painless alternative: Take the dress to the dry cleaner and have it
altered.

         
      
   
