
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Full Monica</ENAMEX>

            At the start of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX> book, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> interview,
and an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> television's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel 4</ENAMEX> (for a reported
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$640,000</NUMEX>)--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press is full of her. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> will see more of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on the globe," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
boasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, saying she would be touring <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bookshops</ENAMEX>, TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>, and radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> in a dozen <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. "With all of us--or all
of us who can still summon the interest--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> will share the emotional
journey she took when she fell in love with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the free world and
later fell into the cross-hairs of special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Usborne</ENAMEX>
wrote from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Mirror</ENAMEX> started
the ball rolling with an "exclusive" interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Golden</ENAMEX>, who described himself as the person
who introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX> and was "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> ever to talk to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Snow</ENAMEX> [her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>] and even before special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> gave her the
go-ahead to tell her side of the story." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying, "I'd
like to think I would live on in a book. I like to be able to reach up on my
book shelf for one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s plays and I would like to think that people
will do that with this [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>'s] book." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Mirror</ENAMEX> interview was
widely picked up across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>--under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexgate</ENAMEX>, the last secret: a green skirt"--focusing
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s account of her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at which, according to
her, he admired the skirt but said he would like to see what was underneath it.
She obliged.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> celebrity
magazine Hello! ran an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who knows her best." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Lewinsky</ENAMEX> said, "The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has been
stressed to the limits, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> feels terrible about it." Asked if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
carried a share of the blame for her relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he
replied that it had been "a relationship between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>," but that "it was
totally irresponsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to get involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> to begin
with." He added, "I respect him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, but I don't respect him as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> had "taught <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">knit</ENAMEX>, which was something that has been extremely helpful" and that he had
never reproached her "or told her that what she did was right or wrong--I just
told her I loved her."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX>, has been spirited away from his pursuers with
the connivance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> "actively
orchestrated" his disappearance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, and sent him with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> to an abandoned mountain guerrilla base. He was traveling "with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 25</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, including trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX> who are also wanted for the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amin al-Zahrawy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Jihad</ENAMEX>,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> has deliberately stoked the confusion surrounding
his disappearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> to protect him when he is at his most
vulnerable." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> has admitted that bin Laden
might still be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are by
the controversy over allegations of institutionalized racism in the London
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police force</ENAMEX>, made by an independent judicial inquiry into a botched police
investigation into the murder of a young black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> is
strongly critical of the proposed solutions to the problem. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> in an editorial that some of the report's conclusions "border on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insane</ENAMEX>," such as one recommending criminal prosecution of "offences involving
racist language or behavior where such conduct can be proved to have taken
place otherwise than in a public place." The editorial also attacked the
government for adopting numerical targets for the recruitment of ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> experience has shown that voluntary
forms of affirmative action can be beneficial, but once quotas are mandated by
law, they soon become counter-productive," it said.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> weekly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Mushahid</ENAMEX>
Assiyasi , prospects for ending the long-running <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lockerbie</ENAMEX> dispute have been
boosted by a complicated deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> under which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> will buy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> had been
due to purchase but have now decided not to. In exchange, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> will
work to lift the sanctions that have been in force against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.
The sanctions are due to be "suspended" once the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> suspected
of involvement in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lockerbie</ENAMEX> bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PanAm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> arrive in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> to stand trial before a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            According to a report in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pan-Arabic al-Quds</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Arabi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> is not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to have
shelved arms deals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdelbari Atwan</ENAMEX> reported that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
hard hit by the collapse of oil prices and blaming Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> for it,
have taken an unpublicized decision to "freeze" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> purchases so that their
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> will also feel the pinch.

             

         
      
   
