
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Analyze
This
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crysal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as a
panic-ridden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> and his shrink. It's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> joke movie, but the one joke is
good, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are great: "Laughs battle formulas and laughs win" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob boss</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Niro</ENAMEX> parodies his own
persona with huge relish" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX>'s put-upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> is refreshingly underplayed. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> note
the conceit's similarity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>'s new series <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> , which
features a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> as well. (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>
the movie hilarious and calls it "a slapstick fever dream.")

            
               
                  Cruel
Intentions
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> screen adaptation of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1782</TIMEX> novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Liaisons Dangereuses</ENAMEX> , this time set amongst
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, gets a mixed reaction. Some like it: a "foxy, snotty,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enjoyably trashy</ENAMEX> update," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> .
Others find the idea of such young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in this tale of sexual intrigue and
betrayal ridiculous: "The liaisons here aren't dangerous, they're incongruous"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jami Bernard</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are either entranced by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>' acting or find the whole concept of fresh-from-the-WB <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vicomte De Valmont</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquise De Merteuil</ENAMEX> "faintly ridiculous" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Holden, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> has links to information on all the film versions of
the novel, as well as sound clips and photos.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX>, Stock
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">& Two Smoking Barrels</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gramercy Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> reviews for
this "cheeky, blackly comic heist picture" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzbaum, Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ), the debut from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Ritchie</ENAMEX>. The plot is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labyrinthine</ENAMEX> and the body count high, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree that the film is "dark,
dangerous, and a great deal of wicked, amoral fun" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Many compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritchie</ENAMEX>'s style to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>'s.

                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Edelstein</ENAMEX> pooh-poohs all the critical oohing and aahing,
and dismisses the film's combination of "the music video syntax of
Trainspotting with the jokey nihilist bloodletting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp</ENAMEX>

               Fiction ." (Read the rest of his review .)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
Story
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's Press</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are
more interested in highlighting the tasty details than debating the literary
merits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di biographer Andrew Morton</ENAMEX>'s as-told-to tell-all about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. No.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> favorite detail: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "enthralled, actually
sexually aroused" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s description of her trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> who delves into the book's form, as opposed to its content, is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>. She says it lacks sourcing and
attribution, "reverberates with the cloying sound of the talk-show
confessional," and has a "propensity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> melodrama and romance-novel
prose." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX> writes in 
                  Slate
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX> is our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>
of female self-pity. (Read the rest of her review , and read excepts from the
book here courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> [requires free
registration].)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Annie</ENAMEX> Get
Your Gun
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marquis Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Advance word from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tryouts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> was overwhelmingly negative, and the show does get plenty
of bad reviews, but it also gets some good ones. Those who like the show call
it "immensely enjoyable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jess Cagle, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ) and say it
"takes a new bead on the familiar old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target</ENAMEX> and hits the bull's-eye with ease"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Zoglin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Those who don't like it say that the new version
(expurgated of several un-PC songs) is an uneasy mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">'40s</ENAMEX> and '90s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensibilities</ENAMEX> and falls flat. "Every so often, though not close to often
enough, something sharp and radiant pierces through the acrid smog that is
being called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Annie Get Your Gun</ENAMEX>,' " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radiance</ENAMEX> mentioned is all from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie</ENAMEX> as played by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Broadway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> Bernadette
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>, who everyone agrees is top-notch. (Find out about show times and
tickets at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  Bright
Lights, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big City</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Theatre Workshop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).
Harsh pans for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Greif</ENAMEX>'s musical based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McInerney</ENAMEX>'s novel of debauched young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manhattanites</ENAMEX>: "The musical is sung
through, and there's something comically embarrassing about hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say
things like 'You got any blow?' in recitative." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Franklin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ). Worst bits: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Goodman</ENAMEX>, who wrote the show's music, book, and
lyrics, has inserted himself into the musical, strolling onstage with a guitar
and narrating in his thick <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> accent; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) songs with titles such as "I
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Drugs</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Wanna Have Sex Tonight</ENAMEX>." As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Isherwood</ENAMEX> writes in
Variety , "nothing fades more quickly than fabulousness"; the
name-dropping glitter of the novel seems hopelessly old hat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>.
(Read an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McInerney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> .)

            Find a movie playing
near you on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  8MM ;

               
                  Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> Cigarettes ;

               
                  Movie -- The 
                  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Houdini Girl</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martyn Bedford</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Perfect Murder, Perfect Town</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiller</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Nightingales</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  
                     Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jawbreaker</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Space</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Music--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Rock</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleater-Kinney</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Traveling Mercies: Some Thoughts on Faith</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Lamott</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Elegant Universe: Superstrings, Hidden Dimensions</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quest for the Ultimate Theory</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian R. Greene</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Blast From the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Past</TIMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Message in a Bottle ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Favorite Martian</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testament</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haruki</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  Death <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of a Salesman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene O'Neill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

            :

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Payback</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simply Irresistible</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Rushmore ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry Cleaning</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werewolves</ENAMEX> in Their Youth , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chabon</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- You're a Good Man</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> .

            

         
      
   
