
   
   
      
         
            Disgust in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing campaign
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> was declared "a disaster" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> ,
which could not have condemned it more severely. It has been "an unrelieved disaster
not just for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Atlantic Treaty Organization</ENAMEX>, but for the very people
the bombing was meant to protect," it said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> attacks have brought about
a wave of righteous nationalism as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavs</ENAMEX> rallied behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that many
of them loathed.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe</ENAMEX> in their high-tech
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jets</ENAMEX> and distant command posts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have so far escaped without a
single casualty," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>--and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> too--who are paying the price for the bombing. And what does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
plan to do about it? Why, bomb some more, of course." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX>
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s motives had been good--"it wanted to stop Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>,
protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and save its own reputation in the bargain. Too many
times, the West has threatened dire consequences and then done nothing. It is
right to feel guilty about acting too late in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, and not at all in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>.
But true atonement requires sacrifice. In expiating its guilt over past
failures, the West has instead sacrificed the lives of the helpless civilians
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. That is unforgivable."

            In interviews published in various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Solana</ENAMEX> denied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> attacks
had increased the violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. "No, no," he told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s campaign began specifically to stop the
violence. ... And we are doing everything we can to stop it." Corriere
also carried an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiro Gilgorov</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>,
who took the same line. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> had been planning the "ethnic
cleansing" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilgorov</ENAMEX> called for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> humanitarian aid for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> pouring into his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> were the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a position to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. The only outcome he ruled out
was a world war. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> doesn't exist anymore, so whom would a world
war be between?" he asked. "If there is a risk, it is that the conflict will
destabilize other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> liberal
press, which has been strongly supportive of the bombing campaign, the focus
shifted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to humanitarian aid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>
said in an editorial that aid was now the priority. "The same concentration
of effort and the same plethora of assets lavished on the aerial war against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> must now be applied to the task of housing and caring for the refugees
reeling out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," it said. "That no preparations of this kind were made
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> or by the alliance military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> as
they laid their plans, is worse than a pity. It shows how feckless <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> have been in their approach to this crisis, and should at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a later time</TIMEX>
be the subject of a serious inquiry."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> exposed its bleeding heart by filling
its entire front page with a picture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> under the
headline: "This is the reality of the war. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of bombing, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. And no hope." In an editorial, the
Independent called attention to "the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualty</ENAMEX> of the bombs"--"the
co-operation on foreign policy and military matters which the West and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> have developed since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>." It said the West would
have to struggle to reintegrate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> into international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> should begin this process by providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
with a generous loan.

            Among the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, still
regarding the use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> as both desirable and a distinct
possibility, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s "peace"
offer to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> had been just "a feint to
split the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX>" and urged the continuation of the war until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capitulated</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> before the offer was
made and rejected, were enthusiastic about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX>'s attempt at mediation.
Nezavisimaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazeta</ENAMEX> said the conflict had given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> an opportunity to be a key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> again on the international stage, while Moskovsky Komsomolets
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> could not lose out in any event. "If his mission fails, he
will have the full moral right to say, 'I did all I could'; and if he succeeds,
the rewards would be tremendous." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> went on, "He would not only greatly
increase his international standing, but the achievement of any peace, however
fragile, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> would slow the deterioration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s political
situation at home."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> papers
highlighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rexhep Meidani</ENAMEX>'s appeal for international help in dealing
with the vast influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> and the establishment of a judicial task force
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> atrocities against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>. The papers were
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of patriotic breast-beating. Under the headline "We Must Go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX>,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> iRilindja <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demokratikei</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> to
liberate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> from the "wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. The refugees
must return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX>, it added: "We will go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX>. There is no other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdelamir al-Rakabi</ENAMEX> warned
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s airstrikes lead to the
capitulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> should prepare for an all-out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX>
drive to topple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. But in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Ra'i</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saleh Qallab</ENAMEX> argued that this fear is misplaced and should not be used as an
excuse for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> to oppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> action in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has
reasons for attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, the fact that one of them is to end the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slaughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Muslims</ENAMEX> is a good enough reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> to support it.
"There is no justification whatsoever for constantly invoking the idea that my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enemy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qallab</ENAMEX> wrote.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> condemned
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for refusing to take sides in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> conflict. It
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel Sharon</ENAMEX> had
made only "vague declarations condemning genocide wherever it may be" and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon</ENAMEX> had refrained from mentioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, "as though both sides were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">massacring</ENAMEX> each other." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said it understood why some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>
felt they owed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> a debt of gratitude for their tenacious opposition to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, but added: "A much-persecuted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, well
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">versed</ENAMEX> in pogroms, cannot stand on the side, watching an institutionalized
process of exterminating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> based on religion and ethnicity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
debt to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> from the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> does not justify <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> apathy
to the horrors the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are perpetrating on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>."

            

               For more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> coverage, click .
            

             

         
      
   
