
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poisoned Dogs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two months</TIMEX> after Muriel
Spark's poem "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mungo Bays at the Moon</ENAMEX>" was published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
her brown <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mungo</ENAMEX> was found poisoned at her garden gate. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press
has copiously reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mungo</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> lost by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist</ENAMEX>, who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 12 years</TIMEX>.

            Although this sounds
like something straight out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spark</ENAMEX>'s wonderfully creepy novels, she and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> are not special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. This is a story of everyday life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX>--and quite possibly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>--of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, and other domestic pets
are killed by poisoning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> in this cradle of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> civilization, this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>-soaked land of vines and olives and cypresses.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I are lucky enough to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susanna</ENAMEX> came into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> to find a very
thin and pregnant spotted white, bitch lying on the sofa in the sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
She was a mongrel, as virtually all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stray dogs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX> are, but
obviously with a powerful strain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatian</ENAMEX> in her and with that alarming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatian</ENAMEX>'s "smile" that looks like a snarl. Soon she had a name, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Allegra</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pups, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brutta</ENAMEX> (ugly) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bella</ENAMEX> (beautiful). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Susanna</ENAMEX> found a good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for
Brutta, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bella</ENAMEX> we kept. After a while, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bella</ENAMEX> were joined by
another stray <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> of a very different kind, a huge white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fluffy sheepdog</ENAMEX> who
was given the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddy</ENAMEX> adopted a posture of world-weary dignity and
behaved like the indulgent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of unruly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>. They accepted him,
though, and liked to tease him mercilessly until he would give in and join in
their games.

            If these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> had a
fault, it was their habit of barking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>, having made it their mission,
most unsuccessfully pursued, to keep the wild boar away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. For
most of the time they enjoyed a happy and carefree existence. Then <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>, there was a blast from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> very near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddy</ENAMEX> came running <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with blood pouring from his face and side. He
recovered. But then, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bella</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allegra</ENAMEX> did not come in, as they
always did, for their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening meal</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Susanna</ENAMEX> discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra</ENAMEX>'s
stiff body lying in grass behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days later</TIMEX> the body
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bella</ENAMEX> was discovered in one of her favorite patches of undergrowth.

            Who could possibly have done this awful thing? I asked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> who performed the autopsy on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra</ENAMEX>. He is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holliday</ENAMEX>, who has been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> and is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society for</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection of Animals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holliday</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to a long line of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> people
who have fallen in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> but have been appalled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. With a city practice, he treats several cases each year
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs poisoned maliciously</ENAMEX> by next-door <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, perhaps objecting to the
noise.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holliday</ENAMEX> endorsed
the general assumption that almost all dog <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">poisonings</ENAMEX> in the countryside are
committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> die in bitter territorial wars between rival
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squads</ENAMEX> of wild boar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> and in the fierce competition between truffle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> seeking a bigger share of the lucrative truffle market by eliminating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>' hounds.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> may find this hard to believe, but gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> are
an even more privileged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. They have a
constitutional right to walk over other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s land without permission. An
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> just going for a walk in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is trespassing--unless
he's holding a gun, in which case it's OK. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hunters</ENAMEX> are allowed to take their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>; other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not. The law requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> to be tied up during
the game breeding and shooting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> (a law we were guilty of breaking in the
cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bella</ENAMEX>).

            But for all that, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> are not happy. They have practically no pheasants or partridges to
shoot at anymore, and they are fiercely protective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> put down in the
countryside in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> by the shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> to which they pay their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dues</ENAMEX>. Consider, further, that nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX> apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">foxes</ENAMEX> are now
protected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, and that owning a gun license is very expensive, and you
will understand why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>'s lot is not a happy one.

            Nevertheless, hunting continues to have an atavistic hold
on many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tuscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 50</TIMEX>, and it is among this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poisoners</ENAMEX>--probably only a handful of them--are assumed to lurk. Their main
targets may not be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs but foxes</ENAMEX>, for which they also lay illegal traps. But
they do not hesitate to place their poisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baits</ENAMEX> close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s houses
where <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> may find them. Together with their
addiction to killing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, they have inherited from their ancestors a cruel
indifference to the fate of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, even that of a much-loved pet. All
attempts to identify the poisoners are frustrated by a tradition of reluctance,
even among their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, to tangle with authority. I called on a neighbor
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> was poisoned along with ours, and he said that if he found the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perpetrator</ENAMEX>, he would give him the thrashing of his life. But he wouldn't dream
of going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. At that level of society, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX> is not so different
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sicily</ENAMEX>.

            We think we know who may have done it. There's an
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who lives nearby, a fanatical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the local hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fraternity</ENAMEX>.
There is no evidence against him, but he once explained to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> how
to make poisoned meatballs with a mixture of legal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>--organophosphates
and others--that cause internal hemorrhaging, which was what killed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra</ENAMEX>.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was seen near our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> around the time of the poisoning. But there's
little point in pursuing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX>, whoever he or she may be. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">poisoning dogs</ENAMEX> is strictly illegal, there have to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who saw the
laying down of the poison, and even then the punishment is only a modest
fine.

         
      
   
