
   
   
      
         
             Lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> for the Gipper!

            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have dallied with social conservatism, libertarianism, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrichian</ENAMEX> "revolutionary" conservatism. Now they are flirting with a new--or
rather, an old--doctrine: nostalgism.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has been trying
to recapture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s magic ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> went west in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. So it's
not surprising that, at this moment of low ebb, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are again evoking
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gipper</ENAMEX>. They have placed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> early '80s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> issues at the heart of their
platform: across-the-board tax cuts and a national missile defense.

            The tax cut notion enthralls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s top echelon,
especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> pushed a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> income
tax cut as the centerpiece of their legislative plan until they abandoned the
idea <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> trekked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macomb</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>,--the wellspring of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>--to flog the tax cut. Presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX> is touting the income tax cut as the key to his campaign.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX> are equally enthusiastic. Someone has
also wound up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> doll, which declares the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> proposal "timid
and pitiful." Tax rates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> says, should be cut back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> levels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, too, is dissatisfied with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> off: He would slash rates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>
percent. (Even as I write this, a letter from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX> has been
dropped on my desk: It says the tax cut idea "harkens back to the supply-side
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. And not a minute too soon.")

            The national missile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> has similarly claimed a top spot on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX>
began talking about the Star Wars revival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>, when a blue-ribbon
commission concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was increasingly vulnerable to
missile strikes by rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The enthusiasm has mushroomed since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> shot a test missile over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> calls missile defense "one of our
most critical" legislative priorities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> is making it one of his lead
issues. (When I saw him speak at a conservative conference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, the
missile defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exhortation</ENAMEX> was his biggest applause line.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>,
too, are making missile defense a campaign priority. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> is obsessed with the topic, berating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> for failing to deploy a shield.

            The clinging to these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> idées fixes is, in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> failure to accept victory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s tax cuts and tax reform
were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> triumphs. They lowered marginal rates from ludicrously high
levels to more reasonable ones, and they spurred the economic expansion of the
'80s (as well as the deficits of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>). Star Wars helped win the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convincing Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> could not compete.

            This Reaganite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fundamentalism</ENAMEX> is not ideology. It is faith: If he believed it, it must
be so. But the problem with idées fixes is that they are fixed. Tax cuts
and missile defense, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, are not wrong ideas. They are insignificant
ones. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> who campaigned on the New Deal, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'99</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are refurbishing bygone notions for an age that doesn't want them.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> cut taxes to spur consumption and revive a sickly economy.
Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are consuming voraciously, and the economy could hardly be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fitter</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> funded Star Wars to intimidate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. Today,
we don't need a national missile defense to defend against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. Nor is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">missile</ENAMEX> shield a wise investment in the battle against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rogues</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terrorists</ENAMEX> are
more likely to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> a bomb-filled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pennsylvania Avenue</ENAMEX> than lob a
missile. Better to spend the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> on intelligence and nonproliferation.

            What must be especially frustrating to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' indifference to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> dogma says you can never
err by offering to cut taxes. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have greeted the tax cut schemes
with a shrug. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have successfully (and accurately) painted the
across-the-board tax cut proposal as regressive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has countered it with
targeted, interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> tax cuts (child care, senior care, health care) offset
by targeted tax increases (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would spend much of the
surplus on a tax break. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would spend it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, debt
repayment, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only about 11 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> favor spending the
surplus on a tax cut, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 70 percent</NUMEX> favor spending it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security or debt repayment. Polls have found that when it comes to taxes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> trust <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> (formerly "tax and spend <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>") far more
than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> far more than congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have won the tax issue so completely that congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have now abandoned the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> tax cut plan. Instead they
are pushing marriage penalty tax relief. (The presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, of
course, are still clutching to the across-the-board cuts.)

            On missile defense, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has outfoxed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. He killed Star Wars in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, but the budget he introduced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX>
ago proposes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.6 billion</NUMEX> for missile defense research. (This is part of an
enormous proposed increase in military spending.) The missile defense money has
pulled the rug out from under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, leaving them with the flimsiest of
criticisms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has delayed the decision on whether to actually
deploy a missile defense until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2000</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> wants time to
conduct <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R & D</ENAMEX> and renegotiate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ABM</ENAMEX> treaty with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The treaty bans
national <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile defenses</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been reduced to insisting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declare now that he will deploy a defense. In essence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
argument is that we need to decide now, instead of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 months from now</TIMEX>, whether
to deploy something that doesn't exist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, won't exist in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 months</TIMEX>, and
probably won't exist until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. This is hardly enough to base a presidential
campaign on.

            There is another reason besides nostalgia why
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> started talking about tax cuts and missile defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
already co-opted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on welfare, family values, the death penalty,
crime, etc. Taxes and missile defense were among the few issues he hadn't
stolen. But now he's the one who's got the tax plan <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> like.
He's the one who has set aside <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> for a missile defense that won't
work. No wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganaut Paul Weyrich</ENAMEX> is urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> to give up
on politics: They can't even out-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan Clinton</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
