
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">update : 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> met in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
to mark the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> birthday. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> noted that this was
supposed to be a party but has turned into a grim strategy meeting, thanks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s main TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and leveled a home
belonging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s spin: "We are
targeting his command and control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>." Everyone else's spin: We're
trying to kill him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> conveyed a proposal from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to allow an
"international presence" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> auspices if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> halts its
bombing and withdraws its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s borders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> rejected the proposal but portrayed it as a sign that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s will is breaking. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> reopened the question of sending
in ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says it's just a contingency plan. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-cynical
spin: They intend to launch a ground war and are just using the "contingency
plan" shtick as cover. The completely cynical spin: It really is just a
contingency plan, showing once again how gutless and unrealistic they are.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/23/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Update on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> high-school massacre : Based on the discovery of a large propane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> planted by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> think they
had accomplices. Meanwhile, several bomb threats and trench coat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pranks</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and elsewhere over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two days</TIMEX> are being treated as
copycat incidents. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editorialists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> continued to debate whether to
blame the massacre on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) secularism and
cultural decline; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4</NUMEX>) inadequate monitoring and counseling of troubled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailants</ENAMEX> were allegedly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> of shock-rocker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>. Click for the 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> and
here
for an analysis of the wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> opportunism that followed a similar slaughter
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/23/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> postponed the destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s last samples of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have the only known samples of
the virus, which was eradicated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> after it had killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. The previous world consensus was that the samples would be
destroyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to make sure <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX> never comes back. The new thinking is
that rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> may already have obtained samples of the virus for developing
a biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should work with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to
develop a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> and to test <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> against the virus. The political
question is what happens if the rest of the world wants the virus destroyed but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> don't. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/23/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The theory
that male homosexuality is genetic suffered a setback . A previous study had
found a specific genetic pattern among gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, but a new study does not find
the same pattern. The most interesting version of the theory is that the gene,
passed along on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> chromosome, makes the bearer attracted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--and that
this trait is supposed to be passed on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> but is sometimes passed on
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>. The author of the old study says the new study is flawed, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> agreed that the new study raises doubts but doesn't necessarily
refute the old one. The conservative spin: This proves homosexuality is a
choice, not a natural condition, so it's OK to stigmatize it. The gay spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homosexuality</ENAMEX> is genetic and therefore natural. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) If it turns out to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genetic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> will just try to eradicate it with gene therapy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
Forget the genetics debate and just treat us equally. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/23/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> found
a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for the missing link between apes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">million-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>, dubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australopithecus</ENAMEX> garhi , evidently used
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> tools to carve up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> it killed and had much bigger teeth than
its apelike ancestors. The theory is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>'s tools enabled it to
augment its diet with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX>, which gave it the nutrition and energy
that eventually allowed it to develop a larger, more human brain and to spread
throughout the world. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/23/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
A government
study concluded that some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX> pulled over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and
searched their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> because they were black or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least 77</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> who were asked by troopers for permission to search their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. The ostensible reason for this racial "profiling" is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> are a conduit for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX> think blacks
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> are more likely to be culprits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> consequence of the study
could be to help black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> get the results of their car
searches thrown out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> as a violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourth Amendment</ENAMEX>. The spins
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) I'm surprised. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) This is awful.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The vast majority of troopers are not racist, and I'm issuing orders that
will stop this practice right away. The reactions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duh</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) This is the way the world is. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Right</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/21/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s 
               government collapsed. The ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">nationalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> lost a no-confidence vote because a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> pulled
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>. Now the opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Party</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Gandhi</ENAMEX>
(former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajiv Gandhi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>), is trying to form a parliamentary
coalition large enough to support a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The early betting is that
this will prove impossible and that new elections will have to be called. The
key questions at stake are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> will become a candidate for prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) whether the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will sign the nuclear test ban treaty;
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> will seek to cool tensions with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> 
               is dumping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Arnett</ENAMEX>. Having kept Arnett
on its payroll but off the air for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> will reportedly use an
escape clause in his contract to get rid of him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. Everyone assumes the
reason is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnett</ENAMEX>'s role as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN Newsstand</ENAMEX>
report that alleged use of lethal nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> had retracted and apologized for the report but let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnett</ENAMEX> stay on the job
after he argued that he had played no substantive role in the report and had
simply performed as an on-air mouthpiece. The pro-Arnett spin: It's unfair to
treat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> this way after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> of loyal service. The anti-Arnett
spin: His reputation has been dead for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, and it's about time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mercifully</ENAMEX> pulled the plug. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Kenyan runner
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Chebet</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Marathon</ENAMEX> . The heartwarming spin: He finally
won the race after finishing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in his last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> marathons. The cranky
spin: Now that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyans</ENAMEX> have won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Marathon</ENAMEX>--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
of them finished among <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>--how about giving some other country
a chance? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatuma Roba</ENAMEX> reinforced the theme of dominance by a
single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, winning the women's marathon for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third straight year</TIMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
