
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">237</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Flawed and Tailored&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               The bombing
campaign--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> so far--is working, says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klaus Naumann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s senior military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. "We will see how they will feel
after a few more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> or what have you of continuously pounding
them into pieces." However, he adds, "We may have one flaw in our thinking."
What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 236</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tragedy Plus Time Minus Taste":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> resumed classes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatfield High</ENAMEX>
School. Many wore white T-shirts imprinted on the front with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Are...</ENAMEX>" and on
the back ... what?
            

            "...
Guaranteed straight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Wade</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            "...
Famous."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Rosetta</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori Hoffman</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "...
Suing."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            "...
Not riding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> for fear of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">misfire</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Holloway</ENAMEX>
(similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ballard</ENAMEX> )

            "Hmm
... that's odd. I could have sworn I had my <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-foot</NUMEX> pole right here
..."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, confused by the question,
replied with slogans for both the front and back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> T-shirt. I
blame the ambiguous use of ellipses. And those damn video games. Violent
movies. The estrangement of too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s life. (Have any
of you phoned him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?) Our failure to embrace a lackluster technical fix
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and his Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX>. The absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> praying in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. (Isn't there some high-tech way to fly him from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to
class, perhaps on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta III</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX>; you know, once it stops
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">malfunctioning</ENAMEX>.) I'll tell you who I don't blame, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>. Or myself. OK, I do
blame myself. I should simply have asked: "What did it say on the back?"
Sorry.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Displeasing</ENAMEX> in content
as well as in form, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s question garnered a record number of responses
scorning the heartlessness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>. It also garnered a record number of
responses, or if not a record, certainly a lot. So, presumably participants
were not as offended as they claimed to be. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boswell</ENAMEX> expressed enormous
sympathy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of an earthquake, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> took him to task for his
showing deep feeling, saying he doubted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boswell</ENAMEX> had even missed a meal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> disdained exaggeration. If anyone wants to discuss this further, I'll
be at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Heston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> hacking around on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playstation</ENAMEX> and giving him a
little talking to. Of course it's his fault.

            
               A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Percent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cotton Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            The front of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-shirts</ENAMEX> says, "We are ..." and the back says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>." Chatfield,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>'s traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, welcomed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> with banners and signs
including, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Are One</ENAMEX>," featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine's</ENAMEX> colors, blue and white, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatfield's</ENAMEX> colors, maroon and white, entwined in a heart.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mom-arama</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Giddily promoting online
shopping for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mothers Day</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> reduces every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> categories of desire,
each linked to shopping opportunities. Which of these are actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo Mother</ENAMEX>'s
Day categories?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Candies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweets</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Beer</ENAMEX> and Cigarettes

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Fashions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inappropriately Erotic Fashions for Mom</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Factory</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faculty Lounge</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> Online

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> off Crack

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Thumb</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Her "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blond" Hair</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incessant Nagging</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leave Me Alone</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leave Me Alone</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leave Me Alone</ENAMEX>!
Oops, sorry.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moms</ENAMEX>-To-Be

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moms</ENAMEX>-To-Beware-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Of</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. Movies and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. Liquor and Porn

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. Music

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Persistent Abrasive Noises</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. Pamper Her

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. Pester Her

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>. Leap out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Closet and Scare the Bejesus</ENAMEX>
out of Her

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>. Perfume

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>. Other Things With
Powerful Odors

            
               Real Yahoo
Mom
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 3, 5, 7, 9</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 15</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 19, 22</TIMEX>

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Heartless online quizzes.

         
      
   
