
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudence
               
               
                  ,
               
            

            
               I cannot agree with your advice to the young
immigrant from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> came to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> when he was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> hasn't done a lot for his accent--though, admittedly, there are rumors
that he cultivates his slow, lumbering delivery.
            

            
               But what if the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had crooked teeth?
Would you advise him to skip orthodontia, telling him "appearances mean nothing
... those who make judgments based on looks and speech are superficial
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Neanderthals?</ENAMEX>" That's a high-minded philosophy, but I'm afraid it may hinder
you in real life.
            

            
               What if this person
wants to study law? Telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that "time will solve all problems" is a
bankrupt idea. My advice to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is to seek help from a speech
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pathologist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX> often do this. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Burton</ENAMEX> wasn't born
speaking the king's <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accent</ENAMEX> is
everything."
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accent</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ax</ENAMEX>,

            Though no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit</ENAMEX> has ever said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accent</ENAMEX> is
everything," she accepts your other arguments. She cannot resist pointing out,
however, that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> has done OK for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who sounds like he is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">growling</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> movie.

            The points you make are more useful than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
earlier oh-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just</NUMEX>-ignore-it approach. Prudie culpa , Prudie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">culpa</ENAMEX> .

            In this particular case,
let's just say when the original advice was given the wheel was spinning, but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hamster</ENAMEX> had gone.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, correctively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudence
               
               
                  ,
               
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX> I must use the laundry
room in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where I'm house-sitting. There is one
thing that I have never figured out about laundry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> etiquette; perhaps you
can clear things up. When a washer or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dryer</ENAMEX> finishes and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> doesn't show
up within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> to collect the clothes, what am I supposed to do if I
am waiting for the machine? Leave it and hope they remember to retrieve it, or
remove the contents and place them on top of the machine or a table?
            

            
               I ask because my
practice has always been to allow <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five minutes</TIMEX> grace, then remove it.
That always seemed fair to me, and I wouldn't expect more of others. However, a
few times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> have arrived while I'm emptying the machine, and they have
been apoplectic! Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> either remove their laundry right away or leave it
for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. Please help.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tired of Waiting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Ti</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> finds your <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> grace period generous.
Putting forgotten laundry--wet or dry--on the machine or a table is perfectly
acceptable in a communal situation.

            The next time you
encounter an apoplectic latecomer, just say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lucky you</ENAMEX>! I don't do this for
everybody." And smile.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, disarmingly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudence
               
               
                  ,
               
            

            
               In a recent column, "" asked for advice about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who lies. Your answer made sense, but I have a curve ball to throw you
in a variation on the same theme: My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, whom I love very much, is prone to
lying. She constantly embellishes her stories and everyday conversation with
nonsensical, made-up whimsy that she expects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to take at face value. When
I occasionally confront her with what I know to be the truth, she gets
defensive and abusive in tone.
            

            
               I am sure this
behavior carries over to her other relationships, as I have discussed this
problem with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who share my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. What must I say
to not only get her to stop lying but also to see the damage she is causing in
her own life?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concerned Brother</ENAMEX>, S.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Con</ENAMEX>,

            Having occasionally confronted your "whimsical"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> with the true version of events, and apparently getting nowhere, Prudie
suggests you have a tough conversation outlining the potential damage
dishonesty can create in relationships with those having less "whimsy."

            Let's be blunt. If your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sis</ENAMEX> is a congenital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, words of warning will have little effect, and you
cannot save her from herself. You don't mention anyone's age, but if you fail
to interest her in therapeutic help, perhaps your sib could try
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">screenwriting</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, honestly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudence
               
               
                  ,
               
            

            
               I am very interested
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who is involved with several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that I fear keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out
due to sex, race, etc. He is quite wonderful, but it is impossible to reconcile
this with the exclusive club business. Who is having the problem here? He
really is so kind and good to me.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scared</ENAMEX> in NYC
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Scare</ENAMEX>,

            You are having the problem, my dear. He is having no
difficulty at all being both a loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and a practitioner of prejudice.
You must weigh your democratic values against the romantic and the personal. If
you can envision a future with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who supports bigotry without it nagging at
your principles, then by all means choose the personal over the political.

            If, however, you see this
cloud becoming blacker over time, then follow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s dictum of "See no evil,
Hear no evil, Date no evil."

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, democratically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudence
               
               
                  ,
               
            

            
               Have you seen those
travel trousers with the zippers at thigh level? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> quick zips and you're
wearing a pair of shorts. Great idea! But there's a problem: I wear only white
socks with shorts and only non-white socks with trousers. Do I have to give up
my custom? What's the answer?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confused</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quito</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Con</ENAMEX>,

            Reversible socks.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
pragmatically

         
      
   
