
   
   
      
         
             Kill and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die for &quot;Credibility&quot</ENAMEX>;?

            At least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> is consistent. When he and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> took over the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, they didn't make much of an
effort to defend the original objectives of the enterprise. Instead, the
emphasis was on "credibility": having got in for whatever reason, wise or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foolish</ENAMEX>, we couldn't just change our minds and get out. In order to preserve
credibility we needed victory, or (as time went on) "peace with honor" or (as
more time went on) a "decent interval" between our withdrawal and the other
side's triumph.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years</TIMEX> on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> and many others are
saying a similar thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Having got in, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> must win or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX>'s credibility--and possibly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> itself--will be destroyed.
But for most who make it, the credibility argument serves a very different
purpose this time. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, it was a last-ditch appeal by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
generally had supported the war for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, the credibility
argument popped up after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five minutes</TIMEX>, and mainly from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who say
they oppose the original decision to get involved--or who avoid saying
precisely where they stand on that basic question. "Credibility," in short,
used to be a cover-up; now it's a cop-out.

            During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, "credibility" did not persuade many
who otherwise opposed the war. As a moral argument it seemed scandalously
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trivial</ENAMEX>, and as a debating point it seemed like moving the goal posts. You no
longer have the stomach to pretend that the mission of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> killing
and dying for freedom for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can succeed, but you want them
to kill and die for credibility? Even geostrategically it seemed wrong: Every
extra day we spent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and treasure on a war we no longer believed in made
subsequent threats to use military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> less credible, not more so.
(And thus, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX> after that war ended, an overnight victory in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grenada</ENAMEX> was hailed, desperately, as the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam Syndrome</ENAMEX>.)

            Credibility is still a
slender reason to kill and die. What would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> say to a grieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>? "Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> died for
credibility." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> have also invoked credibility in answer
to the question of why we fight.

            Perhaps credibility would be worth dying for if it actually
deterred war. That is the argument: If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> believes that you're not only
willing but also certain to use enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to defeat them, you won't
have to start a fight to get your way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, echoes the
arguments over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> when he says that if we don't persevere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
"tyrants in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> will run wild because there's
no one on the block to speak for the values and security that we hold
dear."

            But consider the history
of credibility since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. There have, of course, been occasions when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> let its credibility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, there was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pigs</ENAMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, the fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, the retreat from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> after the bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>. In each
case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and then withdrew after the situation
became intolerable.

            Did these defeats irreparably harm our credibility and
propel would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aggressors</ENAMEX> to believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would never fight?
Perhaps--although I don't remember too many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> saying that the Gipper
had irreparably jeopardized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> security by pulling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX>. (The line between a deft, strategic withdrawal and a collapse of
credibility is in the eye of the beholder.) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> withdrawal from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> didn't prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from using its nuclear deterrent to keep
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yom Kippur war</ENAMEX> later that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            Conversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
wins haven't dissuaded tyrants. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Schwarz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Layne</ENAMEX> have
written: "Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> was not deterred by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> was not deterred by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> action in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel Antonio Noriega</ENAMEX> was not deterred by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ho Chi Minh</ENAMEX> was not deterred by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> action against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Il Sung</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stalin</ENAMEX> were not deterred by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> action
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX>." Tyrants, it seems, act up whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has
been winning or losing.

            Some have argued that because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> represents such a huge
commitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. power</ENAMEX>, it can't be compared to, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pigs</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> made this argument on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> recently.) And
others have said that since this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> operation, it's different--although
the principle is the same whether its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> that are fighting. But
neither of these arguments holds up. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> represented a much larger
commitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> than we see now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> retreated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indochina</ENAMEX>. Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s credibility is said to be at
stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. But who can doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s original mission as a
defensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> would remain strong even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> managed to
prevail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>? Would a crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX> really believe that
he could roll <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> with impunity because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> had failed to wrest
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>'s domination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>?

            It's telling that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">credibilitists</ENAMEX> don't apply their standards to all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Ironically,
there's a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blame America</ENAMEX> First quality to their argument. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cold Warriors</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> hardly argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cuban Missile Crisis</ENAMEX> ended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
credibility. If credibility were such a fragile commodity, we wouldn't have
needed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> buildup after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> blinked during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cuban Missile</ENAMEX>
Crisis, or in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> when they made noises about helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Kippur war</ENAMEX> and then backed down.

            Perhaps the better conceit than credibility is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consistency</ENAMEX> . The consistent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> policy, for instance, of not giving
concessions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> is widely acknowledged to have stymied the once
common hijackings and other acts of terror directed against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. The
consistency of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> policy made the difference. But consider <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>. Today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> maintains only a thin security zone in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern Lebanon</ENAMEX>; deeper in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> guerillas now operate openly in
territory once policed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. But who thinks this retreat has
eroded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> credibility? I doubt military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripoli</ENAMEX>
think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> as softies.

            The difference between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consistency</ENAMEX> and credibility is that consistency implies a reason. You will use
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> to defend some policy or principle. This is inherently more credible than
a commitment to use force for no good reason except that you said you would.
It's more credible because it is more limited and because it's more plausible
that you'll do something if it's something you have a good reason to do,
whether you've said you'll do it or not.

            For example, suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> could establish a consistent
principle that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> will not permit genocide or near-genocidal
ethnic cleansing to take place anywhere they are in a position to stop it
(i.e., there would be no pretense of an obligation to invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> or
far-flung <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>). By discouraging future ethnic slaughters,
that would give an added moral justification to saving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>. That would
be credibility worth fighting for. Unfortunately, most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s credibility
mongers invoke credibility precisely to avoid such a moral commitment.

            Incredible.

         
      
   
