
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=470222513-07051999><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blowhards</ENAMEX> and Blowups</SPAN>

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s beatification by the press. His
oft-recounted experiences in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and well-publicized stances for campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> reform and against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> make him seem noble, rugged, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enlightened</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have ignored his unsavory side, which includes
skirt-chasing and fervent social conservatism ("he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> percent
anti-gay," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>). ... A story gauges the intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heft</ENAMEX> of the presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>. Too-vague <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> touts "lofty ideas but no proposals,"
too-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> hawks "a profusion of proposals that obscure his big goals,"
and too-vague, too-unspecific <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> hasn't shared "either goal or proposal."
... A piece says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> scandal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epitomizes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s dangerous tendency "to substitute
damage control for foreign policy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has brushed off the
charges with the same deft techniques--the dodge, the denial, and the claim of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irrelevancy</ENAMEX>--that characterized its handling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 8</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover editorial, "A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bungled War</ENAMEX>," asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should scrap its initial
goals of establishing autonomy and democracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and settle for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>-style peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is despicable, but his removal would
further destabilize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. ... A story diagnoses what ails the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>:
too much legalism, too little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and the heavy new burden of
monitoring trade issues (such as food regulation and environmental protection)
that were once domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. ... The
magazine lauds a recent crop of video games that emphasize strategy
and good judgment over violent combat. Even though the games are populated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assassins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandos</ENAMEX>, they are not excessively bloodthirsty; one even
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">subtracts</NUMEX> points for gratuitous kills.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story profiles prodigal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ovitz</ENAMEX>. After trying his hand at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, philanthropy, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, and professional sports, he is returning to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinnacle</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> hierarchy through his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists Management Group</ENAMEX>,
which purports to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> more control of their "product." The piece
retreads his feud with his former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creative Artists Agency</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> is
sure to make <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of money and infuriate his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, but there is no
guarantee that this will satisfy his gargantuan appetite for power.
... A piece <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> on his quest to
raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 million</NUMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">2000 convention</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has been tending his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of
money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> all his political life, but his focus on fund raising might
overshadow his campaign message. (Evidence that this is already happening:
articles like this one.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX>
            

            A
profile asks if hedge fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Cramer</ENAMEX> is a financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wizard</ENAMEX> or just an attention-happy blowhard. From a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>: "He really knows
what he's talking about." From an investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>: He's "a very, very good
self-promoter" and "entertainment" only. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> excerpts a new
oral biography of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty Python</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flying Circus</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX> Idle
expresses relief that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX> had "no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> to sulk or feel left
out," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cleese</ENAMEX> admits that they almost called the show Bunn Wackett
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzzard Stubble</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boot</ENAMEX> . ... The cover story lambastes journalists
for pawing through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Robert</ENAMEX>'s personal life, but reveals her shoe size, bra
size, and romantic history anyway.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>
            

            Katha
Pollitt announces her resignation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s masthead, though she will
continue to write her column. She was chagrined at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's recent
publication of a column by conservative education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Unz</ENAMEX> arguing that
liberal education reform has been an unmitigated failure. (See a previous for
details). ... The cover story asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiatt Steele</ENAMEX> is based on unbelievable assertions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>, who
"choreographed" her allegations to make them more "marketable." ... A
piece profiles new for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> specializing in geriatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> and
worries that they will cut services to bolster profits.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARTnews</ENAMEX> ,
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            Yet
another best-of<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> list: the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> most influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
panel makes mostly predictable choices, including sculptor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantin Brancusi</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surrealist Salvador Dalí</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionist Willem de Kooning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Corbusier, Neoplasticist Piet Mondrian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man Ray</ENAMEX>, Impressionist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Monet</ENAMEX>, and "probably the most influential" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX>. The unusual
picks include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Smithson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Judd</ENAMEX>. Surprising omissions: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothko</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Calder</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10</TIMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsweeklies</ENAMEX>' cover packages pander to anxious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> shows
them "the secret life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>," while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> tells them
how to protect Web-surfing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from online perils. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's paranoid
cover package ("it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Flies</ENAMEX> on a vast scale") urges early childhood intervention for difficult toddlers and
"zero tolerance for bullies." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover instructs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to check
the ratings listed on video game boxes, block offensive content on their
computers, and click the "history" button on their browser to see where their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have been. A handy foldout "quality
meter" rates games and Internet sites. (Any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> could predict the
results: educational software gets a "wholesome"; sex and hate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are
"gruesome.") ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX> beseeches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to attend to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>' mental
health ("If we knew a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> had a broken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, we would take that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to an
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.") ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are
already cozying up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of slain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Possible
litigation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Paducah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, have already filed suit against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Basketball Diaries</ENAMEX> , the film said to have inspired the
rampage there.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>,
supported by a network of student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, is winning an Internet propaganda
war. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> argue politely in chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, maintain a sophisticated Web
site, and encourage activism by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> expats. In contrast, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
official says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American anti-Serb</ENAMEX> radio programming reaches "an area the
size of my desk."... A piece explains a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan to revamp <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>,
savvily designed to pre-empt criticism from both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>.
The plan gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> income-tax rebate to be invested in a stock
market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>. At retirement, you choose a payout based on that fund's
performance or on a set of guaranteed benefits. ... In the
cover story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> becomes the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to warn about the declining effectiveness of antibiotics. Some are
prescribed so heavily that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> are growing resistant to them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>,
more susceptible to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microbes</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, are in the most danger.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece describes how the dog <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">genome</ENAMEX> is being combed for clues about human
genetic diseases. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are deliberately inbred, genetic diseases are
easier to isolate and track. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>--aided by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> sleepy
Doberman pinschers--has already targeted the gene for narcolepsy.
... An article profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.S.G. Boggs</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> whose medium
is counterfeited money. Boggs creates exquisite mockups of real bills and
convinces his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> to use them as real cash. He claims to have "spent"
upward of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> in drawn money. He has been exonerated on counterfeiting
charges in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story canonizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Bernall</ENAMEX>, the born-again <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> killed after declaring her faith in God. Her death is called a
divinely ordained act, intended to inspire others to spread the gospel.
... A piece lauds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>
shooting. He has become a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">born-again Hollywood basher</ENAMEX>" and was the only
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to deliver a compelling moral response to the shooting.
... An article reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will
likely fill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> seats. ... An editorial berates congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
"deeply irresponsible" isolationist votes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
