
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cartoon Closet</ENAMEX>

            The reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>'s outing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX>, the purple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubby</ENAMEX>, was widespread
scorn and hilarity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedians</ENAMEX> and column <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> mercilessly ridiculed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> in seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> under the crib.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> comments in
defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, he didn't write the article in question, which
appeared unsigned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Liberty Journal</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> he publishes.
When asked about the charge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> said he had never seen Teletubbies
and didn't know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> was homosexual or not. The notion of
Falwell attacking a cartoon character is too appealing to liberal prejudices to
be easily abandoned.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, if you've ever watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> , you
might well suspect some kind of subliminal messaging. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tubbies</ENAMEX> have
aerials coming out of their spacesuit hoods, which receive programming that's
broadcast on TV screens in their tummies. As they prance out of their bunker
and around the strange, apocalyptic landscape where they live, periscope
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> pop out of the ground and feed them orders. It's both cute and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">creepy</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty College</ENAMEX> apparently got their idea about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> not from watching
the program but from reading such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> . On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> included "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TINKY WINKY</ENAMEX>, THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAY</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TELETUBBY</ENAMEX>" in its annual list of what's "in" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the New Year</TIMEX>. No one got
excited. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , then mocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reactionary hick</ENAMEX> obsessed with the sexuality of puppets. Seems like a bit of a
trap.

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> gay? He is not the first cartoon character
to be outed. More often than not it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> who claim a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> as one
of their own--which also puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> fuss in perspective. At the level of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX>' stated intentions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> have no sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orientation</ENAMEX>. The program tries to recreate the world of toddlers, which does
not involve any level of sexual understanding. But TV programs are group
products, and it's not impossible that references--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX>'s handbag, his
purple triangle antenna, and the tutu he sometimes wears--are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of code
included for the benefit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> has a bit more spring in his
step than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dipsy</ENAMEX>, the other male tubby, it may be because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who
originally inhabited his costume added that dimension. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gays</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX>, and some protested outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who played him
was fired.

            Sexual signals can be
received without being consciously sent. The first cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> to be
accused of aberrant sexual practices were <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX>. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> book
titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seduction of the Innocent</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Wertham</ENAMEX>
attacked the sadistic violence and sexual deviance portrayed in comic books.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX>, he noted, were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> living together who liked to wear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capes</ENAMEX> and tights. Back home at stately <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne Manor</ENAMEX>, they lounged about in
dressing gowns. Wertham was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX> who discovered a message that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>, probably never consciously intended. But that
doesn't mean it wasn't there.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wertham</ENAMEX>'s book led to the adoption of a code of standards
by the comic book industry, which included, among other things, an admonition
that "sex perversion or any inference to same is strictly forbidden." After
this history, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> TV series, which was made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-to-late</TIMEX>
1960s, couldn't plead the same innocence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Wertham</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> were well
aware of the gay take on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX>. Rather than resist it, they gave a
camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX> to the whole series. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, even most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult viewers</ENAMEX>
interpreted the program as broad parody. But once the idea of a gay subtext has
been planted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louie</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilac</ENAMEX> (as played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton Berle</ENAMEX>) isn't just a villain
who likes to wear purple.

            In a curious way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>,
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> have all collaborated in destroying the sexual
innocence of cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> by making an issue out of it. When trying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">elude Elmer Fudd</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yosemite Sam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX> is liable to dress up as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vamp</ENAMEX> around, or imitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Hepburn</ENAMEX>. Is this meant to indicate that he
likes other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> bunnies? Many of these antics were borrowed from vaudeville
comedy, where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> dressing up as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> didn't necessarily imply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> (although the same questions arise in retrospect). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bros.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, where these cartoons were created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and '50s</TIMEX>, was an
aggressively heterosexual milieu. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Jones</ENAMEX> and other illustrators were
mocking stereotyped homosexual behavior, not winking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> in a
friendly way. But while a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> dressing up as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> may not have "meant"
anything in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>, it does mean something in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX>. What has
sexualized these cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> is the change in the culture, which in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few decades</TIMEX> has become not just aware of homosexuality but increasingly
open about and tolerant of it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert</ENAMEX> are another good example of this process.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>, no one meant for them
to be taken as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>. But consider <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> living together, sleeping in the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and taking great interest in each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX>. Predictably, the
"urban legend" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert</ENAMEX> were gay began to spread. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Chambers</ENAMEX> tried to get them banned under an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> anti-sodomy law. (He said they had "blatantly effeminate
characteristics.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Television Workshop</ENAMEX> eventually had to deny
the rumors, which have included an impending same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. But the gay read
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert</ENAMEX> isn't wrong because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> don't endorse it. The same
goes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peppermint Patty</ENAMEX> and her tomboy friend
Marcie, who always refers to her as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sir</ENAMEX>." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles M. Schulz</ENAMEX> created the
strip, he never imagined that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcie</ENAMEX> would be claimed as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protolesbians</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s entertainment has contained an increasing number of apparently
intentional or even obviously intentional gay references. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Lion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simba</ENAMEX> leaves home and is more or less adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pumbaa</ENAMEX>, a
male meerkat and a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warthog</ENAMEX> who live together as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in the jungle. In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> film, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Lane</ENAMEX> supplied the voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timon</ENAMEX> in much
the same style as his flamboyantly gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Birdcage</ENAMEX> . When I
saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> version of the musical, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> roared at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timon</ENAMEX>'s even
more exaggerated gay mannerisms.

            Or consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pee-wee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playhouse</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pee-wee Herman</ENAMEX>
minces about and becomes obviously infatuated with other male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who
conform to gay archetypes. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> may pick up this gay semaphore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
aren't likely to. To them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timon, Pumbaa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pee-wee</ENAMEX> are just goofy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>.

            Elsewhere, the implicit
has become explicit. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Simpsons , Smithers</ENAMEX>, the bow tie wearing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toady</ENAMEX> who trails around after Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>, has become increasingly gay. According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Doyle</ENAMEX>, who writes for the show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smithers</ENAMEX> was originally just a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sycophant</ENAMEX> in love with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>. But lately he has taken to cruising college
campuses in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miata</ENAMEX>, looking for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s episode, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Apu</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">store owner</ENAMEX>, goes down to the docks to donate porno
magazines to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>. The sea <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> calls out to thank him: "Thank you for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jugs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. They'll keep my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from resorting to homosexuality
... for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 minutes</TIMEX>!" The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> all laugh, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> calls out, "Look
who's talking!"

            It isn't absurd for anyone, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>, to notice
these hints, inferences, and references. But it is ridiculous to object to
them. There's no scientific or psychological basis for believing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
are affected in their sexual development or eventual sexual orientation by
exposure to homosexuality--on television or in real life. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of
cartoons are intentionally or unintentionally giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the idea that gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are part of the big, happy human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, that's a good thing, not a bad
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. (If it weren't for gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, there would be no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion King</ENAMEX> --or much
else on the all-American cultural front.) The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> about
recruiting, which leads them to think that gay school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> present a hazard to the young is pure prejudice.

            Anyway, for the religious right, this battle is
pointless because the war is already lost. Gay themes are everywhere.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pee-wee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playhouse</ENAMEX> runs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Family Channel</ENAMEX>, the cable
network <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX> recently sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>. It's just a couple of
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The 700 Club</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
