
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> : A film with half a
plot, no engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> to speak of, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> who speak in
inhibited-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zombie monotones</ENAMEX> as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> had warned them to keep quiet
while someone on the set took a nap. A film that introduces the noxious sci-fi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creature Jar Jar Binks</ENAMEX>, whose bug eyes, lazy shuffle, and minstrelly speech
suggest an alien <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stepin Fetchit</ENAMEX>. A dull and annoying and occasionally rather
offensive film, in other words. Yet here was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' lead
reviewer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, almost alone among major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in showering praise:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t sustains the gee-whiz spirit of the series and offers a swashbuckling
extragalactic getaway ... jubilant ingenuity ... sweetly, unfashionably benign
... no better tour guide for a trip back to the future."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> did acknowledge,
in passing, the film's ethnic stereotypes, the overstuffed plot, Ewan
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGregor</ENAMEX>'s blandness, the foolish spectacle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> acting opposite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">robots</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Portman</ENAMEX>'s resemblance to a costumed block of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>. But in
her inimitable way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> folds all these complaints into an overall rave. It
was a bad piece, and a telling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maslin</ENAMEX> has stood out
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> for being what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, those curmudgeons, so rarely are: She is
upbeat and forgiving, often to a fault. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Mercer song instructs</ENAMEX>,
she accentuates the positive and eliminates the negative. Or, as in the case of
the latest Star Wars episode, she buries her list of negatives so late
in the piece that it barely registers. This habit of combining compensatory
praise with dismissals makes it difficult to know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> actually thinks.
(Her pan of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest Gump</ENAMEX> , for example, was dead-on and brave in its
criticism but also packed to the gills with compliments.)

            The question (not burning, perhaps--except for the poor
dupes who suffered through the charmless <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Phantom</ENAMEX> because the
Times recommended it) is how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maslin</ENAMEX> comes by this generosity. The
paranoid explanation is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s growing dependence on movie ads
compels her, in some oblique and unconscious way, to be an industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">booster</ENAMEX>. Or
it could be that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> is a little too well connected for a film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, as
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> have charged, and afraid to hurt her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>' feelings. Or
maybe she is just, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know her tend to comment, exceptionally
nice.

            The question grows more
curious when you look back at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>'s career and realize that she once had a
strong voice. She started off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> writing about rock 'n' roll for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> and especially for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston Phoenix</ENAMEX> . At the time,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> and the now-defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Paper</ENAMEX> were at the epicenter
of alternative journalism--a training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who
would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> to big city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> and the slicks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> passed through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix / Real Paper</ENAMEX> scene, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Denby, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, film critic
turned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair / New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">profiler</ENAMEX> turned Lolita
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screenwriter Stephen Schiff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wonk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, and

                  Slate
               's own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>, to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a few</NUMEX>.

            It's unfair but true that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who started out at such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and place, in such an atmosphere of heady debate, pot, scant female and
plenty of male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>--such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> will inevitably be noticed and talked
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. So let's get the gossip out of the way: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maslin</ENAMEX> was attractive; early on
she dated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>; she got married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Landau</ENAMEX>, a fellow rock critic
who attended a small concert by a dynamic young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and wrote a
famously prescient piece announcing, "I saw rock and roll future last night,
and its name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX>," and eventually quit his writing job to
manage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Cheever</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheever</ENAMEX> and also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>.

            What's interesting here
isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>'s personal life but the fact that her youthful writing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, say, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Costello</ENAMEX> carries more conviction, and therefore more
weight, than her mature work on the movies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> had a voice: As gung-ho as
she is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but more deeply felt, more confident while still refreshingly free
of the insider smugness of so much writing on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>. But, for some reason, when
she migrated from music to movies, first for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> , then briefly
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , she seems gradually
to have inched away from her personal reactions. The pattern was set long
before she became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988 Sunday</TIMEX> "think
piece" on a rash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglophilic</ENAMEX> "white flannel" costume dramas was typical. For
much of the piece <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maslin</ENAMEX> seemed to criticize the way films like A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Handful</ENAMEX> of
Dust distorted the novels they set out to adapt, the way they reeked of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snobbery</ENAMEX> and voyeurism, the way they substituted rarified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Lauren</ENAMEX> décors
for content. Then she turned her argument upside down, praising a trifle called
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summer Story</ENAMEX> precisely because of its cynical, empty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decorativeness</ENAMEX>.

            To read a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> piece can be a disconcerting, at times
even haunting experience. One senses her scrambling to fill the piece with
everything but her own analysis. More often than not she leads with a lengthy,
detailed visual description of a scene or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. For paragraphs at a time
she leans on plot summary of the timid undergraduate-book-report variety. She
relies heavily--very heavily--on adverbs, which serve to pepper her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noncommittal</ENAMEX> reviews with small emphatic bursts and to jack up her celebrations
(from a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">565</NUMEX>-word review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Goldmine</ENAMEX> : "dazzlingly surreal,"
"brilliantly reimagines," "spectacularly reborn," "dramatically presided,"
"stunningly pretty," "fabulously charismatic," "hilariously decadent,"
"typically wicked").

            When she does give the
thumbs up, especially for an anticipated blockbuster, certain key words and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phrases</ENAMEX>, such as "audience appeal" and "escapist fun," suggest that she is not
writing from her own point of view so much as she's gauging in advance the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>'s reaction. The lead to her review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twister</ENAMEX> called the film "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gale</ENAMEX>-force movie with the energy to blow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> right out of the theater."
This sounds more like publicity copy than criticism; what it expresses is the
impression the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> hopes the film will have on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            To be fair, there is much to be said in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maslin</ENAMEX>'s defense.
She is hardly the first good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to be slightly stifled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
nor, by any means, is she the first frustrating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> to work there. On the
contrary: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Canby</ENAMEX> wrote from high atop a pedestal, panned The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Godfather Part II</ENAMEX> , and indulged in an inexplicable love of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake Edwards</ENAMEX>.
Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canby, Bosley Crowther</ENAMEX> ruled the roost for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>. He wielded
immense power, but who recalls a single thing he wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, especially
compared with the memorable work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Agee</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sarris</ENAMEX> or, above all,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX>?

            And these are tough times for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> in general.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> has expressed the disappointment of a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who
entered the field during the feverish, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kael</ENAMEX>-inspired '70s: Once upon a time
they wanted to grab <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> by the hand and lead them to passionate works of
art, but no one would aim so high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> movies are fewer and farther
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX> (at least in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s opinion--at least for the time being), and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that employ the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> measure a movie's success not
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' reaction but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">opening weekend</TIMEX> gross. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> just don't
matter as much as they used to, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>--though she's still at the top of
the heap, influence-wise--is no exception. Very much to her credit, she hasn't
become bitter about her shrinking influence; she's not stuck in whiny nostalgia
for the way things were. But she has developed a disembodied, ghostly way of
writing about movies--a criticism of lowered expectations. Her main defense of
the disappointing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> ? It's "only a movie." Exactly--and
while we're at it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> is only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> who asks for too little.

         
      
   
