
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugo Home</ENAMEX> 

            Ever since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> began contemplating doing something about war and ethnic cleansing in
the collapsing state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, all sides have invoked history as a
guide to action. Those who opposed involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>--and
who doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> can bring peace to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--argue that the long record
of intractable ethnic tension among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Balkan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> means we should stay
out. Any settlement, they say, is doomed to be temporary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kaplan</ENAMEX>'s book
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balkan Ghosts</ENAMEX> , which advances this thesis regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, reportedly
convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to steer clear of military action there for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interventionists</ENAMEX> also
invoke history. They note the longstanding claim of ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> to the
territory of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> dating back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>' supposed
ancestors, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illyrians</ENAMEX>, settled there. This ancient history forms the basis
of demands for self-determination on the part of the long-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, too, stake a historical claim. Their Slavic forebears
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migrated</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A.D. 500</ENAMEX>, and they contend that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have lived
there ever since.

            In fact, each of these assertions is subject to
qualification, as is made clear in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel Malcolm</ENAMEX>'s masterly (but misnamed)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>: A Short History (my main source along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Poulton</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minorities and States</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conflict</ENAMEX> ). The tie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> to the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Illyrians</ENAMEX> is fairly attenuated. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavs</ENAMEX> did
move into the area around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bulgarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> conquered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> didn't gain control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12 th century</TIMEX>, when
a dynasty of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nemanjids</ENAMEX> invaded it after a period of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> rule.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX> the
Nemanjids basked in their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Balkan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are fond of
noting that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1389</TIMEX> it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazar</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">armies</ENAMEX> made their last stand against the invading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman Empire</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. They're less likely to note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> fought
alongside them. (Explicit references to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as opposed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illyrians</ENAMEX> begin to appear around the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 th century</TIMEX>.)

            During <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500-year</TIMEX> rule, most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>--converted to Islam. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> remained <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Christians</ENAMEX>. That may be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> sought independence <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1804</TIMEX> they rose up and
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1828</TIMEX> broke free. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, however, remained largely content under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbs</ENAMEX>, believing that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> still rightfully belonged to them, did
briefly conquer it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1877</TIMEX> when, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> state made
war on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>. But under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> armistice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> was
forced to withdraw.

            At this point, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>--of both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> proper--commenced their so-called
"national awakening." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Prizren</ENAMEX>, named for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where it met, lobbied for autonomy within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman Empire</ENAMEX>. A
generation later, this movement flowered into insurrection, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>
throughout the western pocket of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> revolted. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> secured
statehood in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>, but before the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> could be resolved, the
entire region was rocked, in quick succession by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Balkan War</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>),
the Second <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Balkan War</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>) and, for good measure, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914-18</TIMEX>).

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> to invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> were knocked out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austrians</ENAMEX>, who were knocked out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> handed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> back to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. After the war,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX>, following Wilsonian ideals of self-determination, straightened up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> into tidy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. With minimal thought on the part of the
mapmakers, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> was folded into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>, which joined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkan</ENAMEX>
territories to form the new state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albania</ENAMEX> appealed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allies</ENAMEX>
for control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> but, considered an insignificant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, was rebuffed in
deference to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> claims.

            As the largest republic
in the multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Its capital of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, for example, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital too. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
again became a battleground. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19 th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalists</ENAMEX> had built up national myths about the heroics of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazar</ENAMEX> and
cast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s status as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>-like holy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> populated with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX>
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s and '30s</TIMEX>, the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belgrade</ENAMEX> pushed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> out of the region and moved <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in--efforts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> resisted, often to their peril.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> again resembled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Station</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Axis</ENAMEX> powers rolled in and carved up the region: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>'s
Fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, headed by a puppet of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>'s, seized the biggest
chunk, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> each occupied a strip. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX>
retook the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>, and when the war ended, the partisan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Broz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> of the reconstituted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">federation</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Communists</ENAMEX> considered ceding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> but instead decided that it
should revert to its antebellum status quo. They deemed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> not an
autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> but a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>.

            In the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> unity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> suppressed most
assertions of ethnic identity. He jailed or killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> and banned <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. But he was, to some degree,
an equal opportunity tyrant: He also halted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> efforts to settle <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, with uprisings sweeping the globe, student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> triggered a wave
of demands for greater <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> autonomy. Tito acceded to a series of reforms,
culminating in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, which gave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> control
over much of its internal affairs. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That year</TIMEX> marked the high point for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX>
aspirations to independence, and it remains the benchmark for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s demand at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX> for a restoration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s "pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>" autonomy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> erupted again, with some Kosovars
clamoring for republichood. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, no longer restrained by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX>'s aversion
to exacerbating ethnic conflict, cracked down. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polarization</ENAMEX> followed: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>--first as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> and then as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> nationalist--whipped up
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> sentiment. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, he stripped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> of its cherished autonomy.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX> proclaimed their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> a republic and, through
channels violent and nonviolent, sought actual independence. Unrelenting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> undertook the massacres of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, which finally precipitated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing.

            That, in a nutshell, is the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. If you can
find a solution to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s mess in there, let me know. Take a snapshot at 1200
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> can claim it; look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.D.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> and it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">kingdom</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> prefers to use the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> benchmark. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> points
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. But even at those points, the snapshot looks pretty blurry.

            Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> began bombing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>, the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX> solution--restoring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s
autonomy but not granting it independence--seemed like a plausible outcome. Now
it's hard to imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovars</ENAMEX> accepting any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> rule. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">victorious</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> may grant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> independence or perhaps divide it up. History
won't decide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s fate. Our actions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weeks ahead</TIMEX> will decide
history.

             

         
      
   
