
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East Stew</ENAMEX>

            A rebuff to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>'s Crown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdallah</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was heralded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> as evidence that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> wasn't a pawn or a puppet of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Abderrahman
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Rashed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Awsat</ENAMEX> , wrote
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> apparent's rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s attempt to get him to meet
secretly with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX> ("Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, I think friendship
has limits")--news of which broke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in the same paper--was a cause for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX> pride. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thought that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> could be "bought,"
or coaxed, or intimidated, he wrote. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> policies could not be bought,
since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riyadh</ENAMEX> was not indebted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. "The friendship between the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> is strong indeed. But there's no reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> should
abandon its commitments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX>, as well as
to its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, just to please the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," Rashed
concluded.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turki al-Hamad</ENAMEX>, another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX> incident confounded those
who believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> was just another pawn on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s chessboard
and therefore had probably already established secret links with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. He
wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown prince</ENAMEX>, the effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, could have
met secretly with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asked, and struck deals with
them behind closed doors, subsequently to denounce <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in the strongest
terms, as many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> did. But he has consistently applied the principle
of "transparency" and candor, believing this to be the best guarantee of sound
policy. "His rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposal is consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>'s
policy of not officially recognizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process
has reached a successful conclusion, at which point <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riyadh</ENAMEX> will make the
appropriate decision," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamad</ENAMEX> added. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> has already said all these
things. So what would have been the point of a secret meeting? That is
undoubtedly what Crown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdallah</ENAMEX> had in mind when he turned down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s proposal."

            A l-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khaleej</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Arab Emirates</ENAMEX>,
claimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> capture its most wanted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX>, in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> abandoning its
policy of rapprochement with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Commentator Mohammed Idriss</ENAMEX> wrote in the
paper that the betrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> had been preceded by another betrayal--that
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Aziz</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aziz</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> at the invitation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulent Ecevit</ENAMEX> to discuss closer economic
ties and the problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatism</ENAMEX>, which both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> feel is being
fueled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' "mismanagement" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> crisis.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> also saw the visit as an opportunity to
persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> to withdraw logistical support for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> bombing raids on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and to speed up the erosion of international sanctions against it. Yet,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aziz</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleyman Demirel</ENAMEX> bluntly refused to meet
him, and he found himself boycotted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. The
explanation for this had to be collusion between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> services, both of them highly active in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, to deliver Ocalan
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idriss</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>
must have been put under "enormous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> pressure" to have agreed to be involved
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s abduction. "And for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to be prepared to exert so much
pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s behalf, the price must have been worthwhile," he
added. "At this juncture in particular, what better price could there have been
than sabotaging any attempt to effect an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> rapprochement<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Quds</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Arabi</ENAMEX> also saw the delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> as its "reward" for
toeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahrain</ENAMEX>, the daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Ayyam</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s abduction boded ill for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He, too, had the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> of several
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>.

            Without directly addressing the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
involvement in the abduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>, the moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the affair had shown "the narrow and very
dangerous line that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> walks in its ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>." It said there was
"no doubt that the military alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> is one of the most important
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has ever signed with any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>" and that "[t]his type of alliance
inherently involves targeting common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, or at least fosters the
expectation that an agreed-upon map of common threats and dangers be drawn up.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> question has naturally found its way onto this map of common
interests." But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has always had very good relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>, who
also see the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. "Consequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> must make a very
sharp distinction between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s war with what it defines as a terrorist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, and its ideological and cultural struggle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," the editorial concluded. "In the aftermath of the tragic incident in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, this distinction must now be expressed openly and publicly in such a
manner to make it clear to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> that we are still their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers,
which see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s human rights record as a serious impediment to its ambition
to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, reacted with outrage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to a photograph issued
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX> blindfolded and manacled in front of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> flag. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa</ENAMEX> , in a front-page comment, called it "a punch in the stomach,"
comparing it to other sadly unforgettable photos such as those of the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guevara</ENAMEX>, the napalm-burnt little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>, and the
despairing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldo Moro</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Brigades</ENAMEX>.
The difference in this case, though, was that the photo was "propaganda
material of a government which calls itself democratic, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of our
times," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

             

         
      
   
