
   
   
      
         
            Learn <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics While You Drive</ENAMEX>

            If you want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>--and who
doesn't, really?--you need "a core set of principles," "a core set of beliefs,"
"a core vision," and "fire in the belly." You must "be true to yourself," "show
that you care," and treat every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> like "a precious soul." And don't forget
to involve yourself with a high-profile cause before you announce your
candidacy--it'll really help your fund raising.

            I know all this because I have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">listening to Prepare To Win</ENAMEX> , a program of audiotapes and accompanying
"workbooks" (I'm not kidding) from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, etc.), and advice on everything
from fund raising to hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to wooing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> is distributing
Prepare To Win to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of potential <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. Would-be candidates
are supposed to listen while they sleep, eat, or drive. (Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX> urging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to listen "over and over again" to the tapes.
[.]) It was inevitable that self-improvement culture, which has infected every
other aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life, would eventually contaminate politics. At last
it has.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are all well-coiffed, well-spoken, well-dressed, and
well-prepped, makes it easy to forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are made, not born. For
every <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> who springs from his mother's womb wearing a blue suit and
speaking in sound bites, there are scores of awkward, ambitious Rotarians
needing guidance. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of yore, aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> learned their trade by sitting
in the party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubhouse</ENAMEX>. But political education has become alarmingly
sophisticated since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOPAC</ENAMEX> began mailing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of strategy tapes to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> now
offer seminars training <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> how to run. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prepare To Win</ENAMEX> marks
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">either party</ENAMEX> has tried to educate prospective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOPAC</ENAMEX>'s tapes, which mix strategy with red-meat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prepare To Win</ENAMEX> is pure process. It mostly ignores <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
positions and concentrates on campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speakers</ENAMEX> urge you to pay
attention to filing deadlines, hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, form a kitchen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
who can rein you in if the campaign unhinges you, court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community leaders</ENAMEX> and
seek their endorsement before you announce, choreograph your
announcement to maximize media coverage, etc. It's all sensible
enough--especially the presentation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Collins</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>--but it's
thunderingly obvious. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX>, I began to ask myself: How dumb
does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> think I am? Listen, for example, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dendahl</ENAMEX>'s leaden account of how to use humor in your campaign.
(.)

            The workbooks exacerbate
this condescending simple-mindedness. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> written questions that accompany
each speech are of the sort I haven't seen since <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>-grade reading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comprehension</ENAMEX>: "How [according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Dunn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>] do you
become an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initiator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Innovator</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX>?" "What did [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ileana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ros-Lehtinen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>] learn as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl scout leader</ENAMEX>?" Answer: Be
prepared.

            At heart, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prepare To Win</ENAMEX> is neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commonsensical</ENAMEX> nor condescending. It is deeply--so deeply that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>
aren't even aware of it--cynical. The superficial premise is that politics is
about harnessing your beliefs, your honesty, and your caring heart for the
common good. The political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> dispensing advice genuinely seem to be
preaching idealism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> insists that your campaign
must be founded on your "core principles" (beliefs, vision, whatever. My
favorite workbook question is: "What are your core principles<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" If you have to
ask ...). The tapes overflow with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polonius</ENAMEX> platitudes: "Be true to yourself";
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> don't care what you know till they know that you care." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
Brownback of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> repeatedly insists that you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as "precious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>,"
not as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>.

            But it's odd to be
celebrating "precious souls" on a tape series designed to teach candidates
exactly how to wring money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> and seduce skeptical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> . While saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> should be true to themselves, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> spend the bulk of their time detailing how campaigns are artifice and
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> must learn to manipulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, images, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>.

            This fundamental cynicism reveals itself in countless small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. Here, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty Paul</ENAMEX> instructs how to
make a candidacy announcement "political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> as the
"main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>." (.)

            The otherwise admirable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> counsels <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> to embrace a cause before they become
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, but not because the cause itself matters: The cause is a great way
to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor base</ENAMEX>. Listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> as she gives cheerful,
happy-talk advice about how to use anecdotes to show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that you care about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and not just policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>, she notes, "are much more responsive to a
strong positive message than they are to attacks." Then, in her final sentence,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn</ENAMEX> offers her real advice: "Leave those attacks for the advertising
campaign." (.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Overwhelmingly</ENAMEX>, I had the sense that my
Prepare To Win <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> had no idea how cynical they sound. Nowhere
is this more apparent than in the presentation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kit Bond</ENAMEX>, a folksy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missourian</ENAMEX>. In this clip (), Bond details his fund-raising philosophy. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proudly</ENAMEX> describes how, during his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> congressional campaign, he refused a
large contribution from someone who wanted him to change his position on an
issue:

            
               At that moment I made the decision that I
am running this campaign. I am not going to be told by any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX> that I
should take a stand they want me to solely because they would give me money for
it. I told 'em, "no thanks." If they want to support me in the objectives I
have outlined, that's fine, but I don't take positions or make votes in
response to offers of contributions.
            

            Bond says this as though recounting some remarkable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>. In fact, what his grand principle amounts to is: no vote for cash.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> does not take bribes! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prepare To Win</ENAMEX> is this passage writ
large. Beneath its pious talk of visions and core beliefs, it is teaching a
lesson about politics that is much shabbier and much more real than the one it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretends</ENAMEX> to teach.

         
      
   
