
   
   
      
         
             Advise and Consent (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Also Obstruct</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delay</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stymie</ENAMEX>)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five months ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Sentencing Commission achieved something remarkable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Conaboy</ENAMEX>
resigned, leaving the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> with exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Since
then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has nominated no one to fill the empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX>. The
commission still has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 million</NUMEX> to spend, and no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> at all over federal sentencing policy.

            Nor has the president
nominated anyone to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sasser</ENAMEX>, who returns home in
May. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX> gray
eminences, including former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hamilton</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">National Security Adviser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lake</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Shalikashvili</ENAMEX>,
have turned down the job. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> did manage to send the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s nomination as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> after the
previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegate</ENAMEX> left and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> announced he would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominate Holbrooke</ENAMEX>. Not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> will be taking office any time soon:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, refuses to schedule a confirmation hearing for him
till the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> agrees to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> reform package.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>, at least, will get a hearing someday. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> again nominated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> as assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
general for civil rights, a nomination the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has refused to consider for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, says
he won't hold any hearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s nomination.

            The appointments process
is a perennial source of indignation for goo-goos. Even so, it seems
particularly grim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. There are different explanations for the various
holdups above--the sentencing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> is empty because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> failed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to compromise on a slate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s nomination was delayed by an almost-but-not-entirely meritless
ethics charge; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> job is difficult to fill because no one wants to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">defend Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, etc.--but together they
suggest a process that is astonishingly screwed up.

            The time it takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> to confirm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> has soared
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>: On average, it took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight and a half</TIMEX> months
to confirm his initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX>, up from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> and
less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>. According to ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Leahy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>, it now takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 260 days</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
to confirm a federal judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>, up from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">183 days</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 86</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> waited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than three years</TIMEX> for confirmation. It takes
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight to 10 months</TIMEX> for the average ambassadorial nomination to be approved. The
administration is overflowing with unconfirmed "acting" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
survey found that "acting" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> hold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX> of jobs reserved for
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX>.

            Some of this mess is to be expected. Filling
positions is always a hassle during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last years</TIMEX> of a two-term presidency: No
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> wants to chuck a good career for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame-duck</ENAMEX> job. And a divided government
inevitably slows confirmations: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> are more skeptical of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are.

            But the screwiness of
the process runs deeper, and almost everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> deserves a share of
the blame. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, especially early in his term, has taken endless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to
nominate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for critical executive branch and judicial openings. The
confirmation process has become massively politicized. "Elections no longer
settle anything," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colby College Professor G. Calvin Mackenzie</ENAMEX>, the leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> on the appointments process. "What used to be the norm--that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wins the election and appoints his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--is no longer. Now the
losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> continues to fight through the appointments process."

            All <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cabinet-level</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> are now fair game for a
confirmation challenge. The deference the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> used to grant sub-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> is vanishing, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> have increasingly deployed secret "holds"
to delay confirmations, often for reasons having nothing to do with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>'s
qualifications. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>, for example, held up numerous ambassadorial appointments
to pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to reorganize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>. Committee chairs also
refuse to schedule confirmation hearings: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> (again) derailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX>'s
nomination as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> by refusing to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> testify. The
confirmation process is "nasty and brutish without being short," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> quipped after his nomination as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> went down in flames.

            The number of
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> has multiplied--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, there are more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times as many as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s time--making it difficult for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to find time to consider everyone. Cumbersome ethics rules have made
simply accepting a nomination onerous: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Shalala</ENAMEX> had to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> just to complete her financial
disclosure forms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nominees</ENAMEX> usually have to give up their lucrative law
practices and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> as they await confirmation, a sacrifice that leaves
them without income for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            It was not always this way. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
was deferential to the (many fewer) presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>. It did much more
consenting than advising. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Fortas</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> nomination as chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> delayed to death, marked the first sign of
change, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> nomination truly ushered in the
era of appointments warfare. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>, partisan interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grandstanding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have freely challenged even obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>.

            You can make a case that
the appointments mess is more aesthetic than substantive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, after
all, is apparently nearing a compromise on the sentencing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will likely nominate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> nomination may be iced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> for a bit longer, but everyone
agrees that he will be confirmed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> will find a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> has already been serving as acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant attorney general</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> refuses to hold a confirmation hearing, he will continue
in that acting job till the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency. These are the
exceptions: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> are confirmed smoothly. And whether or not all the
right jobs are filled with exactly the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> still
manages to negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, the civil rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX> still manages to file cases, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> still manage to impose
sentences.

            But the rising obstructionism does damage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX>, who are elected to remake executive policy, find themselves
hamstrung. Career civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> act in place of unconfirmed presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX>. The career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are unwilling and unable to impose the policy
changes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> may want. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> often skirts the law by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appointing</ENAMEX> "acting" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who "act" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>), depriving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> of its constitutional right to approve appointments. The eternal
shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> means that some cases are adjudicated peremptorily. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--and this has been especially true of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--frequently nominates
the least offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> rather than the most qualified in order to pacify
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The endless obstacles to confirmation deter the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>:
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mackenzie</ENAMEX>, the presidential personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> must frequently offer
a job to its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> choice because the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> don't want to
endure the inconvenience.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">goo-goos</ENAMEX> would cut the number of presidential
appointments by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> or more, lessening the burden on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and
allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to pick better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. They would eliminate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senatorial</ENAMEX> holds. They would simplify background investigations and financial
disclosures. These are promising and admirable ideas--modest solutions to a
modest problem. Appointment and confirmation is a political process, and like
any political process it will always be messy. But it doesn't have to be
this messy.

         
      
   
