
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost</ENAMEX>
            

            Scholarly opinion is
mixed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> . In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed piece
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Greenblatt</ENAMEX> inveighed against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s historical infelicities, errors that he attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cowardice</ENAMEX>. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Norman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX> made Gwyneth
Paltrow the inspiration for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>'s love-struck "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shall I Compare Thee to a Summer's Day?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historians</ENAMEX>, Greenblatt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scolded</ENAMEX>, know that the sonnet, like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> others, was in all likelihood written
to a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. "How is it that a miserably undemocratic, unenlightened culture
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">400 years ago</TIMEX> could be more tolerant of expressions of same-sex love, or the
appearance of it, than our own?" he wondered. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenblatt</ENAMEX> isn't against all
forms of poetic license, though--just those that strike him as politically
incorrect. He writes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> he tried to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> to
devise a screenplay about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s relationship with the homosexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Marlowe</ENAMEX>, whose murder in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tavern</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1593</TIMEX> forms a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subplot</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> . Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> are gentler on the film.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , the usually grumpy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX> called it "charming";
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clemson University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Andreas</ENAMEX> enthused, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> was a pop phenomenon
in his own age. Now, thanks to our modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, he's becoming the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of
pop he always was."

            
               Mass
Appeal
            

            According to recent
reports in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>-led
crackdown on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> is advancing. Among
the most controversial of a plate of new proposals from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
bishops: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> approval of theology department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX>, majority quotas of
"faithful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>" for faculties and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trustee boards</ENAMEX>, and professions of faith
and fidelity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on the part of university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>
has no formal means of enforcing the standards. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s nominally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Fordham University</ENAMEX>--where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX>
is optional and the chair of the theology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> isn't even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>--are
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Universities</ENAMEX> are trying to satisfy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> but
preserve academic freedom, student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> diversity, and teaching quality.

            
               Don't Look
Bakke
            

            The anti-affirmative
action movement is urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to sue their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Determined to abolish
race preferences in higher education, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Individual</ENAMEX>
Rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, is funding a provocative ad campaign telling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that academic affirmative action policies "violate the law." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> successfully used this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was misreading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bakke</ENAMEX> decision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> is currently going after the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heinous</ENAMEX>!
            

            So dismayed are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> at the poor quality of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' speech,
reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , that a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith College</ENAMEX>
requirements and offering electives to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> lose speech tics such as
"whatever" and "you know." Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Simmons</ENAMEX> about the
prevalent patois: "It's minimalist, it's reductionist, it's repetitive, it's
imprecise, it's inarticulate, it's vernacular."

            
               Raising the
Stakes
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and
quirky constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Ackerman</ENAMEX>, testifying before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, argued that a newly elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to try an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who was impeached by the previous one. Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ackerman</ENAMEX>'s claims were dismissed by anti-impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribe</ENAMEX>, they are not without their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, and he has now presented them in
a minibook, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Case Against Lameduck Impeachment</ENAMEX> . Another
project, written with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Alstott</ENAMEX>, is even more outré. In
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stakeholder Society</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> present a novel plan to
fight income inequality: Give all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> a "capital stake" of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000</NUMEX> when
they reach adulthood to spend as they wish. The money would be raised via taxes
on the wealthiest <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and, eventually, the estates of
deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>. The plan has been touted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine. Can a meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> (or at least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>) be far
behind?

            
               How Green Was My
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cali</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are ganging
up on social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Davis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deflater</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' dreams and delusions. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> have pointed out a number
of errors and unsubstantiated stories in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quartz</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ecology of Fear</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>). The errors
range from the trivial (misspelling the name of former Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Deukmejian</ENAMEX>)
to the significant (reporting that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> gated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> when there are, in fact, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spat</ENAMEX> has attracted attention in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>-bashing social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Kotkin</ENAMEX> declared, "What bothers me even as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who was trained as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> is that somebody would so bastardize
Marxist theory to the point of making things up." But in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irvine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Wiener</ENAMEX> contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of a campaign by city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX> to run their most persistent critic
out of town. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>, ironically, has accepted a history appointment <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> miles
away--at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University of New York at Stony Brook</ENAMEX>.

            
               Intelligences
Report
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Gardner</ENAMEX>
made a name for himself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> with his theory of "multiple intelligences,"
which posited that many different kinds of intelligence--musical, spatial,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguistic</ENAMEX>, interpersonal, etc.--balanced differently in different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. A
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Traub</ENAMEX>, assessing the impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardner</ENAMEX>'s theory in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , charged that the multiple-intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> has dumbed
down the curriculum in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. But in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">February Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardner</ENAMEX> renews his call for cognitive pluralism: Not only is there
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> kind of intelligence, but those intelligences, as he calls them,
are only part of the story. He writes, "We should recognize that intelligences,
creativity, and morality--to mention just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> desiderata--are separate. Each
may require its own form of measurement or assessment, and some will prove far
easier to assess objectively than others."

         
      
   
