
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison's Wonderland</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, he left behind
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of pages of drafts and notes for the book he had been working on for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX>--and a terrible dilemma. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>)
wanted the legendary <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> novel they were sure had to be buried in the papers
somewhere. But literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) would surely denounce
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of anything that went beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s known intentions.
Because the manuscript was nowhere near to being a coherent, finished work and
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX> left no instructions, his literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Callahan</ENAMEX>
had to choose between disappointing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amateurs</ENAMEX> and infuriating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>.

            The griping about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> even before
publication makes it clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Callahan</ENAMEX> has taken the side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX> did not leave behind the shapely <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Callahan</ENAMEX> has given us,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Feeley</ENAMEX> wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> . Critics
quoted in the article complain that sections of the novel published as excerpts
during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s lifetime are missing, that important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have withered
or vanished, and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500 or more</NUMEX> pages have been whittled down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX>.

            A scholarly edition,
promised for the future, will enable better-informed opinions by placing this
extract in the context of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s longer manuscript. But on the basis of what
we know, I'd say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callahan</ENAMEX>, who teaches at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis & Clark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, deserves to be commended, not condemned. Without
adding a word (other than the title <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> ), he has culled a nugget
that gives a sense of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX> was up to all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> without harming
any of the alternative conceptions of the work that are bound to emerge.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> doesn't pretend to be a definitive framework or even a
framework at all. It's merely a necessary starting point for an inquiry into
what might have been.

            In an afterword, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callahan</ENAMEX> says that he took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most of</TIMEX>
Juneteenth from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book II</ENAMEX>, the strongest and most heavily plotted part of
what were apparently intended to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts. The story begins in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>, when a black church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> arrives at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sunraider</ENAMEX> on urgent, unstated business. Before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> succeeds in reaching him, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> shoots the racist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunraider</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>. Critically wounded, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunraider</ENAMEX> summons the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">congregation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alonzo Hickman</ENAMEX>, to his bedside. We learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> known as "God's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trombone</ENAMEX>," was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunraider</ENAMEX> ever
had. Though either white or a fair-skinned mulatto, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliss</ENAMEX>," as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> was
known as a boy, was raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX> to be a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>.

            From here, the story
unfolds outward in many directions at once, jumping from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> bed to
various points in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunraider</ENAMEX>'s lives. The turning point for their
relationship was a celebration of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Juneteenth Day</TIMEX>, a holiday commemorating the
day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX> when slaves in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> first learned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> was over and,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years</TIMEX> after the fact, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln</ENAMEX> had issued the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emancipation Proclamation</ENAMEX>. Amid the festivities, a crazed white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> appeared
claiming to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bliss</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. After this incident, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliss</ENAMEX> became obsessed with
his lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and eventually ran away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. We get woozy glimpses of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliss Sunraider</ENAMEX>'s later life as a con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, moviemaker, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX> before
he became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> and a bigot.

            Little of this information comes in the form of
straightforward narrative but instead accumulates through murky fragments. The
language is far more complex and difficult than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invisible Man</ENAMEX> .
In place of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX>: The authorial voice;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunraider</ENAMEX>, who speaks in a number of distinct tongues--as the
child <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliss</ENAMEX>, in dreams, in remembered conversations, and in convoluted memories
poured into a death-reverie stream of consciousness. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read a brief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excerpt</ENAMEX> describing Sunraider waking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX> at his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bedside</ENAMEX>.)

            The passage is
characteristic of the book in both its lyricism and its opacity. We only find
out subsequently that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunraider</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliss</ENAMEX> and that "Why hast <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thou forsaken me</ENAMEX>"
was his opening line at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX>'s revival service, when he would rise,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>-like, from a coffin.

            Only in a few places does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> attain the
narrative velocity of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invisible Man</ENAMEX> . In a thrilling climax we finally
hear the story of how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bliss</ENAMEX> came to be adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX>, and how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX> was
transformed from an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> ne'er-do-well into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of God (it hinges on
a false accusation of rape, a lynching, and some amateur obstetrics). This
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX> could still write in the lucid, explicit vein of
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel but chose to do something more difficult and complex, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thematically</ENAMEX> and stylistically, in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s first love was
jazz--he played the trumpet--and many of the passages in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> are
extended riffs in a kind of free-form verbal polyphony. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Invisible Man</ENAMEX>
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Armstrong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Parker</ENAMEX>.

            At the level of plot,
many things are never explained, among them how "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliss</ENAMEX>," got to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunraider</ENAMEX>,
the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunraider</ENAMEX>'s own illegitimate mixed-race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> (who seems also to be
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX>), and the meaning of the message that prompts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Future fragments may illuminate these issues. But these confusions
seem largely purposeful, not accidents of omission by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX> had finished and published his novel, the story still wouldn't be
whole. It's meant to be up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to assemble the shards into a vase.
For this reason, one doesn't feel cheated by not having all the pieces. In a
curious way, the unfinished state of the novel complements the inherent and
intentional incompleteness of the underlying story.

            Think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> often appear
and reappear in his various novels and stories. It's as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX> and
Sunraider have an independent existence of which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX> offers glimpses and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glances</ENAMEX> in the various pieces he never assembled into a single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">me Juneteenth</ENAMEX> recalled especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Absalom</ENAMEX>, Absalom! in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Compson</ENAMEX> puts together a story that rattles family skeletons and points
up the reality that white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> culture is blacker than meets the eye.
Sunraider yearns to know who his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX> wants to know how Bliss
became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunraider</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> approaches these mysteries through the incomplete
knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. Crucial information is delayed and denied, which
brings us back to the motif of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juneteenth</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when slaves found out
they'd been free for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years</TIMEX>.

            Why didn't Ellison finish--or publish--the book?
The oft-repeated official version involves a fire that destroyed an important
manuscript in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>. But as disastrous an event as that must have been, I find
it unconvincing as an explanation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX> described losing a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>'s worth of
work. He had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> of writing his novel behind him and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost three</NUMEX> more
ahead of him. A more compelling explanation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX> wanted to write a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> novel that would meet the standard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Invisible Man</ENAMEX> while being
an entirely different kind of book. This strenuous ambition was confounded by a
perfectionism that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX> wrote in the introduction to his volume of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">essays Shadow</ENAMEX> and Act , made it somewhat "unreal" to even think of
himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. As he puts it, "my standards were impossibly high."

            Those standards didn't keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ellison</ENAMEX> from writing,
merely from calling it quits. Failing to finish doesn't mean he failed. Indeed,
a great, unfinished work can be more fascinating than a finished <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> because of
the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is drawn into the artistic process. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> is a
truly interactive novel, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">collaborators</ENAMEX>, trying to pull together strands and elements of a story that has
no final resolution. Other fragments and versions will add to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callahan</ENAMEX> has
assembled, not overwrite it. As with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>, the boundaries of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s
separate texts may blur, but the mythic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of the buried story and the
stylistic virtuosity of its telling will remain.

         
      
   
