
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">231</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Ultracolossal&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               An announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> roiled the world of the superjumbo. Who plans to
do what?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 230</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whoooo's Johnny":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> has been such an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> for us
because he truly believes in the power of our products," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Electronics</ENAMEX>. Who is endorsing
what?
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie Cochran</ENAMEX> endorsing open-source software. 'If they share the code, you
must download!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee Lacey</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Kreutzer</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Travolta for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Stayin' Alive Digital Fever Thermometer</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>
Shearer Gabel
            

            
"Perhaps someone should inform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Electronics</ENAMEX> that, contrary to what they
might expect, having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne Gacy</ENAMEX> endorse your clown-makeup line is a bad
call."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "I have
no idea, which seems to cast doubt on the theory that he's such an effective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Harmon</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny</ENAMEX>
Cash narrates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s electronic Holy Bibles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX>'s slated to
voice their new 'Talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Self-Reference Wrap-Up
            

            To our youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, the title of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
question may be as ancient and obscure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bergen</ENAMEX>'s wacky catch phrase:
"I'm a ventriloquist on the radio, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX>!" or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>'s "S'all right." Ah,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Severo</ENAMEX>
remembered: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Originally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX> had a body that was crushed in a train wreck
near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Se単or Wences</ENAMEX>, salvaging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, put it in a box. At first,
those who booked the act resisted; they did not think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would relate to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in a box. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Se単or Wences</ENAMEX> prevailed and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX> proved almost as big a hit as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>." Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heeere</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>. Not quiz question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> was just a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wig</ENAMEX> and a smear of lipstick on a clenched fist, but he made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Se単or Wences</ENAMEX> that
rarest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>, a genuinely funny ventriloquist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Se単or Wences</ENAMEX> died last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> at age 103.

            Some other Johnnies
neglected by quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Angel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelley Fabares</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny One Note</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Too Bad</ENAMEX> (a swell song from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Harder They</ENAMEX>
Come ), and this line of dialogue from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> racially charged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
murder mystery <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sapphire</ENAMEX> , spoken, if I recall correctly, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace</ENAMEX> Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Adams</ENAMEX>): "We got plenty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>." Indeed we do.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> on the Spot
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Cash</ENAMEX> is endorsing
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bibles</ENAMEX>. And he's not just a pitchman; he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>. He's also in on the
manufacturing: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in black narrates the desktop version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX>, scheduled for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> release.

            
               Death With Dignity
Extra
            

            A published photograph of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe DiMaggio</ENAMEX>'s memorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick's Cathedral</ENAMEX> shows
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> seated next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>. Despite the crude color
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reproduction</ENAMEX> used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , you can actually see the cloud of pure
evil hanging over these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. (Or is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Rizzuto</ENAMEX>'s head?) Right behind
them you can just make out a portal opening up to hell, presumably for the
arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>.

            Deeply reverential fun facts:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rock Positano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s events, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiMaggio</ENAMEX>'s foot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. He has also treated the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>.

               The post-mourning brunch was held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Cirque</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Few could eat through
their grief. If by "few" you mean "all."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinbrenner</ENAMEX> said his conversation with brunch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> was
"better than my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>. But I didn't know any mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>." If by "said" you exclude the final sentence.

               Did I make that clear? He's held the naked <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>. Disgusting yet biblical yet disgusting.

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX>'s inadequate circulatory system.

         
      
   
