
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Unclothed</ENAMEX>

            At the outset of her
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> complains that she's been
"misportrayed." "Behind the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>," she sobs.
For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> bares her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> and the world. Beneath a
flimsy undergarment of professed remorse, she exposes a psyche built on
blame-shifting, self-interest, and moral indifference.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. It's not my
fault. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> delivers her canned message in the interview's opening
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>: "I waited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> to be able to express to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> how very
sorry I am for my part in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>'s ordeal. ... I wouldn't dream of
asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to forgive me. But I would ask them to know
that I am very sorry for what happened and for what they've been through." As
the interview progresses, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> defines her "part" in the fiasco
narrowly, leaving others to account for "what happened." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> asks
whether she takes "responsibility" for the affair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> answers, "Not
complete responsibility." Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> came
to her for a sense of "normalcy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> reasonably inquires, "Can't you get
that from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> bats the question aside. "That's something for
him to answer, not me," she says.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. It's just a disease. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> calls the
affair a "mistake" but frames the mistake in terms of technical error and
emotional imbalance rather than moral failure. She refers constantly to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-esteem</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anti-depressant medication</ENAMEX>. When asked why she has had affairs
with married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, she explains, "I didn't have enough feelings of self-worth."
What lesson does she draw from her mistakes<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "I have a lot of healing to do,"
she concludes. Blaming her excesses on a chemical defect allows her to feel
good about her seductive inclinations. When asked whether her behavior with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "out of control," she concedes, "I needed help. I needed to be on
some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anti-depressant</ENAMEX>." But she rephrases the question in flattering
terms: "For someone like me, who's a very passionate, loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, I think you
often get close to that line."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. It's all about
me. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX> conversation in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told her they had to end their affair because it was "not right in the
eyes of God." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> conveys no interest in this moral appraisal. Instead,
she reflects on her own needs. "I was heartbroken," she recalls. "It hurts."
Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> asks about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s refusal to have intercourse with her. "I
felt it was unfair to me ," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> pleads, "that I would never know
what it was like to be that intimate with him." As for the episode in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> exploded in jealousy over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> explains, "I don't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can understand ... how
confusing it would be for me to on the one hand have someone saying things to
you--'I promise this, I promise that, I care about you, I don't want to hurt
you, I want to take care of you'--and then the actions are something different.
... It's pretty tough emotionally." She delivers this speech without a trace of
irony.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. It's about loyalty. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> emphasizes
at the outset that she's "very loyal." She says she "trusted" her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to
keep silent about her affair and feels "violated and betrayed" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>.
Why did she give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> the stained dress that was in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
apartment? Because to do otherwise would have violated her immunity agreement,
she explains, and "I needed to take care of myself and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." Toward the
end of the interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> asks, "Have you learned anything from this
experience<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" "I've learned how important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> replies. "I have
learned the true meaning of friendship."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. It's none of
your business. "From the time I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 years old</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> recalls
with a smile, "one of my first phrases [was], 'You are not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of
me !' And I've been that way ever since." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> suggests that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> were right to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
defiantly retorts, "I don't think so. I don't think that my relationship hurt
the job he was doing. It didn't hurt the work I was doing. It was between
us . And I don't think it was their business."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. It's OK if you don't get caught. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Walters</ENAMEX>
asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> about her phone sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. "It's fun ," the younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman giggles</ENAMEX>. "Did you ever think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> inquires. "I
did," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. "But I never thought she'd find out." In the interview's
final <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> asks, "If you had it to do all over again, would you
have the relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> reflects on what she has
learned. "There are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> that I regret that the relationship ever
started," she says, still grinning. "And there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> that I just regret
that I ever confided in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s pre-interview hype depicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as a
smitten, deluded romantic. She thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul mate</ENAMEX>," went this
spin, whereas he was actually a reckless, ruthless narcissist. What the
interview actually suggests, however, is that both perceptions are true. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man Lewinsky</ENAMEX> seduced was scheming, shameless, and incapable of accepting
responsibility for his conduct. And in her, he met his match.

         
      
   
