
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  My
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear,</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               How could anyone
with all mental faculties intact believe that ? Good God, anyone can see that
"his" purse does not match "his" outfit.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanna</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jo</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> knows that purple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> everywhere thank you for your vote of confidence in their style
sense. And isn't the power of television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> wonderful? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy Brown</ENAMEX> was
a loose and thoughtless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, thereby being a rotten role model, and now Tinky
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winky</ENAMEX> is sending secret messages.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, conspirationally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I read with interest the letter from "." I am a
Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Entrepreneur</ENAMEX> and have had the sometimes unnerving task of interviewing
... a skill that is learned. Until it is perfected we young<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'uns</ENAMEX> rely on
business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and books as to how to interview. In fact, I have used both
the "Tell me about yourself" and "Why do you want to work here?" lines verbatim
because I was following the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>' advice about what makes a good
interview.
            

            
               What the gentleman may have perceived as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amateurish</ENAMEX> and obnoxious could have been a combination of nervousness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inexperience</ENAMEX>. Here was an obviously experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> coming into this young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upstart</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, probably extremely well-dressed and with credentials earned
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> was even born. It is quite humbling for me to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
much more experience than I call and ask to be considered for a
position.
            

            
               I am sorry that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> didn't get a call back, but there still could be an opportunity there.
He could call back and offer to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>. This would give both parties a
chance to learn about each other. Better yet, start a business as a
professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> in his area of expertise: charging a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> retainer for
the privilege of calling him to ask questions whenever they wish. He has so
much experience and, as shown by the last interview, there are a lot of us out
there who could benefit from it.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future Young Entrepreneur of the Year</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Fu</ENAMEX>,

            Thank you for being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> and offering a positive
suggestion to our Crank. It will no doubt lift his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirits</ENAMEX> to hear from one of
the young<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'uns</ENAMEX> who is respectful of his age and experience.

            The generation gap, as
you illustrate, has different ways of being bridged.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, appreciatively

            

               
                  Madame,
               
            

            
               In a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> wrote wondering how to respond to
the "how are you question." Might I offer a suggestion from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               "I'm all right as long as you don't ask for
details."
            

            
               As an alternative,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Middling</ENAMEX>."
            

            
               Yours,
            

            

               --RWH
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear R.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> likes humorous responses to standard
questions. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> she knew used to reply to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How are you?</ENAMEX>" with, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damn</ENAMEX> near
perfect." As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has said before, the "how are you" gambit is really a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">greeting</ENAMEX>, not a question.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
responsively

            
               
                  Dear Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am a high-school
senior who has met with fantastic failure when attempting to interact with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. It's not that they necessarily dislike me, nor I them, it's just that
everything feels so uncomfortable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prom</ENAMEX> is coming up, and I am currently
wondering whether or not to ask anyone. Everyone around me is telling me I HAVE
to go, but it just seems like an uncomfortable hell. Yet if I don't go, I fear
I will regret it for the rest of my life. Any suggestions?
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apprehensive</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 16</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Ap</ENAMEX>,

            To be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> and experience difficulties "interacting
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>" means that emotionally and developmentally you are still working
things out. Everyone does not hop into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy-girl</ENAMEX> thing with ease and
comfort. What supposedly comes naturally can take awhile to arrive.

            That everything feels uncomfortable may mean that
you're more than normally shy and insecure. Or it could mean that you're more
than normally shy and insecure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> will reveal what is comfortable. As for
the prom, there is no need to push yourself into something you would be just as
happy skipping. Plus, it sounds as if you have no one in mind.

            You are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is
not. Trust her that if you decide to do an end run around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">prom night</TIMEX> you will
not, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades from now</TIMEX>, be bemoaning that fact.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, promisingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I work with a guy
I've tried to befriend. In fact, I even introduced him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he's going
to marry. The problem is that he does things like inviting me to lunch,
then--when I'm trapped in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--says he needs to run errands <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. He even
returned one of those grip-squeeze things I'd given him because he wore a hole
in it, and it was spilling the stuff inside. Is he just a jerk? And if so, how
do I continue my friendship with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX>, whom I still like?
            

            

               --Split Loyalty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Rafael</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear Split,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is never sure what the word "jerk" means.
This chap, however, sounds like a clod, and certainly someone deficient in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> graces and good sense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. If you choose to continue with him,
you might try to fluff up his social skills by example. An instance might be if
he tries the lunch/errands stunt again, simply request that he do his chores
without you because your intention was to have lunch. If he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super boor</ENAMEX> and
tries to override you, request that he stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and let you out.

            Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiancee</ENAMEX>, may be a lost cause as a continuing friendship if you call it a day
with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clunk</ENAMEX>. Them's the breaks, kiddo.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
realistically

         
      
   
