
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep End</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). Good reviews for this story of
the disappearance and eventual return of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, based on Jacquelyn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchard</ENAMEX>'s best seller. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>'s turn as the distraught <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is
singled out for praise; many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> call it "an exceptional performance ...
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her best ever" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Some say
the subject matter has a made-for-TV feel, but most conclude that the acting
elevates the film into real drama. 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX> is of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> minds about the film: "I want to say it's subtle, but I
also want to say it's heavy-handed. I want to say it's incisive, but I have too
many problems with its psychological elisions to let it off the hook." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>
the rest of his review .)

            
               
                  The
Corruptor
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> action star <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chow Yun-Fat</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> English-language film (after the unenthusiastically received
Replacement Killers ) gets mixed reviews. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Wahlberg</ENAMEX> co-stars as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rookie partner</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> charged with controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> like this movie better than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chow</ENAMEX>'s last film and say it has
"a stylish patina that puts it a cut above much of the competition" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Holden, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). But the story, an exploration of the line
between everyday palm-greasing and real treachery, does not capture everyone's
imagination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Arnold</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> calls it "a groggy
hotbed of sensationalism." (Find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chow</ENAMEX> on this
fan site.)

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Carrie 2</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM/UA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> agree that this film is a sorry
imitation of the original: "as generic in every aspect as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian De Palma</ENAMEX>'s
original was inventive" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Harvey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ). The plot is the
same (tortured telekinetic teen starts bloodbath when humiliated), but this
time it's just "campy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inanity</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ) with none of
the original's terrifying flair. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX> is
the film's only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>; he calls the direction "astute" and the script
"intelligent." (Find out more about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> film starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sissy Spacek</ENAMEX>
here.)

            
               
                  Wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Commander</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). This film adaptation of
the popular computer game is deemed "so cheesy it could be served on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crackers</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee Graham</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prinze Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Lillard</ENAMEX>
(who is "upstaged by his hair ," according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter pilots</ENAMEX> in the year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2564</TIMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> (an evil race of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>) look like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats reupholstered</ENAMEX> in slimy green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naugahyde</ENAMEX>" (Godfrey
Cheshire, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ). The most notable thing about the film is that
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> for the new Star Wars movie runs before it. (Find out
more about the computer game on this site.)

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928-1999</TIMEX>). In a pre-release publicity coup for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">forthcoming Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> dies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clockwork Orange</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Odyssey</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangelove Or</ENAMEX>:
How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Learned To Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb</ENAMEX> was universally hailed for
a famously uncompromising vision. It was an "amazingly varied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of work"
that was "unified not only by bizarre brilliance but also by its rare ability
to disturb" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). His most commonly cited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shortcoming</ENAMEX> is what many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> describe as "coldness," even in his most
accomplished films. Many of the recent life and work recaps emphasize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">famous idiosyncrasies: 1</ENAMEX>) his reclusiveness (though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Schickel was apparently an intimate); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) his obsessiveness (he was known, wrote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> , to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">projectionists</ENAMEX> personally
and complain about how his film was being shown in a particular theater); and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) maniacal attention to detail (scores of takes were the norm). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
Nicholson, who starred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shining</ENAMEX> , was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> big
enough to talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maestro</ENAMEX> with anything less than total respect:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>'s good on sound," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholson</ENAMEX> said to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>'s good on
the color of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mike</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>'s good about the merchant he bought the mike
from. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>'s good about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who needs some dental work.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>'s good." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX>' take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Hawk</ENAMEX>
Down: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Story of Modern War</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Bowden</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX>
Press). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> are fascinated by this account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intervention in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>. The writing may not be polished, but "[w]hat this demotic,
you-are-there prose lacks in literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finesse</ENAMEX> ... it makes up in pure narrative
drive." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Finnegan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> wish the account gave more of a sense of the historical context. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowden</ENAMEX>'s excellent reporting--he interviewed scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somali</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>--makes for a "vivid, immediate and unsparing narrative that is filled
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and noise and terror" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter courtesy of the New York
Times [requires free registration].)

            Find a movie playing
near you on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Analyze This</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX>, Stock & <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> Smoking
Barrels ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Monica's Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Annie Get Your Gun</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Bright Lights</ENAMEX>, Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  8MM ;

               
                  Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> Cigarettes ;

               
                  Movie -- The 
                  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Houdini Girl</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martyn Bedford</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Perfect Murder, Perfect Town</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiller</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Nightingales</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  
                     Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jawbreaker</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Space</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Music--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Rock</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleater-Kinney</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Traveling Mercies: Some Thoughts on Faith</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Lamott</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Elegant Universe: Superstrings, Hidden Dimensions</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quest for the Ultimate Theory</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian R. Greene</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Blast From the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Past</TIMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Message in a Bottle ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Favorite Martian</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testament</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haruki</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  Death <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of a Salesman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene O'Neill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

         
      
   
