
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> needs to realize
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> espionage is inevitable. A bigger source of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> trouble
is export promotion: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> should quit hawking goods to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
because that trade policy conflicts with foreign policy. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>"
column <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> a consistent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, warning that separation of powers allows the legislative and executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branches</ENAMEX> to broadcast different messages. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX> also praises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Foreign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relations Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Cox</ENAMEX> "for his cheerful refusal to be a
hack or a firebrand.") ... An editorial bids adieu to the old model of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> integration
premised on an omnipotent central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>. In addition to being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scandal-ridden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> has squandered its policy-making powers
to the point of irrelevance.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5, 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The kindly cover profile
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> says he might seriously challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
nomination as the "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of political reform and moral reawakening."
The article credits the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> with: the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform Act</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prescience</ENAMEX> regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> high-tech boom, earnestness, an "active
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> conscience," and "political individuality." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is
compromised by his association with administration scandals. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> argues that abortion is here to stay because it is "an indispensable
part of the middle-class toolkit." Despite the fact that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have moral misgivings about abortion, expediency overpowers
"traditional morality." Pragmatic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>) understand
this. ... "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRB</ENAMEX>" faults <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s moral reasoning in apologizing for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> assistance to repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guatemalan</ENAMEX> regimes. The broader goals of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> required the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to make common cause with oppressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. Rather than issuing mea culpa s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should declassify
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> archives so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> may judge for themselves if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
is guilty.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The fascinating cover
story traces the path of anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Kopp</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> sought in
the fatal shooting of abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">provider Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnett Slepian</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kopp</ENAMEX> began as a
"prayerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of life" but became an "any means necessary" fanatic. The
piece explores the radicalization of anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>, who have moved
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Rescue</ENAMEX>'s nonviolent principles to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army of God</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manual</ENAMEX> , which instructs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> on violent action. The violent strategy
may be achieving its goal: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1992 and 1996</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinics</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> performing abortion declined <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX>. ... A
profile wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX> can translate his discursive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> charm to
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes II</ENAMEX> , where he's now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>. The article asserts that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX>'s success at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes II depends</ENAMEX> "on his ability to relinquish
those very qualities that make him interesting and distinctive": his "harried,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stumblebum</ENAMEX>" style. ... An article focuses on the rebuilding of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>'s brand, which has lost the youth market since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>'s
decline is attributed to the "paradigm shift" toward baggy over tight and the
failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi's</ENAMEX> to retail directly to a new generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who
experience shopping as entertainment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>'s hopes to rebound by subtly
infiltrating youth culture: sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX> concerts, posting flyers,
chalking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX>, and airing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Morris</ENAMEX>-directed commercials during
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The annual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
hype issue is as immense (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">414</NUMEX> pages) and gushy as usual. The meatiest feature
chronicles how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Cohn</ENAMEX> squelched the romance between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Davis Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Novak</ENAMEX> to avoid adverse publicity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>, reportedly
acting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohn</ENAMEX>'s behalf, threatened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> with violence to force him into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">sham</ENAMEX> marriage with a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX>
retreads the story of the industry war between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creative Artists Agency</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upstart Artists Management Group</ENAMEX>. The battle started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> when prodigal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mogul Mike Ovitz</ENAMEX> rode back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMG</ENAMEX>, and proclaimed his intention
to reinvent "the architecture of the industry." The piece explains the
institutionalized tensions between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, and suggests that Ovitz
is off to "a strong start," having already lured away industry "crown jewels"
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Diaz</ENAMEX>. ... Plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> glamour photos: The cover triptych shows the usual fresh crop of
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idols</ENAMEX> to-be. (Never heard of them? Neither have we.) Virtually everyone
who's anyone is depicted in an inside portfolio: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Nymph</ENAMEX>"),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Caine</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Devils"</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Three Graces</ENAMEX>"), etc.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-step program for "succeeding in
the digital age." Revelations: Use e-mail (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 1</ENAMEX>) and not paper (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 5</ENAMEX>). There
is much jargon: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Shift knowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> into high-level thinking." One
sidebar wonders why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> doesn't mention the
antitrust trial in his new book and urges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to "slap their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> with a digital reality check." Another suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is making lavish "investments" in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> as "insurance" against a legal defeat. ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe DiMaggio</ENAMEX> "our first modern media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>"
and "the loneliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> we have ever had." The story predictably applauds his
achievements on the field and sighs over his difficulties off it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's sprawl
story sensibly points out that planning and zoning are inherently local issues
not national ones. Nevertheless, national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> (notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>) are
feasting on the issue, which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> calls "startlingly on track with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>." ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> prints a snippy interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>,
currently visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in search of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>
backing. If he is refused, he says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will not perish." ... Also
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Navasky</ENAMEX> rails against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar for Lifetime Achievement</ENAMEX>.
The only fair way to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> the award, he says, is to "print the names he
named on the back of it." (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> see "" in

                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story surveys the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">E-Mail Nation</ENAMEX>," addressing cyberstalking, office
politics, and online literacy. Conclusion: E-mail's potent mix of intimacy,
anonymity, and speed is reshaping <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. One surprise: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> are
among e-mail's most dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>; although initially daunted by
technological bells and whistles, they find solace and community online.
... A piece describes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s new abortion-reporting
regulations. The rules, which were pushed by pro-lifers, require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to
complete a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-point checklist detailing why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> wants an abortion, list
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s method of payment, and record the total number of abortions they
perform. ... An article details the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s effort to recruit new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> and
retain old ones by establishing on-board "wellness" programs, which include
counseling, personal fitness training, and free <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX> facial massages.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece calls the
killing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou Diallo</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> more explicable than last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s beating of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abner Louima</ENAMEX>. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louima</ENAMEX>'s beating was a premeditated,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unprovoked</ENAMEX> act of barbarism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diallo</ENAMEX>'s killing stemmed from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-crime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patrols</ENAMEX>, where heavy suspicion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> is inevitable, if unlawful. ...
A piece says the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> hair dye ads of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX> ("Does she or doesn't she?"
"Because I'm worth it") were seminal declarations of female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">self-determination</ENAMEX>.
New hair color offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> "an immediate and affordable means of
transformation." ... An article describes trendy new wrinkles in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX>' previously starchy marketing techniques. The original fount of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preppiness</ENAMEX> has been reduced to deploying an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of image-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to reclaim
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> from faux <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Lauren</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> eviscerate
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy and mock the notion of a strategic
partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumably</ENAMEX>, if we don't engage this landmass, it
will fall on us." ... The cover story, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Gospel According to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>," narrates his transformation from sinful wretch to fervent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">believer</ENAMEX> and his carefully phrased supplications to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>.
... A piece challenges recent findings that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> don't harm their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s development by working as an "affront" to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> who stay home
or work out of necessity. The study will make it even more difficult for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> to take time off from work to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
