
   
   
      
         
            <STRONG><EM>Slate</STRONG></EM>, Version<B><I> </B></I>2.0

            As 
                  Slate
               's design
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>--yes, I'm wearing black--I could essay at length about the redesign
that debuts in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s issue. I could speak volumes about our ambition to
balance white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> with type, and art with copy. About our quest to create
more readable Web pages. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> new navigation that makes dancing through

                  Slate
                to find interesting articles all but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">effortless</ENAMEX>.

            But instead of boring
you with self-serving "designspeak," I've prepared a concise roll call of
what's new and different in the new and different

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> -- our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> complete redesign since we launched
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  What's
New?
               
            

            

               New Content Views
            

            We've
created <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> new ways to view 
                  Slate
                contents.

            

                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Today</ENAMEX>" lists everything posted since <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous day</TIMEX>.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Complete</ENAMEX>" lists the entire current content of

                     Slate
                  .

               The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation Banner</ENAMEX>," that maroon stripe that says
"
                     Slate
                  " at the top and bottom of every

                     Slate
                   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, uses color coding and drop-down menus to
give you access to any page in 
                     Slate
                   from any other
page in 
                     Slate
                  . The only catch is you have to have a
modern browser such as Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.0</NUMEX> or the forthcoming Netscape
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX> browser.

            

            I'll tell you more about
how to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation Banner</ENAMEX> in just a minute.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Today</ENAMEX> is the default
home page of 
                  Slate
               , which means it's what you'll see
when you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. If you want
to see a list of the entire current content, just click the Complete button on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Navigation Banner</ENAMEX>. If you really prefer this one, we encourage you
to bookmark it (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX>) or put it in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">browser</ENAMEX>'s Favorites
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">folder</ENAMEX> (in Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Sections</ENAMEX>
            

            We've sorted our content
into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sections: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briefing</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Features</ENAMEX>," "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24/Seven</TIMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utilities</ENAMEX>."

            

               Briefing

            

            Think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Briefing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> as your quick hit on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s news. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>,
summarizes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 ET</TIMEX>. "International
Papers" does the same for the world press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times a week. "In Other
Magazines" sizes up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and other major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">periodicals</ENAMEX>--usually before they hit your mailbox or local newsstand. We also
chart the critical consensus about books, movies, art, and music in "Summary
Judgment" and spare you from having to watch the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk shows by offering
you the gist in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (check in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> to prepare for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
sessions at the water cooler). There's more good stuff in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Briefing</ENAMEX>, including
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>," and "
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Favorites"</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of useful links to other reportage and commentary--and
gossip--on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>). We invite you to explore.

            

               Features

            

            Under the Features
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rubric</ENAMEX>, we've grouped our regular articles, news commentary, and arts and
culture features. This is also where you'll find our regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>--such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> on economics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> on culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> on
politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> on movies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX> on fashion, and more.

            

               24/Seven

            

            24/Seven pulls together
the 
                  Slate
                features that are updated repeatedly
throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>: Our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary"</ENAMEX>; the e-mail give-and-take of "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book Club" and "Dialogues</ENAMEX>" about the pressing issues
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>; e-mail dispatches from hither and yon; as well as our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moneybox</ENAMEX>"
meditations on business, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" commentaries on politics, and
"Culturebox" on ... well, you guess. 

            

               Utilities

            

            Think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utilities</ENAMEX> as
your 
                  Slate
                toolbox, the place to get

                  Slate
                business done. Go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utilities</ENAMEX> to send us an
e-mail, to get e-mail from us, to sound off about an article, to search

                  Slate
               's archives, or to update your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> profile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">info</ENAMEX>. (You say you're not a 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>?! Click
here
to sign up for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $19.95</NUMEX> and enjoy a world of benefits, including e-mail
delivery and access to our archives.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click on Utilities</ENAMEX> if you want to print
the entire issue using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>, or if you're dying to inspect our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masthead</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Boiler</ENAMEX>
                  Slate
               ").

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation</ENAMEX>
            

            I promised to teach you how to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banner</ENAMEX>, didn't I? So, here goes. (Remember you must have Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> 4.0
or better or the forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX> for this function to work.)

            Move your cursor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation Banner</ENAMEX> at the top
of this page, and click on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Briefing</ENAMEX> section head. A "drop down" menu will
appear and reveal the contents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Briefing</ENAMEX>. Now, move your cursor to the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> heads. Additional menus listing the contents will drop down. To select
an article in a drop down menu, click on it. Congratulations, you've mastered

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">navigation</ENAMEX>.

            The beauty of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation Banner</ENAMEX> is that every page now contains a complete

                  Slate
                table of contents. You don't have to click back
to the big table of contents every time you find more good stuff to read. Of
course, if you fancy the big table of contents, just click <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Today, Complete</ENAMEX>,
or the 
                  Slate
                logo.

             

            
               More Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation News</ENAMEX>
            

            Another fabulous thing
about the drop down menus is that they list the headlines of the most recent
postings in multiple-entry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dialogues</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explainer</ENAMEX>.

            
               Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More Good</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation News</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today in Slate</ENAMEX>"
            

            Running down the left side of every article you'll
find "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               ," which is our attempt to
persuade you to check out other good stuff currently on our site. These would
be on any topic. By contrast "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               " box
contains links to relevant 
                  Slate
                pieces--new or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>--that are related to the page you are currently reading. We'll also
continue to list links to the best Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and to pertinent articles in
the "Related on the Web" box. Look for both boxes at the bottom of most
stories.

            Have I left anything
out? I think not. But we're eager to hear what you think about our new look and
feel. Please address your comments to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. We look forward to hearing
from you.

         
      
   
