
   
   
      
         
             War by Numbers

            Do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> grow faint at
the sight of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>? Certainly the poll-watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> thinks
so. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are now urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> not to
"rule out any option." Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> insists that "he has no intention" of
committing ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war front and remains convinced that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airstrikes</ENAMEX> alone can persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to swear off their favorite pastime
of rape-and-pillage.

            Of course it is possible
that the parsable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> sees political advantage in allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to push him into a ground conflict of uncertain cost and consequence
(Who knows the true meaning of "has no intention"?). But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> may
also be misreading public attitudes. Polls taken during <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military
engagements from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is
pretty tough--tougher probably than our misty-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>.

            True, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kohut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the Pew
Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, have repeatedly warned that the public will cool once <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
casualties are incurred. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> got scant comfort from the public. Polls showed the expected
"patriotic bounce" when the action started but it was relatively small and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evanescent</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last week of March</TIMEX>, only slightly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> approved of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s handling of the situation--a far cry from
the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> plus who applauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. This
despite the fact that the conflict had most of the hallmarks that,
historically, have made for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> support for military interventions:
humanitarian purpose, concerted allied action (usually good in itself for a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-point boost in the polls), and an identifiable villain.

            Still, that initial
lukewarm response didn't surprise polling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karlyn Bowman</ENAMEX>, for example, pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are always
wary about putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in harm's way especially when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests aren't
well understood. And, despite his lingering credibility problems on foreign
policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did manage to rally some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the public behind his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> airstrikes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. "Perhaps that's because the public is more
familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> issue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowman</ENAMEX> noted, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is less clear-cut."

            Since then, however, public opinion has gradually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toughened</ENAMEX>. And that doesn't surprise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> either. Even at the start of
the bombing the public was remarkably realistic. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25-26</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> poll, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 53 percent</NUMEX> then approved of the airstrikes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
percent agreed ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> would be required to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> to back down. Expectations that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lives would be lost
even in an air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> have ranged from the high <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">60s</NUMEX> to the low <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80s</TIMEX>. Still,
support for the actual use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> hovered in the lower <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40s</TIMEX>.

            Then came a week
saturated with coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> atrocities and a very sharp rise in public
attention to the conflict. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> poll taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1-2</TIMEX>--partly
before confirmation of the capture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Macedonian</ENAMEX>
border--showed that support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX> had risen to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68 percent</NUMEX>. And a
majority, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54 percent</NUMEX>, expressed strong or moderate support for the use of
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to end the conflict (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83 percent</NUMEX> supported sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to
rescue any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> of war). By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post /ABC</ENAMEX>
poll found <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX> support for taking to the ground. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News/ Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> poll found that an astounding <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> if it was the only way
to stop the fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Bolstering that average were hefty majorities
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> normally pacific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74 percent</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81 percent</NUMEX>).
Thus do politics make strange foxhole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX>.

            What accounts for the rapid shift in opinion? Apparently
not presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s strong support among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early April</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> poll <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 54 percent</NUMEX> approved of his
handling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> situation; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX> thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> didn't
think through its plans sufficiently, a finding supported by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times /<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX> poll taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5-6</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> poll, however, also
found majority support for ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> if needed to stop ethnic cleansing or
to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> from power, and the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News/ Washington Post</ENAMEX>
poll (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 8</TIMEX>) shows <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> supporting ground troop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX> fail to deter the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>.

            Obviously, horrifying
footage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> played a role in rallying the public. But perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
are not the wimps that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>--sometimes seem to think.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Kull</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX>'s
Program on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Policy Attitudes</ENAMEX>, points to his own studies and a
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAND</ENAMEX> study showing that from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, public support
for bellicose action often surges in the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> casualties. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1991 Persian Gulf War</ENAMEX> remained at very high
levels even at the start of ground combat operations in which most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
expected (incorrectly) that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> would be high. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>
intervention, high initial public approval of the humanitarian aims had faded
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> as the public came to perceive that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had wandered into
the middle of a long-running civil war. Still, support for strong action
actually rose briefly after the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>.

            But, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kull</ENAMEX>, "One would not expect a real bounce
until you see some signs of success." What jades the public on military
intervention in civil wars such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> is the prospect
that the sacrifice in lives and treasure may be in vain. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> may find
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solidarity</ENAMEX> in the memory of defeats past and present, but when it comes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rallying America</ENAMEX>, nothing succeeds like success.

         
      
   
