
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo Con Games</ENAMEX>

            For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> have pronounced it unwinnable. The
atrocities continue unabated , they say. Air power alone will never get
the job done. It's another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has blown it. Everything
we do makes the situation worse. Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> can win the
war remains to be seen. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing is certain: They can't win the
debate over the war as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are allowed to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> it with the
following hidden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Selective</ENAMEX>
Scrutiny
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Policies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> observe that
many things have gone badly since the air war began: Ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> have been
killed and expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> nationalism has grown in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. It's easy to associate bad outcomes with the current policy. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> seldom apply the same kind of scrutiny to alternative policies. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
had forsworn the use of force against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, what would the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
ultimately have done to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX>? If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> had launched a ground
war, what would <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> be doing now? If, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> observe, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have
managed to cleanse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than four weeks</TIMEX>, what difference could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
have made by beginning a ground force buildup (which takes considerable time) a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month ago</TIMEX>?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Policy-makers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> think their job is to examine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> not foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX>. So they discount <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s
behavior as an objective consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s subjective decisions. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> ethnic cleansing follows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
action not as the product of free will but as a reaction determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
action. So while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> on the ground report on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> atrocities,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> and the newsrooms in effect pass the blame to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            This bias has produced a bizarre
blame-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>-first spin on the right. "We have ignited the very human rights
catastrophe the war was started to avoid," declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columnist Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> compared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waco</ENAMEX>, arguing that
just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s actions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX> "precipitated" the murder-suicides by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Davidian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, his intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> "has
unwittingly produced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the great humanitarian catastrophes of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>." While some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> allege that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
unnecessary belligerence provoked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to ethnic cleansing, others say his
timidity about using ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> "emboldened" the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to the same effect.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> even gets the blame for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> hostility. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judd Gregg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of "pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> into a corner and
putting them in a position where they're no longer able to do anything but to
react in an aggressive way towards our action."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> butcher <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX> or drive
another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>-bites-man story. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombs what
it thought was a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> and instead hits a caravan of civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, killing scores, it's a man-bites-dog story. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> treated the casualties caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> as the lead story from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
overshadowing far greater casualties caused during that time by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>.
"This may have cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> the moral high ground," declared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>,
invoking the moral-equivalence formula usually despised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' role in pushing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> in the middle
of a war zone was scarcely mentioned.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Sleight</ENAMEX>-of-Hand
Inferences
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unachieved</ENAMEX> to unachievable.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s media report news instantaneously and expect it to be made
instantaneously as well. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two weeks</TIMEX>, their verdict on the bombing
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> leapt from unfulfilled objectives to failure to impossibility.
Since air power hasn't brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to their knees in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> conclude that it never will. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have decided it's
"doomed to failure," according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX>. Never mind that under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
plan, the bombing will become more severe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Critics
constantly compare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. They infer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lessons from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>: that
"gradual escalation" never works and that "bombing" can't break an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>'s
will. The trick in invoking such analogies is to ignore the differences: that
the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is being waged by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>; that no
superpower is willing to prop up the targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>; and that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s air
power and surveillance are vastly more precise than the "bombing" technology
used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinner</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> on the right argue that because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is untrustworthy,
so is the war. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> put it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> citation
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for falsely denying his affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is "a
timely reminder of the mendacity that drenches his presidency, including his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> policy." Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> on the left argue that because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> failed to intervene in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, its intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is morally
suspect and probably racist.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. Hidden</ENAMEX>
Dichotomies
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Empirical/moral.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Centuries ago</TIMEX>,
scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> invented a strict separation between talking about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> the world is and talking about the way it ought to be. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s media,
following this premise, separate "editorial" from "news" judgments. The only
standard by which "news" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> feel comfortable evaluating a policy is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> or failure, not right or wrong. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s consensus about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s policy is "not working." As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> put it to Deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , "The atrocities
continue. What success can you point to that any of your strategy has worked?"
The alternative perspective goes overlooked: that the question is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
must do, that atrocities are a challenge rather than a verdict, and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should persevere precisely because they continue.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Political/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should have destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> by now and never should have
sworn off ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. They deride these as "political decisions" and mock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> for refusing to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> because it contains cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">treasures</ENAMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>. "The idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> object to
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and therefore we shouldn't do what is necessary to win this war,
is, in my view, ridiculous," protested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> . But
what's the definition of winning? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> say they're
not just seeking a one-time victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. They're trying to develop
what is essentially an international policing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>. This is a political
as well as military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">project</ENAMEX>. It entails compromising with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> who are more
cautious about applying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and authorizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. Otherwise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> would have to police the world alone, which is unsustainable politically
(thanks in part to vociferous opposition from many of these same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>), not
to mention militarily.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Harm/help. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> maintain
that the bombing isn't helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>. "I don't care about dropping any
more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Danube River</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> fumed on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> .
"I don't know how that helps those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The question, he argued,
should be "What is the best way to help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and save these lives? Not
how we can bomb another oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refinery</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
Schieffer ended the show by noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> were still being purged
and asking "whether what we are doing is doing any good."

            This dichotomy rules out
the fallback strategy that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have articulated from the
outset: to make the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s "victory" outweigh the rewards.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> used to defend this concept (which they called "deterrence") when
it was preached and practiced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. If the punishment you
administer to the current <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">troublemaker</ENAMEX> fails to stop him, the theory goes, at
least it will make the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troublemaker</ENAMEX> think twice.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Self-Fulfilling</ENAMEX>
Doubts
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Practical futility. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>' verdict is in: The war is "doomed" and "already lost." On Late
Edition , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "doesn't give, after a month
of this, any impression that he is backing down." Quoting a report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> see no sign "that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is changing his strategy or about
to break," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talbott</ENAMEX>, "Are we losing this war?" Other talking heads
asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is "not united" and won't be able to "stand up" as the
conflict wears on. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is not on our side," warned former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adviser Brent Scowcroft</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> . "It is going to be very
difficult to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> together."

            Of course, the best way to assure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
doesn't break, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> comes apart, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> loses the war
is to predict that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> won't break, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will come apart, and that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will lose the war. These predictions bolster the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>'
morale while undermining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Dodd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, observed on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patience</ENAMEX> and resolve are as important a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> today
as actually the airstrikes are."

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Moral authority. Rather than
call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> pass this off as a widespread perception by
others. They call it a "moral authority" and "public relations" problem, asking
how it will "impact" his "ability to lead" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> in war. "There is
a common drum beat on the airwaves," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 15</TIMEX>,
"that you, personally, lack the moral authority to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "does not
inspire" great "loyalty," adding, "He may have a conflict of interest if he
sends in ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. It would be hard to save his skin and their skin at the
same time." By questioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s moral authority in this pseudo-objective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> destroy what's left of his moral authority.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> credibility. Self-styled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hawks</ENAMEX> fret that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will lose the war and thereby expose its impotence. This
"lumbering and clumsy" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>, incapable of "managing such brush fires as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," could "lose the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> against the ruin of a rump
state," warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX>. "If the perception is that for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> tiny little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> ... has withstood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,"
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX>, will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> be exposed as "a paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger</ENAMEX>"?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, grimly intoned, "Many are
predicting that this will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>." And all because, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX>'s words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "staked the survival of the most successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> in history on bright new academic ideas cooked up far from the
battlefields on which they now flounder."

            Having defined anything
less than the total recapture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and the restoration of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> as
a failure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are ensuring that such failure will be interpreted
as catastrophically as possible. As for their suggestion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
credibility is too precious to be risked in war, you can understand their
reluctance. Even tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
