
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial bluntly criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s cautious
intervention strategy for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> ("horribly wrong") and urges the West to
assume control of the region. The piece acknowledges that this will be
difficult "from the air alone" but doesn't directly recommend ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.
Another editorial berates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for foreclosing
the ground troop option, thus goading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> into further obstinacy
and tying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s hands. ... An article calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX> a
"tyrant," a "little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>," and a poor choice for the position. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> is
neither restrained nor tech-savvy enough to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> through its
current legal and business challenges.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story claims
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of his own
achievements. Because his crime crackdown has succeeded, further reductions in
lawlessness are coming at the cost of increased friction with innocent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Racial hysterics and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dinkins Democrats</ENAMEX> exploit incidents like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diallo</ENAMEX> murder to sully the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s success. ... An analysis claims that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have abandoned foreign policy principles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> was gearing up to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticize Clinton</ENAMEX> for coddling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> bombing
short-circuited this argument. So now some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
for attacking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>, claiming that humanitarian interventions exhaust <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. ... An article argues that military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foolhardy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> insist the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> help dispel <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> perceptions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military weakness and give our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> a peek at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s military. But
there is no real reciprocity of access, and we find ourselves hosting such
dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> who perpetrated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> crackdown.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story examines
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Counterculture</ENAMEX>": the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> priesthood. It attributes the plummet
in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> entering the priesthood to pedophilia scandals,
disillusionment with celibacy, and "the increasingly secular nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
life." Contemporary seminarians try not to disengage from mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,
but they are disgusted with a popular culture that celebrates contraception,
premarital sex, and godlessness. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> suggests
that his presidential run is all about proving he's not an idiot. The theme of
his campaign--also the subtitle of his memoir--is that he's "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most
misjudged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> figure." Though there is some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> revisionism--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>
told him, "You're not a joke like you once were"--he is still widely considered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unelectable</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The newsweeklies all run worried, doubtful cover
stories on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war and eavesdrop on the high-level conversations behind
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               stresses the historical angle, calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centuries-old</ENAMEX> "tinderbox" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX> will ignite.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's history lesson: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> started not because of
ethnic cleansing but because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> intervention. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
                argue that the strikes compromise both dicta of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> Doctrine because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> isn't acting with either maximum
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> or an exit strategy. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
                report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>,
"This isn't a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> commercial. This is going to be a sustained
effort."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               psychologizes that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' suicides caused his "clear
longing for certainties, a need to be in control." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">describes Milosevic</ENAMEX> as "one of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> of history"
but then wonders if he's crafty enough to outmaneuver <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> anyway. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> cheer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
campaign against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> 
               calls him "the smartest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>," while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> rappelled down a mountainside to rescue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>
defends  his handling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou Diallo</ENAMEX> shooting to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . "[The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>] is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX>," he
offers.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>
blames the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the disintegration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspection
efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Eager to assassinate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>--and supported by
presidential orders--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> hijacked the intelligence operation designed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Special Commission</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to track <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s weapons development, thus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">destroying UNSCOM</ENAMEX>'s credibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> also alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> know-how in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
... A story describes the courtship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hinckley Jr.</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had murdered her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, when both were confined to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. The romance developed steadily until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinckley</ENAMEX> began to
pester a hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharmacist</ENAMEX> who resembled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> lambast the "pathetic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incoherence</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> foreign policy and urge a return to the more moral
and aggressive approach of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> era. ... A piece calls the
protests against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diallo</ENAMEX> killing "a ludicrous moral pageant" and an attempt
by the "prevailing ideological power structure" to delegitimize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>
in particular and conservative governance in general. ... The cover
story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> has been ignored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> because he
was a paragon of virtue and praises recent efforts to spiff up his media
image.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Esquire</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            An exposé headlined
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DWB</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Driving</ENAMEX> While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>) slams <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Pipeline</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Enforcement</ENAMEX>
Administration-sponsored program to catch drug "mules"--which effectively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets minorities</ENAMEX>. Cops are trained to pull over, interrogate, and search on
the basis of "indicators," such as air fresheners, fast-food trash, lack of eye
contact, and insufficient or excessive luggage. The indicators are often a
proxy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorist</ENAMEX>'s race: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trooper</ENAMEX> admits he was trained to target
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Ms.
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April/May 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The feminist magazine
relaunches with articles on subjects predictable (female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, abortion clinic violence) and less so (adultery, the benefits of
eating soy). ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> narrates her face lift. At first, she feels
like "female goods in a dick-driven market," but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks later</TIMEX> finds her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smoother</ENAMEX>, younger face a source of pleasure and confidence. ... A photo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Praise of Women</ENAMEX>," features shots of impoverished or oppressed women
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, with lushly worded captions. ("Though worlds
apart geographically, we are all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>.")

         
      
   
