
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX> in Love

            Early in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> , the narcissistic twit we are supposed to believe went on to write the
greatest dramatic poetry in the language steps outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> to offer
words of solace to a snaggletoothed urchin, originally slated to play <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Juliet</ENAMEX>,
who has just been fired. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, it turns out, is a particular aficionado of
stage violence. The best parts of plays, he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> as he prepares to feed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">passing alley cat</ENAMEX>, involve dismemberment and murder.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> asks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s name. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Webster</ENAMEX>," he replies. There is a beat, as if to
cue audience laughter, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> walks away. The scene, which serves
no purpose in the film's plot (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> will later be instrumental in
stirring up the suspicion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>), is indeed a joke:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Webster</ENAMEX> is the name of the bloodiest of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> dramatists--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jacobean</ENAMEX> stage. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">torturer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> will grow
up to write revenge tragedies such as The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Devil</ENAMEX> and The Duchess
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malfi</ENAMEX> . Get it?

            The scene I've just
described is an exemplary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX> moment: A literary in-joke that turns on
the accidental, and wholly conjectural, collision of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> historical figures.
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX>'s best-known plays, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Travesties</ENAMEX> , grows out of his
discovery that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dadaist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tristan Tzara</ENAMEX> all spent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>, and imagines what their table talk might have been
like.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> co-wrote the screenplay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> , and over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX> a number of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have tried to
excite my interest in the movie by invoking this fact. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX>'s name,
familiar to anyone who cares about modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> or who took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP English</ENAMEX> in
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, signifies a deft blend of high culture and high wit, deep thinking
and schoolboy cleverness. I keep hearing and reading the words "smart fun" in
connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> , and (leaving aside that the movie
is neither) smart fun is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stoppard</ENAMEX>'s stock in trade. Watching his plays, you
feel smart. What could be more fun?

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> demand erudition of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. Stoppard
supplies it. I am surely not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who walked into the Vivian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaumont Theater</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arcadia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX> knowing next to nothing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> landscape gardening or chaos theory; by the time the play was
over I felt as though I did. And while many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theatergoers</ENAMEX> will arrive at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX>'s most recent play, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Invention of Love</ENAMEX> , with some notion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>'s glorious career and tragic end (especially if they have already
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seen Moises Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross Indecency</ENAMEX> or read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Barker</ENAMEX>'s novel The
Eye in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Door</ENAMEX> ), few will be familiar with the life and work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">classicist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.E. Housman</ENAMEX>, and fewer still will have any prior knowledge
of the differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> editions of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> love poet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Propertius</ENAMEX>. But playgoers will leave the theater flush with the thrill of
having learned something about these arcane matters, even if <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> later they
will be hard pressed to say just what they've learned. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> lies
in his ability to excite our intellectual curiosity and, in a stroke, to
satisfy it.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stoppard</ENAMEX>'s plays, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">messy</ENAMEX> and diffuse complexities of history, science, philosophy, and art are
tied into neat and compact parcels. The plays share a certain puzzlelike
quality; they are full of easy paradoxes and diverting logical conundrums.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX> belongs to an international literary tradition--call it brain-teaser
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modernism</ENAMEX>--whose theatrical godfather is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luigi Pirandello</ENAMEX>, and which includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge Luis Borges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Queneau</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italo Calvino</ENAMEX>. For
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, literature is a grand chess game of mental possibilities, an
irresistible occasion for philosophical showmanship. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX>, born Tomas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straussler</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>, has also shown some affinities with the
playful philosophical playwrights of his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carel Capek</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1920s</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavel Kohout</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Václav Havel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>.) But whereas
Borges at his best elicits from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> a shudder of metaphysical terror, and
Calvino stimulates a spasm of epistemological ecstasy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stoppard</ENAMEX> consistently
induces in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> a frisson of self-congratulatory pleasure.

            Stoppard, who started out as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and theater
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, turned to play writing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX>, at a moment when, as he once
said, "the least fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> was as fashionable as the most
fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>." When the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Theatre</ENAMEX> staged his first full-length
stage play, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rosencrantz and Guildenstern Are Dead</ENAMEX> , in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> (he had
previously done radio pieces for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>), he joined the fashionable ranks of
such <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">playwrights</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Ayckbourn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Pinter</ENAMEX>. Today,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosencrantz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guildenstern</ENAMEX> and the rest of his early work-- The Real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inspector Hound</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jumpers</ENAMEX> , as well as numerous short plays for
stage, television, and radio--are best appreciated as part of the golden age of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">silliness</ENAMEX>, a moment that produced such indelible monuments of the human
spirit as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Hard Day's Night</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty Python</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flying</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus</ENAMEX> .

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, Stoppard
augmented his play writing with screenwriting, enhancing his highbrow
reputation by supplying scripts for auteurs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainer Werner Fassbinder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Losey</ENAMEX>. (By then the least fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> was as fashionable as the
most fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> since, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX> has readily indulged
himself with hack work ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia House</ENAMEX> ), middlebrow entertainments
( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ), and pre- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in Love house calls as a
script <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana Jones</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Crusade</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> recently commissioned a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats screenplay</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX>. But while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX> has slummed a bit for the big screen, he has done
some of his most serious and demanding work for the small one: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional</ENAMEX>
Foul , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, addressed the moral dilemmas faced by a group
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> at a philosophical conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Squaring</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980-81</TIMEX> , broadcast in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, brought the playful
self-consciousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travesties</ENAMEX> to the deadly serious events
surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin Shipyard</ENAMEX> strike and the subsequent government
crackdown.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX> still scoffs at the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> can be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> of political awakening or social change: "If I wanted to change the
world," he once told an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>, "the last thing I would do is write a
play." "The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'role' of the</ENAMEX> theater," he has written, "is much debated (by almost
nobody, of course), but the thing defines itself in practice <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost
as a recreation. This seems satisfactory." Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX> has shown intermittent dissatisfaction with the kind of intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jeux d'esprit</ENAMEX> that made his name and has committed himself to a more
ambitious theater of ideas. The philosophical puzzles--about chance and order,
appearance and reality, science and art--are increasingly tethered, in plays
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Real Thing , Arcadia , and The Invention of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> , to a more conventionally theatrical register of feeling. As in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare in Love</ENAMEX>, we get smart fun and pathos too.

            But what we get is mostly less than meets the eye:
the erudition of the cocktail party and the emotional range of a good TV
sitcom, middlebrow pleasures dressed up in the trappings of high
learning--modernism without difficulty. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX> is often called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>
of ideas, but he is more accurately a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> of the idea of ideas, just as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare in Love</ENAMEX> is a movie for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in love with the idea of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX>, who will no doubt share screenwriting credit with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard</ENAMEX> in the film version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats</ENAMEX> , once referred to his poetry as a
"superior amusement," a description that applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoppard's</ENAMEX> plays as well:
They are amusing, and they make us feel superior.

         
      
   
