
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Quarterbacking</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX>
            

            An
editorial laments the mess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has made of war and
peace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> can claim vindication, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> dropped its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX>
demands for full access to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> and for an independence referendum in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> botched its central aim--prevention of ethnic cleansing--and bears some
responsibility for bombing fatalities. ... The cover story claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> brinkmanship spurred some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> concessions during negotiations, including the extra <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> for
withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and a trimmed demilitarized <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> did hold
its line in how it carved up peacekeeping zones: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> will govern the
region that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> coveted. ... Another piece suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Africans</ENAMEX> have less to celebrate about
their recent elections than they think. The peacefulness of the process would
seem to augur well for continued reconciliation. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' vast parliamentary majority will silence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>, and votes were
split neatly along racial lines.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story denounces the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>' prosecution of the
war and its settlement. A weaker <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will result from the idea that we can
triumph without peril to our armed forces. Air power only worked when combined
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> pressure on the ground and the threat of a ground invasion. The
settlement is fatally flawed: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> can't be trusted, ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combatants</ENAMEX> can't
coexist, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> will continue to agitate for their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">National</ENAMEX> sovereignty is overrated, according to an article . Supporting nationalist aspirations is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humanistic</ENAMEX> and consonant with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' rebellious roots. Plus, the
more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> splinter, the longer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will dominate the fractured world
stage. ... "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRB</ENAMEX> " bemoans the abolition of the draft. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> view
military engagements as distant exploits. A national service requirement would
relink <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compatriots</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s foreign
policy.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 13</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story follows a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s "harassment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>" as she
leads workshops, distributes pamphlets, and investigates complaints. Recent
legal decisions, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, have made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> liable
for indifference to sexual harassment among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Conclusion: Trying to
distinguish harassment from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> schoolyard taunts is a clumsy but
worthwhile process. ... College tuition is rising <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to three</NUMEX> times
faster than inflation, another piece reports. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explanations: Universities vie to</ENAMEX>
supply the most luxurious amenities; generous federal loans mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> can
afford higher tuition; and the steep fees are a way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> to have
wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> effectively subsidize poorer ones.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover package wraps up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>" series by profiling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> icons and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> lauds the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> as an embodiment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s courage and
diversity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Aaron celebrates Jackie Robinson</ENAMEX> for inspiring civil rights by breaching
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s color barrier. Others honored include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nehrus</ENAMEX> are rated the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>'s greatest dynasties. ... The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">100 Worst Ideas of the Century</ENAMEX>"
are also named, including <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition, The Jerry Springer Show</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barney,</ENAMEX>
and letting interns staff the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shutdown.
... An article dampens enthusiasm about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s victory. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>
drew a moral line against barbarism but failed in its primary aim, which was to
avert a humanitarian catastrophe. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is saddled with an unstable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and
an intact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story says stress causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>, memory loss,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immune deficiency</ENAMEX>, impaired cognition, and even a thick waist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> respond to
more stressors than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do, but their blood pressure spikes less in reaction.
Stressed-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are more likely to be listless when they're not tense and to
overreact as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. ... In an essay , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> urges "a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internationalism</ENAMEX>" based on values and law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West</ENAMEX> must start a moral crusade
to excise "the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> of ethnic conflict" by rebuilding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>,
strengthening the economies of southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and eventually welcoming
some more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. ... A glowing review of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> movie notes the campy
merchandising that accompanies it. Coming to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> near you: a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers Swedish Penis Enlarger</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX>
            

            The
already-outdated cover
story wonders if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> will hold. ... A
piece says the food-stamp program is funding the war in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. With poverty down, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are raiding food-stamp surpluses for
extra cash. ... An article examines the booming international car-theft
industry, which is virtually ignored by law enforcement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Vehicles</ENAMEX> are picked
off <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and smuggled abroad, where foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to three</NUMEX>
times a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> retail price for them. The most commonly stolen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda Accords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camrys</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece investigates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binjamin Wilomirski</ENAMEX>, author of a heart-rending, highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lauded</ENAMEX>, and completely fake memoir describing the atrocities he (never)
suffered as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> death <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. Wilomirski, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss Protestant</ENAMEX>
since birth, may be a charlatan, or he may simply be deluded. Most troubling is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s willingness to value the memoir's drama over its truthfulness.
... A survey of the nascent presidential race declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> ideologically indistinguishable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is so flourishing
"that politics has almost begun to seem irrelevant." ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
Remnick opines that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> have suffered from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">naiveté</ENAMEX> in general and from his seduction by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> fatalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Kaplan</ENAMEX> in particular. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s explication of the
debate that arose out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>'s work.)

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover package assesses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s coronation as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece
argues that "compassionate conservativism" is merely a loose translation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s triangulation and asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to flesh it out with specific
policy proposals. But another piece suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Lindsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s top
economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, is the very embodiment of the phrase. Despite his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedigree</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> ardently supports government assistance to the
underprivileged. ... An editorial crows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s capitulation
represents a triumph for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, hawkish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> relationship, and interventionism.

         
      
   
