
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  8MM
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX> plays a
straight-arrow private eye who enters the seamy world of hard-core porn in
pursuit of information about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in a snuff film. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' reactions are all
over the map. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> gives the film <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and says "it deals with
the materials of violent exploitation films, but in a non-pornographic way; it
would rather horrify than thrill ... it is a real film. Not a slick
exploitation film with all the trappings of depravity but none of the
consequences" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> take the exact
opposite stance: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX> calls it "an
unapologetically sleazy ordeal that delights in twisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>, a tawdry
piece of work whose only raison <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d'être</ENAMEX> is making the skin crawl in the name of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">box</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> profit." Most reactions to the film are negative, but each critic
cites a different flaw. Odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> out: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , so unfazed by the subject matter as to call the film "insipid" and
"mild." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
Cigarettes
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call this piece of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '80s</TIMEX>
nostalgia a "dismally unfunny farce" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ).
There are plenty of interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Ricci</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
Affleck, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janeane Garofalo</ENAMEX>), but the script, which follows a gaggle of young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> on their way to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> bash in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Village</ENAMEX>, is
said to be unsalvageable. The film's only high note is a soundtrack with some
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> songs that evoke the era better than any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> do. (Check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> on
the official site.)

            

               
                  The
               

               
                  Other
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista</ENAMEX>
Pictures). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sugarcoated</ENAMEX> and manipulative is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> describe this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> film about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mentally handicapped young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni Ribisi</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juliette Lewis</ENAMEX>) who fall in love. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX> lays into the film, saying it's
"shameless in its use of mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> as a gimmick, a prop, and a plot
device. Anyone with any knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> is likely to find this film
offensive" ( the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Those who condemn the film say its
real message is "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entally</ENAMEX> challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in love say the darnedest
things!" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). However, quite a few
softies like it: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ribisi</ENAMEX> eventually win you over" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ); "by the storybook conclusion I was cheering them on,
against all critical instinct" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Holden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> opens his review with what sounds like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joke</ENAMEX> ("A beautifully acted love story") but isn't; he's the film's biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>.
(Check
out this site devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ribisi.</ENAMEX>)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The Houdini
Girl
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martyn Bedford</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedford</ENAMEX>'s sophomore novel,
after the acclaimed Acts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revision</ENAMEX> , is called a gripping but flawed
work. The story follows a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magician</ENAMEX> uncovering the details of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s recent death and unpeeling the layers of deception that she had
wrapped herself in. The thriller side of the book is well crafted, and the
dialogue, pacing, and plotting keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> engaged: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX> is the genuine
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of unmistakable flair and accomplishment" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey Harrison</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ), but many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> say he does not show
the same skill level in revealing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' emotional lives. (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
[requires free registration].)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect Murder,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect Town</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Schiller</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>). Jumbled, messy, and
"frustrating to read" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) is
how most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> describe this rushed-to-press book about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>
murder. Not only does the book repeat and contradict itself, but the author
doesn't even try to offer an answer to the most essential question of all:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whodunit</ENAMEX>? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> speculate that the shoddiness is a result of the book
being published before it was ready, in order to fill the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> vacuum.
(Read this excerpt that ran in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  Not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX>
Nightingales
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). This
recently discovered early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Williams</ENAMEX> play has been stunningly
staged--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise the acting, direction, and costumes--but they debate
whether the work itself is amateurish or fully formed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> concedes that "there are definitely moments to wince
over" and that it is "the work of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> still unsure of his voice" but still
sees enough flashes of brilliance to make the performance worthwhile. Daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Isherwood</ENAMEX> agrees, saying the play "is manifestly not a
piece of juvenilia." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are less generous and note a heavy reliance
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">melodrama</ENAMEX> and film noir tropes; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fintan O'Toole</ENAMEX> writes
that the play is no "lost masterpiece." (Find out more
about the show at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  
                     Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jawbreaker</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Space</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Music--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Rock</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleater-Kinney</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Traveling Mercies: Some Thoughts on Faith</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Lamott</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Elegant Universe: Superstrings, Hidden Dimensions</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quest for the Ultimate Theory</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian R. Greene</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Blast From the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Past</TIMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Message in a Bottle ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Favorite Martian</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testament</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haruki</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  Death <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of a Salesman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene O'Neill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

            :

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Payback</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simply Irresistible</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Rushmore ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry Cleaning</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werewolves</ENAMEX> in Their Youth , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chabon</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- You're a Good Man</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  She's All That ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">24 Hour Woman</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Still <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- My Name Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Mothers Didn't Tell Us: Why Happiness</ENAMEX>
Eludes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Woman</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Crittenden</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabelle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Strout</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heavy Water</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
