
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;Nothing but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cash&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Devise a pair of words to fill in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> blanks--one word each--as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> cable, describes his shift away from the old
network economic model: "Our goal over time is to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> into __________
and __________."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 204</ENAMEX>)--"Stay!":
               

               

                  
                     Who said this to whom about what, "Keep on doing what you're
doing, and don't call us, we'll call you."
                  
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, shortly after her appalling discovery
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had promised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> a job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX> if only he
would sign the damn peace treaty."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Genome Project</ENAMEX> said it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Genome</ENAMEX> Project
when asked for advice."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, regarding his concerns about working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Van Dussen</ENAMEX>
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emperor</ENAMEX> told us that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> when they sent us to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>. Now you say the
war is over? I wonder why he didn't call."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ballard</ENAMEX>
               

               "Oh my
God! The call is coming from inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Watched</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX> " Fredericksen
               

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

               Instead of our regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> work, let's go outside
under the big, old dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">elm</ENAMEX> and show a filmstrip, i.e., let's quote a few
highlights from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Weiner</ENAMEX>'s dark and charming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> obit
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Gottlieb</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>, Dies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Took LSD</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>," an account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ran MKUltra</ENAMEX>, a project that dosed unsuspecting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with hallucinogenic
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>.

               

                  "In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case, a mental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> was dosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX> continuously
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">174 days</TIMEX>."

                  "The experiments were useless."

                  "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> awarded Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distinguished Intelligence Medal</ENAMEX> and
deliberately destroyed most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MKUltra</ENAMEX> records in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>."

                  " 'Gottlieb never did what he did for inhumane reasons,' Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marks</ENAMEX>
said."

                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX> ... developed a poison <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">handkerchief</ENAMEX> to kill an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX>, an
array of toxic gifts to be delivered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>, and a poison dart to kill
a leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>. None of the plans succeeded."

                  "He bought land with an old log <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> outside a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, where he practiced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of his lifelong hobbies, folk dancing and
herding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX>."

                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> alike say Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX> was
a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>."

               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Arch</ENAMEX>'s
Answer
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> said it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John O'Connor</ENAMEX>
about his offer to resign as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, on turning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX> submitted a
pro forma resignation, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> law requires, and received the above
reply. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, in what was seen as a sign of his impending retirement, he
invited all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> in the archdiocese to see him celebrate the Chrism
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

               "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> turns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>," says archdiocese
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Zwilling</ENAMEX>, "and I think many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cardinal</ENAMEX>
expect that will pretty much mark the end of his term as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX>."

               With its characteristic
accent on youth, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> prohibits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinals</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX> to hold certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
or vote for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>. Before accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>'s resignation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> is
expected to name a successor to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hickey</ENAMEX>.

               
                  Movie Math
Extra
               

               Match the numbers with
the movie lore they enumerate. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> refer to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> movies produced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> (i.e., excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line</ENAMEX> among others.)

               
                  The
Numbers
               

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52.7 million</NUMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25.3 million</NUMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.95 billion</NUMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.48 billion</NUMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. 34,168

               
                  The
Lore
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> Total cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX> rationalizations.

               B. Average production cost of a movie.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> Average marketing cost of a movie.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> Total engineering cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, a giant talking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese sandwich</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Number</ENAMEX> of movie screens in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Number</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who've dozed during a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX> movie.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Number</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who envied those dozing
through a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> movie.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H. Box</ENAMEX> office receipts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. Insured value of Meg Ryan</ENAMEX>'s perkiness.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Admissions</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.

               
                  The
Answers
               

               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-B,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-C, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3-H</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-E.</ENAMEX>
               

               
                  Fun
Fact
               

               During the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>
sweeps period, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> most watched programs on cable TV were wrestling
shows.

               
                  Common
Denominator
               

               That scamp <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and her sexual shenanigans.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
