
   
   
      
         
            <EM>Mummy</EM> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soup</ENAMEX>, With <EM>Onion</EM>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  The Mummy
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>
("What grand, ghoulish gore!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> )
are outnumbered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> ("hopelessly overwrought and deeply dopey,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ), who say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) it's not remotely scary; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sarcasm</ENAMEX> and self-conscious irony grow tiresome; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) it's permeated with
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> racism; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) the mummy isn't a real mummy, he's "a mutating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Light</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Special Effect"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>,

                  Slate
               ), or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX> writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]f
you made a nourishing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> out of white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX> ,
this fellow is what you would find at the bottom of the pot." (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>).
"The movie is a disappointment. A big one" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> run negative early reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menace</ENAMEX> , complaining that the film is dialogue-heavy, not especially
exciting, and marred by weak acting. Both agree that the fight scenes, an
extended desert chase sequence, and the special effects and scenery are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">top-notch</ENAMEX>. The reviews mention in passing that this disappointment is a natural
result of the advance hype but don't mention their own roles in generating that
hype. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX> opens his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> review with this questionable line:
"To get in, you needed a ticket, more precious than a passport out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>."
(Find out the latest news on the film on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). Good reviews for this corny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capra</ENAMEX>-esque
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> comedy about a working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s fight to keep its precious but
hilariously tacky home from being demolished for an airstrip. The film is "[a]
triumph of sustained silliness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Seiler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ), which pokes
fun at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s bad taste while elevating their home-grown values and
simple familial love. On the down side, the film's pretty much a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-trick
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pony</ENAMEX>: It "continually dares us to sneer at their garish tastes" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Holden, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Somehow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> come out smiling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anyhow</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to watch the trailer.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricky Martin</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Martin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are feasting
on the English-language debut of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menudo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. The album itself is deemed passable musically--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> has a
"serviceable" voice (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ) and a set of reasonably
catchy tunes. But what's really on sale is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> himself. Going for him: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
infectious charisma as seen at his terrific performance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammys</ENAMEX> and
which is constantly on display on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) boyish good looks--he was named one
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People 's</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">50 Most Beautiful People"</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) he's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>. Also important is the press's hunger for a new trend to write about,
which has led to the recent designation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> music as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Big Thing</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s poppy crossover album is just what they're looking for. (This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> has photos, sound
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clips</ENAMEX>, and info on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Publication
            

            

               The Onion
               . The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>,-based satiric
newspaper/Web site rides a wave of recent publicity: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Dumb Century</ENAMEX>
(written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>) is now No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' paperback
best-seller list, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Dikkers</ENAMEX> appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conan O'Brien</ENAMEX>'s
show, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> has signed a deal to make a series of TV specials.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> attributes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onion</ENAMEX> 's wildly popular deadpan
humor to its location. "Instead of allowing itself to be sliced, diced,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sautéed</ENAMEX>, and served up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spago</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balthazar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Onion</ENAMEX> , by just sitting
out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, has grown into something large, beautiful and
strange-shaped, like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-H</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> exhibit with a blue ribbon on it at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin State Fair</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the latest online issue.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Town</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Kidder</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidder</ENAMEX>'s
exploration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northampton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, interesting but unfocused. He writes mainly
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy O'Connor</ENAMEX>, but his story is interspersed with tangents
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s history and various oddball local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Yagoda</ENAMEX> writes
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , "somewhere along the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidder</ENAMEX> must
have decided not to write a book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy O'Connor</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidder</ENAMEX>'s reporting, but most find the discursive style slow going. (Listen to an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidder</ENAMEX> about how he decided to write
this book. [Requires free registration.])

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drowning People</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mason</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>). The 21-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and good looks are cited as major factors in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockbuster</ENAMEX> advance (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX>) and ballyhooed publication of this ponderous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gothic</ENAMEX> novel. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are not amused. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX> calls it
a "hokey tragic romance" and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Friedman</ENAMEX>
says it "reads like a high school essay--'write the story as if you were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte Brontë</ENAMEX>.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> gives the book its only upbeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>, praising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>'s "compelling voice" and calling the author
"remarkably assured." (Read an excerpt from the book here.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgments</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Movie
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Midsummer Night's Dream</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Searchlight Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediocre</ENAMEX> reviews for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> millionth recent film
adaptation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> play. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> is posh (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calista Flockhart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kline</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Everett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Tucci</ENAMEX>), but the magic never
quite gels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kline</ENAMEX> is singled out for his excellent Bottom. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s in

                  Slate
               .)

            
               Book
            

            
               
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dangerous</ENAMEX>
Friend
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX> Just (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polite</ENAMEX> reviews for
Just's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 th</NUMEX> novel, which follows a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> working for a
nongovernmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann</ENAMEX>-Haupt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">raves</ENAMEX> ("extraordinary") in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
