
   
   
      
         
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> declared "peace," said it had negotiated a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">accord</ENAMEX> with ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim Rugova</ENAMEX>, urged ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to return to their homes, and called further <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing an assault
on "peace, unity, and understanding." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> ridiculed the
statements as lies, inadequate concessions, and a "charm offensive." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
said the bombing has now cut off supplies to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> said the news comes too late, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> has already been ethnically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cleansed</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Having closed the borders through which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> had been fleeing,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> sent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> spin:
We're welcoming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> back. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> spin: This is part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' pretense of reconciliation. The completely cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> spin: The
Serbs need the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> as human shields. (Check out "" for

                  Slate
               's latest coverage.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> 
               is ratcheting up its threats 
               against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> over the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
would "not permit" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to send in ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> its
"protectorate." Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> the targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> .
This raised alarms throughout the world, until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> retracted
the claim and explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> had merely discussed the targeting option.
The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is pretending to entertain this option to placate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hard-liners</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He's nuts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) He's playing his usual cagey game. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) He doesn't
understand that you don't play games with nukes. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rongji</ENAMEX> failed to agree on terms for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Backstage</ENAMEX> reports say that the deal is nearly complete but
that the hostile atmosphere in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, particularly over reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
espionage at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>, makes it futile for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to push <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
admission now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu</ENAMEX>, who is visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, told reporters that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) he has
"no knowledge" of the alleged nuclear espionage; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) he is "impatient" to
improve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s human rights practices; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) if he had meant to influence the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> presidential election, he would have shelled out a lot more than the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China</ENAMEX> is accused of funneling to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. While holding
out against lucrative trade concessions demanded by Wall Street and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu</ENAMEX> is offering to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> own <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> cell phone
and Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, which presumably would undermine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s ability to
quash domestic dissent. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will take this deal because we
care about freedom. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) We'll reject it because we care about money.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The Y2K
"conceive-a-thon" is on. Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 9</TIMEX> the
conception date most likely to lead to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> born on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2000</TIMEX>, and
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> are reportedly competing for the honor/shame. The most
charming/egregious case is a contest among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, selected by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
radio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> from among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX>, to conceive the "millennium
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>" in separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. If any of the couples
succeeds, the radio station will pay a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> prize. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> says
she asked her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, "How does it feel to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's going to be
in the public and everybody knows that she's going to have sex <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>?"
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> offered interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> advice about ovulation and timing,
concluding: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX>, start your engines." The spins on the race:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) It's grand and fascinating. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's sick and pitiable. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It's sick and
fascinating. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/9/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missouri</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> rejected a ballot measure 
               that would have allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to
carry concealed handguns . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX> had spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to promote the measure. The sunny spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's a victory over the gun
nuts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's a victory over big money. The cynical spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's a victory
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>militia <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> spawned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
It's a victory for a well-funded scare campaign led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. The
political analyses: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's a victory for suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/7/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> found
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three 500-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inca</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mummies</ENAMEX> on top of a volcano in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>. After
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incas</ENAMEX> were ritually sacrificed, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> quickly froze in the cold
weather, leaving them so well preserved that their internal organs remain
intact and the hair on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> is still visible. Religious artifacts that
were evidently part of the sacrifice were also recovered. The anthropological
spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mummies</ENAMEX> will teach us all about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inca</ENAMEX> religious practices. The medical
spin: They'll teach us all about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inca</ENAMEX> diet, health, and genetics. The cynical
spin: We owe it all to human sacrifice. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/7/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> 
               finally 
               handed over the 
               suspects
in the 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lockerbie</ENAMEX> bombing case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> blew up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> plane
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, most of them <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basset Ali al-Megrahi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamen Khalifa Fhimah</ENAMEX>, were sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>,
where they will be tried under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> law. In exchange, the 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> 
               has lifted sanctions it imposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> to punish
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> for sheltering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>. The spins, in order of descending optimism:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) It's a landmark in the establishment of effective international law. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's
a triumph of negotiating perseverance by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> are convicted, the bombing's
true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mastermind</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar Qaddafi</ENAMEX>, will escape justice.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Serial 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> spreader <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nushawn Williams</ENAMEX> 
               was
sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four to 12 years</TIMEX> in jail. He was accused of infecting at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> by knowingly exposing them to the virus through unprotected
sex in exchange for providing illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to them. His sentence is part of a
deal in which he pleaded guilty to statutory rape and reckless endangerment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' excuse for continuing to have unprotected sex after a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> told him
he had the virus is that he didn't believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s spin:
"He's not an evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. ... He feels badly that he's ill. He expressed to me
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> he may not live out his sentence." The naive retributive spin: He
should have been sentenced to death. The sophisticated spin: He has been.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               The 
               alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melissa</ENAMEX> virus was
busted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David L. Smith</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX>, was arrested on
charges of conspiracy, theft of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, and interruption of public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX>. The virus jammed up the Internet by replicating itself in
multiple e-mails it transmitted from infected computers. The dramatic spin:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> is an ingenious villain, and the computer security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that pursued
him were ingenious sleuths using sophisticated technology and techniques. The
boring spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-old</TIMEX> bankrupt nerd, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America Online</ENAMEX> turned
him in by letting law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> see the log that showed which phone
line had been used to post the virus. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
