
   
   
      
         
            Suffocating the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> made
a comeback on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s front pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straw</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> extradition proceedings against him could go
ahead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> claimed that it would now be "several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>" before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">83-year-old</TIMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> would either be sent
for trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> or freed. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> decision was warmly
welcomed. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s
said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the mere fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> is to be
subjected to extradition proceedings constitutes "an irreversible victory for
the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." It represents "the birth of an effective universal
jurisdiction for dealing with crimes against humanity and, at the same time, an
unequivocal warning that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> will not be a refuge for
blood-stained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>."

            In another editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> said much the same thing, welcoming the
arrival of "a supranational judicial structure that will be able from now on to
knock down the protective barriers that tyrants throughout the world have
erected around themselves." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> welcomed the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>--had failed in
their efforts to get him freed.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> took the opposite view. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> called
Straw "a straw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" and ridiculed his claim to have made his decision "with an
open mind." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> does not allow his open mind to
be troubled by the fact that, long after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> peacefully relinquished
power, his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> are pleading for his return. Nor does the damage
inflicted by the affair on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> national interests, already palpable in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falklands</ENAMEX> and on our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 million pounds</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$320</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>], disturb the peace of the ministerial open mind." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Mail quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straw</ENAMEX> had "demeaned his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>" with a
vindictive decision.

            The main story across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, though, was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s admission
that it accidentally bombed a refugee <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. This gave rise to much
comment that clean wars don't exist and renewed support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s decision to
continue the bombing. "Wars mean casualties" said the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , calling
once again for the deployment of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. And the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> had an
editorial saying exactly the same thing: "If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> is to blame for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carnage</ENAMEX>, then that has only underscored the inadequacy of air power. Forces on
the ground is becoming urgent." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said the West has no choice but to
continue fighting and quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proven√</ENAMEX>ßal proverb: "Once one has started
suffocating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, one has to finish it." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> press reported broad
support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bundestag</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s commitment to the war and noted
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> reservations about its peace plan.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> reported huge flight
delays in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> because of congestion in the skies caused by military aircraft
bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> domestic civilian flights are now departing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX>, it said. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>'s world affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX>, was coming under fierce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> government criticism for "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> bias"
in his coverage from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>. "In an astonishing attack, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
accused him of presenting at face value claims by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> about damage done
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> attacks, being grossly simplistic in suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> assault
has united the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, and of swallowing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
propaganda about the impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>'s air raids," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said. In an
editorial, the paper defended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s reporting from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, but attacked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> for being so quick to blame <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> for the deaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in
the disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> incident.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s
inordinately clumsy handling of the news when it first broke must have left
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> weeping tears of joy," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
had no evidence at that time to show who was to blame, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacon "</ENAMEX>did the credibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX> nothing but harm by alleging that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> had done the killing themselves to embarrass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disastrously</ENAMEX> gave the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> might stoop to the black propaganda
at which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> excels."

            
According to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX>, certain
"rebel" worker <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> have found ways of breeding in defiance of the convention
that only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">queen bees</ENAMEX> are allowed to reproduce. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Oldroyd</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Herald</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that in normal bee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> only the queen is
allowed to lay <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, and if worker <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> lay their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, they are destroyed in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX>, which can identify the queen's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> by a special
chemical she marks them with. Because of a genetic mutation, however, certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> are able to put a fake royal marker on their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, making other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> think
they are the queen's. The forgery enables a worker bee's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> to survive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thrive</ENAMEX>, and reproduce, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oldroyd</ENAMEX> said.

             

         
      
   
