
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolls</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, an alcoholic,
mentally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Exley</ENAMEX> published a "fictional memoir" whose
subject was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> manhood as embodied by football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX>. The
book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A Fan's Notes</ENAMEX> , became a cult classic and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Gifford</ENAMEX> is
everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> will never be: graceful, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted</ENAMEX>, daring, physically perfect.
writes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX>'s standing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, "I know of no way of describing
this phenomenon short of equating it with being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican</ENAMEX>." And
once, when their paths crossed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> writes, he wanted to shout at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">godlike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, "Listen, you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a bitch, life isn't all a goddam football
game! You won't always get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>! Life is rejection and pain and loss."

            Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX>, who died
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX>, feel pity and fear for the life <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX> now leads as the
consort of monomaniacal talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and tabloid cover girl <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX>? Would he revel in or lament <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> emasculation by
humiliation from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> because he had a one-night stand with a megamammaried
miss? What would Exley make of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s story in the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> on the nightmare of being married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> by her first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX>, who offers this observation, "I see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX> with
the same confused look on his face that I used to get. To me it clearly says,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'What</ENAMEX> hit me? How do I get out of here?' "

            The tabs recently have been offering a series of unhappy
meditations on the nature of masculinity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. For example, also walking that
long <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from gridiron glory to gelding is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Namath</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX>. His 37-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was so bored watching him golf away his retirement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , that she fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Namath</ENAMEX>. She is now dating plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Novack</ENAMEX>, who is,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, "a renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in penis and breast
enhancement." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Namath</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> reports, is "devastated." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broadway Joe</ENAMEX>
should have seen it coming. When he got married, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>,
now she calls herself <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tatiana</ENAMEX>. Any divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> can tell you that when Debbie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">becomes Tatiana</ENAMEX>, it's time to freeze your bank accounts.

            The news about young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manhood</ENAMEX> is no more encouraging. According to the tabs, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idols</ENAMEX> are as
exciting in the sack as a sack of wet oatmeal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> barmaid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linnea Dietrichson</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> picked her up at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX> and took her back to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. "He looked flabby and pale. He
was drunk and fumbling. It lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX> fell asleep."
Devastating as this revelation is, it is unlikely to appreciably affect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX>'s ability to lure more barmaids up for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> fumble.

            And according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> had to hire "sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX>" in order to show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole</ENAMEX>
Kidman how to make love on camera for the film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> . According
to an "insider" on the set of the sexually explicit movie, the real-life couple
was "totally unconvincing as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX> had absolutely no
chemistry." So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Duffield</ENAMEX>, who had sex <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times a day for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> documentary series (maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> could broadcast this during
pledge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>), were brought in as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>. "They had a good look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX> and then they shook their heads and kinda winced," reports the
Star . "They took over the set and showed how it was really done."

            On to the self-pitying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weenie Fabio</ENAMEX>. The long-haired model was hit in the nose by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> while
promoting a roller coaster ride at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Busch Gardens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. Since he
dispatched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> with his own bare beak, did he proudly roast the bird and
serve it for dinner? No, he took to his bed. "He's still too shook up to talk,"
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flora</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . "He's been in bed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>!"
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fabio</ENAMEX> complained, "It's not funny--I could have lost my model good looks."
Let's see, he was hit in the schnoz by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> and had to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stitches</ENAMEX>. If you cast your gaze over the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, you'd be hard pressed to
find anything that is a starker example of tragedy.

            How about the fatuous? According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> says he will marry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> if she promises to "lose and keep
off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an extra five</NUMEX> pounds that always seem to plague her." In turn, he promises
to give up drinking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> does not say that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aniston</ENAMEX> keeps off the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> pounds, he promises not to grow hair out of his ears or ever say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>,
can you squeeze this thing on my back?" According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , the
reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> is hesitating to marry the eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aniston</ENAMEX> is that he is afraid of
alienating his gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>.

            More charming are the
merely naughty. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> published an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsourced</ENAMEX> item claiming that an unnamed potential presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> was
worried that a picture of this youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPC</ENAMEX> dancing nude on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> was out there
somewhere. Well, now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> has revealed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPC</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. (Keeping Tabs was hoping it was the too-perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>
but is also relieved it wasn't the so-far-from-perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ominously</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> has denied the story by saying, "Yeah, and green
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have landed on the lawn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>." It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX> who used almost the same space alien dismissal when stories of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s affair <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> broke in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> .

            Then there are the creeps. Perennial bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Busey</ENAMEX> is
again trying to put his marriage back together in his unique way, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busey</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>, married his latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tiani</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>, he was
addicted to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. But even after he stopped taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, he continued to be
abusive to her. Tiani started reading codependency books by best-selling author
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melody Beattie</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> eventually met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, who, according to
Tiani, "bonded really well with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>. She was helping us through some rough
times." Then, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, he was arrested for beating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiani</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busey</ENAMEX>'s
bonding with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beattie</ENAMEX> continued apace when he moved into her home. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
insists, however, that there's nothing going on between them and that he is
totally focused on repairing his marriage. Toward that end, he tells the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , "I'm going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> Quatrine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> for anger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management classes</ENAMEX>." Maybe something beautiful will come of all this. It's hard
not to get choked up when you read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busey</ENAMEX>'s promise to his estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, "I'll
be there when the restraining order has expired."

            Perhaps only the antics
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Redgrave</ENAMEX>'s estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> could top that. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Clark</ENAMEX>, who has been married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 30</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, fathered a child <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX> by his personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>. (Note to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>: Try to hire someone who looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Hellman</ENAMEX> to be your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>.) The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicolette</ENAMEX>, kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s
identity as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> a secret and went on to marry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> found out he was married to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of his
stepbrother, he insisted that the truth be revealed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicolette</ENAMEX> split,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicolette</ENAMEX> began seeing a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plumber</ENAMEX> who was doing work on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">house.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> demanded that the plumber not hang around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicolette</ENAMEX> and their son
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolette</ENAMEX> got so angry she filed a restraining order against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>. He
retaliated by filing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> against her. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, the whole sordid mess comes
down to this: "If I didn't have a prostate condition that plumber would never
have gotten close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicolette</ENAMEX>. But sadly, I haven't had sex in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> also expressed the hope that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX> could continue with their
marriage. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, they couldn't.

            OK, maybe someone can top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Busey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX>. That is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Richey</ENAMEX>, widower of country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Wynette</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wynette</ENAMEX>'s funeral
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richey</ENAMEX> virtually had to be kept from jumping in her grave after her.
Now it appears that he may have been simply assuring himself she really was
dead, at least according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wynette</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, who have filed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>
million wrongful death suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richey</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. The suit, reports the
Star , claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richey</ENAMEX> ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wynette</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s advice that she be given
immediate medical attention (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 miles</NUMEX> away), and instead
continued to administer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX>--which had been prescribed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>--to
the failing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>. According to published reports in the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX>
was not called until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wynette</ENAMEX>'s death, nor was an autopsy
performed.

            Do the tabloids offer any hope for the male of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>? Just this promise for the future. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> is adopting yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, and she plans to name this one after her
late former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. Welcome to the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra Farrow</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
