
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">244</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS Eyes Are Smiling&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Fill in the blank
on this tax tip from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> collection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. "If you don't
want to pay your taxes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> all you have to do is say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> magic words:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">_________ _________</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 243</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Crush on You":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     "All great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> have known that feared
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> must be crushed completely." Who served up this baloney on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, to
inspire whom, to do what?
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader of the Makah tribe</ENAMEX>, inspiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> armed with pointed spears and
high-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> to tear into the 'feared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>,' who was, at that moment,
peacefully sorting baleen."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Shuger</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'voices</ENAMEX>' telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Van Ark</ENAMEX> to liberate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, in yet
another strange twist on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Knots Landing</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> explains why the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is funding research on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crushinator 6000</ENAMEX>, an alternative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crushinator</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>
Bu
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, to all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, to finally get those <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. (The head <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> learned
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> from a very cool <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Kamensky</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>, on using the proper blender setting for pulverizing 'those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">f**</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> tomato skins.' She gets a little obsessive about her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koegel</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Oder</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            With the glorious
exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crispin</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> speech from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> , there is nothing
more demoralizing than an inspirational address. That sort of thing generally
entails a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> or an east regional sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> exhorting you to do something
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pointless</ENAMEX>, painful, or profitable to someone else. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physics</ENAMEX> has few
inspirational speeches: Unify that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field Theory</ENAMEX>! Writing novels, performing
surgery, preparing a light and elegant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soufflé</ENAMEX>--each must be done without
rousing declamation. Sex sometimes includes a heartening oration, but usually
toward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, urging you on to mutual victory; such remarks are rarely
delivered at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">halftime</TIMEX>, when you're lurking in the locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, glum and
battered. (The exception here is phone sex, where the inspirational speech
pretty much is the sex.) "For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>"--that's what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gladiators</ENAMEX> used to say. Not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> seek inspiration from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, although a surprising number do seek sex there, frequently for money.
But they think themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accurs'd</ENAMEX> and hold their manhoods cheap. Poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bastards</ENAMEX>.

            
               Motivational
Answer
            

            Coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Riley</ENAMEX> tried to
inspire his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Miami Heat</ENAMEX> to beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX>. They didn't.

            
               From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad to Verse</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Below, a new form of cut and paste poetry.

            The rules:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> lines, each with the same number of words.

               The words in each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> must originally appear adjacent to each other in a
newspaper headline.

               The headlines must all come from a single edition of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>.

            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Daredevil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soprano</ENAMEX>
Cow valve
Heart boy
Smart toilet

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18, 1999</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX> mental patient
Crack, not ping
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> awaits fate

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18, 1999</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit similar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poems</ENAMEX>.

            Also welcome--a good
name for this verse form.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Personification of uncompromising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">belligerence</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>.

            Close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner/Katzenberg</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
