
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee Go Home</ENAMEX>

            Every
time the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> goes into battle, anti-war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> blame the causes
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> of the conflict on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. They excuse the enemy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regime</ENAMEX>'s aggression and insist that it can be trusted to negotiate and honor a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> resolution. While doing everything they can to hamstring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
administration's ability to wage the war, they argue that the war can never be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s claims to the contrary are lies, and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> should trim its absurd demands and bug out with whatever
face-saving deal it can get. In past wars, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> accused these domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of sabotaging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> morale and aiding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. But in this war,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> aren't bashing the anti-war movement. They're leading it.

            Last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>--went on television to discuss the war.
Here's what they said.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               The atrocities are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s fault. "Once
the bombing commenced, I think then [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> unleashed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>,
and then that's when the slaughtering and the massive ethnic cleansing really
started," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickles</ENAMEX> said at a news conference after appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press . "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s campaign has been a disaster. ... [It]
escalated a guerrilla warfare into a real war, and the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> and innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>." On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> blamed the
ethnic cleansing on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intervention. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s bombing campaign has caused
all of these problems to explode," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> charged in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor speech
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">replayed on Late Edition</ENAMEX> .

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The failure of diplomacy to avert the war is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
fault. "I had doubts about the bombing campaign from the beginning,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> offered on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> . "I didn't think we had done enough in the
diplomatic area." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickles</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s prewar peace proposal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> "a
very arrogant agreement" that "really caused this thing to escalate."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should not support the war. When
asked whether they would authorize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "to use all necessary force to win
this war, including ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickles</ENAMEX> --who had voted a month
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, along with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, not to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> air
campaign--said they wouldn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickles</ENAMEX> questioned the propriety of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
objectives," calling its goal of "access to all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> ... ludicrous."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, voted not only against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> resolution
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authorizing Clinton</ENAMEX> to conduct the air war--which failed on a tie vote--but
also in favor of legislation "directing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ... to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Forces</ENAMEX> from their positions in connection with the present <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Republic of Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>." When asked whether he had lobbied his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to defeat the resolution authorizing the air war, as had been
reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> conceded that he had "talked to a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> during the
vote" but claimed not to have swayed anyone since it was "a vote of
conscience."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. We can't win. "I don't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> will ever raise
a white flag," warned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickles</ENAMEX>. DeLay agreed: "He's stronger in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> now than
he was before the bombing. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are rallying around him like
never before. He's much stronger with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and others." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
"has no plan for the end" and "recognizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> will still be in
power," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>. "The bombing was a mistake. ... And this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ought
to show some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and admit it, and come to some sort of negotiated
end."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. 
               Don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> propaganda. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underestimated NATO</ENAMEX>'s resolve more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> had underestimated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice chairman</ENAMEX> Gen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Ralston</ENAMEX> asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "had
already started his campaign of killing" before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> intervened. Nickles
dismissed both arguments. "This war is not going well," he declared. "I heard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> say, 'Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> miscalculated how, you know, steadfast we
would be in the bombing campaign.' But frankly ... we grossly miscalculated
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s response would be." Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickles</ENAMEX> volunteered, "I would take
a little issue with [what] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralston</ENAMEX> said. ... The number of killings prior
to the bombing, I think, has been exaggerated." Moreover, given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
desperate need to "bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to the table," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> cautioned, "It is not
helpful for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s spin machine to be out there right now saying that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is weakening." The truth, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>, is that "nothing has
changed."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Give peace a chance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> said it was "highly unlikely"
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s release of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> captured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> were
continuing their atrocities and weren't offering to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s conditions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> called this refusal "really disappointing" and a failure of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.
... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ought to open up negotiations and come to some sort of
diplomatic end." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott implored Clinton</ENAMEX> to "give peace a chance" and, comparing
the war with the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> high-school shootings, urged him to resolve
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict with "words, not weapons."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. 
               We have no choice but to compromise.
Unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> finds "a way to get the bombing stopped" and to "get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
to pull back his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>" voluntarily, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> faces "a quagmire ... a long,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protracted</ENAMEX>, bloody war," warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "only has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> choices," said
DeLay--to "occupy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> out" or "to negotiate some sort
of diplomatic end, diplomatic agreement in order to end this failed
policy."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>.
We're eager to compromise. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has insisted all along that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> must
allow a well-armed international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to protect the ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>. When asked whether "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> ought to insist" that these
requirements "be met" as a condition of negotiation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> twice ducked the
question. Nickles advocated "a compromise," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> expressed interest in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s proposal for a "lightly armed" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
rather than a fully equipped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. "Surely there's wiggle room," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>. "Obviously, [the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>] don't want them heavily armed, but they've
got to be armed sufficiently to protect themselves. ... So, I think something
can be worked out."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. 
               We'll back off <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Nickles discounted
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> halt its ethnic cleansing in order
to halt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombardment: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> says, 'Well, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has to
do all these things, then we'll stop the bombing.' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>, I strongly believe we
need a simultaneous withdrawal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, have a
stopping of the bombing, and an insertion of international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>-keeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s formulation put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>: "Let's see if we can't
find a way to get the bombing stopped, get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to pull back his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>,
find a way to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> [to] go back in." And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> suggested that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> should pull out unilaterally: "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> saw that he had
made a mistake putting our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> ... he admitted the mistake, and
he withdrew from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>."

            Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who make these arguments unpatriotic. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
reply that they're serving their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by debunking and thwarting a bad
policy administered by a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. You can be sure of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> things:
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is arguing exactly the opposite of what it argued the last time a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> into war, and exactly the opposite of what
it will argue next time.

         
      
   
