
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muteness</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince George</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that he is forming a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to explore whether he
should run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. After a parade of adulatory speeches from committee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, he fielded questions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked whether abortion should be
illegal in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trimester. "That's a hypothetical question," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.
What about global economic instability<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "I won't have specific remedies or
specific suggestions until I start moving around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> replied.
Should we build a missile defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> even if it violates the anti-ballistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">missile treaty</ENAMEX>? "I will be glad to answer all those questions once I get out in
the course of the campaign," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> offered, ending the press conference.

            What a charade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
"campaign" has been underway for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. He has plotted strategy, assembled a
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, pitched to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, courted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, and written letters to
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> expect to collect <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of March</TIMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three months</TIMEX>, his "exploratory" committee
will raise money and build a campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> remains clueless about
many national issues and, on others, he knows he can only lose votes by being
pinned down. Moreover, the longer he postpones his candidacy, the longer he
deprives his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> of a target, thereby starving them to death. For these
reasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is claiming immunity to policy questions. And he's getting away
with it, thanks to several excuses.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. I'm doing my job. At his press
conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> refused to answer questions about tax cuts and other "issues"
until <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> finishes its legislative session in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. He explained that being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> is his "job" and that he had promised <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> he would stay home
through the session. "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who does in office what I say I will do," he
insisted. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the exploratory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, seemed deeply moved. "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s keeping his commitment to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> shows what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> is," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbour</ENAMEX>.

            Lest anyone contemplate
the convenience of this excuse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> spun it as a sacrifice. He regretted that
he wouldn't be "able" to visit key primary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. "Some have said,
'Well, you're gonna be too late in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,' " he lamented. But "I've got a
job to do." The press swallowed this line whole. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "is understandably
reluctant to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> at least until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> concludes its work,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> . "He has defied conventional wisdom by
refusing to travel the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to raise money and court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Read my principles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> outlined his
"core, conservative principles"--"limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>," "low taxes," "free and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> trade," "local control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>," "strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>," and "personal
responsibility." When asked about specific issues, he referred back to his
principles. "How exactly do you plan to preserve the prosperity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>?" asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. "When I start to emerge out of the state after the
legislative session," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, "I'm going to lay out an economic stimulus
package that will do just that. You heard the principles by which I'll be
making decisions." On foreign policy, he said only that his "framework" would
emphasize what's "good for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Read my testimonials. To
deflect scrutiny from his own views, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> stacked his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
can vouch for him. At the press conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of
state, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shultz</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, Condoleeza
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>, vouched for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s toughness on foreign policy. Reps. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Bonilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, vouched for his racial inclusiveness.
Pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Dunn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, vouched for his belief in individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> would do about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s meltdown, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
cited his "principles," babbled about missile defense, and said, "I of course
will be relying upon the briefings on details from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>."
With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> like these, who needs positions? "He has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shultz</ENAMEX>
advising him on foreign policy," observed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> with delight.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> moves
serve him particularly well on social issues. He has conspicuously courted
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> he
made a pilgrimage to coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>. Without publicly
embracing any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>'s positions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> elicited from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> the
magic words, "He loves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>." Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are particularly excited
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s recruitment of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Gerson</ENAMEX>.
Noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerson "</ENAMEX>wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> speech in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barnes inferred on Meet the Press</ENAMEX> that "one issue on which we're going
to hear a lot from [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>] is cultural conservatism."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Read my polls. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s advantages
lie in politics rather than policy, he steers attention to his campaign
juggernaut rather than to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on this stage
represent the best of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>," he boasted at his press
conference. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blunt, R-Mo.</ENAMEX>, handed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> who have already endorsed your candidacy," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
distributed a similar list to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> chat shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marveled at Bush</ENAMEX>'s deluge of endorsements, his bottomless coffers, and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">godlike</ENAMEX> standing in the polls. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> never explicitly brings up money or polls,
because he doesn't have to. But he counts on them to keep the press pining for
him while he stiffs policy questions.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.

               Shame on you. When pressured to clarify his
positions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> morphs the question into attack politics and attack journalism.
"I will campaign on my beliefs and my principles, and I will not engage in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">petty</ENAMEX> politics of personal destruction," he insisted. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked him
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> who associate him with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s moderation.
"I'm going to try to work hard not to play the typical political game of
tearing down your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> sniffed, "and I would hope others wouldn't
tear down my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> provide another handy shield. "I
had doubts and concerns about what a campaign would mean for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>," he
confided to the assembled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribes</ENAMEX>. "I convinced my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that I love her and
I'll always love her. That's the only thing that'll overcome the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>-grinding
aspects of national politics." From the podium, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> front <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, implored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> to endure the
campaign's "trial by fire." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has milked this protective anguish for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.
Never mind that according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , he privately told several financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, "I love my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. And I love my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>. ... But they
don't have a veto on this."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s portrayal of substantive interrogation as
nasty nit-picking has completely suckered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reported that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> were trying to "pose litmus-test questions" and "tear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> down."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> accused them of "picking at his credentials" and warned, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
will accept only so much battering." Quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>'s demand
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "take some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>" on "abortion, taxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> rights,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> groaned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan "</ENAMEX>seems poised for another round of
bashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX>." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> said of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s vagueness: "We need to define what we mean. Are we for a single-rate
flat tax? Or are we, as I am, for tripling the tax deduction for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX>? Are we for affirmative action based on need, as I am, or based on race?
Are we for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of school, or are we for
federal bilingual education programs? I'm arguing for plain talk, not weasel
words." To which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> replied, "Why won't you abide by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">11 th Amendment</ENAMEX> and stop criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>?"

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> suffers
in silence as his fund-raisers bleed the field dry. "I'll play the hand I was
dealt," he shrugs stoically. Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>. He can't help it. He was born with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver gag</ENAMEX> in his mouth.

         
      
   
