
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">195</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Suggestive Gestures&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> received a letter offering advice on
an ongoing investigation. From whom; suggesting what?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 194</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unaffordable":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     After a call from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Motors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Bradsher</ENAMEX> of the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archives</ENAMEX> said, "You have to think in terms of corporate memories. There is
probably no one around who knows anything about this stuff." What stuff does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> need help remembering?
                  
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> minivan, the 'Ford <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YellowStar</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
               

               "The
schematic of the rather messy, and sadly unsuccessful, 'pudding-filled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airbags</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Spiegel</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNamara</ENAMEX>'s gentle, charming wit. It's for a miniseries."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX>
               

               "The
brief yet tumultuous reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General√</ENAMEX>≠simo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
               

               "I can
see where this is going, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>. Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> cooperated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, but it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> that made <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">19 zillion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> ads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Seger</ENAMEX>'s 'Like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
               

               Click
for more answers.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz debuted, 
                  Slate
                was free. Now, to commemorate our first
anniversary, in an act of incredible corporate generosity that is every bit as
good as providing health insurance (I'm sure that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> will make this sort
of thing more available should <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> prove profitable), 
                  Slate
               
is once again free. I like to think of it as my personal gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. (And the high concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> in the atmosphere that
sustains life on this planet--hey, it's on me!) Enjoy. Because, at the risk of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sentimentality</ENAMEX>, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> that make it fun for me. We've
come a long way together from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>'s ass (which, while not free, is
surprisingly affordable), and if online technology were not in its infancy,
right about now I'd be buying you all a round of free-range rug <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shampoo</ENAMEX>. Maybe
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Thanks for playing.

            
               Professionally
Researched Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> can't remember if it profited from its German
operations under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>, so it has hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> to help it recall. A key
detail--did it lose control of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Werke</ENAMEX> before or after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> entered the war?

            It is <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> litigation, not the love of
learning, that has sent several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> into the archives, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meier</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank</ENAMEX>,
both of whom hired prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>. However, the natural bias of their
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> can make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> uneasy.

            "Among certain corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, there is an
ideology that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are unfairly maligned and that they are less
powerful than they are made out to be," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Pinto</ENAMEX>-Duchinsky
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brunel University</ENAMEX>.

            On the other hand, the
pay is terrific, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miriam Kleinman</ENAMEX>, who works the other side of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> for a class-action law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>: "Some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have limousines
picking them up."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>'s
Anniversary Extra
            

            A guest extra marking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz.

            Granted this corner of the quiz to fill how I
choose, I'm going to live the dream of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> who's ever had an
especially good answer rejected: I'm going to run my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozen</NUMEX> favorites that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>, in his "wisdom," callously spurned.

            

               "Covered with festering sores, of course."

               "A saucy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>, fresh from the hairstylist."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, polling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>, if you catch my drift."

               "They don't."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s pale, puffy ass."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CLINTON GETS OFF</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> .

               "A pissed-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>."

               "That new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanking Ned Devine</ENAMEX> .

               "The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX>."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey Silver</ENAMEX>, explaining his decision to green-light <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pig</ENAMEX> in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abattoir</ENAMEX>.
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ehrlichmann</ENAMEX>, describing what he liked best about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Nixon</ENAMEX>."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Tori Spelling</ENAMEX>."

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s miserable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>.

            Strong <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s
unexpectedly flammable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinto</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
