
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">224</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Spring Break&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-week</TIMEX> congressional recess, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
answered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> this way: "I would describe it one word--quizzical. Like,
why? And what?" How did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> spend his vacation?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 223</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Who?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    
                                       
                                          
"I'm on top, I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years old</TIMEX>, I don't want to get hurt anymore, and I've got
nothing left to prove." Who said this about
what?
                                       
                                    
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrymore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Hepburn</ENAMEX>, turning down the lead in yet another remake of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Schoenberg</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
Stephanopoulos, on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s insistence that for the next book he use a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ghostwriter</ENAMEX> and, for the media tour, lose the rug."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marilyn L</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Burton</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Anne Townsend</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

            "Every
single one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who broke up with me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>
Krone, telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> why she's going to kill him."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard A</ENAMEX>
DeCamp
            

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Let's take a rare glimpse
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz Tower</ENAMEX> (it's not yet killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as that new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast Building</ENAMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> we start heaving copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue</ENAMEX> off
the observation deck) and learn what it takes to get a hefty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> to your table to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s desk where it is signed into law. By
which I mean: How did we select <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s question? By rejecting these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "Fill in the blank in
this remark by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Webber Wright</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to hold a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in
contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. 'I don't think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should be __________. My focus is to
be fair to all sides.' "

            A good way to get at an
important story, but nixed on formal grounds. We ran a fill-in-the-blank just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. We try for variety in form as well as in subject matter.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said, 'You've seen someone else handle it up close and personal, so
you know you can survive it. It's not so foreign to you.' Handle what?"

            A nice ambiguous remark
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> would do well with, but it refers to too trivial a story,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodd</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>--going into the family
business.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film The Basketball Diaries</ENAMEX> , the computer game <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortal Combat</ENAMEX>, and the
Internet sex site <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meow Media</ENAMEX>--what's the connection<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            A pleasing juxtaposition
of elements, and it's sure fun to type out "sex site <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meow Media</ENAMEX>," but rejected
for both form and content. We've used this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> recently, and it's a
lightweight story.

            I began hoping to do
something with either the war or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s contempt citation, and eager
to use "I give the headline; you give the lead," or "I give the answer; you
give the question," or "I give the caption; you describe the photo," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> nice
forms we've not used lately. But nothing turned up that worked that way. I'm
relieved that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s back in town.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-Pound</NUMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jockey Julie Krone</ENAMEX> said it about retiring.

            In her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year</TIMEX> career,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krone</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,541</NUMEX> races, earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $80 million</NUMEX> in prize money, and broke more
than a dozen bones. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, she won the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belmont Stakes</ENAMEX> and rode <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> winners
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saratoga</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last November</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadowlands</ENAMEX>, she broke her right
knee riding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>; she won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more races before going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.

            
               Have Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candied Egret</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Grace, It's for Charity Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Benefits"</ENAMEX> column in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> listed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two dozen</NUMEX> events coming up this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. A few highlights:

            
               Event
               : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sting</ENAMEX> is
among those singing a tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>.

            
               Tickets
               :
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beneficiary</ENAMEX>: The rain forest.

            

               Downside: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sting</ENAMEX> is singing tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>.

            
               Event: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Young professionals</ENAMEX> throw
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            
               Tickets: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beneficiary: Leukemia Society</ENAMEX>.

            

               Downside: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
gooned on margaritas and their own benevolence.

            
               Event: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX> honors
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinal O'Connor</ENAMEX>.

            
               Tickets: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beneficiary</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>.

            

               Downside: Chance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX> could stop by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX>
party on way over, get tanked on margaritas, make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> pass at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>
Rose.

            
               Event: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX> and others read
from their own stuff, honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>.

            
               Tickets: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beneficiary: Adult literacy</ENAMEX>
programs.

            

               Downside: Could be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> God's wrath descends on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of literacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> in corollary damage from
lightning strike.

            
               Event: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nobu</ENAMEX>, hold <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sunday Night Supper</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tickets: Free</ENAMEX>! A percentage of each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> goes to charity.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beneficiary</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groups</ENAMEX> that provide
meals to the homebound.

            

               Downside: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overt</ENAMEX> use of phrase "crumbs from rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s table"
could cause scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> to die of embarrassment.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Agassi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>,
and that darned beaver. There's your wacky sitcom, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bigshot</ENAMEX> development
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jerk</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
