
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TK&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               It happens in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> a day, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> calls it "the oddest kaffeeklatsch in the history of Western
civilization." What goes on?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 205</ENAMEX>)--"Nothing but Cash":
               

               

                  
                     
                        Devise a pair of words to fill in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> blanks--one
word each--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> cable, describes his shift away
from the old network economic model: "Our goal over time is to turn viewers
into __________ and __________."
                     
                  
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunters</ENAMEX> and gatherers."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.G. Lord</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jon</ENAMEX>
Delfin , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Shaw</ENAMEX>
               

               "Dharma
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. (He was promptly fired.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tullis</ENAMEX>
               

               "Cash
and checks."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Lyle</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imbeciles</ENAMEX> and quick."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamar Haspel</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcontents</ENAMEX> and loners. ('We're going to steal the Internet's
thunder!')"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Strauss</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gays</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX>. (Turns out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> was right all along.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
               

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

               It's a little too easy to
disdain television, although please do, especially that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Medical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> , where, just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX>, I saw some kind of vomiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chihuahua</ENAMEX>,
which, let me tell you, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long day</TIMEX> working for some big jerk at the ...
No, wait, I lie: It wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Medical Center</ENAMEX> , it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> ;
and it wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chihuahua</ENAMEX>, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX>; and she wasn't vomiting,
that was me. But the point stands: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX> is like tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or take-out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pizza</ENAMEX>; it's not really good, but it's so conveniently available that we dully
consume it instead of making the effort to go out for really good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> or some
truly magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> from, like, a solid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> tap. And yet, if you ask
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about their actual No. 1 recreational activity, it's watching
television. And if you ask them their imaginary No. 1 recreational activity,
it's stripping naked and firing out the window at passing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> with that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> from that show, you know, the pretty one. So perhaps it's a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facile</ENAMEX> to blame all our problems on some sap from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> cable, when the fault, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, is with some whole other sap entirely. If you write me, I'll send you
his name.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ace Award Winning</ENAMEX>
Answer
               

               "Our goal over time is to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> ."

               Tired of relying on ad
revenues from so-called "popular" shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> to
own part of a home shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, is expanding its efforts to sell
souvenirs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> did well hawking a music CD, a tie-in to its miniseries
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> , and expects to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> a lot more stuff once it ties
together TV shows, home shopping, and the Internet. "We've made it clear that
figuring out ways to drive sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> through our broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> is a
key ingredient we see in the overall mix," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>. "And that means one
thing--an anatomically enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw Action Figure</ENAMEX>," he did not add.

               
                  New Furby/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Dole</ENAMEX>
Extra
               

               A new version of the annoying yet popular toy and a
new presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> from the awkward yet enduring political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are
aggressively courting acclaim.

               Some comparisons:

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oft-Cited Personality Trait</ENAMEX>
               

               New Furby: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spunky</ENAMEX> playmate.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>:
Thin-skinned perfectionist.

               
                  Core Belief
               

               Furby: Provide cuddly animatronic fun.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: Cut taxes, build
anti-missile system.

               
                  Positions on Other Major Issues
               

               Furby: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Undisclosed</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole: Undisclosed</ENAMEX>, but
promises, "We're going to be laying out positions on all these issues."

               
                  Handicap for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential</ENAMEX>
Candidate
               

               Furby: Overly programmed.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: Same thing.

               
                  Slogan
               

               Furby: "Collect them all for phenomenal Furby
fun!"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: "Let's make this a
crusade!" (Antecedent unclear.)

               
                  Nickname
               

               Furby: Pretty much just "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX>."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: "Miss <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3-by</NUMEX>-5 Index
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Card</ENAMEX>" (as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> undergrad).

               
                  Hair
               

               Furby: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three "wild</ENAMEX>" fur designs in all new wildlife
colors and patterns.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: Can't tell from
newspaper, but former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Castellanos</ENAMEX> says, "She's a tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>; she's as
hard as her hairdo."

               
                  Recent Innovation
               

               Furby: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep sleep</ENAMEX>" lets new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furby</ENAMEX> go to sleep
quicker and stay asleep until turned completely upside down.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: Same thing
(unconfirmed rumor only).

               
                  Common
Denominator
               

               Crummy TV shows, crummy
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
