
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Trap</ENAMEX>

            It occurred to me, while
laboring to write this column and make a bit of money to support my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
that it would do wonders for my stifled creativity to drive somewhere tropical,
sip single-barrel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX>, and have sex with a tawny barmaid. Of course, when I
was at liberty to do all that I didn't. Instead, I'd think, if I could only
meet a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> and put down roots, I'd be less anxious about earthly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impermanence</ENAMEX> and be really poised to cultivate my creativity ... By a
not-so-strange coincidence, this conflict is prominent in lots of recent
movies, among them <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Walk on the Moon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metroland</ENAMEX> , and Among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> , which explore the natural impulse to settle down vs. the equally
natural impulse to be wild and free--the yearning for permanence vs. the
claustrophobic dread of monogamy.

            No dilemma causes men
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to fantasize so intensely about splitting themselves in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and</TIMEX>
taking both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. And none provides more fodder for melancholy middle-aged
comedy, from the heavyweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milan Kundera</ENAMEX> in The Unbearable
Lightness of Being to the fluffy screwball machinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces of</ENAMEX>
Nature . In the latter, currently the most popular movie in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the
filmmakers strain to bring together free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock</ENAMEX> and affianced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fuddy-duddy Ben Affleck</ENAMEX>. Then they do a bizarre about-face and deliver a paean
to the bliss of domesticity. That ending satisfies no one, but you can
appreciate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX>' lack of options: Kundera resolves the conflict by
hurtling his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX> down an incline and crushing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> to a
pulp.

            It's worth remembering that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kundera</ENAMEX>'s sexual parables
unfold against a backdrop of totalitarian repression, whereas our own grapple
with a more confusing legacy: the counterculture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>. Set in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Walk on the Moon</ENAMEX> devises a deliciously resonant dual setting: a
Catskills <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to which middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> migrate to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">swim</ENAMEX> and eat and play mah-jongg, and the gathering hippies at nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodstock</ENAMEX>.
The proximity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'60s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hedonism</ENAMEX> puts a sort of lunar spell on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Lane</ENAMEX>), a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> whose own "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> of love" was
cruelly brief. She got pregnant at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> and promptly married the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liev Schreiber</ENAMEX>)--now a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repairman</ENAMEX> who's stuck in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> fixing
broken sets in time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Armstrong</ENAMEX>'s moon walk--and settled into a life of
looking after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chopping vegetables</ENAMEX>. So, let's see: hot weather, free
love in the breeze, an anti-establishment, pubescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Paquin</ENAMEX>),
and an absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. Into this sexually tremulous milieu comes Viggo
Mortensen, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>-driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peddlers</ENAMEX> who make regular trips to the
compound to sell shmattes to bargain-hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>. A rangy,
purringly diffident blond gentile with blue eyes and a cleft chin, he watches
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX> slips on a tie-dyed T-shirt, then leans his lips toward her bare
throat--and bites off the dangling price tag. One can hardly blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX> for
saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family</ENAMEX> shmamily."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Walk</ENAMEX>
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> , which is directed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Goldwyn</ENAMEX> (the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in
Ghost ) and written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Gray</ENAMEX>, feel miraculously right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>'s
script seems meticulously worked out, right down to setting the moonwalk
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX> in her own libidinal orbit. But if the writing is tidy, it's
never glib--it has too much texture for glibness. I think back with pleasure on
the shared fascination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marty</ENAMEX> and his young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> over how many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> it
takes him to drive from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Catskills</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>, the bubbly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonchalance of the Catskills women</ENAMEX>, and the presence in the margins of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, who find it increasingly difficult to coexist with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Purple Haze</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skinny-dippers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s lib.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Lane</ENAMEX>'s performance puts her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of the
best young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actresses</ENAMEX> alive. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX> is at an age when you can see in her skin
the last traces of girlish pliancy but also where the cares have begun to leave
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX>. Alone in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> with her cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, she seems to be
smelling her own faint over-ripeness; when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mortensen</ENAMEX> holds his stare a beat too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> bends toward his as if it knows, on a cellular level, that this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> lies nourishment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mortensen</ENAMEX> have an extrasensory rapport--they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magnetize</ENAMEX> each other. When you see them at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX> it's through the aghast
eyes of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, who thought of herself as a groover until she caught a
glimpse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> in a most unmomlike state of sexual ecstasy--Dionysically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pickled</ENAMEX>.

            This kind of picture has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> thrusts: It either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> with the suffocated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> who, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibsen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>, strives to break free of a repressive patriarchal hold, or it
demonizes a culture that tempts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to put their own gratification
before their responsibilities as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Walk on the Moon</ENAMEX> leans to
the side of "family values" but scapegoats no one--neither the decent but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insensitive Marty</ENAMEX> nor the opportunistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>. Even the moralistic mystic of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lilian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tovah Feldshuh</ENAMEX>), can't forestall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX>'s flowering.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lilian</ENAMEX> embodies the culture's eternal wisdom but also its antediluvian folly.
Greeting the news of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">granddaughter</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> menses, she blurts, "Mazel
tov !" and then slaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>--a tradition evidently meant to celebrate
the beginning of reproductive life, while reinforcing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s sense of shame
over the fact that she's now "unclean." A culture so stern would drive most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into the tie-dyed bosom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>, even if he didn't look like Viggo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mortensen</ENAMEX>.

            He might, for instance, resemble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Ross</ENAMEX>, who plays the
militantly nonconformist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Bale</ENAMEX>), in
Metroland , based on an early novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Barnes</ENAMEX>. The time is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>:
After a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> absence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni visits Chris</ENAMEX> at his suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> row <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
He's there to deride him for having a genteel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Watson</ENAMEX>), a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, and a job snapping pictures for an ad agency--and to remind him
that once, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, they shared an ambition to escape such soul-quashing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogeneity</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni</ENAMEX>'s point would be more pressing if he weren't
such an unpalatable poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> for freedom--pasty with dissipation, with thin,
purplish lips. Plus, he's an unmistakable sponge. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> and his missus are
having an arid patch, sexually speaking, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni</ENAMEX>'s exhortations prompt heady
flashbacks to less confining times: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arty photographer</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, when he learned how to make love to les 
               femmes from a
lusciously soft-thighed coquette called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annick</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elsa Zylberstein</ENAMEX>). But that
idyll was cut short when he met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion</ENAMEX>. Torn between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> free-spiritedness
and the gnawing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> sense that he ought to set about structuring a life,
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> drifted--more or less by default--into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Englishwoman</ENAMEX>'s
arms.

            
               Metroland , while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poky</ENAMEX> and schematic, is full of disconcertingly sharp talk between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>
before, during, and after sex. And while it's true that you can't pack as much
psychological detail into a movie as you can into a novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Hodges</ENAMEX> bring out the yeasty subtext of even the
most brittle encounters: The suspense is in waiting to hear how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> will
phrase what you've already read in their faces. The movie's triumph is the
casting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> in an unusually self-possessed role. I found her prim little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Lisa</ENAMEX> smirk and teasingly buttoned-up demeanor almost maddeningly
sexy--more alluring by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> than the smeary-mouthed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> sexpot. Bale, a
wonderfully sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who here looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adam</ENAMEX>'s apple,
can only stare open-mouthed, helpless, knowing she's his destiny and not even
much minding that it will take him back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metroland</ENAMEX>. Is it unfair to skew the
case for a life of suburban domesticity this way? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX> is such a diabolical
minx that she makes the prospect of a life amid those metros and under those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gray</ENAMEX> skies more seductive than an endless luau. I wish I could tell you for
sure that the "happy" ending isn't meant to be ironic, but that's not how it
felt to this aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suburbanite</ENAMEX>.

            In Among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> , another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> romance in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> and security play footsie, the rover is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>: an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
"climbah" named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Griffiths</ENAMEX>) who joins up with a cowboylike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of
daredevil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Postlethwaite</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>--they have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 miles</NUMEX> of
mammoth electric towers to coat in a mere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>, goes in for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Hine</ENAMEX>-like images of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> high in the air, at once
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dwarfed</ENAMEX> and exalted, with synthesized strings to provide a touch of foggy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mysticism</ENAMEX>. Much of Among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> affords an agreeable blend of the gritty
and the synthetic, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">treat</ENAMEX>. "You love it up here,
don't you?" says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffiths</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is starting to fall for the older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreman</ENAMEX>. "Oh, I'm king up here, lass," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Postlethwaite</ENAMEX>, looking more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leathery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asiatic</ENAMEX> than ever, like the mummified fossil of some early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
Griffiths, who played a free spirit in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Muriel's Wedding</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>) and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">simpy Hilary du Pr√</ENAMEX>© in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s Hilary 
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> , has a large
nose and receding chin and looks quite homely from one or two angles. But from
the only angles that matter she's beautiful, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> has a darting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> to boot.

            There's no reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> couldn't have made
a lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> of it--scaling rocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">romping</ENAMEX> naked through abandoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>, gazing in awe at big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rigs</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Beaufoy</ENAMEX>
( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Full Monty</ENAMEX> ), has a thing about bringing macho <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> down to earth
with a thud. Last time the deflation was funny and it worked; this time the bad
vibes make the whole picture wither. If any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> could have synthesized the
impulses to rove and stay put, it's this one, but Beaufoy throws in the towel
at the point where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Walk on the</ENAMEX> 
               Moon
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metroland</ENAMEX> are just getting warmed up.

         
      
   
