
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">198</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Chat and Argue Choo Choo&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next month</TIMEX>, hoping to re-establish cordial relations, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 140</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> will board a chartered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> bound for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX> What
will they do when they get there?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 197</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man Has Needs":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     
                        
                           
                              Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX> Press
assesses the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX>-to-be-announced presidential bid of his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playmate Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. "He is convinced that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> stumbles, if
G.W. stumbles, in a field of pygmies, he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>. This is not just a need
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">____________</NUMEX> on his part."
                           
                        
                     
                  
               

               
"Frequent flyer miles."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward H. Hernandez</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Cornog</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb</ENAMEX>
Stavin , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Smith</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris Jackson</ENAMEX>
               

               "Higher
speaking fees."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lithium</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mat Honan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Combs</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Katz</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael Laufer</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liebensraum</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
               

               "Seeing
himself unattractively represented in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of editorial cartoons as a
leathery-faced half-man, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Powers</ENAMEX>
               

               Click
for more answers.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Why engage in a futile
act? If it's just plain stupid to continue making rambling, drunken, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late night</TIMEX>
phone calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX> despite a court order--hypothetically
speaking--what's to be gained by running a no-win campaign in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>?
Well, you get your message out, shape the debate, and perhaps gain influence
over the eventual winner. That explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX> thing. But what about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>? Here, it's defeat as self-aggrandizement. He transforms himself from
a vitriolic TV gas bag into a candidate for the presidency. That ought to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impress Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX>.

            
               Adoring
Answer
            

            "This is not just a need for adulation on his
part."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> was taking a
leave from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , a program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> say he is bored with, much like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, I add editorially.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the feisty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reactionary</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary, capturing the state
with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> of the vote. This would be difficult to repeat, suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>
McSlarrow, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>'s campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, because much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> (including sister <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX>) is unavailable, because the field is so
crowded, and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> have "wised up," I add, quoting only myself, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who finds simple joy in the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>'s campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>."

            
               Extra
Special
            

            "Let's say somebody is
acquitted, and it's one of those acquittals in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was guilty
..."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>'s
Anniversary Extra
            

            I'd like to share
something that I've been keeping to myself for some time. This is a real letter
that was entrusted to me by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and to him by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and I really
can't say more than that. Please, read until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> for the shocking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">denouement</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1984</TIMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metro Goldwyn Mayer</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10202</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Washington</ENAMEX> Blvd
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culver City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            Dear Sir,

            I am writing to you with regard to the motion
pictures, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Dolly</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Way We Were , Superman</ENAMEX> ,
Yentl , and possibly more, but at the moment those are the titles
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uppermost</ENAMEX> in my mind.

            My voice has been recorded and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX>'s
face and name have been associated with the sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> and recordings made by
the motion picture industry. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> is not involved then I apologize
and am writing in error. I do not have access to the names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>
involved in the production of the motion pictures associated with my voice.

            My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muffin Kennedy</ENAMEX>. I am the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph P.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Swanson Kennedy</ENAMEX>. You may remember me from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. I
represented the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> on the radio from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>,
and was heard throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pacific War Zone</ENAMEX>.
The subject matter discussed in the broadcasts came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, and
anything said by me was said with the permission of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
government and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>.

            I have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of amnesia since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> and
unfortunately lost my identity. I have come back to many incidents in my life
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year and a half</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX> has annoyed me throughout the years
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of hers. They have entered my home wherever I have lived without
permission. They have shocked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to the extent that I blacked out
whatever they were doing.

            I have not been paid one
penny for the records, tapes, or motion picture sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> made with my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>. I did not give permission for anyone to record my voice. I did not at
any time sign a contract allowing any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> or anywhere else to
use my voice in the production of a motion picture. I do not want my voice used
again by the motion picture industry, nor do I want any more songs
recorded.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muffin Kennedy</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX> ) OK, I
made up that last part.

            
               Common
Denominators
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>, thwarted
erotic desires.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
