
   
   
      
         
            From Here to Exurbia

            "Not since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX> of
Dreams has a film so touched the heart and filled the soul!" proclaims a TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reviewer</ENAMEX> in an ad for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> . That would be enough to keep me
away-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> didn't fill this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, it functioned as
a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soul laxative</ENAMEX>--but I'm happy to report that the comparison is wide of
the mark. The ways in which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> does not evoke <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of</ENAMEX>
Dreams would fill a book. In fact, they do fill a book-- Rocket
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> , on which the movie is based. It's a memoir by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer Hickam Jr.</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retired NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> who grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coalwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.Va.</ENAMEX>, and who got himself out
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> (where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX>) by throwing himself into
the fledgling science of rocketry. To describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Homer</ENAMEX> of the movie (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gyllenhaal</ENAMEX>) as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lad</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> dust on his face and stars in his eyes would be
both softheaded and imprecise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>'s eyes aren't fixed on the Spielbergian
heavens but on earthly means of getting off the ground: the mix of saltpeter
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> that causes a rocket to soar without exploding, the shape that keeps
it from spiraling into populated areas, the thickness of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> that prevents
its nose cone from melting, the trigonometry that's employed to track its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trajectory</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> isn't a paean to fancifulness but to
trial-and-error perseverance, to a process and not an end. At its best, the
movie evokes that blend of thrill and terror that comes from mixing two
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> together without being sure that an instant later you'll still be
standing there in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece.

            On its most basic level,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> is a square, inspirational "go for it" picture, but it's
agreeably guileless for such a manipulative genre. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Johnston</ENAMEX>
( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocketeer</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>), works in a straight-ahead manner that doesn't
rough you up. The movie builds to a couple of climactic science fairs, but
they're presented almost as afterthoughts, and in moments of tragedy one's
tears are quietly coaxed instead of jerked. The tension between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalwood</ENAMEX>'s
malignant, subterranean caverns and the allure of space exploration has so much
resonance that the story doesn't need the hard sell. It opens at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>'s cultural turning points: the appearance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> satellite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sputnik 1</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalwood</ENAMEX> (and everywhere else) gathered
on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> to get a glimpse of the moving dot of light in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> sky.
"They could be dropping bombs from up there," says someone. "Don't know why
they'd drop a bomb on this place," comes a voice of reason, "Be a waste of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sputnik</ENAMEX> is the spark for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Homer</ENAMEX>'s impulse to build <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>,
but in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> the know-how and materials are almost nonexistent. A
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> with only so-so grades, he seeks the help of the class brain,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Owen</ENAMEX>), a skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">redhead</ENAMEX> with a complexion that could charitably
be likened to the surface of the moon. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Dell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chad Lindberg</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lee</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Lee Scott</ENAMEX>) can't believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX> would befriend such a
geek, but it's a measure of the movie's grace that after a couple of early
gibes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> begin to work together with a breathlessness that leaves no room
for geek bigotry. Barred by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer Sr.</ENAMEX> from launching test <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> on mining
company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">property</ENAMEX> (the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is mining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> property), the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rocket Boys</ENAMEX>
trudge <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight miles</NUMEX> to a flat gravel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, on which they build a block house
and raise a flag. The flag-raising isn't milked for its patriotism: It's a
deeply goofy gesture and totally consistent with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>' sense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">momentousness</ENAMEX>. At the behest of a vivacious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Dern</ENAMEX>),
they're working toward entering the state science fair and competing for
college scholarships, but their true goal is simpler: making those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> go
straight and long.

            Most movies about science
aren't as lucky as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> , which features failures more hilarious
than the slapstick set pieces of any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX> pictures. There is nothing
quite like a rocket that goes wrong--the power of nature harnessed to a blind,
petulant dervish. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> that defiantly explode before they leave
the pad and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> that spitefully take fences and vegetation with them. There
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> that spin around in an escalating panic before blowing up and
rockets that somersault off their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> and make a beeline for the nearest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population center</ENAMEX>. The centerpiece of the movie is a montage of disasters to
the tune of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ain't That a Shame</ENAMEX>," but it ain't a shame, really: It's an
exhilarating spectacle.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exhilarating</ENAMEX> and a little sad. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> evokes an
era when information was precious, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> could get excited about the
appearance of a text called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Principles of Guided Missile</ENAMEX> Design that
hardly anyone knew existed. There was a connection, however small, between a
thingamajig one could build in one's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and the stuff that was heading for
outer space on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>. But there are other aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Homer</ENAMEX>'s existence
that don't leave you feeling so nostalgic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worshipping Werner Van Braun</ENAMEX> (to
whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> writes letters) seems creepy in our post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lehrer</ENAMEX> era. And just
looking at the coal dust in the air made my lungs ache and an old cough come
back. I won't spoil the coda by revealing it here, but it's the kind of coup
that only movies can bring off and, watching it, I shed my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> unashamed
tears in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX> of filmgoing. (Not my first tears--the first tears I
didn't desperately attempt to conceal.)

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> is
a good movie, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickam</ENAMEX>'s memoir could have yielded a great one--less
formulaic, more nuanced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cooper</ENAMEX>) is shown bullying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> into abandoning his education and going into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>, a perspective less
tragically shortsighted than plain moronic, given the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> are
dying all around him either from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cave-ins</ENAMEX>. The real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickam Sr.</ENAMEX> didn't
want his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">miner</ENAMEX> but a mining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> ; he longed to see the
boy follow in his footsteps but to go beyond them, too, and to use his science
to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> safer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocket</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> weren't as out of sync with their culture
as the film implies. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sputnik</ENAMEX>-shaken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made</ENAMEX> science and math a top priority in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--one reason why science fairs
had so much funding and national attention. It's hard to buy the trumped-up
scene where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX>--another myopic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX>--warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dern</ENAMEX> not to give her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> "false hopes" (although this does give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dern</ENAMEX> a chance to do her rubber
lips specialty, gazing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> in wordless horror while her mouth
continually reforms itself like some strange <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Gumby creature</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> suggests that if it weren't for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russkies</ENAMEX> would still own outer space!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> ffice 
               Space , a comedy written and directed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beavis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butt</ENAMEX>-head and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> , is about what happens to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> when they move to exurbia and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">don</ENAMEX> white collars. A take-this-job-and-shove-it movie about the crushing
malevolence of the corporate environment, it's on the verge of being really
good. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Livingston</ENAMEX>), an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> at a generic software
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, is suffocating under his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lunbergh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Cole</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> who
punishes underlings from behind a strenuously mellow affect--each demand or
rebuke prefaced by a seemingly upbeat "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yyyyeah</ENAMEX>." It's not the viciousness
that's making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> seethe in his cubicle, but the relentlessly
nonconfrontational confrontationalism of it all. When a hypnotherapist keels
over from a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> in the middle of giving him instructions on how to
relax and follow his instincts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> emerges with an aura of serene
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indestructibility</ENAMEX> and a gonzo rebelliousness that makes him, paradoxically,
more attractive to the faceless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> whom his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has hired to
downsize the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            The gags in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Space</ENAMEX> aren't
anything-goes: They're rooted in what sociology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn S. Chaucer</ENAMEX> calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sadomasochism in Everyday Life: The Dynamics of Power</ENAMEX> and Powerlessness
(the title of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> book). The powerless become exquisitely sensitive to the
insults of modern society: copy machines that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> who cut them off in
traffic. And you can't get away from it. As he has proven on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> has radar for corporate BS. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> falls for a mousy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX>) at a theme restaurant where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> all look like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weird</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al" Yankovic</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are forced to "express themselves" by selecting a
minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> pieces of "flair"--buttons with stupid slogans to be pinned on
their uniforms. The sneak preview <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> laughed gratefully at this, finding
something liberating in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>'s depiction of a business world that
has--doubtless taking its cues from one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>--institutionalized zany informality.

            In fact, the audience
laughed all the way through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Office Space preview</ENAMEX>, experiencing
shocks of recognition big and small. But they still left disappointed. For a
start, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>' faces are so much less interesting than the mythic,
totem-pole visages in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>'s cartoons. More cripplingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> has spent too
long in television, and his narrative peters out without a decent payoff. It's
a testament to the rage and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> that he has brilliantly tapped into that
he can't get away with a subdued conflagration and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> twist at the end.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> leaves us the way his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> leave his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>: smoldering in our cells,
hungering for a little confrontation.

         
      
   
