
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Splat</ENAMEX>! Bam! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pow</ENAMEX>! <BR>@#<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">$%</NUMEX>&amp;!

            Fear no more, earthlings,
the age of frustration and humiliation is over! I am the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
Avenger, who hath descended to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> from the planet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galleria</ENAMEX> in a
nuclear-fueled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town & Country</ENAMEX> minivan (base price: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27,385</NUMEX>, left
sliding door standard in most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>) to save you from the dark <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of
turbo-charged capitalism and shoddy customer service.

            OK, enough with the superhero shtick. It's
unsustainable over several paragraphs.

            Here's the problem: Like
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, I've been doing my part to fuel the Dow to absurd
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heights</ENAMEX>. My own personal consumer confidence is high (up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5 percent</NUMEX> just this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>!), and my spending is profligate--laptops and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s toys and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed whackers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> tables and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>. They make it, I buy it. Retail,
even.

            But what do I get in return, except for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express Membership</ENAMEX> Rewards points (which I can apply toward, among other door
prizes, an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NBA Black Leather Zip Daytimer</ENAMEX>") and a personal note from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> thanking me for my help?

            Frustration is what I get. When I went searching The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot</ENAMEX> for a replacement charger for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skil Twist Xtra Flexi Charge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interchangeable Power System Cordless Screwdriver</ENAMEX>, did anyone there know what a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skil Twist Xtra Flexi Charge Interchangeable Power System Cordless</ENAMEX> Screwdriver
even was? No. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX> charged me <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> for a ticket I didn't
want and didn't order, could I even get anyone on the phone in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 15</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>? Also no! When I ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chechnya: Calamity in the Caucasus</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and received instead a copy of Early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> Mysticism: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX>,
Quran, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Miraj, Poets and Theological Writings</ENAMEX> , did I get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> in the form
of a refund or a copy of the book I needed? No! (Although I am now a recognized
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>.)

            Just as I was writing
this last paragraph, I received an e-mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>-wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bezos</ENAMEX>. I
figured he was writing to apologize (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bezos</ENAMEX> claims to know what I want to read,
so why shouldn't he also know when I'm mad at him?), but instead his
e-mail--which he apparently sent to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flacks</ENAMEX> his new, sure to
lose money and at the same time boost his stock price another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">200 percent</NUMEX>
venture, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com Auctions.</ENAMEX> I think I'll start by auctioning off my copy of
Early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> Mysticism: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quran, Miraj</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poets and Theological</ENAMEX>
Writings .

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digresses</ENAMEX>. Now, I understand
retail. I'm not naive. In order to boost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> earnings to meet the
cosmically greedy expectations of a handful of Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> who've
never sold anything in their lives, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> must cut, cut, and
cut again. Pensions are out, job security is out, and customer service is most
definitely out.

            This column will not
address such issues as pension rights and job security (though it will refer to
them from time to time out of guilt--at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, earlier in my life, I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretended</ENAMEX> to be a democratic socialist, and I was for a time an actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kibbutznik</ENAMEX>).

            This column instead will seek vengeance for you, the loyal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer.The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>, at a
dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. I was seated next to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who said he was one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventors</ENAMEX> of corporate voice-mail routing systems. (This, of course, was a
lie--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of corporate voice-mail routing systems.) I told
him that, in my humble opinion, the advent of voice mail and the disappearance
of live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> meant longer waits on the telephone for help.

            He said I was wrong. I told him I felt this fairly
strongly. He again told me I was wrong: Surveys show that the waiting period
for help has been cut by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX>, or some such number. I then told him that
earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> I had spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven minutes</TIMEX> pushing buttons in order to make a
single airline reservation.

            He told me it was just my
perception that I spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven minutes</TIMEX> pushing buttons. Then I called him an
asshole, and that was that. It was then that I decided the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer
needed help battling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of corporate arrogance. I felt I was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to
lead the charge. But like most selfless impulses, I thought about it for a
while and the feeling eventually passed.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> was born again. He was born again
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toys</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Us</ENAMEX>, where none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> seemed to know what a potty seat
was, and he was born yet again at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Rent a Car</ENAMEX> counter at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Guardia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX>, where the reservation he had made and confirmed suddenly ceased to
exist, and where he got yelled at for his troubles.

            And so, this column. Here's how it works. You
e-mail your tale of woe--inferior products, ignorant customer service--to
shoppingavenger@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> will use his reporting skills, which have been described
by some as "almost supernatural in scope" (and have been described by others as
"adequate" and "sort of pathetic") to extract on your behalf grudging apologies
from faceless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> come, first served
and, be warned, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> looks askance at the bearing of false
witness. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that deserve praise will be praised. Onward!

            P.S.: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
will also entertain questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mysticism</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
