
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Ask Not What You
Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Constitutionally Do ...</ENAMEX>
            

            I'm not sure I quite see what's odd about accepting
a post that, as an abstract legal matter, you think is unconstitutional (see
""). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, for instance, believe that all independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> (such as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>) are unconstitutional, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> was mistaken in
upholding this "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." Does it really follow that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who believes this can't in good conscience go to work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>?

            I don't think that such punctilio is really morally
or professionally obligatory. The battle over the constitutionality of
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> was fought in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>; it was won by those who've
argued that such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are constitutional. For our legal system's purposes,
that's that, at least until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> reverses its views. A fair-minded person
might say, "Given that the law as interpreted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> authorizes such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, I
feel that I can do good/do my duty to my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by working for this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>."

            Same for the independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. Now, if one thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was not just unconstitutional but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immoral</ENAMEX> , that would be a different story; for instance, if one thinks
that it violates basic human rights to outlaw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, going to work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX>
would be a bit iffy. But I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really think this (or should
think this) about the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> statute.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Volokh</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA Law School</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>

            
               Inflated
Inflation
            

            After referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> don't expect rising gasoline prices to trigger inflation, ""
concludes with the rhetorical flourish, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>--isn't inflation primarily
measured as a rate of increase in cost?"

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> cited and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> seem
confused. Inflation is an overall rise in the price of goods and services. The
key word is overall . The increase or decrease in any particular item not
only does not, but cannot, produce inflation. When the amount of money in
circulation is fixed, if expenditures rise in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area, a fortiori, they fall
in another. Inflation, by definition, occurs when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> increases the
money supply faster than the real growth of the economy, because this increase
is the only way more money can become available to chase the same number of
goods.

            A logical corollary is that inflation cannot be
"triggered" by increasing wages, farm prices, or health care costs. If <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and
medical care tripled in cost, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would of necessity spend less on other
things to pay for the increase or cut down on the food and medical care they
purchased.

            Falling demand for other
things would necessarily result in falling prices for those things. Wealth
would indeed be moved around, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> enriched, and others would be
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>. But there would not be, nor could there have been, an
overall increase in prices. An overall increase in prices is only
possible when there has been an overall increase in the amount of money in
circulation.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weinberg</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>

            
               Groaning
            

            In his "" lamenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Groening</ENAMEX>'s absence from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comic Journal</ENAMEX> 's Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> list, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX> claims that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groening</ENAMEX>'s
willing, if somewhat ironic, embrace of the marketing bonanza his creation has
unleashed may have cost him his rightful spot in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comics</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">highbrow</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">subculture pantheon</ENAMEX>."

            Oh, really? Then why is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX>, surely the all-time top marketing whore, listed in the No. 2
spot? There must be a better explanation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Groening</ENAMEX> being left off the list,
and there is: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life in Hell sucks</ENAMEX>. It hasn't been funny or insightful for
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. True, the same thing can be said for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> , but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanuts</ENAMEX> had a solid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> of brilliance before burnout. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX>'s
reputation is entirely dependent on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two 12</NUMEX>-episode series, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Is Hell</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">School Is Hell</ENAMEX> . The entire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> since then has just been
Akbar-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX> minimalist filler. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> confirms this, by the way, by only
talking about the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> in his article--an undisputed
fact, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comics Journal</ENAMEX> wasn't ranking animators.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Scarborough</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Chicago</TIMEX>

             

         
      
   
