
   
   
      
         
            Let's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blame Bill</ENAMEX>

            The
frustration of the bellicose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> at the half-hearted pursuit of the
war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> vented itself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> attacking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who, it said, has "proved his absolute inadequacy as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>, stumbling on a stage that is bigger than his talents can
match and performing with hesitancy, frailty and fear." It added, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his war
will not be serious until Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> listens to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, rather than the
latest opinion poll. He has never countenanced a campaign plan; and in the
absence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, even air power has been misapplied. ... Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
retreated into the semantic ambiguities for which his presidency has become
infamous." The editorial concluded that "[f]or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> peace and for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the true, high reckoning begins: it is called failure."

            The
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a report that
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> were struggling "to hold
back a growing tide of criticism of their leadership of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict."
Along with other papers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported cracks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British</ENAMEX>
bipartisan support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> offensive. In an article in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> on foreign affairs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>, called for the establishment of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of inquiry into the war and
the "diplomatic failures" that preceded it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> described the bombing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> as "an act of gross incompetence." He said, "To use
outdated street maps for an operation of this kind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beggars</ENAMEX> belief."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Guardian</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on "gloom" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
hardened their demands for a halt to airstrikes before they will agree to
support peace moves in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. Having consistently urged the use of
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> finally recognized in an editorial that "the
possibility of a ground attack has dwindled." It said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have been willing to do their bit but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "could not muster the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will</ENAMEX>, or lacks the necessary political weight, to commit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
ground action." The central issue now, it said, is that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, acting
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, must have preponderant physical power on the ground,
whatever the formalities of status may be." The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> 's
front-page lead spoke of "an unmistakable whiff of panic and confusion in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX> of war."

            There
was gloom on the continent as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> emptied of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>" and said in an editorial that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> knows--"because we have been at pains to tell
him"--that he need not fear a land offensive, and he knows the limits of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air bombardments</ENAMEX>. "He can, at his leisure, test the unity and determination of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>," it added. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way or another, it is always he who holds the
cards." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ta Nea</ENAMEX> published a leaked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
document warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montenegro</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> are in imminent danger
of economic and political collapse because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis. The
displacement of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 600,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> threatens to destabilize the
entire region, it said. The "restricted" memo, dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 29</TIMEX>, was reported to
have been sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Solana</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            With
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only five days</TIMEX> to go before voting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> general election, the
government of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is reported to be reconciled to
defeat. The main headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maariv</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
as saying, "I'll apparently lose." One senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> , "We don't have many good reasons to be optimistic."
Meanwhile, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more public opinion polls showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One Israel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> is moving inexorably ahead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> deciding, because of the polls, to take personal charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX>'s
TV advertising campaign.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
led
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe Arens</ENAMEX> accepting the possibility of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
state. He reportedly said that recent developments have made territorial
compromise inevitable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> described the hatred among different religious and ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that has surfaced during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> election campaign. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> TV
debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yusef Lapid</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinui Party</ENAMEX> which
seeks to reduce the influence of ultra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX>, challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli Suissa</ENAMEX>,
the ultra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior minister</ENAMEX>, with the words: "Maybe you'd like to put
me in a concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>?" To this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suissa</ENAMEX> replied, "You've already been in a
concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and you didn't learn your lesson."

            The
firing of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>
Duma provoked little surprise in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kommersant</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX> has been under threat of dismissal for at least
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Stephasin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s choice to succeed him as
acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, has already been offered the job at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> said it is understandable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> ran out of sympathy for
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose main political support came from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>, who "have proclaimed
as their basic goal the overthrow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX> is going without loss of face because he is already recognized as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who saved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> from an abyss. His chances of winning the next
presidential election, if he decides to run, are "very high," the paper
said.

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on the booming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> warned that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is running out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. With unemployment at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> low, there
aren't many motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> left for the labor market to absorb, it said. "As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> pointed out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, faster adoption of new technology has
helped productivity growth to increase. But this may well prove temporary. When
the economy runs out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the laws of supply and demand take over."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> ran a front-page article about unexpected difficulties facing the
new single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency, the euro. It said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Central Bank</ENAMEX> has a
major problem creating a consistent monetary policy because of growing economic
disparities among the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Euroland</ENAMEX>." It said, "While some Euroland
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are enjoying American-style growth, others are on the brink of
recession."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> has been fined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lire</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $2,200</NUMEX>) for plagiarism. He was found to have copied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> notes from
a song by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albano Carrisi</ENAMEX> in his song, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Will You Be There?</ENAMEX>" The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> agreed there were extenuating circumstances because both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriters</ENAMEX> had
been inspired by old blues music.

         
      
   
