
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">238</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-Meta-4&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "The so-called
low-hanging <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> has all been picked."
            

            
               "All of the cards
have fallen the wrong way at the same time."
            

            
               "If all you do is
fix the watch, nobody ever builds a better watch."
            

            
               "Everyone's in
deep yogurt."
            

            
               These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> lines
have something in common. What?
            


             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 237</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flawed and Tailored":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               The bombing campaign--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> so far--is working,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klaus Naumann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s senior military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. "We will see
how they will feel after a few more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> or what have you of
continuously pounding them into pieces." However, he adds, "We may have one
flaw in our thinking." What?
            

            "What
if they just don't have feelings? (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music swells ...</ENAMEX>)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. Mattick</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> won't tell us how to use any of our really good bombs."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Some
of the pieces we pound them into may still be large enough to commit
genocide."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "Oh,
sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>, the war may seem funny now, but what if our killing all those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> inspires a violent video game? What about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Because when you are up in the woods shooting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, you just think, 'Hey,
they like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.' OK, that's not really my answer to this question. It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert L. Ransome</ENAMEX>'s answer to an entirely different question about what
might inspire his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Manes</ENAMEX>, to sell a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TEC-DC9</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>. Still, a
very good answer, isn't it?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            There was much less
resistance to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> question than to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> quiz.
Perhaps because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s has a clear foil, in uniform, speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>. It
doesn't get any comedier than that. Or because rationalization is worth
observing and mocking. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> T-shirts, on the other hand, are a minor
crime; it is unbecoming to chide weeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the deceased for not
reacting in a more stylish way. It is appropriate, of course, to attack
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand-wringing commentators</ENAMEX> who offer lame explanations for teen violence, and
many of you did--target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>; not offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> ... well, you know. (It is
curious how few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> connected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories displayed
side by side on every front page for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>--hmmm, where would these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get
these violent ideas?) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> tactical problem emerged in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naumann</ENAMEX>'s
discussion. Because the bombing is continuing for longer than had been
anticipated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> risks running out of targets. This is not a problem for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flawless</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            The flaw: Our plan won't
irresponsible. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naumann</ENAMEX> puts it, "This flaw may be that we believe that
no responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who is at the helm of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> can wish to
run the risk that his entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will be bombed into rubble before he gives
up."

            
               Either/Or
Extra:
            

            

               "This is absolutely not about buying and selling organs."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Nathan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, refers either to his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s new "Give a
Kidney, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Get a Toaster</ENAMEX>" plan, or to its offer of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> death benefit to the
family of any organ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>.

               "We're letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, personalize their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keller</ENAMEX>, marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heinz Ketchup</ENAMEX>, refers either to biologically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">altered chickens</ENAMEX> born in the shape of letters of the alphabet, or to putting
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX> on stuff.

               "It's not like they are just sort of randomly whacking away and knocking
off whatever happens to come off."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geologist Craig Feible</ENAMEX> refers either to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> or to the extraordinary skill of ancient stone toolmakers revealed at a
newly discovered site in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>.

               "What's frightening to me about such changes is not the specific change,
but the direction they suggest."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville Schell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of the journalism school
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, refers either to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Anderson</ENAMEX>'s
breast reduction, or to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's decision to run ads on their front
page.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> can tell the difference."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Jurgensen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , refers either to the previous joke, or to the difference between
news and ads.

               "I don't know how stupid they think we are."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter McDonough</ENAMEX>, spokesman
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>, refers either to your ability to
make up your own joke, or to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s thwarting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> from
shaking hands with newly arriving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>.

               "It's a disease of our time."--TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Lear</ENAMEX> refers either to
shows like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> or ... well, actually, he does refer to shows like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> .

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goofy Teutonic</ENAMEX> confidence unwarranted by
history.

         
      
   
