
   
   
      
         
            Selective Reading

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subscribers</ENAMEX> who receive our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>-friendly
text edition, 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
               , should have received by now an
e-mail message containing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MySlate</ENAMEX> tool, a k a "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasserman</ENAMEX>." It is named
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich Wasserman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kirkland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, a 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> who
took up the challenge of producing a way to print out selected articles from

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                rather than the whole thing. The tool comes as a
Word document with an Install button and simple instructions. Once it's
installed, whenever you have 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                on your screen you
can call up a menu of articles with check boxes to pick the ones you want. (You
can even choose between all the items in a multi-item <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> like
"Chatterbox" or only some of them.) Then the tool will print out your personal
edition of 
                  Slate
               , formatted in two columns for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 1/2</NUMEX>-by-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> paper,
with its own table of contents, containing just the stuff you want. Note: This
gizmo only works with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Word 97</ENAMEX>. But if you've got the right word processor--and
if, for some reason, you don't wish to consume every word of

                  Slate
               --the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasserman</ENAMEX> is pretty cool. Thanks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                itself is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">readable</ENAMEX> and printable by any version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Word</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.0</NUMEX> or later), by recent
versions of most other major word processors, or by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Word Viewer</ENAMEX>, a free bit of
software (which you may already have as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">98</NUMEX>). There's also
a version for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Acrobat</ENAMEX> or a free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acrobat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>. 
                  Slate on
Paper
                is available, at no extra charge, to 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> only. (To subscribe, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, including a free

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">umbrella,</ENAMEX> click here.
We give you the umbrella, in case that's not clear.)

            We now offer a lavish, not to say bewildering,
variety of ways to access the splendors of 
                  Slate
               , and more are on
the way. Here is a summary:

            

               Read 
                     Slate online at slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> . Current contents and recent (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archives</ENAMEX> are free. Most older stuff is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> only.

               
                  Listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
                   through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audible</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> . "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" and several other

                     Slate
                   features are now available in audio versions, for listening
through your computer, through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows CE</ENAMEX> device, or through a portable
proprietary gizmo that lets you listen on headphones or through your car radio.
You must subscribe to this service through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audible</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

               Get 
                     Slate
                  's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> daily e-mail deliveries . The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery includes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> and other features. If you sign up for all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> deliveries you will get most of 
                     Slate
                  's current content
soon after it appears on the site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subscribers</ENAMEX> only. Click
here to sign up.

               Get the weekly 
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                   Word document by e-mail,
containing all of 
                     Slate
                  's contents for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> specially
formatted for printing out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subscribers</ENAMEX> only. Click
here to sign up.

               
                  Download 
                  
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                   directly from our site, in
Word or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Acrobat</ENAMEX> format. (You can also download the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MySlate</ENAMEX> selective
printout tool here, as well as free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> for Word or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acrobat</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subscribers</ENAMEX>
only. Click here to sign up.

               
                  E-mail any individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> article to yourself or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.
Just click on the icon at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of each</TIMEX> article. E-mailing yourself is
a good way to save an article for future reading or to get a compact, text-only
version for printing out. This service is free. You don't have to be a

                     Slate
                   <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX>.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP Instant Delivery</ENAMEX> . Using this free software from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>,
you can have 
                     Slate
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'s Today's Papers</ENAMEX> waiting at your printer every
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. Or (if you don't want to leave your computer and printer on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>)
it will automatically connect to the Internet, fetch and print <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>
when you turn your machine on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the morning</TIMEX>. We've made it easy to get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>-friendly version, but with a bit of effort
this software can also be used to fetch and print any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> on

                     Slate
                   or other Web sites at any time. Click here
to set it up.

               
                  
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper on Paper</ENAMEX> . If you really want a paper version
of 
                     Slate
                  , we will send you a weekly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>-page edition by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mail</ENAMEX>,
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> (our cost). Call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">706-3330</TIMEX> to subscribe.

               Coming soon: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> printer-friendly printouts of individual

                     Slate
                   articles, 
                     Slate
                   on your PalmPilot or Windows
CE device, 
                     Slate
                   on your e-book.

            

            Also: 
                  Slate
                inscribed on a loaf of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>; 
                  Slate
                beamed into your head while you sleep;

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recited</ENAMEX> to you by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX> the talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topiary</ENAMEX>

                  Slate
                (
                  Slate
                articles carved into your shrubbery);

                  Slate
               -by-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massage</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moneybox</ENAMEX>" communicated through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> secret
pressure points on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> only); the 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ballet</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>" reinterpreted for the dance); the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX>'s New

                  Slate
                (we pretend to publish it, you pretend to read
it--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> only); and much more.

         
      
   
