
   
   
      
         
            Whistling in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy</ENAMEX> emerged as the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to threaten the solidarity of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo D'Alema</ENAMEX> called for the air attacks to stop and for
a return to negotiation. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy Slows Down</ENAMEX>, Tension in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>" was the main
headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> , which in a front-page editorial condemned the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> for backtracking so quickly. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s "dignity" and its
"international role" demanded "more serious behavior," it said. "Even the most
frenetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waltz</ENAMEX> turns to which, unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> diplomacy has accustomed
our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX> in the past usually take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than one day</TIMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> said. "In an effort to save the unity of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> and to
prevent a government crisis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo D'Alema</ENAMEX> has split with his international
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were
gathered, saying that this created "a major incident" at the summit.

            D<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'Alema</ENAMEX>'s claim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
that "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> has induced the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to suspend their military
offensive against the civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>" was thoroughly discredited
by reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> on the scene of increased <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> brutality against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX>. A report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> gave
an account of the brutal removal from their home of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s leading human
rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayram Kelmendi</ENAMEX> and his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kastriot</ENAMEX>, who was told before being
taken away to kiss his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for the last time because he would never see
them again. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s decision to expel Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> from the region, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> noted that
neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> had done that.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> continued, alarm grew in the
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> over the apparent lack of clear war aims and the growing fear
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will not succeed in restoring peace to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> without committing
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> said
in a nervous editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that, by ruling out in advance the commitment
of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> before a negotiated peace agreement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> that
its undertaking to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> went only so far--"not exactly the kind of
message to send to an adversary as you go to war." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, by "his bestial
behavior," had courted the disaster now befalling his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said,
but it added: "The world is full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX>. It is also full of oppressed
minorities struggling to be free. Which <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> do we bomb? Which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> do
we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>? When do we charge to the rescue and when do we shrug and look
away? What are the rules of the game? After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, nobody knows."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the
missile attacks, far from frightening "the great ethnic purifier of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>," had made him look almost in the right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> would not be
saved, the editorial added--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> will sooner or later return to the
negotiating table, but that will without doubt be only to effect the partition
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figaro</ENAMEX> also envisaged the partition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> as the undesired outcome
of the war, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> getting the inhospitable mountains and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> the
fertile plain, and it blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for letting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> call the shots by
failing to take responsibility for its own security. History has shown that
military campaigns are only successful if their aims are defined beforehand,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> said, comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> to "a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who whistles in
the dark to reassure himself."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> called for a
political solution, saying that if the bombing goes on for long, the alliance
will become increasingly divided. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>
proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> independence be made "a declared goal of policy--after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, if Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> complies with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX>, sooner if he does
not"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> had already agreed
to the objective of the war--to protect the human rights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>--and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should not balk at the prospect of a long campaign to
achieve it; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> urged the expedition of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>
loan to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> sweet.

            Despite feelings of solidarity with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were generally gloomy and apprehensive
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> offensive. They feared it could fatally damage the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority of the United Nations</ENAMEX> and lead to a resumption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">benefiting Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> and weakening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> by setting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
against each other. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Hayat</ENAMEX> , Abdelwahhab
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Badrakkhan</ENAMEX> wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, by abrogating to itself the right to
decide on the use of military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, had effectively "delegitimized" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>. He called for a new international agreement of the kind that replaced
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Nations</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, for it was unacceptable that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> should become "merely a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go to complain or
engage in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> debates over texts that everyone knows the big powers will
be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to treat with contempt."

            In the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX>
daily <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Awsat</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">al-Husseini</ENAMEX> said the bombing reflected the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s growing penchant for "military solutions as a
substitute for considered plans to impose peace and protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from
massacres." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> expressed concern over the precedent it set for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
military intervention in the internal conflicts of any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. "If tensions
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> grow in the future, what is there to prevent the
former raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> issue and threatening intervention there?" she wrote.
"And if the aim of the intervention is to protect oppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, why,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ask, doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> intervene in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, whose human rights record
vis-a-vis the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> is as bad as it can be?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selectivity</ENAMEX> in approaching issues of human rights and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-determination</ENAMEX> is a long-standing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> trait, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">al-Husseini</ENAMEX> said, adding
that "its resolve in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> perhaps has more to do with upholding the
credibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> as its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary approaches, and to
ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> does not appear weak." But,
she went on, "the airstrikes could not only provoke <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> retaliation against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, but trigger ethnic conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>, which has a
large ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>," and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Balkan</ENAMEX> explosion would severely weaken
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> said that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> get bogged
down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> conflict, as is likely to happen, this will benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>,
the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on the receiving end of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action. It also
described the bombing as a step toward initiating a new, modified <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> and
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> could turn into a latter-day version of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, or even
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.

            The most cheerful
assessment of the situation came in the main headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
daily eRilindja <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demokratikei</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO Brings Peace</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>," it
said.

             

         
      
   
