
   
   
      
         
            Who's Worse, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>?

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> find
a silver lining in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> outrage over the bombing of its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>:
The famously withdrawn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> may finally expand its role in world affairs.
... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> defends
day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>. The onliners have helped the market by driving down commissions
and encouraging efficient pricing. ... A column
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feasts on Larry Summers</ENAMEX>' ill-suitedness for the politicking-heavy job of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> ("Imagine the effort required for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to feign interest
in the idiotic ramblings of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, next to whom the stupidest
graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summers</ENAMEX> ever met was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX>.").

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has been more a relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> than a
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis, sheltering and protecting the displaced as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> became mired in bureaucracy. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is not in the
business of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> on wheels; it should be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>," an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> sighs. ... An editorial argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> riots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> are a
warning that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should stop underestimating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX>
sentiment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. ... A piece explains the drubbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX> has received from
fellow military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> are suspicious of his pedigreed
background and political connections; worse, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s half-hearted military
strategy smells to them of another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. ... A delightful essay slams <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germaine Greer</ENAMEX>'s new book as "a sour and
undiscriminating litany of charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 16</TIMEX>
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> installment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX> series is devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, "the
shadow story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> if you missed the first installment.)
... A brief history rates monogamous marriage, education, employment,
and improved health among the major developments in the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> over
the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand years</TIMEX>. An accompanying time line illustrates women's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progress</ENAMEX>, beginning with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> and ending with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue University</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> women's <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. ... A piece reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are close to creating the first artificial womb.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drawback</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> suspect that fetuses perceive their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>'
emotions in utero. ... An article surveys changing attitudes toward
female sexual pleasure, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Aquinas</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century</ENAMEX>
allegation that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is defective and misbegotten" to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> study suggesting
that orgasms may be linked to fertility. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s food
columnist gushes over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>, calling her "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s superego."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> blasts the hype surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars: The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX>
(its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> turns in major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> were "carefully engineered" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>) but
splashes the film on its cover anyway. Inside, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> brands the film "a big disappointment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Fisher</ENAMEX>, a k a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Leia</ENAMEX>, dryly reminisces about her metal bikini and crush on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>
during the filming of the original trilogy but says she can't even remember
what the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> installment was called. Time applauds the film's splashy
special effects but deems it short on "human magic" (for more early returns, check

                  Slate
               's own "").

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> defends her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> policy
from charges of poor planning and incoherence, and tallies her successes
instead: She consolidated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> support for airstrikes at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX>, has
deftly cultivated consensus among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and is drafting a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marshall Plan</ENAMEX>" to restore stability to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. ... The
magazine tracks how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> around the world are funneling money to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Émigrés</ENAMEX> write checks to organized fund-raising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, which then smuggle cash and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> over remote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
wonders how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> will survive the transition from
honeymoon to full-fledged campaign. ("If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> were a movie, he'd be the new
Star Wars : the closely guarded, breathlessly anticipated next episode in
a multigenerational saga of family destiny.") ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> lauds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> debut, citing her gutsy stances on gun control
and huge potential to win centrist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. She "is running the campaign she
wanted her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to run."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story christens professional wrestling "a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art
form," albeit a savage one: Fifty episodes of a popular wrestling TV show
included "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,658</NUMEX> instances of grabbing or pointing to one's crotch, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">157</NUMEX>
instances of an obscene finger gesture, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">128</NUMEX> episodes of simulated sexual
activity, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> references to urination." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX> also enact
crucifixions, sadomasochism, and prostitution. ... A sidebar speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> is probably
hoarding chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, including nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, blister <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, choking
compounds, and hallucinogens. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> predicts softer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
stances on gun control and abortion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> has sounded the cry for
increasing restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> have
been "mute" on abortion. (For 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s take
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s halfhearted pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stances</ENAMEX>, click .)

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece describes how the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is currently being
published in exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> by a ragtag bunch of twentysomething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, which serves as a lifeline for dispossessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovars</ENAMEX>, is lukewarm on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> and favors the establishment of an international protectorate.
... A mesmerizing article describes how a cadre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, fresh from recent victories over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX>, are going after the
gun industry. Amazing detail: The idea of suing gunmakers, one of the lawyers
says, came straight from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial decrying the
ever-widening scope of tort lawsuits. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> chronicles the
transformation of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby nephew</ENAMEX>, born with a severe genetic cranio-facial
disorder. A series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> has given the baby eyes, fingers, a navel, and
an airway for breathing.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>
            

            A
jubilant cover
story congratulates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX> for the passage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s--and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>--statewide voucher system. To avoid charges of being
anti-public-education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> cannily referred to the vouchers as "opportunity
scholarships." ... An editorial mocks the overtures white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
make to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are "dorky and patronizing;" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is
"schoolmarmy" and self-righteous; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is "cartoonish"; and none is serious
about dismantling the racial and ethnic classifications that still plague
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law. ... A piece recommends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> be awarded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX>. "Shouldn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who saves the world financial system
rank with one who makes a fundamental discovery in the field?"

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24</TIMEX>
            

            Almost
the entire magazine is devoted to opposing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> intervention. The
editorial declares that the intervention "has failed catastrophically." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s release of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POWs</ENAMEX> was a "humane gesture that
should be built upon." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> must stop bombing and let the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>
negotiate on their behalf. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> at its core should police
the peace. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hayden</ENAMEX> calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s war" a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>-style
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quagmire</ENAMEX>" that should be abandoned. ... An article argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is "the armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX> of the new capitalist global order." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> averted its
eyes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s atrocities until it was clearly in the strategic interest
of capitalism to intervene.

         
      
   
