
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Apples</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oranges</ENAMEX>
            

            In "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eliza Truitt</ENAMEX> discusses installing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> on a
PC with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Windows</ENAMEX> already installed on it. She doesn't compare the
reverse; that is, installing Windows from scratch on a machine with Linux
pre-installed on it. It is no piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>, if not downright impossible, for
the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to perform this sort of install. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Installing Linux</ENAMEX> on a PC with
Windows already loaded is far easier.

            In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truitt</ENAMEX> do not generally
install their own operating systems of any type and make heavy use of help
desks on a day-to-day basis to keep their systems running. She talks about
configuring printers, connecting to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, and so forth on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>--I wonder
if she has ever done the same on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows</ENAMEX> machine. Very few computer users
install their own operating systems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>; they buy their computers with
the system pre-loaded. There are plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> who sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> boxes with
Linux pre-installed, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Research</ENAMEX>, and so on.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truitt</ENAMEX> writes, "compare that with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Windows 98</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$199</NUMEX>
for a full setup, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$89</NUMEX> for an upgrade, or bundled for 'free' as part of nearly
every non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> computer." I think that it is pretty nonsensical to make
the statement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> is "free" under any circumstances. Nor does Truitt
note that when you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX> from any of a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> you get far more
than just the OS that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are accustomed to. You get a full
development system with an unlimited server-based OS. The equivalent software
would cost upward of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> if you were to try to duplicate it from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--an unlimited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows NT</ENAMEX> costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>. The
databases, programming tools and applications included in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Linux</ENAMEX> are worth many
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> more--if you can find them at all for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows NT</ENAMEX>.

            If you expect to attract
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to 
                  Slate
               , you really need to do a better job in
presenting balanced, factual reporting.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Larson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Free for
All
            

            I just read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX>'s "," and I feel I have to
write to make a few points. The very <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph contains a stunning number
of errors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linus Torvalds</ENAMEX> is the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> kernel, but he is
by no means the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>. There are literally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX>, who have made contributions to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> distributions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is not derived from an operating system
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU</ENAMEX> is not an operating system but a software <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> that runs on
many operating systems (mostly Unix-based OS's, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> is also supported
by many of the packages). The proper name for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX>, not "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU/Linux</ENAMEX>."
And just for your information, there is a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU</ENAMEX> operating system" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, it's called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HURD</ENAMEX> and it is different in a number of respects
from Unix.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX> makes the claim that just because software is
freely distributable, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have no means of recompense for their work.
That is simply untrue--there are many ways that software can remain free but
still allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> to get paid (just look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RedHat</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>).

            Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> provides no graphical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user interface</ENAMEX>. The truth is that you have a choice--if you want a text
interface you can have it, if you prefer a graphical interface that's fine too.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX> also makes the totally unsubstantiated (and untrue) claims that there is
very little in the way of application software for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> and that very few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use it: The latest estimates of the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> run into the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>--how can that be "so few"?

            Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX> claims that free software is less tested
than commercial software. I use both commercial software and free software in
the course of my work (I'm adminstrator of a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NT</ENAMEX> and Unix
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>), and it's pretty clear to me that it's the free
software that is rigorously tested and the commercial software that gets
released just as soon as it appears to run. Why? Because the incentive to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of free software is to make her package the best, so releasing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inadequately</ENAMEX> tested software will do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s personal reputation no good
at all. The incentive to a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is to get the application on the
shelf so she can derive income from it; if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version 1</ENAMEX> happens to have bugs in
it, the bug fixes become a selling point for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version 2</ENAMEX>.

            I'm not anti-commercial
software or even anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. I am in favor of choice and freedom though,
and your article doesn't exactly encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to exercise their choice and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bennett</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lancaster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zero Zero</ENAMEX>
Sum
            

            It doesn't make a big difference to me--or, I
suspect, to most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Linux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>--whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truitt, Shuman</ENAMEX>, or any other Windows
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX> or not (see ""). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Linux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> don't primarily
care about competing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, or decreasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>'s wealth, or
giving away something for free. Linux <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> simply are creating systems
they themselves enjoy using and find productive.
            

            The main reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are increasingly
concerned about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> increasingly attempts to set
proprietary standards for how data are exchanged. That is, technical and legal
documents are often found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Word formats, access to online and
banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> often requires the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>-only software, multimedia
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> often come in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>-only formats, and hardware often only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. This is not because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> are
necessarily better, but because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, and that's
what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are going to focus their efforts on when writing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and
software; there are, after all, only limited resources for writing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and
front-end software.

            So, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> have about Windows are
related to whether network effects involving proprietary content formats are
going to exclude them from some areas of public and commercial life. Just like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truitt</ENAMEX> would not enjoy being forced to struggle with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Linux</ENAMEX> users
don't enjoy being forced to do their work on Windows using its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WIMP</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interface</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> needs to
become more sensitive to concerns about interoperability and open standards.
Recent efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in the areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XML</ENAMEX> and other Web standards are
encouraging. Clear support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Java</ENAMEX> would also be good (and would, in the
long run, benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>). I hope that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> matures, so will its
attitude toward standards and cooperation. The computer market is big enough
that it does not need to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>-take-all.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas M.</ENAMEX>
Breuel
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Simple
Elegance
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eliza Truitt</ENAMEX>'s article,
"A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor of Linux</ENAMEX>," on her experiences with her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Linux installation</ENAMEX> provides
wonderful inspiration for the intimidated. But a word to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truitt</ENAMEX>: The term
"elegant" in science and technology has a special meaning apart from common
use. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elegance</ENAMEX> is not synonymous with "simple." Rather, it refers to the most
terse solution to a problem. Such a solution will tend to be cryptic to
the uninitiated. Therefore, "elegant" is most often used by those after the
fact of having used a procedure successfully. For the others, I would venture
to say, their word for it would be arcane.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Imai</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>

            
               Emperor Has No
Clothes
            

            Please note in your fascinating "" on hara-kiri
that there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point on which I believe you are mistaken. In feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who would order suicides in place of executions was the
shogun, or military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. Emperors, excepting the period from the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 19 th century</TIMEX> to the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, have yielded little if
any power in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> society.

            One fascinating example
of ritual suicide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> that still regularly appears
in movies and television in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is the story of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> samurai. According to
this actual historical account, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> period shogun
antagonized a rival to the point where this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> drew his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>. This all
occurred in front of the shogun, which meant serious trouble, because
displaying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shogun</ENAMEX>'s presence was punishable by death. Despite
the fact that he was forced into this situation, the offending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> was
sentenced to death and committed suicide as you described in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.
After this, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> of the condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>'s samurai decided to take revenge.
They coordinated an attack on the enemy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> and murdered him. Honor called
on them to avenge their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s death, but the laws forbade murder. After
regaining their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s honor, all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> samurai went to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s grave and
also committed hara-kiri to take responsibility for breaking the law. The site
of these samurai's graves is still a well-visited location in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
Cojerian
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
