
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Pork Quoi</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               A big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-page ad running in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> today features a photo of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">piglets</ENAMEX> vigorously suckling a sow's teats. An ad for what?
            

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 234</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Can't Kuwait":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               You give the lead, I give the headline from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait Times</ENAMEX> :
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tips To Reduce 'Burden' of Students</ENAMEX>."
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> could hardly believe his ears. 'You'll give me <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a dinar</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>?'
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> said. 'And all I have to do is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s
homework?' " -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Poniewozik</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Offering controversial advice to overwhelmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> unveiled a new
motto: 'It's not a setback, it's an opportunity.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "Koran
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> now available."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX>
            

            "In an
effort to give young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> more time to study, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> today
began enrolling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Carry Your Sons to Class</ENAMEX>' program."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cavanaugh</ENAMEX>
            

            "In a
new twist on the controversial practice of 'redeeming' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> from
bondage, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>'s education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> is proposing to buy up the whole inventory
in order to provide every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> with a personal bearer.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'You</ENAMEX> wouldn't believe how heavy those backpacks are,' he told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. 'No
wonder test scores are down.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Why Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bother To Read the Paper II</ENAMEX>: If you've
ever attended an event that was covered in the press--a ball game, a
demonstration, a series of seemingly motiveless break-ins at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>--you know how little the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> version resembles your experience. Oh,
it often gets the least important things right, the facts, the small <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"t</ENAMEX>" truth.
But the tone, the texture, the feel of the event is never correct, and that's
where you find the capital "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">T</ENAMEX>" truth. Here's how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> put a similar
problem, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18, 1775</TIMEX>: "We must consider how very little history there is;
I mean real authentick history. That certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> reigned, and certain battles
were fought, we can depend upon as true; but all the colouring, all the
philosophy, of history is conjecture."

            To more vividly convey that coloring, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> encourage their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to wield the tools of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>,
opening a story with an evocative detail, such as these leads, both from the
front of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Estela Lopeze</ENAMEX> dreamed of saving
enough money to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> to open a clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and build a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-bedroom <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>"; and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rani</ENAMEX>, an illiterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">washermen</ENAMEX>'s
caste, changed into her prettiest sari <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one recent morning</TIMEX>."

            When this technique
works, you get a powerful story, albeit one whose subject is not revealed until
around the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> paragraph. When it doesn't, you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Bragg</ENAMEX> and a queasy
feeling in your stomach. And when both news and coloring are avoided, you get
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait Times</ENAMEX> and a nice <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> nap.

            
               Unburdened
Answer
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KUWAIT</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> have advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to stick to
their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> timetable and carry only those books needed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> besides
taking extra care to sit straight while studying. This advice is significant
taking into consideration the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are faced with a
pressing problem--backaches. The culprit here is the school bag which every
student carries to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> crammed with books and they end up with various
back-related problems, such as backaches or backbone injuries. Addressing a
issue of such importance concerning the younger ones of society, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
Times met with a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and sought their opinion."

            My favorite expert
opinion comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dina Al-Refai</ENAMEX>, family medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>: "All these aches
may instill in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> a hatred towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and finally have a
negative impact on his academic performance, she remarked."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuwaiti Fun Facts Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>

            

               Amirs, or princes, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Sabah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> in
consultation with prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> figures for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 200 years</TIMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, adopted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> shortly after independence, provides for
an elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Assembly.</ENAMEX> It also permits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amir</ENAMEX> to suspend its articles
during periods of martial law.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amir</ENAMEX> twice suspended constitutional provisions, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976 to 1981</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1986 to 1992</TIMEX>, and ruled extraconstitutionally during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these</TIMEX> periods.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> cannot change their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> bans formal political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do not have the
right to vote or seek election to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Assembly.</ENAMEX>

               According to government statistics, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92 percent</NUMEX> of the indigenous work force
is employed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreigners</ENAMEX> constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX> of the private
sector work force.

               Domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> are not protected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Law</ENAMEX>, and unskilled foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> suffer from the lack of a minimum wage in the private sector and from
failure to enforce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Law</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Males</ENAMEX> must obtain government approval to marry foreign-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> restricts freedom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>.

               Public gatherings must receive prior government
approval, as must private gatherings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> that result in
the issuance of a public statement.

            

            Really, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> worth
going to war for ...

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Kuwaitis are rich lay-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abouts</ENAMEX> waited on by
impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
