
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial warns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to do some birthday
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soul-searching</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> must establish an international protectorate in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> that guarantees refugees the right of return, and it must reassure a
wary world that it will not make a habit of waging war on sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.
Failure could mean "terminal decline." ... A long, fascinating
survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> says the narrow interests of some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s "broader vision" and wonders whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' conflicting positions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> could strain the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> in the future. ... An article describes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>-run <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> anti-smoking
campaign. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> billboard features a bikini-clad tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, poolside with
cigarette and black socks. The campaign is demonstrably successful, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> wants to slash its budget.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willing Executioners</ENAMEX>," says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbs</ENAMEX> actively support the ethnic cleansing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and the murder of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> honestly believe themselves to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> did not
need to push them into violence. The piece is full of chilling anecdotes about
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' "gratuitous sadism" and indifference to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> suffering. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> slams <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> for acting as a conduit for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
propaganda. Rather than try to subvert or oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>'s censorship, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happily</ENAMEX> accepted it in exchange for "access."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story deplores
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americanization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> politics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>
hired by the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Finkelstein</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> and others for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>--have brought
sound bites, attack ads, and wedge issues to the campaign. Sadly, this has
removed all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> politics and left it just as vapid as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montenegrin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Djukanovic</ENAMEX> calls him the West's best hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
stooge, he has become an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">democrat</ENAMEX>. Problem:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> may take the opportunity provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing to depose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Djukanovic</ENAMEX> and install a more subservient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. ... A feature marvels
at military food, which now includes a barbecue chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich</ENAMEX> that lasts
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> without spoiling and airdrop rations that "flutter, rather than
plummet, down to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, lest they take anyone out in the process." Next step:
"a transdermal nutrient delivery system"--that is, a food patch.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                
               and

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">spring</ENAMEX>'s most anticipated war--in other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars: The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               gushes over the "fresh, handsome, grand" new movie and
publishes a fold-out guide to its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and techno-military toys. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
Moyers interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX>' "true theology."
(Moyers: "In authentic religion, doesn't it take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kierkegaard</ENAMEX>'s leap of faith<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>: "Yes ... that is what 'Use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>' is.")

            The real war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is featured inside, as it is
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">berates NATO</ENAMEX> for its self-congratulatory and ill-timed
birthday celebrations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">berates NATO</ENAMEX> for its obfuscation of civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               dusts off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> thesis,
which doubted the "coercive effects ... of air attacks." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McNamara</ENAMEX>
tells 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that "it is totally inappropriate for
an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, in the middle of a war ... in which there are great
difficulties ahead ... to be talking about mistakes." He then blames military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> for overestimating the effectiveness of bombing.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> was first peopled by "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow Coalition</ENAMEX> of ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>," not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bering Strait</ENAMEX>-crossing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>
commonly depicted in history textbooks. New evidence suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>
migrated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Rim</ENAMEX> in canoes and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> followed the frozen
shoreline to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> predicts that the research could
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relegate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> to "just another <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellis Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>" and
threaten their hard-won legal rights.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports on
new research showing that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 450</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal species</ENAMEX>--including giraffes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goats</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>--become sexually aroused through homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rubbing</ENAMEX>,
entwining, and kissing. Dissenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> question whether close genital
contact is really sex. The piece does not include reaction from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story frets about widespread hearing loss. Noisy
appliances will soon sport warning labels, and earplugs and earmuffs will
become ubiquitous. ... The magazine reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> met secretly
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> but decided not to arm them. A story says that half the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> under
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 15</TIMEX>. ... A piece says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> have
fueled an enrollment boom with deep tuition discounts and open enrollment
policies. ("It's against our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> perspective to be elitist or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exclusionary</ENAMEX>," explains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26 and May 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> devotes a
double issue to money. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece chronicles the frenetic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Meeker</ENAMEX>,
the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> who orchestrated stock offerings for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape, Priceline</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX>. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who once worked in a sweatshop defends
them. Conditions aren't as bad as union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> indicate, and immigrant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers grouse</ENAMEX> only about losing work to cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> abroad. ...
An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> gripes about how tough it was to grow up rich. She doesn't even know
how much is in her trust fund.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
                
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece opines that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, is responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
underestimation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s obstinacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> is adding a dark afterword
to new editions of his book on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> diplomacy. ... The cover story
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charts America</ENAMEX>'s "struggle to rediscover a compelling patriotic language" and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exults</ENAMEX> in the "new, crunchier" patriotism embodied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
Nation
                
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story charts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milken</ENAMEX>'s attempt to become "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Walton</ENAMEX> of gray matter" by acquiring a
"cradle to grave" series of education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, from preschools to vocational
training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. The piece chides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milken</ENAMEX> for failing to include critical
assessments of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> junk bond markets in his textbooks. ... The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> publishes an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>voucher screed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Unz</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s ban on bilingual education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unz</ENAMEX> writes that public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are
vital to social cohesion and proposes an ideological truce on the issue: If the
left will acknowledge that its efforts to reform public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have failed,
the right will stop pushing "to turn our public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> over to ideological
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zealots</ENAMEX> or the marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
