
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trapped</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is trapped. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slobo</ENAMEX> made financial arrangements for a luxurious exile,
but since his indictment as a war criminal the most he can hope for is a safe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haven</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belarus</ENAMEX>. Not beloved by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> might be hard-pressed to
retain power even with the support of his secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX>, and
state-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. ... The cover story argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> economy has stalled
because of a complicated tax system, overgenerous welfare, and excessive labor
costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> is dragging down the euro, but both might rebound because the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is deregulating, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> are learning accommodation, and a
cheaper euro may boost exports.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice presidency</ENAMEX> is worth more
than a bucket of warm piss. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veeps</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> were administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is a "Principal" who enjoys <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet-level</ENAMEX> authority and
has weekly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-on-ones with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, the press is
likely to focus more on his stilted campaigning than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his eight years</TIMEX> of insider
experience. ... An article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mocks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s scripted stump appearances.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Opinion-makers</ENAMEX> may be tired of her act, but she is savvier than she seems. Her
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-control stance and neutrality on abortion appeal to the increasingly
prosperous and moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>, allowing her to seem like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>. ... A piece attacks the rumormongering about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
past. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> raised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> for bad-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> behavior. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> won't care about
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did, and nor should they. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disclosure</ENAMEX>: 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah</ENAMEX> wrote the article.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6</TIMEX>
            

            
Adventure is the theme of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> installment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s millennium
series. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> explores his own brain through magnetic resonance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imaging</ENAMEX>, finding the physical locations for his ability to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> of familiar faces, and his storytelling ability. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist Richard Ford</ENAMEX> and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Crouch re-enact Huck Finn</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>'s voyage down the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi River</ENAMEX> and pen their respective reactions:
Crouch rejoices that it's no longer anomalous for a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a white man
to share a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>; but the trip leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> unsettled about his own latent
racism. ... A photo essay documents <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in an "adventure
competition" in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> had to hike, kayak, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rollerblade</ENAMEX>, and swim across
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">360 miles</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jungles</ENAMEX>, mountains, lakes, and islands. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> had
to include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, use traditional, nonpolluting modes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>, and perform a social service project along the way.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover report slams the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cox</ENAMEX> report for asserting more than it
proves and hysterically claiming that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
are asked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The report actually documents the theft
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warhead</ENAMEX>'s technology. ... A related article contends that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s military is no challenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>'. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has no aircraft
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> or long-range strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>. One ominous note: If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> did steal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> technology, it could take a great leap toward nuclear parity.
... A piece urges national mental-health reform. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> good step: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bill to require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> to cover mental-health treatment just as they
cover other kinds of medical care.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story exults that now is the best time ever to be black
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Black employment, home ownership, academic achievement, and college
enrollment are up; out-of-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">wedlock</NUMEX> births, violent crime, poverty, and welfare
enrollment are down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> aren't celebrating because they fear an economic
downturn and because equality is still elusive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whites</ENAMEX> still outearn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>,
black unemployment is twice the rate of white unemployment, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> of
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are disenfranchised because of felony convictions. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> profiles middle-class black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homesteaders</ENAMEX> who are
regenerating ghettos. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> common and successful idea: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>-run credit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story clucks over the dismal state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino-U.S.</ENAMEX>
relations. One vivid detail: After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
produced an anti-NATO music video. ... Horrified by the rise of casual
office wear, the garment industry is launching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> campaign to popularize
formal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attire</ENAMEX>, says an article . All kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> are getting in on the act:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Puffy" Combs'</ENAMEX> "fall collection is full of dressier sportswear."

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> questions the canonization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Stein</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>
who perished in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s dubious miracle--a prerequisite to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sainthood</ENAMEX>--was to "cure" a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> girl named after her who overdosed on Tylenol
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. ... A piece describes the manifold accomplishments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Varmus</ENAMEX>, who has won bipartisan support for
the research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, focused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> on nuts-and-bolts research rather than
disease-of-the<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-week</TIMEX> fads, and artfully guided the human genome project. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varmus</ENAMEX>'
peaceful reign could be interrupted when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> decides soon if it
should fund research performed with scientifically valuable but politically
controversial stem cells from human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryos</ENAMEX> and fetuses. ... A writer
joins <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> trekking through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhutan</ENAMEX>--a remote, devoutly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>, and
unusually fecund <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--in search of fertility blessings. None of the
pilgrims produce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but all are charmed by the enormous penises that
decorate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s walls, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX>
            

            An
editorial darkly warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is modernizing and expanding its military in
order to displace <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s dominant power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cox</ENAMEX> report might
finally rouse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to the hostility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and end our
destructive policy of engagement. ... The cover story denounces the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum of American History</ENAMEX>. Multicultural prejudice distorts its
presentation, stripping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s history of its heroic high points. ...
An article flays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign Committee</ENAMEX>: He is an artless buffoon whose only asset is
his family name, which he uses to woo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and to intimidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
