
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peace Deal by Next Week</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> hit the wrong targets again in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>. A bomb struck a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX>, and the homes
of several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s explanation: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX> was "misdirected for technical reasons." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> explanation: The
sick and the newborn are "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> has
reportedly accepted a peace plan drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sticking points: He objects to a peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and to the withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> stops
bombing. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> say they're "not that optimistic" about a deal, but
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> predicted "a political settlement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next week</TIMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
consensus on the use of force splintered. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> called for an invasion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> threatened to veto ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy</ENAMEX> recommended a bombing
halt for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> resolution is announced. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York</ENAMEX>
Times reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX> supports stationing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s borders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prepping</ENAMEX> for ground war will force
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to consider a deal. The counterspin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prepping</ENAMEX> for ground war will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">force Milosevic</ENAMEX> to call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">bluff</ENAMEX>.

            

               A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> at a suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> high
school. No one died, evidently because he aimed below the waist. He
had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> but only used the latter. Afterward, he tried to shoot
himself but couldn't do it, saying, "Oh, my God, I'm so scared." Theory <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: He
was distraught because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> had broken up with him. Theory <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: It was
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of school, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> said, "he's been wanting to do this all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year long</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cited the shooting as another reason to tighten
gun laws. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> called it "yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> attack in a
comfortable suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>." The reassuring spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> shootings are
unlikely to happen in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. The cynical spin: That's what officials
in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> school
massacre.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> passed another gun control measure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
amendment would require background checks for all purchases at gun shows and
for anyone who tries to buy back his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> from a pawn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. It would also extend
some background checks from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one to three days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> called it another
retreat for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>--in part due to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> shooting earlier in the
day--and a big campaign issue for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, who cast the deciding
vote after a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-50</NUMEX> tie. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) We're dismayed by these school
shootings. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) We're delighted that these school shootings are discrediting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are fleeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> like scalded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mad dogs</ENAMEX>. The conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spins: 1</ENAMEX>) Gun laws are unenforceable. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> administration
doesn't do enough to enforce gun laws.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> approved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s choice for prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. He is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Stepashin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. This comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> fired then-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> and survived an impeachment vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>' will to oppose him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legislators</ENAMEX> blew off
their steam in the impeachment vote and had little interest in fighting over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stepashin</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) They worried that if they rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stepashin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> would
nominate someone worse. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) They worried that if they rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stepashin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> might call a new election, threatening their jobs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) They figure they
don't need to reject <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stepashin</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> will fire him soon enough.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> struck down two-tiered welfare benefits.
This affects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that restrict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> to the benefits they had
received in their previous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, ostensibly to discourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from
benefit-shopping. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-2</ENAMEX> decision. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
It's a victory for the right to welfare. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's a victory for equal rights. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
It's a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who want to block <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> from restricting civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberties</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It's a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who want to block <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> from
regulating business and restricting property rights. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Rather than pay more to
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will equalize benefits by paying less to old
residents.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> ousted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. He
was soundly defeated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> after other candidates
quit so that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> could unite behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spins: 1</ENAMEX>) Now the peace process can move forward again. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The election wasn't
between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX>; it was between a dovish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>) and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawkish dove</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The election wasn't about the peace process; it was
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s tribal domestic politics. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The election wasn't about issues;
it was about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is slimy and untrustworthy. Check
the latest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election</TIMEX> results here .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charismatic</ENAMEX> is one race away from winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triple Crown</ENAMEX>.
Having won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Derby</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31-1</NUMEX> odds (the longest long-shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>), he surprised the bookmakers again by winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preakness</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8-1</ENAMEX>. A
victory in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belmont Stakes</ENAMEX> would make him the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triple Crown</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. He was such a disappointment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> tried to sell him for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$62,500</NUMEX>, but nobody bought him. His jockey in both
races, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Antley</ENAMEX>, is coming back from a bout with drug abuse in the late
'80s and a weight problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale ride" for
"the ex-claimer and the comeback <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>." ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Nag to Riches</ENAMEX>," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's not such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>'s trainer
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, who have already won numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triple Crown</ENAMEX> races. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> loves
being disrespected, and he strutted before and after the race to show up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bookies</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson-Sally Hemings</ENAMEX> controversy flared up
again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">descendants 1</ENAMEX>) invited some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemings</ENAMEX>' descendants
to attend an exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gathering (the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monticello Association</ENAMEX>"); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
voted down a motion to eject the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hemings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> from the gathering; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) voted down
a proposal to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemingses</ENAMEX> honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> immediately; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) appointed
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to decide whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemingses</ENAMEX> are real descendants or impostors
(despite demonstrated genetic links). The spin from the inclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffersons</ENAMEX>:
The rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are racist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snobs</ENAMEX> who won't acknowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> had an
affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>. The spin from the exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffersons</ENAMEX>: "We're not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">racists</ENAMEX>. We're snobs."

         
      
   
