
   
   
      
         
            The Politics of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>

            "There are some things so
intangible that only culture explains them," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> said to me many years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. It had been a long, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>-filled dinner, and the talk had turned to serious
matters. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>, was warming to his subject: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX> affair with claret--red <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>--was one of the great, and for him
joyous, mysteries of life. Another, he continued, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>'s
proclivity for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">port</ENAMEX>. As you can tell, his interests were limited, but he was
making a (vinous) version of an argument that has been given great credence in
intellectual circles of late.

            Culture is hot. By
culture I don't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionism</ENAMEX>--they've always been
hot--but rather culture as an explanation for social phenomena. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> now use
the concept of national or ethnic culture routinely to answer seemingly complex
questions. Why is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> economy bursting with growth? It's obvious:
our unique entrepreneurial culture. Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> unable to adapt to
capitalism? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, it has a feudal, anti-market culture. Never mind that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture was around to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> stagflation, not to mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feudalism</ENAMEX> seem to have adapted nicely to
capitalism.

            Cultural explanations persist because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> like
them. They make valuable the detailed knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' histories, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> have in great supply. And they add an air of mystery and
complexity to the study of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>. But beneath them usually lurks something
more simple and straightforward--such as politics.

            Consider claret. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> drink <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX> because for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> of that region
were given preferential tariff treatment for powerful political reasons. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 th century</TIMEX>, when our story begins, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> actually liked and
imported vast quantities of somewhat acidic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Rochelle</ENAMEX> (now the
Charentes region north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>), a sunny and frost-free area, whose wine
exports were aggressively promoted by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke of Aquitaine</ENAMEX>. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duke</ENAMEX>'s lands included <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX> died, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1152</TIMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquitaine</ENAMEX>, married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Plantagenet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Normandy</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years</TIMEX>
later, he became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. (Their fiery
relationship was memorably replayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter O'Toole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Hepburn</ENAMEX> in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX> .)

            Initially, little changed, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>, like her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
still favored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Rochelle</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bordelais</ENAMEX> coveted the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> market and
worked tirelessly for special favors. Over time, as it always does, the
lobbying worked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> set up a classic political trade that
would make any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Street</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> proud. In return for support against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> (who knows why, they were always at war in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
would exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX> from the principal tax on its exports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Rochelle</ENAMEX> miscalculated and did not counteroffer, infuriating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, who
decided to favor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX> further. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> ordered that all his household
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> would come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>--a huge order, since it included the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s
supplies. "What finally decided it against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Rochelle</ENAMEX> was not the acidity of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, but the disloyalty of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>," writes wine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>. Thus was born the special, mystical relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">port</ENAMEX>, in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th century</TIMEX> the naval rivalry between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, on the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, on the other, was still intense. In this
diplomatic game, keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> happy was crucial so that its seaports,
particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX>, would not become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> bases. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1703</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> struck a
deal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Methuen Treaty</ENAMEX>, which got <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> itself with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> powers. Naturally, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> got something out of
it--a lowering of import tariffs on its products and some royal patronage. When
war between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> did break out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> consumer market
needed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substitutes</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> proved cheap and--within a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--readily available. Amusingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> that created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> were not actually the sweet wines of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but rather normal
table <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>. Far from having a natural affinity for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">port</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> simply
drank it because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> had already made inroads into the consumer
market.

            The moral of this story is not that taste, let alone
culture, doesn't matter. After all, once the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> got hooked on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>
they stayed with it even after most preferential treatment abated (around
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1453</TIMEX>). And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>'s love of red <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> has had massive, global
effects. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, it created the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX> wine industry. Whole
swaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>, including much of what is now considered the best wine
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, were cultivated in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> demand. Also, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
were the global superpower and style setters of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th century</ENAMEX>
world, everybody copied their tastes. That's why <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>, the most expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> in the world are made
from the same grape (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cabernet sauvignon</ENAMEX>) and in the same style as red <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>,
down to the shape of the bottle.

            But culture itself can be shaped and changed. Behind
so many cultural attitudes, tastes, and preferences lie the political and
economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> that shaped them, even in something as intangible as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and
food. All of which makes me glad that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great powers that lost out in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>'s power struggles were <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, or we might be savoring
the delights of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">borscht</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauerkraut</ENAMEX>, washed down by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gallons</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX>!

         
      
   
