
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">203</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Gloat, Little Gloat Worm&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seafood Restaurants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX> can all make the same
boast. What?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               

                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 202</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Sentence?</ENAMEX>": Under pressure from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX> will add a single sentence to each
print ad for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winston</ENAMEX>. Saying what?
               

            

            "Banned
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, but now qualifies as an assisted-suicide device in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "Due to
interference from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX> regrets to
announce that it will no longer include a free toy in every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winstons</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "No
cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camels</ENAMEX> were used in the marketing of this product."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Henley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Powers</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            "These
fine tobacco products can be comfortably smoked through a tracheotomy
hole."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Golub</ENAMEX> and Meg
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolitzer</ENAMEX>)
            

            "Smoke
up: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX> needs a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capitol building</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Poniewozik</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers. 

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            After smoking a pack of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camels</ENAMEX> a day for a dozen
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, I gave it up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. I still miss it. Cigarettes stimulate thought,
distract from woe, and require playing with matches. Cigarettes promote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimacy</ENAMEX>: What could be sexier than sharing a smoke, passing that small fire
from hand to hand? Cigarettes impose form on your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>; they are a means of
demarcation: You smoke <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after something and before something else. And they
look so cool. I'd be smoking right now if it weren't for the part about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hideous respiratory illness</ENAMEX> and coughing away my life in a painful and
protracted demise.

            I intend to resume the
habit as a delight of old age; my first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> check will just about
cover the cost of a carton. Smoking will offer a reliable indoor pleasure that
I can enjoy seated, much to be desired in my decrepitude. And malignancy
develops slowly. With a little luck, by the time I contract a fatal disease,
I'll already be dead. You'd think instead of messing around with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX>
would produce a brand it can market to old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. Call it <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden One Hundreds</ENAMEX>.
Use the slogan: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, feeling lucky?"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delightful Double</ENAMEX>
Negative Answer
            

            "No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additives</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> does not mean a safer
cigarette."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston</ENAMEX>'s "no bull" ads
proclaim that the cigarettes are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> tobacco with no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> was
shocked--shocked!--to learn that some might interpret this as a health claim.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18 months</TIMEX> since the campaign began, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winston</ENAMEX>'s market share rose from
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.86 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.93 percent</NUMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sermons</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            All preached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>; none
actually heard by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Better Than Evian"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Blackburn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of the Pilgrims, Congregational</ENAMEX>)--Promotional fee paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perrier</ENAMEX>. At
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX>, sacred product placement.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thirsty?</ENAMEX>!" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev. Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale D. Hansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Luke's</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX>)--What would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> drink? Or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Blackburn</ENAMEX>?

            "Are There Any <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rats in Your Cellar?</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas K. Tewell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth Avenue Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX>)--Either that's a metaphor
or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> has started a pest removal sideline.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Divine Maitre d'...</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Barrie Shepherd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Presbyterian</ENAMEX>)--Would you ask the divine wine
steward what goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>? And send over a bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Perrier</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Winsomely toxic
products.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
