
   
   
      
         
             Stop <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making Sense</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gerth</ENAMEX> is famous for being a terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. Here,
for example, is a sample from the series that won <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gerth a 1998 Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX>
for national reporting, announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>:

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s decision was valuable to
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX> because it enabled her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to do more business with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but it had also been sought by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral Space and Communications</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Electronics</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors Corporation</ENAMEX>, seeking to do more
business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
            

            That may not seem so bad, until you consider dozens
of such sentences strung together. And take a closer look. Why the "but"?
Something was "valuable to Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX>" but "had also been sought by"
others? "But" suggests a contradiction, but there is nothing contradictory
about the notion that an item valuable to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would be sought by others
as well. Many investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, and the impenetrable
prose is held to be the price you pay for the dirt they unearth. But this small
example illustrates how bad writing can actually help an investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
to paper over the holes in his case. He can imply something without saying
so--in this case, that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s decision" must have been motivated as a
favor either to this Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, or to those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            Stripped of clutter and
confusion, the gist of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX> series was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
had helped a campaign contributor to leak important military secrets to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            The longer version (still a lot shorter than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth's</ENAMEX>) is
this: Several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> would like to hire the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> space agency
to launch satellites for them. They are legally prohibited from doing so
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> worries about sharing aerospace technology with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. But the law also allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to waive this rule on a
case-by-case basis if doing so is in the "national interest." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidents</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have granted these waivers, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> launches had
been approved.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> missile carrying an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> exploded just after takeoff. The satellite's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>, subsequently helped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> figure out
what went wrong. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gerth</ENAMEX> revealed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> study concluding that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> had spilled national security secrets during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> accident review.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s conclusions led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> to begin a criminal
investigation.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, Gerth
reported, had dealt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> investigation "a serious blow" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. He had "quietly" permitted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> to export to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> the same technology
supposedly leaked in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> incident. He ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> concerns
that approving this technology transfer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> would make it harder to convict
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> of harming national security by leaking it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years earlier</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX> also
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> was a generous contributor to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>.

            In other words: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
possibly in violation of the law; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) this imperiled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national security; but
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "quietly" let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> off the hook. Let's take these claims <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            First, the claim that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> had a "corporate mindset in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">priority</ENAMEX> was to fix" the failed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX> makes this sound bad,
even treasonous. But this is an example of useful bad writing that implies more
than it delivers. After all, if you're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of launching satellites
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>--with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government approval--it's not unreasonable to
take some interest in making sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> work.

            Furthermore, tucked away in part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> series (a
piece not nominated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>) are the following <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> facts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-accident</ENAMEX> report was initiated not by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> but by its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The
report was released to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> by accident: An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> faxed it off
before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> vetted it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> tried in vain to block the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transmission</ENAMEX> just after it had occurred. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX>,
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> voluntarily revealed this breach of security to the
government, precipitating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> investigation. None of this proves that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> wasn't disloyal or criminally negligent in its dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. But
it certainly complicates the story, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX> either downplayed it or left it
out.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the claim that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> security. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX>'s prize-winning articles do not mention a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
report concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> security was not harmed by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> accident
review. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> report was revealed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>,
but even subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX> pieces make no mention of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX>'s original piece
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> believed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> had "significantly improved the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">reliability of China</ENAMEX>'s nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>." By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX> was writing, with a
tinge of desperation, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> "did not find grave damage but did
conclude that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> national security had been harmed." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX> also
failed to mention that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> reaching this highly qualified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX> had a long-standing grudge against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. This information is also
courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which quoted public testimony from a
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had "neutered" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "quietly" approved the second
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> launch in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX> means to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was
attempting to hide an out-and-out favor to a political crony. But a subsequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX> article (also not nominated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>) revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
immediately notified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> decision. Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX> really
be serious? Submitting a decision to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> counts as "quietly"?
Moreover, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX>'s article the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> released a series of documents
detailing the decision. The documents show, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX> himself acknowledged in
reporting them, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> and all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s top national
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> recommended that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> approve it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
added that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>'s initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>!-- recommended
approval.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gerth</ENAMEX> waited until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> after his leadoff article, to mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s predecessor,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, had approved all the waiver applications that reached his desk and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself "routinely followed the practice ... signing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> waivers." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> allowed launches by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Electronics Corp.</ENAMEX>, an aerospace firm
also subsequently accused of giving secrets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, which backed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> campaign. Late in his prize-winning series, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX> wrote some harsh
things about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' lobbying of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but he scarcely mentioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> connections.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX>'s series of articles did illustrate how, under
current campaign finance law, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is certain to make national security
decisions affecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to which he is beholden. If he'd presented it that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>--as an example of the need for campaign finance reform--he would have had a
more honest piece, though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> less likely to win a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>. But what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX>
alleges, and fails to prove, is the much more glamorous charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
short-circuited existing laws to allow a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> to sell
ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> secrets to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. If true, it would probably count as
treason, which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> briefly considered adding
this charge to the list of impeachable offenses. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerth</ENAMEX>'s reporting fell far
short of demonstrating this--a fact that would be obvious if his writing were a
bit better.

         
      
   
