
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">251</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Now Even Reformier&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Gary Bretton</ENAMEX>
Granatoor of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Wise Synagogue</ENAMEX>, at the forefront of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
Reform Judaism, says, "There is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morei Derech</ENAMEX>,
which means role models, and they are lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> taking on responsibilities
that in the past many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregants</ENAMEX> felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> had to do." What
responsibilities?
            

            
               
                  (This question
courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 250</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musa</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ake</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Musashimaru</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akebono</ENAMEX> to become
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> 
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yokozuna</ENAMEX> . Why is this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noteworthy</ENAMEX>?
                  
               
            

            "No
kidding!!! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, one of these days I'm gonna get cable TV!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>
Aranha
            

            
"Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> says so."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musashimaru</ENAMEX> is actually a ring-tailed lemur."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer</ENAMEX>
Gabel
            

            "By
dominating sumo, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have finally got the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> back for beating
us in manufacturing."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX>
            

            "
'Because there is no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> calendar,' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encyclopedia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> sputtered with rage. 'Your story's a fake. Therefore,
you're the real jewel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Poniewozik</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Few things are more amusing than the national games
of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Even the box scores are funny, so comical are the names of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>. (Although <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> is brilliant: Small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars ram</ENAMEX> a
huge ball into a goal. It looks ultra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, like demolition derby with a
higher purpose.) But for sheer tedium, nothing can rival our own national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pastime</ENAMEX>. When you are in the field, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX> of that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the
inning is spent doing nothing: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> is simply holding the ball. And when
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is hitting, you spend nearly all that time sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dugout</ENAMEX>.
Thus, for any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the game is spent doing nothing at all.

            Of course, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12-minute</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarters</TIMEX> of a
professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half hours</TIMEX> to televise, but at
least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> they have the decency to call that downtime what it is: a TV
commercial.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Baseball</ENAMEX> is also,
incidentally, the only sport where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> can smoke during the game; you used
to catch appealing glimpses on television of some professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> puffing
away. It made a welcome change from the spitting. I think a lot more people
would watch figure skating if they let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> smoke. And diving. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sumo</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Gaijin
Answer
            

            For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 300-year</TIMEX> history of sumo,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> became grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> by defeating another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX>.

            Both are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polynesian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samoan</ENAMEX> ancestry. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akebono</ENAMEX> became the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">yokozuna</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wrestlers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, and
Mongolia are also currently active. A few foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rikishi</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX>--have become popular, but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> charge that
they prevail through sheer size rather than agility. Musashimaru weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">473</NUMEX>
pounds.

            
               Neck and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neck</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            "I just read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hominem</ENAMEX> remarks about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX> and his neck. Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris K.</ENAMEX> put
his own neck on the line. Is it scarf-worthy? Maybe he should have it pierced
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> or something. We all have necks. The question is, do we stick it
out? Do we risk it? Or is it just a love item?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfa-Betty Olsen</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>'s Can
You <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top This Bloated Indulgence Extra</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to find a sentence in an
actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> that embodies conspicuous consumption and fatuousness better
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home</ENAMEX>" section:

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>, the urinal has taken its stand alongside
the bidet and the working fireplace as the latest must-have in the
well-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom suite</ENAMEX>."

            Submissions due by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7</TIMEX>.

            
               Headline
Haiku
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cosmic Blasts</ENAMEX>,
Clues
Of Things to Come
In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tests</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
Drug <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Found Just</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Times</ENAMEX>"), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hammett</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Fat jokes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pokémon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ono, Bono</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
