
   
   
      
         
             How Big a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safety Net</ENAMEX>?

            Why do we have a social safety net? It depends on
whom you ask. Some say it's a matter of political prudence (e.g. "The
alternative to a safety net is a revolution"). Others say it's a moral
imperative.
       Among the latter, the most influential is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>
of philosophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rawls</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> likens the safety net to an insurance payout.
Here's his argument: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back</ENAMEX> before you were born--in fact, before you were even
conceived--nobody knew you were going to develop into the sort of sophisticated
individual who reads 
                  Slate
               . For all anyone knew, you might have
been born without enough skills to boot up a computer--or to earn a decent
living.

            If your unborn soul
could have bought an insurance contract, then you'd probably have snapped up
some kind of "skill insurance" in which everybody pays premiums, and those who
land in the shallow end of the gene pool split the pot.
       Of course, you didn't buy insurance. But that's only because
there are no telephones in the world-before-birth, so the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX>
couldn't contact you. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>, you would have
bought the insurance if you could have, and that creates a moral obligation
upon all to pay the premiums.
       That's a very powerful argument, but it's incomplete. Here's why: It
offers no estimate of how much insurance your unborn self would have
wanted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> says we should enforce a bunch of hypothetical insurance
contracts, but you can't enforce a contract if you don't know what it says. So,
to convert the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rawlsian</ENAMEX> argument into a concrete policy, you first have to
determine what terms we'd have written into those pre-birth agreements.

            
Here's how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> solve that problem:
They guess. Most of them guess that our unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">selves</ENAMEX> would all have cheerfully
signed on for a pretty substantial welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> and not a
philosopher, I am inclined to think about such questions a little more
deeply.
       How much insurance would an unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> want to buy? We already know a
lot about the demand for insurance from available data on how much of it (fire,
life, disability, auto, etc.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the real world buy.
       Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> demand more insurance than others do because they face more
risk. So before we can estimate how much skill insurance your pre-birth self
might have purchased, we must first estimate how much risk you were facing when
God was handing out the brains.

            
The right way to measure risk is to measure the
statistical variance of the possible outcomes. In this case, that means
measuring the statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">variance</ENAMEX> of human talents. You can't measure talent
directly, but you can measure it indirectly--say by observing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
similar education and training, and measuring the variance in their earnings.
After you've controlled for education and training, earnings are at least a
rough measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>.
       Once you've measured that variance, you've measured the risk, so you can
go back to the insurance markets and observe how much insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose
to buy when they're facing similar risk levels. That gives at least a rough
estimate of how much we should all be paying into the general welfare pool.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Kahn</ENAMEX> (of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Bank</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Hopenhayn</ENAMEX> (of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Rochester</ENAMEX>) recently
sacrificed a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch hour</TIMEX> and the back of an envelope to computing that rough
estimate. The bottom line turns out to be astounding: If you take the insurance
metaphor seriously, then <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX> with the
fewest skills--should be permanently unemployed and on welfare. In other words,
the present-day welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is not nearly as large as it ought to be. So, if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rawlsian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> had bothered to do a little arithmetic, they might
have discovered that their arguments are a lot stronger than they dared to
expect.
       But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kahn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopenhayn</ENAMEX>'s arithmetic leaves something out. They
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implicitly</ENAMEX> assumed that it would be costless to identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with the
fewest skills so that we can put only those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the dole. That assumption
becomes invalid if highly skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can hide their abilities in an attempt
to defraud the system. Policing such fraud can make social insurance policies
considerably more expensive, and when insurance is more expensive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want
less of it. Factor that into the equation, redo the calculations, and
you end up concluding that the fraction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> on welfare should be
just <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.6 percent</NUMEX>--in other words, practically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>.

            
The truth probably lies somewhere in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 23</TIMEX>
percent and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.6 percent</NUMEX>: We can't costlessly observe each other's skills, but
we can't costlessly hide our own skills, either. In other words, maybe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> net should be drastically expanded, and maybe it should be drastically
slashed. Not too definitive a conclusion. But it's the result of just one
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>'s work, and it's more precise than anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> have
come up with in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the quarter century</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> first made his argument.
       Personally, I'm not sold on the insurance metaphor to begin with, for
reasons that could fill a separate column. But the broader point is that if
your argument is based on metaphors, you should be prepared to treat those
metaphors with respect. If the safety net is really just like insurance, then
we should be buying it in quantities commensurate with our other insurance
purchases. And we should be making an honest effort to calculate what those
quantities are. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> don't seem willing to meet that
responsibility. That's why we need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
