
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">214</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Nutkin&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               You give the brief lead; I give the headline from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s
Independent : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Letter Reveals Nutkin Was a Savage Squirrel</ENAMEX>."
            

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 213</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three for All":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     Fill in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> blanks with the same word in this remark by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>: "There is no __________ ... I know what _______ is. There is
no ________ going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>."
                  
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Denial</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>
               

               "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Dancing</ENAMEX>.' It's from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s cameo in the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> production of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Footloose</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Well, not yet, but without rent control ... "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
               

               
"Arguing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Corp.</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Krause</ENAMEX>
               

               " 'Tim
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX>.' And then added, 'Tim <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carvell</ENAMEX> was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. And you, sir, are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>
Pascover , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Fein</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> )

                

                

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX> began his
apologia this way--and I quote from bad memory--"The continuation of crime,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, suffering, and death is what keeps me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Schweitzer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX> in business." But in assembling <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>, the persistent problem is not
trivializing the great events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> (although that is an enduring
tradition both for us and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX>) but neglecting them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>, after all,
runs but a single question, and it seldom refers to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s most important
story. I am, perhaps, feeling a little uneasy over the question selected for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> when every front page reports the bombing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. But remember,
although a question ostensibly neglects a vital story, its answer may be
piercingly relevant. And there is also this to consider--a squirrel! And it's
savage! And it's named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nutkin</ENAMEX>! Thank you, and from all of us here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, good
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.

            
               Once, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twice</ENAMEX>, Three
Times the Answer
            

            "There is no unrest ... I know what
unrest is. There is no unrest going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>."

            No unrest. But plenty of arrests, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">574</ENAMEX> so far in
ongoing protests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou Diallo</ENAMEX> shooting--former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. And there are also
ongoing investigations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> by both federal and state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> noted that most
cops don't use excessive force. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX> noted that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most days</TIMEX>, he doesn't
kill anyone, either. Well, he didn't note it, but he might have.

            
               Try To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> It My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fairness & Accuracy in Reporting</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> broadcast gave a distorted view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX> protest, grossly
exaggerating support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Smith</ENAMEX> reported that "most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> did not applaud." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> wrote "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 40 percent</NUMEX> of the audience
stood up and clapped," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
percent, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. Oh, lordy, I've quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>. I'd better go lie down.

            OK, I'm back. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAIR</ENAMEX> notes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> devoted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> shots to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> standing to applaud,
but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 15 percent</NUMEX> to those refraining. Kvetch, kvetch, kvetch. Surely this
was a directorial decision designed only to provide the most appealing shots,
frequently down the front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>'s dress. A random check of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
file footage reveals the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s commitment to accurate reporting.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EVENT: Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
War demonstration, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC MOSTLY SHOOTS</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> placidly nibbles a
blade of grass. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> placidly nibbles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raquel Welch</ENAMEX>'s ear.

            
               EVENT:
Protest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC MOSTLY SHOOTS</ENAMEX>: MacGyver blows something up using just a
can of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peaches</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">poodle</ENAMEX>.

            
               EVENT:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC MOSTLY SHOOTS</ENAMEX>: Only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 miles</NUMEX> away, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SeaWorld</ENAMEX>, sexy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Crawford</ENAMEX> models swimsuits with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Shamu the killer whale</ENAMEX>.

            
               EVENT:
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Crusade</ENAMEX> sacks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Constantinople, 1204</TIMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC MOSTLY SKETCHES</ENAMEX>: Some lovely fluffy clouds.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> lacks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> with self-knowledge, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
