
   
   
      
         
             War Powerless

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants to
send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> peacekeeping mission to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. If all
goes as planned (though what goes as planned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>?), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> will
spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three to five years</TIMEX> disarming ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerillas</ENAMEX>,
replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> with ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, and generally restoring
order to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Godforsaken Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. The mission is a superb idea, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noble</ENAMEX> effort to pacify the troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> before war spills into the rest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            It's also illegal. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is "briefing" and "consulting" with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> but will not seek congressional approval. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> insists
that it does not need such approval: "Ample constitutional precedent" (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>) proves that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX> can conduct such forceful
operations without a congressional say-so. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, it seems, agrees.

            It is probably hopeless, and certainly unfashionable, to
remind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that they are wrong. Few passages in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX> have been more abused than <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 1, Section</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.11</NUMEX>, which gives
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> sole power "to declare war [and] grant letters of marque and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reprisal</ENAMEX>." Constitutional history is fuzzy on many matters, but on this it is
pellucid: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> intended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> alone, to decide whether
and when to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into combat. (According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, "letters of marque
and reprisal" are, roughly speaking, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX> equivalent of
our small-scale military actions.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> allowed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> could
authorize defense and immediate retaliation in the case of a surprise attack.
Otherwise, the authority belonged to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Our elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> were
supposed to deliberate, slowly, on this most consequential of state actions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> feared, above all, that a vainglorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> would, if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unchecked</ENAMEX>, drag the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into foolish foreign entanglements.

            This principle of
congressional supremacy guided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occasionally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> declared war before sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>; mostly it didn't.)
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' military influence began to wane as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> grabbed more and
more power. The seminal event was the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX>
waged with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> approval and virtual silence from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The shift continued
through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and the secret invasions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> reasserted itself by passing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Resolution</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
veto. Under the resolution (more commonly known as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Act</ENAMEX>"), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 days</TIMEX> to obtain congressional approval of a military action. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> does not vote aye, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> must come home.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Resolution</ENAMEX> has been a monument to
congressional fecklessness and presidential bullying. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has
called the law unconstitutional and proceeded as if it (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>)
didn't exist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of executive power, ignored the
war powers clause and resolution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, usually so obeisant to "original
intent" when interpreting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, were more cavalier on the subject
of war powers.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> skirted congressional war powers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> and
denied that they applied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> war. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has ducked them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. (When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> cite "ample
constitutional precedent," it is this "ample," but hardly constitutional,
record, to which they are referring.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> have euphemized away the
seizure of congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, minimizing their uses of force as "surgical
strikes," "police actions," or "immediate reprisals." They have cited the
pressures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>: At a time when any regional flare-up might provoke a
nuclear confrontation, they argued, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> needed a single, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> hand on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tiller</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> said, "You can't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> grumbled but
didn't stop the erosion of its power. Whenever a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> dispatched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would pipe up that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was ignoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Resolution</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would argue it
didn't apply. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would gripe a bit more, and by that time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
would be on their way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The resolution has become a convenient cover: It
allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to complain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is breaking the law without
forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to take any real responsibility. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> goes awry,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can load all the blame on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> goes well,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> takes all the credit anyway. "There's nothing in it for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Alterman</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Speaks for America?</ENAMEX>: Why
Democracy Matters in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Policy</ENAMEX> . "No one is going to make his career as
a great foreign policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>." The political adage states that politics stops
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>'s edge. In fact, politics doesn't even start. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> just isn't
interested enough.

            This time around, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> isn't even bothering to invoke
the war powers clause or resolution. Both the rescue of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and the ongoing
bombardment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> are undoubtedly military operations as contemplated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>. Both expose <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX>, and neither is an
immediate retaliation for an attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> bombing has
been going on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has not signaled any
willingness to abide by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Resolution</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> engagement is
scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has no intention of ever
putting it to congressional vote. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has never held a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resolution</ENAMEX> vote on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> mission, which began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.) Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
perhaps exhausted by impeachment or simply supportive of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, has
been notably silent. "There is war powers fatigue," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholar Richard Haass</ENAMEX>.

            The fact remains that the
congressional surrender of war powers is anti-democratic and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-republican</ENAMEX>.
The most important duty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--the power to wage war--is now held by one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and his unelected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, who were elected to
deliberate and make these nasty decisions, have abdicated the duty the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX>
intended them to have. Their abdication deprives the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of the
chance to hear and participate in debate. It is no coincidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
war, the only recent military engagement preceded by a vigorous national
debate, was also an operation that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> supported wholeheartedly. Do
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> even know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is?

            Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have cooperated in
abandoning war powers. The indifference of congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> is not
surprising: Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, they have generally endorsed the
executive's war-making authority. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' indifference is more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">demoralizing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, after all, endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' war powers when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> were sending in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX>. Why don't they now? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, too,
seems hypocritical. After all, he fervently participated in the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
movement, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Resolution</ENAMEX> was a great triumph of that movement.
Now that he owns the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> he once feared in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cavalierly</ENAMEX> dismissed constraints on his power.

            Congressional war powers are not an entirely
lost cause. A few stubborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> are still shouting about it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>, wants to amend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Resolution</ENAMEX> to give it more teeth.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, to agree to them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Campbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, an
international law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, has championed congressional war powers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> he tried and failed to invoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Resolution</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnia</ENAMEX> mission. Now he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, are circulating a letter
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> that they will send to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. The letter
insists that "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> compels you to obtain authority from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
before taking military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>." So far, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> and Frank
have enlisted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 34</NUMEX> co-signers, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> shows no signs of
paying attention.

            You can see why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> wouldn't listen.
A congressional debate and vote on whether we should intervene in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> could
be a fiasco. The intervention could be stopped by a block of isolationist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Our failure to intervene might well cause the war
to escalate and spread. But the absence of such a debate and vote may be worse.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is most necessary when it is most inconvenient.

         
      
   
