
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Merchant of</ENAMEX> <EM>Menace</EM>

jokes per se. Some of my best jokes are ethnic. Like the one about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> on a beach who screams "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>! My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurologist</ENAMEX>! Is
drowning!" Or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scotsmen</ENAMEX> who tuck <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> bills into their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s casket
and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> who swaps the bills for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> check.

            But what about a sober drama featuring evil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mercantilists</ENAMEX> whose technologically advanced robots enslave a peace-loving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> and all at the bidding of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emperor"</ENAMEX>? Oh, right, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercantilists</ENAMEX> also have slanty eyes, wear long robes, and talk just like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chan</ENAMEX>. They attempt to hide their crafty schemes from the outside world
by forcing the conquered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to sign a faux treaty. They are ruthless and
cruel in their occupation.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Crichton</ENAMEX> wrote a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>-bashing film
(and novel) back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rising Sun</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> roasted him for
exploiting racial fears. But the racial stereotyping in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX>' latest
Star <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wars epic, The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> , is far worse, and nobody
seems to care.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Crafty Japanese</ENAMEX> trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> aren't the only heavy-handed ethnic stereotype in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom</ENAMEX>
Menace . As the story continues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> slip past the evil <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> to a
nearby planet. There, they attempt to repair their broken spaceship but are
stymied by the hook-nosed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parts shop</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watto</ENAMEX>--who also
happens to have a thick <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> accent! (To hear an example, click ".")
Psychological manipulations that work on almost everyone fail with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watto</ENAMEX>--"Mind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ticks don'ta</ENAMEX> work on me ... only money! ," he cries--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> get what
they want only through the bravery of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted slave boy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anakin Skywalker</ENAMEX>). At
the end of the desert planet sequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anakin</ENAMEX> is emancipated but separated from
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, who still belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watto</ENAMEX>. Even in a galaxy far away, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are
apparently behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade.

            And then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar Jar Binks</ENAMEX>, the childlike sidekick with
the unmistakably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Indian</ENAMEX> accent and enormous buttocks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar Jar</ENAMEX> is likable,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">easygoing</ENAMEX>, and dumb as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>--always being scolded or saved from death by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi knights</ENAMEX>. His stupidity and cowardice are running jokes throughout the
film. And his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gungan</ENAMEX>, are a brave but primitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> who throw
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spears</ENAMEX> and rocks at the oncoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> in the climactic battle sequence. Only
Hispanics escape <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>' caricature, which is actually something of a mixed
blessing since <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> often rightly complain that they are ignored in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> race debate.

            In fairness to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX>, he gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
traits to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Amidala</ENAMEX>), and there is a black man
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Jackson</ENAMEX>) on the august <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jedi Council</ENAMEX>. And true evil in this movie--the
so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> --resides in a handsome white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palpatine</ENAMEX>) and a towheaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anakin</ENAMEX> Skywalker/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX>).

            Until this last episode, the Star Wars series
has shown a happy, multiculty universe, in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of sentient species
coexist, more or less peacefully. This hardly gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> license to revive
racist stereotypes. But it makes the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> seem like a lapse in
taste rather than morals. What's especially puzzling, though, is that film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> have by and large given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> a free pass. A smattering of reviewers
griped about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar Jar Binks</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> was offended by the
"blatant ethnic stereotype" behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watto</ENAMEX>, "the hook-nosed merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insect</ENAMEX>." But
far more typical was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reviewer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, who gushed:
"the junk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watto</ENAMEX> is a little masterpiece of design: cinnamon stubble on
his corrugated face, chipped rocks for teeth, the raspy voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brando</ENAMEX>'s
Godfather speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>? Even without the visual clue of
the hooked nose, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watto</ENAMEX>'s accent is clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>. Or click "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>;
listen again; and you tell me: Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> crazy or am I?

         
      
   
