
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keanu Reeves</ENAMEX> stars in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>,
dystopic sci-fi thriller. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> give high marks to the computer-enhanced
special effects but are divided on the merits of the ambitious plot and the
everything-but-the-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">kichen</NUMEX>-sink filmic provenance, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soylent Green</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Terminator 2</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> actioners. For some the effects are enough:
It's "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big, fat, honking comic book of a sci-fi-martial-arts adventure
flick. ... It has stu-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freakin</ENAMEX>'-pendous special effects, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hipster</ENAMEX> sang-froid out
the wazoo and a story line that makes only as much sense as it has to" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
O'Sullivan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). A grudgingly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appreciative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>
says that at its best the movie brings "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> action style home to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> in a mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> adventure with big prospects as a cult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic</ENAMEX> and with the future very much in mind" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
Others criticize the convoluted story line and call it strictly genre and
strictly for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">20s</ENAMEX>, for whom the script's pretentious
mumbo-jumbo of undergraduate mythology, religious mysticism and technobabble
could even be a plus rather than a dramatic liability" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Variety ). (To see the trailer and some fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Keanu pics</ENAMEX>, visit this fan
site; check out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  10 Things I
Hate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About You</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>, many of whom
admitted they had been gearing up for "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> things I hate about this movie"
reviews, are charmed, if not in love with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> offering.
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Taming of the Shrew</ENAMEX> .) Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX> writes it "may be the cheekiest 'literary' update yet--a
post-riot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grrrl</ENAMEX> gloss" of the play. Many gush over the foxy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stiles</ENAMEX>. Complaints are mainly a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>'
upscale-high-school-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">caper</NUMEX>-film fatigue. A few find the film irritating:
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Harvey</ENAMEX> says, "it lurches all over the map,
encompassing dialogue both inspired and juvenile." (Visit the
official site.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s
Fortune
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October Films</ENAMEX>). Critical response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX>'s
warm 'n' fuzzy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Gothic</ENAMEX> tale covers the spectrum. Most are tickled pink:
"a small miracle" with "an irresistibly companionable spirit" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). The classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> deep bench (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Neal</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Close</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris O'Donnell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX>) does not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disappoint</ENAMEX>, and most play twinklingly kooky oddballs. However, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
are not so keen. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than one</NUMEX> call it "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> lite" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> ) and say "[t]he fabled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> atmosphere fails to jell"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). A small cadre is seriously
disappointed: "another footnote to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> career that is fast becoming all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">footnotes"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) or, more simply, "[h]e falters again"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ). (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>, visit this site, which has links to interviews and essays about him, and
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  A Walk on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moon</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews, tending toward the
negative, for this tale of sexual liberation set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> who married too young is on vacation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catskills</ENAMEX> with her two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> when she meets a sexy, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blouse peddler</ENAMEX>. The rest?
As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> says, it's "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> small step for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blouse Man</ENAMEX>, a giant leap for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Kantrowitz</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> writes
that the film's nice, if "you look past the gaffes and clichés." On the
positive side, most say the acting is great, and though the film "doesn't take
enormous chances," it is nevertheless "extremely satisfying" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ). 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Edelstein</ENAMEX> is more positive than
most, praising the "deliciously resonant dual setting: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catskills</ENAMEX> summer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> to which middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> migrate to swim and eat and
play mah-jongg, and the gathering hippies at nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodstock</ENAMEX>." ( the rest of
his review.)

            
               
                  The
Out-of-Towners
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldie Hawn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>
star in a remake of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> film that's "so feeble and unfocussed as
to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> of There's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Something About Mary</ENAMEX> appear to
have suckled at the bosom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristophanes</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Van Gelder</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree; few put it so well. The plot: A nice
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> goes through the wringer in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> (lost luggage,
muggings, etc). The film's only breath of fresh air is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cleese</ENAMEX>, who plays a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">snobby</ENAMEX> hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basil Fawlty</ENAMEX> to good effect. (For more on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>, check out this site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Financier</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Strouse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Excellent
reviews for this doorstop-sized biography on the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX>: "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magnificent</ENAMEX>, insightful study" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maury Klein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> are impressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strouse</ENAMEX>'s extensive research, which turned up a
truckload of new details on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>'s life and, more importantly, by the
balanced portrait that she provides of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose biographies have to date
been colored by vindictive accounts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> with axes to grind. The
strongest negative comment comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ,
which warns that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> without an interest in business and financial history
may find some of this material wearisome" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lingeman</ENAMEX>). (To buy the book
click here.)

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life and My Life With the Times</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Frankel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>). Decent reviews for former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankel</ENAMEX>'s memoirs: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX> Just calls it a "a smart, tough, scrupulous book" in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ; in that fair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>'s traditional
negative-comment spot (the penultimate paragraph) all Just can come up with is
that there's "a whiff of the puritan about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Frankel</ENAMEX>, and perhaps also the
rustle of score-settling." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> note that his personal life--if you
can even say he had one--gets short shrift, and most say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankel</ENAMEX>'s time at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">helm</ENAMEX> is not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as interesting as his flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in his childhood and
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the best backhanded compliment is
provided by another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> review, this one from the daily
paper: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Kluger</ENAMEX> writes that the book has "only occasional spasms of the
immodesty that almost by definition infects all who venture into
autobiography." (To buy the book click here.)

            Find a
movie playing near you on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mod Squad</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EdTV</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dates</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Futurama</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- All Too Human: A Political Education</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief of Unbearable Urges</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englander</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  True Crime ;

               
                  Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> and I ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces of Nature</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renewal</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  
                     Movie--
                  
                  The
Deep End of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corruptor</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage: Carrie</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  Wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Death-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  Black <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hawk Down</ENAMEX>: A
Story of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Modern War</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Bowden</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Analyze This</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX>, Stock & <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> Smoking
Barrels ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Monica's Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Annie Get Your Gun</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Bright Lights</ENAMEX>, Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> .

            

         
      
   
