
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> Alert

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are now
warning their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that the current escalation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> airstrikes
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> could culminate in a major military offensive aimed at bringing down
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Quds Al-Arabi</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> bombings were virtually a repeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert</ENAMEX>
Storm except that they were conducted in slow motion so as to deflect media
attention and thus avoid an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> backlash like the one that followed last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>'s campaign. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahrain</ENAMEX> daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akhbar al-Khaleej</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assayed Zahra</ENAMEX> wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was now carrying
out its intention to carve up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> along ethnic and sectarian lines and to
trigger a civil war that would unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zahra</ENAMEX> referred to an
interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliyet</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Ricciardone</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> in charge of "transition" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
imposed by the no-fly zones was intended to be permanent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricciardone</ENAMEX> also
intimated that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has no future as a united <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s plans.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricciardone</ENAMEX>'s interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliyet</ENAMEX> was also discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi Arabian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Aswat</ENAMEX> , which highlighted his remark that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> was
most likely to be deposed suddenly in a military coup. But, in sharp contrast
to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zahra</ENAMEX> wrote, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> paper stressed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricciardone</ENAMEX> said that he
thought the chances of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> breaking up after the overthrow of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> were
minimal.

            Meanwhile, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotsman</ENAMEX> quoted "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> saying there was now a clear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy to oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s
regime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months to a year</TIMEX> through small-scale but continuous air attacks.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has so
far been highly successful in keeping up public awareness levels. "Scale is
important," the unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> went on. "Too much bombing will raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hackles</ENAMEX>, but a continuous campaign will achieve what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>,
including those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, crave--the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>."

            The massacre of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was the subject of much editorial comment
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> seeing it as a kind of karmic revenge for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s refusal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> to act against, or at first even acknowledge,
"the extraordinary genocide in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>--the worst action of its kind since the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">world war</ENAMEX>." It said, "Those who died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bwindi Park</ENAMEX> have been, in a
sense, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of past indifference of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , in
an unfortunate play on words, declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in its main editorial: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bwindi</ENAMEX> set out in search of mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX>. They met instead murderous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guerillas</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also said that "the prosecution of
those suspected of war crimes in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> massacre should be pursued with much
greater vigour in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> set up for that purpose in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arusha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening</ENAMEX>
Standard led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a report that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> threatened
to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> before the murders, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> failed to pass on the warnings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> listed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> or areas of the world that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Foreign Office</ENAMEX> described as
dangerous to visit.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Vision of Uganda</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with
a report not mentioning the murders but stressing that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> abducted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> had escaped, and it placed this next to an account of a 19-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Namibian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1999 Face-</ENAMEX>of<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">-Africa</ENAMEX> modeling contest at the Windhoek
Country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>.

            The link-up between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>, the TV evangelist, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Scotland</ENAMEX> to launch a new
telephone banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was the subject of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> page
feature in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , which said questions might
be raised over "why a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> presumably looking for long-term deposits might team
up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who believes the world as we know it might be about to end." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Scotland</ENAMEX> "must just hope that it can recoup its investment before
Armageddon looms," the article concluded.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> event in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> was an
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> in which she said that she
doesn't believe having oral sex was vulgar: "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> for lunch;
others prefer a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>." She also said she would never again fall in love with
a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prague Post</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> had sought to reduce its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> debt to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX> by
selling it a place on its latest mission to the space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mir</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. According to the paper, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slovak</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said that
since the debt would probably never be collectible, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slovakia</ENAMEX> had decided
instead to take advantage of this opportunity to send the first Slovak citizen
into space.

             

         
      
   
