
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peril</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX>

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> it has been an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> article of faith--as cherished as our belief in free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are corrupt, venal, and incompetent: This was established by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX>, left unshaken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>, and reinforced by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>.
Impeachment was supposed to affirm it once and for all. But now the unthinkable
has happened: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have regained their faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>.

            Fully <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> trust the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to handle domestic problems, and
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 70 percent</NUMEX> trust the feds on foreign policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s job
approval ratings remain near record levels.

            Nowhere is this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Awakening</ENAMEX> more alarming than in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">March Washington Post</ENAMEX> poll pegs job approval
ratings for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> nationwide at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> are especially favored. While <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
struggled in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> elections, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> routed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> by
record margins. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">govs</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, now
score approval ratings above <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX>.

            This faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> consequences for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> relates to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
presidential campaign. Desperate for a hot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> jokes--all but carved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s image onto <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Rushmore</ENAMEX> already. And
the happy numbers have made any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> who lives in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>
think he deserves a promotion to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. Among those touted as
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> running <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tommy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Ridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Engler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cellucci</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Graves</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leavitt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Racicot</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> consequence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">govs</ENAMEX>' popularity is that it
is persuading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> have found the Holy Grail. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> believe, have invented a brilliant new politics that
transcends ideology. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> (who include, not least, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> themselves) use the same phrases over and over to describe them: The
govs are a "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>" and a "new breed." They have "a distinct approach" and
"a new way of governing."

            What is this magical new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>? They combine fiscal conservatism and softer social policy. They have
turned deficits into gigantic surpluses while still cutting taxes. They have
slashed welfare rolls and unemployment. They have increased funding for popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> policies: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> training, health care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cleanups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> wants to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> salaries and an
extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$116.5 million</NUMEX> on child care for the poor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> just boosted education
spending by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600 million</NUMEX>.

            Unlike the savage congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>
have perfected the soothing language of politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, for example, has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abjured</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-only" education: He calls his program "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-plus."
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-only says you don't count, you're not important. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>-plus (says)
we recognize the treasures of your language and heritage," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Journal</ENAMEX> . "The policy is the same , but
the tone is different" (emphasis added).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> have
learned how to form multicultural coalitions, another feat that has eluded
their congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confreres</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX> won a majority of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> vote in his run; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> polls extremely well among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> have allied with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> and borrowed their best ideas. They are even willing to offend
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">die-hards</ENAMEX> of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>: Few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> talk much about
abortion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has irritated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> by emphasizing public education and
largely eschewing vouchers.

            So, essentially, the new form of government invented by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Co.</ENAMEX> is ... Clintonism: fiscal conservatism, deficits into
surpluses, welfare reform, sweeteners for social programs, lots of euphemizing,
and a willingness to co-opt the other side.

            Not that there is anything wrong with what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> have done. Their accomplishments are genuine and their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are
thriving. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s eagerness to embrace them does suggest a certain
hypocrisy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX>, after all, have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> crediting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s polls to alchemy: He has lucked into the best economy in history. But
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s popularity is alchemical, then so is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>'. (Likewise, if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' popularity is legitimate, then so is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s.) All of them owe
their sky-high poll ratings to the economy and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few ounces</NUMEX> of good sense. Of
course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> managed to turn deficits into surpluses.
Of course they cut welfare rolls. Of course they have delighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> by
goosing popular social programs with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">extra millions</NUMEX>. You would have to be a
moron not to have been a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> while tax revenue surged,
unemployment vanished, and crime fell.

            It's easy to be a statesman when all the options
are good. The test of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' "new way"--and the test of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rediscovered</ENAMEX> political faith--won't come till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the lean years</TIMEX> follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> fat ones.

         
      
   
