
   
   
      
         
            Solution or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semantics</ENAMEX>?

            

               The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group of Eight</ENAMEX>" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>) approved "general principles on

               the political solution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis
               ." They
include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) "withdrawal from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> of military, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and paramilitary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "deployment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> of effective international civil and security
presences," and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) "substantial self-government for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>." The upbeat spin:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has agreed with our conditions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> is isolated and will have to
cry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>. Peace is at hand. The skeptical spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> hasn't agreed with
us on the meaning of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>," "effective," "international," "security,"
"presences," "substantial," or "self-government." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The price of winning
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s endorsement was that we had to put the interpretation of these terms
under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> jurisdiction (thereby giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> veto
power) and that we had to remove "all" from the description of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> that
must withdraw.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> died in a
crash during a training mission in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>. They are considered the
war's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> casualties. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warplane</ENAMEX> shot down a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MiG-29</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fighter</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> medical aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> was reportedly struck by a
bomb but without causing any injuries. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> denied
responsibility. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim Rugova</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and arrived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Everyone wants to know whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> had forced him
to pretend on television that he was seriously negotiating with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reported that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> had developed a plan to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into a
"semi-permissive" environment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--i.e., with or without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s
approval--by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> denied it.

            

               Huge tornadoes killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 43</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> , injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 500</NUMEX>,
and destroyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX> tornadoes reported, the largest was said to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">half-mile</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> wide, with winds surpassing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">260 mph</NUMEX>, and reportedly raked
the ground for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> line on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> was that
Oklahomans were comparing the devastation and trauma to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX>
bombing. "There was a sense that the storm was occurring right in front of a
nationwide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, and it undermined once again the persistent naïve feeling
... that what we can watch so closely we can somehow control," proclaimed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . "We have perpetuated the myth of a kind of visual
coexistence with twisters. But to watch your own tornado is a little like
watching your own funeral."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX> 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> testified that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made a "very forceful" unwanted sexual advance toward her in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. Speaking under oath in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hiatt Steele</ENAMEX> trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> grabbed her breasts, kissed her, and put his hands "all over me."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has testified previously that he made no such advance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>. The
trial is officially about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> obstructed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> when she denied knowing about the alleged
advance, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s unofficial interest is in whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did it and
how much lurid detail the trial will provide.

            

trading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> after its first close above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>. The media yawned.

            

               C
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harismatic</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Derby</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30-1</NUMEX>,
he was the longest long shot to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derby</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX> and was only the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> horse to win from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> post in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-racing world was shocked. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s feel-good story lines focused on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
the underestimated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, who was offered for sale in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> but had no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">takers</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Lukas</ENAMEX>, who got the victory despite the fact that rival
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trainer Bob Baffert</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> favored <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> in the race and had won the last
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Derbys</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) jockey <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Antley</ENAMEX>, who had been thinking of quitting the
sport after a bout with drug abuse in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX> and a weight problem last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX> lost his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>. He got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
percent of the vote in a special election to fill the seat vacated by former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker-designate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-La.</ENAMEX> The top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> finishers, who got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
percent and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX>, respectively, will compete in a runoff. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times played up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s showing, saying he "fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just</NUMEX> short" of making the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">runoff</ENAMEX> and suggesting that he would have made it if a rival hadn't cut into his
vote. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> expressed relief that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX> won't become their "Y2KKK"
problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX>'s spin: Now that everyone knows my views, the sizable vote I
received shows how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> agree with me. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' spin: Now that
everyone knows his views, the sizable vote he received shows how many people
agree with him.

         
      
   
