
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold</ENAMEX>

            I don't want to project too
much onto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX>'s bluesy charmer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> --to argue, for
instance, that it's the work of an old master summing up. But it sure feels
that way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Rapp</ENAMEX>, has provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> with a blueprint not
only for an ensemble comedy but also for a comedy that honors the very idea of
an ensemble. It's no wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> fell on it. As early as M*A*S*H
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> seemed more taken with the ebb and flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> than
with the isolated treks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. It's not just that he likes to tell
stories with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple strands</ENAMEX>, or that he gets bored easily with one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consciousness</ENAMEX>, or even that he cherishes some '60s utopian fantasy of the
collective. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> suggests is that for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> order in
the universe can't be discerned in the comings and goings of lone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> but in
the interactions among vast and disparate collections of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. This time out,
he transforms the bad vibes of his other films into a vision that's positively
serene. He celebrates a universe that has found its equilibrium and the easy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> in which it rights itself when a nasty bit of flotsam threatens to throw it
out of whack.

            The movie takes place in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep South</ENAMEX>, which was also the setting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>'s edgy, disharmonic
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">thriller The Gingerbread Man</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>). The opening is teasingly
misleading, as if to make you think you're seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gingerbread Man</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">II : In Holly Springs</ENAMEX>, a small, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> cotton <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis Richland</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles S. Dutton</ENAMEX>) staggers out of a blues joint semi-drunk, then drops his
bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX> when a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> glides ominously past. So he heads back
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, steals a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, then ambles past the railroad
tracks and peeps into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> where a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX>) has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undressing</ENAMEX>. Then he climbs in the window of a big, antebellum <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and takes
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> from a glass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> at the foot of the main staircase.

            So far, so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Gothic</ENAMEX>. Except that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>, it turns
out, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s gentlest spirit, loved even by those passing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, who are
his fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> at that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>--he couldn't find his keys.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> he was spying on is the runaway niece of the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cookie</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orcutt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Neal</ENAMEX>), he works for. He'd promised to clean those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> before
he went to bed. And, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> buys a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surreptitiously</ENAMEX> slips it behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> of the blues joint to replace the one
he'd swiped. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rufus Thomas</ENAMEX>) pretends not to notice, but when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>
leaves he turns to his chesty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Wilson</ENAMEX>) and says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> is even
again."

            That's the core of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> is even again." It suggests a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in
which everything is in balance, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> accept the good and the bad, in
faith that it will all even out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. The picture sits vaguely in the
comic-mystery genre, but it's more of a relaxant than a thriller. There's a
violent death and a cover-up, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have to figure out what really
happened before an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is condemned to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>--or worse. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>
doesn't let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s outrage mount. The act that kicks the movie into a
higher gear comes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nearly half an hour</TIMEX> in, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> is in no hurry to get to
his narrative point. That's probably because he has to eliminate Cookie to do
it, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Neal</ENAMEX> isn't someone you want to get rid of. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, now in
her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">70s</NUMEX>, has shrunk in physical stature but has otherwise swelled--I don't
remember her having such power in her lungs. When she sucks on her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX> and
stares at the gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> and upbraids her late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> for leaving her behind,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> clearly wants her to take all the time in the world.

            How do you convince young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> to watch and emulate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>? It's so much easier to push a filmmaker like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>, whose
brilliant sequences you can screen and dissect in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> studies class.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> uses a distinctive color palette here--a lot of neonlike primary colors,
as if the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> were a blues joint--but his mastery is in his
offhandedness, in how he conceals his own storytelling. There's always a sense
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are living even when you're not watching them, maybe
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> don't seem "on" the way they do for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>
catches them in his gaze and gives them the once-over and then they go about
their business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actors</ENAMEX> I didn't think I'd want to see again--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ned Beatty</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Moffat</ENAMEX>--I wanted to see more of, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris O'Donnell</ENAMEX> is positively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reborn</ENAMEX> as a bumbling young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> who only wants to make out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX>
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station house</ENAMEX> soda machine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney B. Vance</ENAMEX> shows up as an
officious homicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> from a nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> who finds <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Holly Springs</ENAMEX>' lazy
informality irritating, but none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wants to answer his queries: They
want to flirt with him, and he can't help falling into their easy rhythms.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Close</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camille Orcutt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s
histrionic niece and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the church theatricals (currently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salome</ENAMEX> ), whose hysterical obsession with hiding the
"disgraceful" truth throws the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> into an uproar. I was surprised to find
Close in the movie, since her clenched, overly controlled acting seems at odds
with what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> usually goes for. But this might be her best performance ever.
Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camille</ENAMEX> is like a steely, demented temperance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> who keeps charging
into otherwise relaxed settings and throwing them into chaos. ("You'd think the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> could take their stupid crime tape with them when they leave!") She
pairs beautifully with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camille</ENAMEX>'s simple-minded, vaguely
schitzy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cora</ENAMEX>, who's so browbeaten that whenever she's called on to
talk, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX> comes flowing out of her mouth like lava.

            The truth in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> isn't ferreted out <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">à la Murder She Wrote</ENAMEX> ; it emerges in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dribs</ENAMEX> and drabs--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> here, a piece of evidence there--as if by natural
law. You might even say that the truth emerges as a consequence of chaos and
not from some misguided pursuit of order. What seems, on the surface, as
ingratiating a movie as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> has ever made, is actually packed with
subversive ideas. It ends on a note of blithe miscegenation--just the sort of
punch line to send the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilles</ENAMEX> of the world screaming from the theater swiping
at invisible bugs.

            As a young movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, I made the wrong sort of name for
myself by swooning in print over many a nubile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>. Yes, I was often
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promiscuous</ENAMEX> in my praise and, yes, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">affaires</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la</ENAMEX> tête were often
sadly short-lived. But I've practiced the critical equivalent of abstinence for
many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now, and it's time to reassert what can never be forgotten: It is
the right, nay the duty, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> to fall and fall hard. I see no point in
writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Been Kissed</ENAMEX> --a pleasant but annoyingly insubstantial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen</ENAMEX> comedy--unless I can pull out the stops and say it's worth seeing, it
demands to be seen, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX>, who is at once the dizziest and most
magically poised comedienne in movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrymore</ENAMEX> plays a frumpy
newspaper copy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who's ordered to go undercover as a high-school student
by a nuttily competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Marshall</ENAMEX>). Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX> a convincing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frump</ENAMEX>? Surprisingly so. She hits her slight speech impediment harder than usual
and further relaxes her already shlumpy posture. Trying to fit in with the
"cool" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, she seems heartbreakingly defenseless. You could mistake her for
an ordinary, unaffected nerd, except that the genius Barrymore timing is in
every breath, every screwy inflection, every pratfall. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, I thought
that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Been Kissed</ENAMEX> might be the most fun teenpic since
Clueless , but ultimately the movie takes too many shortcuts even on its
own dumb, formulaic terms, and it can't make up its mind whether it wants to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pander</ENAMEX> to teen-age fantasies of good looks and popularity or to scold
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> for being so shallow. No matter. The picture would have to be a hell
of a lot worse to keep me from going back to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX> bite her lower lip and
that shy smile spread meltingly across that sweet, eternally girlish face and
...

            Wait, maybe I'd better switch to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Matrix</ENAMEX> , which
made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first week</TIMEX> and seems poised to become a phenomenon.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Wachowski</ENAMEX>, it's a mishmash of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
sword-fighting ghost epics, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kafkaesque</ENAMEX> virtual reality fantasies, Cronenbergian
visions of cybernetically enhanced flesh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wonderland</ENAMEX>
surrealism, post-apocalyptic urban grunge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX> -like battles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX> vs. machine, and portentous lumpen-Zen posturing ("I can only show you the
door. You have to walk through it"). It shouldn't make a lick of sense, let
alone feel all of a piece, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Matrix</ENAMEX> is actually one of the more
lyrical sci-fi action thrillers ever made, in which space and time become love
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slaves</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>' witty visual fancies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keanu Reeves</ENAMEX> makes a lean,
strikingly beautiful tabula rasa <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, twisting out of the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> that
elongate like silver beads of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>, and he's partnered by the equally hard,
blank, and androgynously gorgeous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie-Anne Moss</ENAMEX>. Walls and pillars explode
around them but the sleek, geometric lines of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> never soften. The
machines, in comparison, seem fuzzy.

         
      
   
