
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several years</TIMEX> it has evidently
become fashionable for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> to have all their servers march out singing
birthday greetings to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Am I the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who finds this
intolerable? I've stopped going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that follow this custom if I can
avoid them. (My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> likes the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> at some of these places, so compromises
must be made.) The noise makes conversation impossible, and I can't help but
wonder if that's my meal being ignored in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> during the song.
            

            
               Am I being petty?
Shouldn't servers be respectful of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>? What can be done?
            

            

               --BH
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, get a grip.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> just sang "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Birthday</ENAMEX>" to herself: It takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 seconds</TIMEX>. If it
is your meal being ignored for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly one</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of a minute, Prudie
does not think the delay will harm the flavor. Let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hasten to add that
she, too, finds the wait staff singing the birthday song rather hokey and
believes that the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who dislike it more than you and I are the
"honorees." It is always embarrassing, but certainly not worth the boycott of a
good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks you need to hook up your sense of humor to your
tolerance mechanism and find something really objectionable to dislike ... such
as the "suggested" tip printed on the bill.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, proportionately

            

               
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Note From Prudie : What</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> call grown-ups is still riling
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, so here is a knock for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> that was at least
civil.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               You stated, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
sounds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> as though you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> are a little more formal than
the times," when that he felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should address <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in a more formal
manner than using their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names. You may be correct that they may be out of
touch with current (rude) customs of our society. In my day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were
taught respect for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX>, and one of the methods used was form of
address. Today, the television and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> do the job that once was the
purview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Back then we had no <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, no drive-by
shootings, no graffiti on the walls, etc. I, for one, am glad that I was raised
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who had a value system. I still get up when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> enters the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>,
open a door for her, and offer my seat on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. Somehow I am happy to be too
formal for "your" society.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Norm</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie applauds your
standing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and holding doors, but must point out that calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> by
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name, if they wish it, is a different issue. Please be assured that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knives</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are not caused by calling Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie</ENAMEX>."

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, realistically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               While watching the impeachment trial, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> revealed to me that he had an affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of ours
some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years ago</TIMEX>. It went on for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> that we were in a commuting
marriage, living in different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years ago</TIMEX> she came out on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
to visit us for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>, and has continued to correspond during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>.
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says he was ashamed of his lie and that they had promised never to
tell me. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past years</TIMEX>, I have asked him if there was anyone else, and he
always lied. He said the reason for the continued correspondence was that if he
stopped writing I might get suspicious. So, I wrote her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and
told her to stop writing--plus what I thought of her morals.
            

            
               After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX>, I
cannot get this out of my mind. I think I love him and want the marriage to go
on, but other days I feel so used that I can't believe I am still with him.
I've spoken to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> twice and that helped for a day or so. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>, and I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>. What should I do? Am I dumb to try to make this work? I also
suspect him of other lies, but my views of reality are definitely
skewed.
            

            

               --ep
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear e.</ENAMEX>,

            Where to begin? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> wants to tell you so many
things. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> is that you must find the way that is right for you to feel good
again. That old canard that "confession is good for the soul" usually only
seems to work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> confessing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lover Boy</ENAMEX>'s disclosure has clearly put
your life at sixes and sevens.

            Of course your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s behavior was lower than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snake</ENAMEX>'s tail in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon rut</ENAMEX>. He has not only lied to you but also to the woman
he cheated with. You, however, evened the score somewhat by writing to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. God only knows what's going on in their
household.

            Therapy that improves
things for only "a day or so" is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s idea of effective help. You might
want to try someone else. Since you suspect other lies, you might want to have
a trial separation. On the plus side, you say you love this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and the affair
you know about ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade ago</TIMEX>. On the minus side, feeling you're
never getting a straight story is a major impediment to the comfort one feels
when there is trust. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you find your way to peace and resolution,
and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> will most likely be a competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapist</ENAMEX>, perhaps of the
marriage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> variety.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, empathetically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               You recently ran a letter from about unwanted
sympathy for what was a great example of how to live a life. I also have some
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> where I get very uncomfortable with sympathy. I am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sons</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of them died while they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, one from an auto accident
and the other from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Yes, I loved them deeply and still have a hole in my
heart for them. The problem is when, in conversation, someone asks general
questions, such as, "How many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are devastated if I
tell them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, but I lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. If I say one, I am bypassing an important part
of my life. If I just say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, I am not giving a very truthful
answer.
            

            
               I have adjusted well
to these tragedies. It has been hard. I don't want to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in an
uncomfortable position. There is also a part of me that hurts, but I don't
really want to expose that to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany Father</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Alb</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie bows low to a man
such as yourself who, having lived through what is said to be life's cruelest
event, is trying to do the honest, philosophically correct, and thoughtful
thing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests that you tailor your answer to the situation. If it is a
passing social encounter, with what you would call "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>," say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
If you encounter someone with whom you feel rapport, you might say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, with
a brief explanation, and allow that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to express sympathy. Let your
instinct guide you. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> wishes to suggest that you are not playing your
history false by not informing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you lost. Let the
decision about what to say, and to whom, come from your heart, the place where
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> now live.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, respectfully

         
      
   
