
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">236</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Tragedy Plus Time Minus Taste&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> resumed classes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatfield High</ENAMEX>
School. Many wore white T-shirts imprinted on the front with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Are ...</ENAMEX>" and
on the back ... what?
Send your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to 
                  newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 235</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pork Quoi?</ENAMEX>": A big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-page ad running in
many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> today features a photo of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">piglets</ENAMEX> vigorously suckling a sow's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teats</ENAMEX>. An ad for what?
            

            "A law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> specializing in medical malpractice suits (photo is of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pamela</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>)."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montreal Expos</ENAMEX>' all-new, low-budget 'farm' system."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
don't know, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Medved</ENAMEX>'s CONVINCED that this ad directly leads to
school shootings."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Milner</ENAMEX>
            

            "Bob
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>'s 'Open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letter</ENAMEX>' tribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nikonovich-Kahn</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Johnson</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "Got
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pig</ENAMEX>? The other white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Joynt</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Oberg</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Poniewozik</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bjorn</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Davis</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            To most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig symbolizes greed</ENAMEX>.
None associated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> with its traditional attributes, dirty or foul
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smelling</ENAMEX>. None exploited "pig" as an epithet for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>. There were no pigs
in pokes, no when <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs fly</ENAMEX>, no in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>'s ear, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pigmeat Markham</ENAMEX>, no pork
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">salad Annie</ENAMEX>, no Gadarene <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">swine</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piggly Wiggly</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. B. White</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilbur</ENAMEX>, no
there in the wood the piggy-wig stood. No <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> littles. No pearls before. No
turning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> into. How did we lose our rich tradition of porcine references? Did
it all go wrong when we left the farm? Many's the happy hour we spent by the
sty, a volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> mythology in our trotters, contemplating the
particularly rank aroma of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. Well, we're city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> now, and our foes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">wear</ENAMEX> deodorant. And carry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prada</ENAMEX> bags. Made of ... oh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lord</ENAMEX>! No!

            Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> has
always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">comical animal</ENAMEX> because it's so much like us--a college graduate
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, yacking away on a cell phone while it's stuck in traffic in
its rotten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX>. OK, bad example. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pigs</ENAMEX> can pretty much eat everything we do.
An ecological theory of the kosher laws suggests that they're meant to
proscribe <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> who'd compete with us for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> we need. This theory is a
little hazy about lobsters. Who, by the way, can also be made into a durable
and attractive handbag. If you eat a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will call you
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>. But not the other way around. Lobsters: not funny. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pigs</ENAMEX>: funny. A pig
dancing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>: hysterical.

            
               Porcine on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dotted Line Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            The copy reads: "After
all she's done for you, doesn't mom deserve <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>, and to be
compared to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">barnyard animal</ENAMEX>?" except for the final phrase, which is merely
implicit. It's an ad for an online flower service. In a curious bit of marketing, the offer
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> off on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s Day <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> doesn't expire until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31</TIMEX>. So, buy your
mom something nice, eventually, when you get around to it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Highways Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Since moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, I've noticed that
about every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> has a vanity plate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want the world to know their
names (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HERMAN</ENAMEX>), their tastes (BLU MNMS), their dreams (KRE8 IT). And sometimes
it seems they just want to confuse you. (I've puzzled over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHAKYPL</ENAMEX> for long
stretches of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX>. Why pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> so your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> can say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHAKYPL</ENAMEX>?)

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motor Vehicles</ENAMEX>' vanity-plate-availability site, you can input a plate, and see if
it's already taken. Hence the following quiz: Which of the following plates
have been spoken for, and which are still up for grabs?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNIQUE</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">UNIQUE 2</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. MANLY

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. BIGOT

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RACIST</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. 4SKIN

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. HERPES

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MARILU H</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. SATAN

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. BOBDOLE

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANSON</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. KINSLEY

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. YUGO

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. NEWSQIZ

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UGLY</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. GOYZ

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. BEDWETR

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. DIANETX

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIAR</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. ANORXIC

            

               Answers
            

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNIQUE</ENAMEX> and UNIQUE2
have been claimed, which is just sad ("I'd like my plate to read UNIQUE. Oh,
it's taken. Well, then how about UNIQUE2<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANLY</ENAMEX> is available for at least as
long as it takes me to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMV</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIGOT</ENAMEX> is taken, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RACIST</ENAMEX> is not. Go
figure. 4SKIN is taken; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HERPES</ENAMEX>, oddly, remains available. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MARILU H</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATAN</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOBDOLE</ENAMEX> have all been claimed, although the site doesn't specify by whom.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MANSON</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KINSLEY</ENAMEX> are both still available. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YUGO</ENAMEX> is taken, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEWSQIZ</ENAMEX> is still up
for grabs, as is UGLY. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOYZ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BEDWETR</ENAMEX> are both taken, which means that
somewhere out there there's a car being driven by an unashamed incontinent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. And, finally, depsite what you might expect for a state that's home to
the entertainment industry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIANETX</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIAR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANORXIC</ENAMEX> remain unclaimed.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX> and its discontents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Got Milk?</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
