
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Typos</ENAMEX> and
IPOs
            

            Snobs that we are, we like to pretend that we don't
think much about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , the only roughly comparable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> on the Web.
But the truth is that it does cross our radar screens from time to time. Do we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">regard Salon</ENAMEX> as our competition? Yes and no. We are somewhat direct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> for advertising dollars, but for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> the question is more
complicated. The real competition for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> in any medium is the
clock: There are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 24 hours</TIMEX> in a day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangely</ENAMEX>, the least competitive rival
claimant for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">those hours</TIMEX> is likely to be a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. Print
magazines, which depend on direct mail for generating subscriptions, usually
find that their best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> they most closely
resemble. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s does best with the mailing list of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , and so on. This isn't because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are persuaded to switch, but
because someone who has already eaten a blueberry bagel is more likely to eat a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberry bagel</ENAMEX> than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is to eat a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bagel</ENAMEX> of any
sort.

            In a fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>,
similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> are even more interdependent since the viability of this
sort of enterprise is unproved. The cold, hard fact is that we need
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> to prosper and vice versa. The warm, throbbing fact, however, is
that we are only human. And rumor has it that they are as well. Human emotions
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schadenfreude</ENAMEX> --and there must be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> word for reverse
Schadenfreude : distress at other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s happiness--inevitably
complicate rational business judgment.

            Despite our best efforts, we couldn't help noticing lately
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> has announced an IPO. That stands for international poetry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oktoberfest</ENAMEX>. Just the thing for a political-cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. No, actually,
IPO stands for initial public offering. That is, they're selling stock, a more
unusual enterprise for a political-cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two and a half</NUMEX> million
shares will be offered at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $12</NUMEX> a share. That will raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX>, if
they pull it off (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">minus a few million</NUMEX> for the midwives). And this is for less
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX> a share, the value of the whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX> would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $130 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief's shares would be
worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $6 million</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">That $130 million</NUMEX> would be an astonishing figure
for a political-cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> even if it made money. It's about what the
queen of the genre, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , went for in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, when it was still
profitable. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> is losing money at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and
admits that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> will probably increase. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> also claims to be
much, much more than a political-cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, and we intend no insult by
describing it as such.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Peretz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ,
has joked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> that he'll only sell TNR for "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> times
losses." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> are asking even more, and it's no joke. Or
at least, it's not only a joke.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty Peretz</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, is seeing his own joke come almost precisely true as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-owner</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TheStreet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, which is losing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and is going public at a
price that would value the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX>.)

            And what do we at 
                  Slate
                think about this? If
we had any sense, we'd be delighted. After all, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
                must be worth ... well, a lot. Maybe more, maybe
less, but same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, we can't go public
ourselves. But a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> IPO certainly will help when it's time
to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> for our allowance. Also, our goal is to become profitable. If the
Salon IPO works, "the market"--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s answer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delphi</ENAMEX>--will have declared its judgment that this sort of thing can become a
real, profit-making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>.

            Trouble is,

                  Slate
                has been ridiculing the Internet bubble all along. (See
almost any random item for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six months</TIMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Gottlieb</ENAMEX>'s recent
piece on ".") How can we convince ourselves that this one particular IPO is a
rational reflection of actual economic potential if all the rest are a
reflection of something closer to clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX>? The truth is that we
can't. The deeper human truth is that we don't especially want to. The good
fortune of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is annoying enough (however good your own fortune may
be). At least let us cling to the belief that it is unjustified.

            Now that we've made our general attitude toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> and its IPO perfectly unclear, let us take a look at that IPO
prospectus. We were alarmed to discover that it is riddled with typographical
errors! Typos are an athema to any high-qualidy publcation. Careless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proofreading</ENAMEX> is a shure sign of inner wroght. Although we certainly do not wish
to discourage anyone from investing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , we feel an obligation to
inform our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> about these troublesome lapses. They are especially shocking
in a formal government filing, vetted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, in which inaccuracy can
result in disastrous lawsuits. And yet:

            

               The prospectus reports revenues of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,058,000</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nine months ending Dec. 31, 1998</TIMEX>. (And <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> of that in advertising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">barter</ENAMEX>--an ad for an ad--leaving cash revenues of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.7 million</NUMEX>.) This
cannot be right. It is clearly far too low, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Talbot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor-in-chief</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>," told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX> that revenues "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>" were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX>. It might be
mathematically possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> in revenue during the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months of 1998</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last nine months</TIMEX>, thus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX>
million for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>--except that the prospectus also reports revenues of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1</NUMEX>
million for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all 12 months ending March 31, 1998</TIMEX>. It is unthinkable, of course,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbot</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>, grand high executioner, and
maximum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>--would have lied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . Especially when
Salon "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>" gave the same <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX> figure to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. So, clearly the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> figure is a typo.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbot</ENAMEX> also told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that "profits
won't come until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>." This was barely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> began. So, the
prospectus is surely mistaken in saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.3 million</NUMEX>
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April through December of 1998</TIMEX>, and "We expect these operating losses to
increase for at least the foreseeable future." Of course, "profits won't come
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>" doesn't necessarily mean that profits will come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. It depends
on what you mean by "until." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> told a trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Link-Up</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two months</TIMEX> before the dawn of bliss--that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> is slated [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] to turn a profit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>." It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgrace</ENAMEX>. How could Salon be so sloppy as to report large and growing
losses in its prospectus when it actually is already profitable?

               The prospectus states: "Our revenues depend on a
limited number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> who are not subject to long-term
agreements." And, "We anticipate that our financial results ... will continue
to significantly depend on revenues from a small number" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. The
problem here is probably the classic misplaced "not." They mean to say: Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> are subject to long-term agreements, and our financial
results will not depend, etc. After all, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January/February</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX> cites <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbot</ENAMEX> as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> has
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> long-term." Or maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJR</ENAMEX> is the sloppy
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here. Did it omit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbot</ENAMEX>'s explanation that all those long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>
will contribute insignificant revenues?

               Here's a real puzzler. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>
told PC <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> that it "gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> page views, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>" from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> because its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> is so classy. And yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> prospectus refers to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's average CPM [cost
per-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX>] of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX>"! Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPM</ENAMEX> actually sunk by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>? More likely that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX> is supposed to be an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$83</NUMEX> or a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$123</NUMEX>.

               On a subject of particular interest to

                     Slate
                  , the prospectus says this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's paid
membership program: "As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1999</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 1,050</NUMEX> members
enrolled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon Members</ENAMEX> program." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two zeros</NUMEX> probably were dropped
here, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> each would be merely <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>, and yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talbot</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> that revenues from the program
were "above what our projections were." Were they projecting fewer than a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>? Unlikely. So the truth must be that they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,500</NUMEX> or even
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, since it goes without saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbot</ENAMEX> could not have been
trying to mislead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX> .

            

            Let us, though, just for the heck of it, consider the
possibility that perhaps the prospectus is accurate and all these quotations
and citations from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbot</ENAMEX> and others at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> are in error. Is such a
thing possible? Although highly unlikely, it's possible, we suppose, that all
these distinguished publications repeatedly misheard the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> in the
same way, although he has no speech impediment that we know of. Surely, though,
it is impossible to imagine that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> themselves have been
lying, spinning, and covering up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX>, after all, expose these
practices--we do not commit them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Talbot</ENAMEX> has had
inspiring things to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and the truth. In particular, he has
spoken of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's dedication to a mission of exposing important facts.
And he has made pointed comparisons to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzines</ENAMEX> that are allegedly
content to sit on their fannies and analyze or summarize. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> published the important fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> had an adulterous
affair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX>. Many could not see the importance of this fact, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salon</ENAMEX> said it revealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s chief congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>
as a hypocrite. Those who go around exposing unpleasant facts about other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had better be truth-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tellers</ENAMEX> themselves. Buckling his swash on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbot</ENAMEX> declared: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fearless journalists</ENAMEX>, true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> shouldn't be worried
about perception or spin. They should be worried about the truth and concerned
about the truth, and that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's guiding principle here."

            Let's not be sentimental. Let's consider this as a pure
business matter. Here is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief, and director
who is marketing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as what might be called a "truth play." Truth is
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unique Selling Proposition</ENAMEX>, its market niche, its core
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competency</ENAMEX>, its brand value. It would be sheer folly for such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to
invent preposterous lies and spins and feed them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most prominent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>. That's why the only logical explanation is typographical errors
in the prospectus.

            Thank goodness we don't hav these poblems at

                  Slat
               .

         
      
   
