
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story foretells the possible demise of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> that repeatedly saved the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th century</ENAMEX>
from disaster." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political and economic power overbearing,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is wearying of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX> role. Even so, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> will
probably ally themselves against brewing trouble in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> defends the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s policies against charges of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incoherence</ENAMEX>. In order to preserve post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> relevance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> needs
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) tight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European-American</ENAMEX> cooperation; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) beefed-up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> responsibility
for security; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) continued expansion of membership to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>'s expected settlement in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lockerbie</ENAMEX> bombing case a triumph of diplomacy. After being lobbied by the likes
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar Qaddafi</ENAMEX> may finally concede to the
extradition and trial of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. In exchange, the West would lift its
sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover package on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> and race. One cover story applauds the long-term investments that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and historically black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> are making in training
minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for high-tech jobs. The programs, which start early and
feature intensive mentoring and peer support, are a limited but meaningful step
in reversing black underrepresentation in high-tech industries. ... The
other, more alarmist, cover piece decries the underrepresentation of young,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>. Foreign degree
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> don't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> well enough to teach effectively, edge their
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> out of the field, and may eventually return to their native
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lands</ENAMEX>, brain-draining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> research. ... The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> is feigning innocence and false injury in his new book.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> has not actually read the book. He does, however, criticize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> college graduation speech.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> a carefully crafted mirage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bezos</ENAMEX> has promised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> a retail revolution, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s stock price and lofty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideals</ENAMEX> may be deflated by competition, overvaluation, and all the old-economy
difficulties of the retail trade. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles Zinedine
Zidane, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>-elect of a
newly heterogeneous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zidane</ENAMEX>'s "cooler," "more modern," and "more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inventive</ENAMEX>" style of play is supposed to be a metaphor for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s blossoming
multiculturalism, but he is reluctant to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, and French racism
runs very deep. ... A long piece chronicles the harrowing experience of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who unknowingly adopted a schizophrenic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> struggled to find
his birth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s medical history, which had been withheld by the adoption
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>, and committed suicide when he learned of her terrible mental illness. A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generation ago</TIMEX>, adoption <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> considered mental illness to be strictly a
product of poor upbringing, and too private and unpleasant to disclose to
prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The covers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
feature tell-alls by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> about their bruising stints in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               excerpts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>' new book, which repeats the
standard criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ("a complicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> responding to the
pressures and pleasures of public life in ways I found both awesome and
appalling"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> is kinder to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, whom he depicts as
passionate and strong. Among the juiciest scenes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX> refusing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> seat <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> officially offered it to him and
National <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Security Adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Lake</ENAMEX> teaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> how to salute
properly.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. There is a soft-focus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> on the cover, and there are softball questions inside ("You signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your first</TIMEX> book <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.
What was that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like?</ENAMEX>" "Is it easier to be anonymous in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>?"). When asked if she believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s allegations,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> opines that it was a mutually consensual but "unpleasant" encounter
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were not apt to say no." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sidebar</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> combed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>' autobiography
for tips on how to seduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> excerpts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s account of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>. Without
even a passing reference to the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> calls his former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX> "politically astute yet prone to self-destructive acts; deeply patriotic
yet wont to hazard his achievements on tawdry practices." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s reputation
for double-dealing came from his fear of confrontation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> stemmed
from his tendency to give wildly impractical orders that he never really wanted
implemented.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> '
cover analyzes the ever-accelerating presidential candidacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> run <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> stories, too. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> have the same
take: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s greatest liability as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is his air of inevitability,
which exposes him to an upset in the primaries. When asked to comment on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> tells 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> is really one of
the really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> also surveys the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> "a superachiever ... who battled sexism ... and lived
out feminist ideals perhaps even more consistently than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who wear feminism
on their sleeves like, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A reverent profile of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John le Carré</ENAMEX> defends him from the lowly designation of "spy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>" and
bemoans his under-recognition in literary circles. ... A piece describes
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Rudolph</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fugitive</ENAMEX> accused of bombing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Atlanta Olympics</ENAMEX> and
several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abortion clinics</ENAMEX>, has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk hero</ENAMEX> in the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
mountains where he is being sought. Fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> identify with and may
even be protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> because they view his pursuit as part of a
government conspiracy to oppress them. ... An article recounts the
murder of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Guatemalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> and human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, committed just after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of his damning report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s record of political
killings. In a campaign to discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>-led human rights investigations,
government and army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> spun the murder as a homosexual crime of
passion, resulting in the arrest and (finally abandoned) prosecution of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
                
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week</TIMEX> in a
row, the lead
editorial calls for an investigation of and attention to the Juanita
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> story. ... A conservative pundit argues that feminism is dead
and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is to blame. He has dealt a mortal blow to the women's
movement by forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to ignore his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> of
sexual harassment and rape. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rogan</ENAMEX>, a possible contender for Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Feinstein</ENAMEX>'s seat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>-elect of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party.

         
      
   
