
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> Stocks <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">by Moonlight</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update: The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International War Crimes Tribunal</ENAMEX> indicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> for deporting and murdering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s grudging public spin: This sends a message that
war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> will be held accountable. The counterspins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> is a
toothless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> that indicts but rarely convicts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It will be tougher to
negotiate with an indicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The indicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> will become
more militant and violent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>'s answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> shouldn't negotiate with
war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> anyway. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> spin: The indictments strengthen the case for
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.

            

               The stock markets are adding <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening trading hours</TIMEX>. NASDAQ
will expand its trading hours <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> is
likely to follow. The upbeat spin: The current <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> are relics of Wall
Street's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">white-shoe era</TIMEX>; the global economy obeys no clock, and neither should
the trading floor. The downbeat spin: Longer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">trading hours</TIMEX> will require
everyone from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to the press to retool their
operations. The ticker-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> spin: Late<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-hour</TIMEX> trading, which will be lighter
than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">business-hour</TIMEX> trading, will cause stock prices to seesaw. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The night</TIMEX> owl
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">spin: 24-hour</TIMEX> trading is coming.

            

               Dolly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cloned sheep</ENAMEX> is aging prematurely. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX>
discovered that the cells of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> are as worn as those of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> from which they were cloned. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> mystery: Does this mean that
clones assume the age of their genetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> mystery: If her cells
are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 years old</TIMEX> but her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 years old</TIMEX>, how old does that make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dolly</ENAMEX>?
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> mystery: Since sheep don't get gray hair, how will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> find
physical signs of aging?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Supper</ENAMEX> was unveiled after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> of
restoration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> scrubbed it of grime but also removed layers of
retouching, leaving blank spots on the canvas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> spin: It's "the most
important restoration of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>." Everyone else's spin: The earlier
touchups were faithful to the original; now that they're gone, even less of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX>'s work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX>.

            

               A congressional report accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> of nuclear
espionage
               . The gist: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> filched the designs for
all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">warheads</ENAMEX> currently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>; has used the designs
to update its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>; and has been stealing secrets from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> for
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s spin: The findings were fabricated to divert
attention from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s spin: The most damaging
information was taken before I took office. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spins</ENAMEX>: The evidence is thin, and there's no way to trace what really happened.
The committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s spin: Only the unclassified portions of the report
were released, and the classified findings are even more damning.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> will plead guilty to conspiring to solicit illegal
contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>
               .
In exchange for his plea, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> will say that there's no evidence that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> committed espionage against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
reports. This does not jibe with the earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> investigation, which
leveled suspicions at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' line: The case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> was
shakier than they had thought. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> line: It's an outrageous
cover-up. In other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal news, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> dropped charges against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hiatt Steele</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spin 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is finally through. Spin
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Wait, he's still prosecuting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spin 3</ENAMEX>) Wait, he's still
preparing to indict the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Volpe</ENAMEX> pleaded guilty to sodomizing Abner Louima
with a stick
               . After fellow cops testified against
him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volpe</ENAMEX> admitted his actions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in horrific detail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volpe</ENAMEX>'s spin:
He apologized to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for hurting them, but not to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louima</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s spin: By telling the truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volpe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> scored a major
victory against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> brutality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX>'s spin: By supporting
Louima, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharpton</ENAMEX> scored a major victory against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> brutality.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> struck a tentative deal
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> will cede his territorial claim on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. In
return, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to govern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and to control several holy sites. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> will also allow the declaration of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and will permit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> to be established in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. The triumphant
spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> has already resolved the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> issue, the thorniest area of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> relations. A niggling detail: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> has yet to form a
ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> or present the plan to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> may sue their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for not protecting them against sexual
harassment. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> may be forced to pay damages to a
fifth-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decided, if she can prove that school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were "deliberately indifferent" to her torment. The conservative
spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schools</ENAMEX> will now be held liable for garden-variety taunting. The liberal
spin: No, they won't, because it's almost impossible to prove "severe and
pervasive" harassment.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menace</ENAMEX> has raked in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$102.8 million</NUMEX>. The film sold <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28.5 million</NUMEX>
worth of tickets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>--a new high for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">single-day</TIMEX> and opening-day
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grosses</ENAMEX>--but its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$61.8 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> gross lags <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> behind that of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost World: Jurassic Park .</ENAMEX> The spin: The reviews were disappointing
and so are the returns. The counterspins: A record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-day</TIMEX> gross of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$102.8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> can't be disappointing, and the press is wailing about "disappointing"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grosses</ENAMEX> to atone for overhyping the film. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s explanation: We
could have shattered weekend records by releasing the film on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
but chose to accommodate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> by opening on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s backup
explanation: Ticket sales were depressed by predictions of long queues and
sold-out shows.

         
      
   
