
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Groening</ENAMEX>

            I have before me the
current issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Comics Journal</ENAMEX> , which features a list of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
greatest comics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Valiant</ENAMEX> at the bottom to
Pogo, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krazy Kat</ENAMEX> at the top, with room for everyone
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Crumb to Captain Marvel</ENAMEX> in between. There is no place in it, however,
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Groening</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life in Hell</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynda Barry</ENAMEX> (whose
work often shows up next to his in the pages of alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weeklies</ENAMEX> across the
land) gets the nod for her brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie Pook</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comeek</ENAMEX> (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Up-and-coming comics superstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Katchor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Knipl, Real Estate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Photographer</ENAMEX> checks in at No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>. But those anxious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bunnies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bongo</ENAMEX>
and their sidekicks, the deadpan fez wearers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>, are conspicuous
(to me, anyway) in their absence.

            This is a shame, since
Groening, better known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> , and now of the
much-hyped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Futurama</ENAMEX> , is also an important figure in the world of
pen-and-ink serial cartooning. He is the link between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jules Feiffer</ENAMEX> (who earns
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> spots on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Comics Journal</ENAMEX> 's list) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dilbert</ENAMEX> (who earns
none). He is also part of the explosion of brilliant graphic work that began in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1980s</TIMEX> and has so far produced an array of permanent contributions to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture---the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love and Rockets</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Sacco</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Spiegelman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maus</ENAMEX> , to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a few</NUMEX>. Unlike
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX> is not interested in rigorous draftsmanship or extended
narration, but he is, like them (and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katchor</ENAMEX>), committed to
using cartoons as a way of addressing reality. Life in Hell hits us
where we live: under the thumb of well-meaning, rational, but ultimately
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">psychotic</ENAMEX> and abusive authority. Hell is other bunnies--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>, girlfriends. We (I mean all us bunnies, fez
wearers, and miscellaneous snaggletoothed, pop-eyed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-fingered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>)
seem hard-wired for sadomasochism. Even the exuberant, indistinguishable lovers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX> spend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> devising new ways to baffle, dominate,
and mind-fuck each other.

            To paraphrase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry David Thoreau</ENAMEX>: When reality becomes
cartoonlike, the only place for a realist is in cartooning. It's no accident
that the rise of serious comics (or "graphic novels" as some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> chose
to call them) came at a moment when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> fiction was relatively moribund.
For its part, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> arrived at what was a relatively bad period
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies and was part of what will be remembered as an explosion of
inventive network television programming: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">thirtysomething</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne , My So-Called Life , Twin Peaks and</ENAMEX>, of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> .

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> ,
now midway through its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, has outlasted them all. It began
as a series of fill-in segments for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tracey Ullman Show</ENAMEX> . (Oh, for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of yesteryear! Of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jump Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shannen Doherty</ENAMEX>-era
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90210</NUMEX> , of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alien Nation and Roc</ENAMEX> ! Where have you gone,
Keenen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory Wayans</ENAMEX>?) These crudely drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>episodes were like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX> stories optioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna-Barbera</ENAMEX>. They featured the grind and
humiliation of lower-middle-class family life, and they centered not on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX> but on the beleaguered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">early Homer</ENAMEX> was hardly the sweet-natured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oaf</ENAMEX> who quickly replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>. His voice was growlier, his temper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quicker</ENAMEX>, and his shaky masculine pride always on the line. The first bit I
recall seeing involved <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Homer</ENAMEX> falling for the aggressive sales pitch of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">RV</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>, and his willingness to bury his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> under crushing debt in order
to look like a big shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>'s eyes, and theirs. (The current <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>,
in contrast, is a creature so utterly without pride as to qualify for a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sainthood</ENAMEX>.)

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fledgling outfit</ENAMEX> with nothing to
lose, put the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> slot, up
against <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cosby Show</ENAMEX> , then the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The upstart
did not just so much challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cosby</ENAMEX> as envelop it: In perhaps the most
sustained of the winking pop-culture references for which it has become famous
(and on which it came to depend rather too heavily as time went on), The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> soon featured an avuncular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> with a
penchant for multicolored sweaters.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">justly</ENAMEX> celebrated for the density of its cultural allusions and the rich detail
of its visuals. The best episodes project two dimensions into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> better than
any animation since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s features of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> or the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Jones</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrie Melodie</ENAMEX> shorts for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> But the show's real achievement is in
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, a range of comic types as vivid as any in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX> the feminist-intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">icon</ENAMEX>, the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> is the extraordinary marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marge</ENAMEX>, a marriage that has had its tests (Remember that slinky French
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">bowling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>? That country-and-western diva? The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hero sandwich</ENAMEX>?
The nervous breakdown on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX>?), but has endured since the end of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disco</ENAMEX> era. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> sneered during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> campaign that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
needed more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waltons</ENAMEX> and fewer like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX>, you knew it
was over for him--and not only because he seemed to be wishing for an end to
electricity and indoor plumbing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> are our truest, best selves:
stupid--maybe; lazy--you bet; suspicious of authority--always; willing to do
anything about it--not really; but above all, loyal to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>, our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, our little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, our hometowns, our bad haircuts, and
our favorite brand of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> may be hip and ironic, but
unlike, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ren & Stimpy</ENAMEX> , it has never been
cynical.

            Its success resulted from the unlikely collusion between
Groening, a left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> (and self-described <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX>) from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, a right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX> has always insisted on (and been granted) freedom from network
interference, his show is still a creature of contradictions. It pokes endless
fun at the corporatization of all aspects of life (think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duff Gardens</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mind-numbing</ENAMEX>, totalitarian theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>; or the robotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> clone
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBain</ENAMEX>; or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malibu Stacy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>-like doll <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Simpson</ENAMEX> lives for)
even as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have become among the most recognizable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">icons</ENAMEX> of
corporate culture. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This January</TIMEX>, the spiky hair and bulging eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> mysteriously found their way into a photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> patrolling a
street in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron</ENAMEX> that accompanied a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> Magazine essay by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX>. An "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note" the following week
explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> in question signs all his pictures by holding a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart Simpson</ENAMEX> mask up to his lens--and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> erroneously assumed that
the mask had been held by a passing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            "As much as I love the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> show," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groening</ENAMEX> recently told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, "I also
love the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> figurines. To me the figurines are part of the
creative product." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX>'s willing, if somewhat ironic, embrace of the
marketing bonanza his creation has unleashed may have cost him his rightful
spot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Comics Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">highbrow/subculture pantheon.</ENAMEX> I'm sure
he's not as upset about it as I am.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> since its debut, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> has
spawned a raft of imitators and has launched a boom in prime-time animation.
Some of the products of this boom have been unsurprisingly dreadful (Remember
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critic</ENAMEX> ? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duckman</ENAMEX> ?). But others have been pretty good--the
tragically misunderstood <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beavis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butt</ENAMEX>-head , for instance, and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creator</ENAMEX>'s subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> . And now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, ever eager to flog
its winning formulas to the point of exhaustion, has come up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Family</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The PJs</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Futurama</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have
been generous to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Futurama</ENAMEX> , confident that it will pick up steam as it
goes along. I'm not so sure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visually</ENAMEX>, it's stunning. The screen is packed with
puns for the eye and teasers for the brain. But the writing is slow and
stilted, and the situations already seem tired and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">didactic</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s
episode was as cuddly as an episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Full House</ENAMEX> , and the previous one,
in which it's discovered that the moon has become a vulgar tourist trap, seemed
recycled from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> outtakes right down to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whalers on the Moon</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">singing panorama.</ENAMEX> Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Futurama</ENAMEX> will pick up. I make no
predictions.

            Except one. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand years from now</TIMEX>, if robot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> want to know what life was really like in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-20 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, they will look to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hell</ENAMEX> and
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> . No, there were no talking rabbits, and human hair was not
sculpted into yellow spikes or blue pylons (well, not that often anyway). But
everything else is pretty much accurate.

         
      
   
