
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> Crackup

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two weeks</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have raised a ruckus over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s failure to promptly
remove a suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>. Making the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s case on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, blamed the spy
fiasco on "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of inattention and a feckless photo-op foreign policy."
But when asked how he would treat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> sketched a policy hardly
distinguishable from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. And when asked about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loose nukes</ENAMEX>, he
conceded, "I don't know the answer to this. Maybe it's inappropriate for me to
come on this program."

            It's painful to watch
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> discuss foreign affairs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. No doctrine binds together
their complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s actions. While calling him soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, many
quietly espouse the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> policy of trade<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">-plus</NUMEX>-scolding. While
demanding boldness abroad, they have opposed military action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. And while falling back on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> rhetoric, they
ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> sale. Winning a presidential election on foreign
policy will be hard enough. Winning it without a coherent message will be
impossible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> identity crisis is fourfold.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
               . Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
see the spy scandal as an opportunity to revive <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> rhetoric. They allude
constantly to "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>" and "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosenbergs</ENAMEX>." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of failing to "clean out a nest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> who've stolen the most vital secrets since the Rosenbergs
went to the electric chair." At a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, another presidential
hopeful, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, compared the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> case to past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">espionage</ENAMEX> and warned that it might precipitate another "arms race."

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, however, realize that nuclear
threats are now diffuse rather than concentrated in one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. Appearing on the
same show with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, rejected the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
model: "I accept the fact that [the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> on us. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do." At
tried to broaden the discussion from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, which has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> that can
reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, whose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX> such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> could end up on
the black market.

            The missile-defense
debate highlights the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> dilemma. The original Strategic Defense
Initiative was supposed to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> against a massive nuclear
strike by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. By contrast, the missile-defense program approved
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> is designed to stop one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> fired by a
rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lugar</ENAMEX> can't agree on
which kind of threat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> poses, they won't be able to agree which kind of
anti-missile system the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> should stand for.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Capitalism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> made this the linchpin of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. China</ENAMEX> policy. Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has renewed most-favored-nation trade
status for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, approved legislation enabling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to sell China
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">nonmilitary</ENAMEX> nuclear technology, and killed a proposed ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> sales to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> signed up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> to sponsor
legislation to relax restrictions on exports of encryption technology, despite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s objections that this technology might be passed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-leaning business community launched a lobbying blitz to
remind "hawks" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> "will be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest computer
market in the world by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>."

            Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s best-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hawk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, is leading the charge to restrict trade with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as punishment for its spying. "The continuing problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> human
rights violations, espionage, and possible technology transfers suggest that
this is not the appropriate time for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to enter" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>, he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Like-minded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> denounces
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who have sided with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policy of "trade above all else in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Constructive engagement. Having ripped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
engagement policy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is already locking and loading the same
critique for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "The policy of engagement has devolved and degenerated into
a policy of appeasement," he declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">engagement</ENAMEX> has led to nuclear proliferation, deterioration in human rights, and
now laxity against espionage.

            Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> avidly defended
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">engagement</ENAMEX>, however, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, agrees.
"The more we're involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the better off we are--for us and for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> area," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. "It's also important that
we stress our views on human rights. If we aren't engaged, we can't do that."
Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyo.</ENAMEX>, rejected his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' fierce response
to the spy story: "I've never supported the idea that every time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> does
something we don't like we ought to submit a thing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and get after
them."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s identity crisis
over engagement is almost comic. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> pointed out on This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>, had pioneered engagement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai Communiqué</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
Will exploded: "I was for impeaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Communiqué</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> have learned to brush off <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
of engagement by quoting the policy's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> aren't sure whether to blame
the spy case on ideology or corruption. Some want to paint <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> as soft on
defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, calls the case "symptomatic of the casual
attitude with which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration views issues of national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>." Others want to blame it on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, for example, demands an investigation of "the allegations about
technology transfer [and] all these campaign contributions that came out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>."

            Nor have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> figured out whether to blame
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in general or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in particular. Many have grown more disgusted
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s triangulations than with congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>'
straightforward liberalism. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton China</ENAMEX> policy from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> has been
subsumed into the permanent campaign," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ,
citing objections to that policy "from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> alike."
Moreover, given the political damage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has suffered by unilaterally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impeaching Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> fear that the merits of their arguments
will once again be drowned by charges of partisanship. Sure enough, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> of using the spy case for
"partisan point-scoring."

            To beat the partisanship rap, several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are invoking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, cites "a growing unrest" over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> "on both sides
of the aisle," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of
trying to "cover up" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' "bipartisan" findings of laxity in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> tried to goad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>,
into blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> for suppressing those findings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX> shot him down: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> party position, because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have
worked very closely together on this issue."

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s approach to
world affairs has been aimless and inconsistent, assailing his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy
from all directions is hardly the way to make that point. The opposite of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inconsistency</ENAMEX> is principle. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has yet to figure out what its
principle is.

         
      
   
