
   
   
      
         
             Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're So Screwed Up</ENAMEX>

            Let's stipulate that you
are unique, unfathomable, singular, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sui generis</ENAMEX>. Now, let's find out how to
categorize you, classify you, and sort you into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that explains your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">temperament</ENAMEX>, your career choices, the strength of your immune system, and your
ability to make up puns.

            Here follows an
admittedly random guide to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> popular methods designed to explain who you
really are. I deliberately picked systems that purport to pinpoint something
intrinsic in our natures. I judged the ease of use and
applicability of each system, and since all of them illustrate their
points with the lives of famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, I also gauged how successfully each one
explains the process by which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIRTH</ENAMEX>
ORDER
            

            Would your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> say you are more like:
a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos the Jackal</ENAMEX> or b) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>?; a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Schlafly</ENAMEX> or b)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Nightingale</ENAMEX>?

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank J. Sulloway</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Born To</ENAMEX>
Rebel: Birth Order, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Dynamics</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creative</ENAMEX> Lives , if your loved ones
chose a), you are a typical firstborn--an achieving, status conscious,
defensive, incipient fascist terrorist. If you're a b), you are certainly a
"laterborn"--a bold, compassionate iconoclast.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sulloway</ENAMEX> is hardly the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to extract personality
distinctions from birth order. His twist is to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darwinism</ENAMEX> to show how the
familial struggle among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> for parental attention accounts for everything
in society from social rebellions to scientific revolutions. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sulloway</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universe</ENAMEX>, firstborns are dictatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> who just don't get it, but they're
happy to oppress freedom-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laterborns</ENAMEX> who do. So how does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulloway</ENAMEX> explain
that the greatest scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX>, is a firstborn? He doesn't.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sulloway</ENAMEX> (surprise! he's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>) also
thinks his findings should be applied to selecting corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. In a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nutshell</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldests</ENAMEX> need not apply. As devoted as he is to birth order as a
personality determinant, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sulloway</ENAMEX> allows other variables to creep into his
theory to account for those rare firstborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>. "Whenever one
encounters a firstborn radical (and family life does occasionally produce
them), such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are likely to have experienced substantial conflict
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>. Parent-offspring conflict makes honorary laterborns out of some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firstborns</ENAMEX>." This is a little like saying all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and all women
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prefer cats</ENAMEX>. So a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> is either an honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">honorary dog</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Ease of Use:
                Excellent.
You already know your own status and it's easy to ask others, "Do you have
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">siblings?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sulloway</ENAMEX> also provides a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-variable formula to measure "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Own</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Propensity To Rebel</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Applicability:</ENAMEX>
                As a method
of understanding yourself and others, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sulloway</ENAMEX>'s theory seems rather limited,
except if you're in charge of hiring for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>
Explanation:
                He was the youngest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PERSONALITY</ENAMEX>
            

            Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> act like that? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hippocrates</ENAMEX> believed
the answer was in the balance of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> bodily <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX>, or humors--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, black
bile, phlegm, and yellow bile. This notion lives on in our language <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. We
all know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are essentially hotblooded, or melancholy (which literally
means "black bile"), or phlegmatic, or who view the world with a jaundiced eye.
Plato, less interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>' inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> than in their behavior as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, redefined the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> humors in social terms: as artisans,
guardians, rationals, and idealists. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Keirsey</ENAMEX>,
you are one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> types, you were born that way, you will always be
that way, and you can find out which one you are by taking the temperament
sorter quiz on his Web
site. Sample questions: When the phone rings do you: a) hurry to get it
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>? or b) hope someone else will answer? Do you find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorists</ENAMEX>: a) somewhat annoying? or b) rather fascinating?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keirsey</ENAMEX> does not muck
around in your excretions in order to determine your personality. His criteria
come from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Jung</ENAMEX> by way of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Briggs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel Briggs Myers</ENAMEX>, who created the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers-Briggs Type Indicator</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> translated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jung</ENAMEX>'s idea that
personality is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pairs of preferences--the most famous being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extroverted</ENAMEX> and introverted--and created a systematic test to discern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
types. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keirsey</ENAMEX> has redefined these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pairs this way:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Expressive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>) or Reserved (I)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observant</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Introspective</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tough-minded</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>) or Friendly (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheduling</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>) or
Probing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probing</ENAMEX> might better be defined as looking for alternatives]

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sets of pairs can be matched up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
different ways--with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keirsey</ENAMEX> organizing these into those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Platonic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>. For example, I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NT</ENAMEX>, which makes me a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rational</ENAMEX>, therefore naturally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curious</ENAMEX>, restless, and doubting. More specifically I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ENTP</ENAMEX>. As Keirsey
writes: "A rough draft is all they need to feel confident and ready to proceed
into action. ... [They] have been known to engage in brinkmanship with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ENTPs</ENAMEX>] like to spar verbally with their loved ones."

            OK, he nailed me. As an example of how uncanny the
type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sorter</ENAMEX> can be, take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, who Keirsey classifies as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESFP</ENAMEX>. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keirsey</ENAMEX>'s book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Please Understand Me II</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESFP</ENAMEX>'s are described as
"inclined to be impulsive and self-indulgent, which makes them vulnerable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seduction</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pleasure</ENAMEX> seems to be an end in itself ... they will do what they
feel like in the moment rather than what is good for them in the long run ...
blaming someone else if things don't turn out well. ... Intent on pleasing
everybody, [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESFPs</ENAMEX>] can appear fickle, even promiscuous, to other types." On the
other hand, maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is just too hotblooded.

            
               
                  Ease of Use:
                Good. I
recommend taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Temperament Sorter II</ENAMEX> and ignoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Character Sorter</ENAMEX>,
which I found confusing and not particularly accurate.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Applicability:</ENAMEX>
                High. I
feel I now understand better why I keep acting that way. It's also given me the
sly sense that I know why other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are acting their way. Of course, that's
very ENTP of me.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>
Explanation:
                According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keirsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Idealist</ENAMEX> (an NF),
what else? More specifically, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INFJ</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INFJs</ENAMEX> have an unusually strong desire
to contribute to the welfare of others. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INFJs</ENAMEX> are scarce, little more than
one percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, which is too bad, considering their usefulness
in the social order."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTELLIGENCE</ENAMEX>
            

            Until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Gardner</ENAMEX> came along,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> was like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>: It was large, permanent, and unified.
Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> he published his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frames of Mind: The Theory of Multiple</ENAMEX>
Intelligences , which cleaved intelligence into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> components. Recently,
like a breakaway republic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> has added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighth</NUMEX> intelligence and is
considering a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> rejects the notion that intelligence is a
"single, general capacity" that can be measured by taking a test. He believes
an intelligence is the ability to "solve problems or create products" in a way
that society values--that having it must have conferred an evolutionary
advantage to us, and that there is biological evidence for it. That is, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> can be destroyed due to brain injury, which could be called the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who mistook his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> for a hat" criterion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> says if you excel at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of intelligence, it has no bearing on whether you'll be skilled at
another. Instead of burdening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> ways to be inadequate instead
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, multiple intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> says the theory liberates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
find their own set of strengths.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> original intelligences are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">linguistic,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical</ENAMEX>, logical-mathematical, spatial, bodily-kinesthetic, interpersonal, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intrapersonal</ENAMEX> (my favorite, since I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> for self-absorption). The
latest addition is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturalist</ENAMEX> intelligence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardner</ENAMEX> defines it as "the ability
to recognize and classify <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, minerals and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> says you can
see it in action in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know every kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX>, or sneaker, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">automobile</ENAMEX>. He is also considering adding existential intelligence, which, he
says, refers to the inclination to ask: "Who are we? Where do we come from?
What's it all about? Why do we die?" This could also be known as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gevalt</ENAMEX> " intelligence. Since I felt that his theory left out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
are skilled at the use of the senses of taste and smell, I lobbied him to add
culinary intelligence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> wasn't biting. I decided to forgo making a pitch
for my own area of brilliance: procrastination intelligence.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> is to apply his work to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>, since he believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> excelling in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguistic</ENAMEX> and logical-mathematical intelligences to reward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who share
those intelligences. He also believes that while our propensity toward certain
types of intelligence is inborn, our abilities are not fixed. Understanding our
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of strength and weakness, he says, can provide more self-awareness and
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> move to a "higher level of skill."

            
               
                  Ease of Use:
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardner</ENAMEX>
says, "Common sense, self-observation, and talking to others should suffice to
tell you what is distinctive about your mind." But we want a quiz, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX>!
One is available in the book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">7 Kinds of Smart: Identifying and Developing</ENAMEX>
Your Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Intelligences</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Armstrong</ENAMEX>, which offers choices such as,
"I enjoy entertaining myself or others with tongue twisters, nonsense rhymes,
or puns" and "I find it difficult to sit still for long periods of time." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MIDAS</ENAMEX> Web site provides descriptions of the intelligences, links to
other multiple intelligence sites, and sells multiple intelligence testing
materials (prices range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 to $35</NUMEX>).

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Applicability:</ENAMEX>
                Assessing
multiple intelligences probably has most value for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
feel they have made a wrong career choice.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>
Explanation:
                In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frames of Mind Gardner</ENAMEX> writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>
exemplified interpersonal intelligence.

            
               BLOOD
TYPE
            

            What would Hippocrates think of a recent best
seller that asserted that our health, diet, and even our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> are
determined by our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> type? He would probably get to work on The Bile
Bible . But if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hippocrates</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, he wouldn't be at all surprised.
They've been obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> type and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 30 years</TIMEX>. They
also choose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> with "compatible" blood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> assemble
work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> based on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> type. Luckily, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy died in time to
save us from the corporate bloodletting fad. Until now.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eat Right for Your Type</ENAMEX> , naturopath <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. D'Adamo</ENAMEX> writes that our ancient genetic heritage is represented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> human blood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, A, B, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>--and that we must follow the
nutritional dictates that evolution laid down. He says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Type O</ENAMEX> is the most
ancient blood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the one of the carnivorous big-game <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>, the
self-reliant, risk-taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX>. A later mutation is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Type A</ENAMEX>, he writes, that
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> adapting to an agrarian diet, who were cooperative, law-abiding, yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">high-strung</ENAMEX>. Next came Type B from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mongolian</ENAMEX> nomads, the most flexible and
creative of the blood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX>. Finally, a modern quirk, is the rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>, people
who are somewhat confused, edgy, sensitive, yet charismatic. According to
D'Adamo, eat the right <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> for your type and your immune system will be
strengthened and you'll lose weight.

            Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Adamo</ENAMEX>'s understanding of human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX> is, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Meikle</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Human Origins</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona State University</ENAMEX>, "completely worthless." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meikle</ENAMEX>, there is
no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Type O</ENAMEX> is the earliest blood type--quite the opposite since A
and B occur in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX>. Nor is it likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> went from being
primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">carnivores</ENAMEX> to omnivores. Among living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter-gatherers</ENAMEX>, he says, most
of their calories come from vegetable matter, because bagging game is
difficult. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who are able to eat the most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> are agriculturists," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meikle</ENAMEX>. "They keep [<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>], raise them, and eat them."

            Not surprisingly, this kind of information is of
little interest when you've got a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> volume ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook Right</ENAMEX> for Your
Type ) to your best seller. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Kelly</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturopath</ENAMEX> who works in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>'Adamo's
practice says, "It's not a productive way for me to spend my time debating with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have a different belief system. We try to help sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get
better."

            
               
                  Ease of Use:
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ouch</ENAMEX>. If you
know your blood type, it is easy. If you don't, march down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>,
donate a pint, and they'll tell you.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Applicability:</ENAMEX>
                Scientific
questions aside, I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX> (OK, OK, I am charismatic), and I'm not
following any diet that encourages me to eat a lot of snails.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi Explanation</ENAMEX>:
                None.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Adamo</ENAMEX>'s promotional materials do quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hurley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Type O</ENAMEX>), in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> interview, saying she read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Adamo</ENAMEX>'s "absurd book,"
followed his plan, and "lost an astounding amount of weight."

         
      
   
