
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I work in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>). Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> (married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>, unmarried female) are spending an inordinate amount of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> together during office <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are beginning to talk. These two
spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least an hour</TIMEX> a day in closed-door "meetings," <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another 15 minutes</TIMEX> here
and there during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> chatting and occasionally whispering. They go out to
lunch together, and she even came into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> just to talk to
him. (They went into her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, shut the door, and emerged <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour later</TIMEX>.
Then she left.)
            

            
               Neither of them has any business reason that
requires "meetings." It is at the point now where other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are making
comments about this relationship. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> monopolize each other's time, and
the bad part is that now he is telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> he is too busy to do some
tasks.
            

            
               Prudie, I don't think this is anything more
than a flirtation (I guess I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX>). But my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and I cannot
figure out a way to tell him (or her) that this is affecting the work
environment, their reputations, and our morale.
            

            
               I'm writing because I need to know who should
talk to him or her. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> don't feel close enough to either of them to
say what needs to be said, but neither do we want to make a big thing of it by
telling his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>. He is the senior of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved. How should we
handle it?
            

            
               Thanks,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anonymous</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear An</ENAMEX>,

            Let's review: He is married, they have no business
reasons to get together, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is chirping about their lengthy
closed-door "meetings," they whisper, leave to have lunch together, and you
think there is no more than a "flirtation." This is like imagining that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> died in a standing position at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of natural history.
Of 
               course they're having an affair, but Prudie compliments you on
your high-minded and generous assessment of the situation. Now, what to do
about it?

            You and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> must rethink your reticence
about not saying anything to anybody. The fact that you are an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lothario</ENAMEX> now finds himself too busy for some tasks, means the
involvement has begun to impinge on the workplace.

            Do you have a human
resources <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>? It is pledged to confidentiality and could intervene.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees that speaking directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> would probably not be
useful.) If your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is too small to have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, then a designated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> must go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX>--he being senior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--and
lay out the situation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is all for romance (she doesn't even mind it in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>), but when it complicates the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> something needs to
be done. Please note that we are not dealing with the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is
married because that is none of our business.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, proactively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Your response to ""--recommending that a
soon-to-be-married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> break off relations with highly unsupportive
soon-to-be in-laws--struck a deep, dark chord in me. My problem is similar
except that my fiance doesn't always realize the extent of his mother's
manipulations or their possible effect on our relationship. Mostly she tries to
make him feel like hell via barbed remarks and/or the silent treatment for
"deserting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" in order to be with me. (She has always relied heavily
on him for emotional support following her divorce from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.)
            

            
               Obviously I can't
point out what a horror his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is, but it's very difficult to watch him
take these unrelenting guilt trips. Plus, I worry that this ever so slightly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipal</ENAMEX> situation is going to get in the way of his commitment to me. Is there
any hope?
            

            

               --Do Tell
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Do</ENAMEX>,

            There is not only hope, there is a strategy. Prudie
will now give you the roadmap.

            Do not point out that the beloved's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">witch</ENAMEX>. He already knows. This is a wonderful opportunity to cement your
relationship as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>: Be his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, not his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attacker</ENAMEX>. In the interest of
seeing the big picture, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you can get him to talk about what he is
feeling when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jocasta</ENAMEX> does a number on him. Discuss, in general terms, the
nature of guilt and point out--as sympathetically as you can--that her divorce
had very unhappy consequences for her. For that is the crux of her acting out:
She has made your intended into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>-substitute.

            You also might try
killing the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> with kindness. Include her when you can, and let it be
your suggestion. It will disorient her totally. Just know that her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurosis</ENAMEX> has nothing to do with the love you and the beloved have for each
other ... and then see to it. You can do an end run around her by understanding
the game and by not responding in a destructive way.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, strategically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I truly like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, but is
he technically my brother-in-law--as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> insists--or--as I believe--a)
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> or b) my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s brother-in-law? The polite answer
is, of course, call him whatever he wants to be called, but we are all curious
as to which appellations are technically correct.
            

            
               Yours
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">faithfully,</ENAMEX>
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genealogically Confused</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Gene</ENAMEX>,

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Post</ENAMEX> is long gone, her answer to your
question has been preserved. She relied on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>, which said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loosely</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>."

            So ... your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a "loosely," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is sure he's a swell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, Postally

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Recently a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine posted something
untrue about me--using my real name--on an electronic bulletin board. The
subject of his posting has caused me real embarrassment and discomfort. What
should I do?
            

            
               Thanks for your
help.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Golly</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Good</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is thinking of the
forest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranger</ENAMEX>'s adage: Fight fire with fire. Make your own posting on the same
bulletin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> refuting the erroneous message. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would also question your
appellation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>."

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, correctively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> wants
to have sex even though we have only been going out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX>. I feel that
this will change our relationship and make it more complicated. She says that
if I were a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I would have sex with her. Should I hold out until I feel
the time is right or give in now?
            

            

               --Luke
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Lu</ENAMEX>,

            If your dilemma is
genuine (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels a faint pull on her leg) by no means should you be
maneuvered into bed. Tell your shy <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">violet</ENAMEX> that if she doesn't approve of your
timetable you're certain she can find someone who will accommodate her.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, suspiciously

         
      
   
