
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cure</ENAMEX> for Sinophobia

            Trying to make sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relations these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> can reduce even the most resolute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinologist</ENAMEX> to a blubbering wreck. At the
moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> are pummeling each other over<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: the Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> bombing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> espionage detailed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cox</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
technology export policies, the renewal of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s normal trade (formerly most
favored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>) status, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s application to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> support for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> democracy, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sympathy for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s wavering endorsement of
nuclear nonproliferation, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s persecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s persecution
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s surging anti-Americanism.

            Oh, and I forgot to mention that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre. Happy
anniversary!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> question has
produced a kind of mass hysteria in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The
extremes--Sino-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> bashers--have kidnapped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy.
Business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> insist that our economic partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trumps all
else. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, are screaming for a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, demanding
that we confront the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evil Empire</ENAMEX> before it grows too mighty. (This
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> continues a long and deplorable trend, described by

                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in "": The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> out of
presidential power inevitably accuses the ruling party of being soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
but then adopts the same accommodationist policies as soon as it wins the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>.) And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, human rights, and
labor demand that we break with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> until it stops: persecuting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">destroying Tibet</ENAMEX>, oppressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>, and mistreating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            So what's a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> to think? Here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> to
wisdom for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. China</ENAMEX> policy.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               Disaggregate:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> want to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy hostage to their pet
issues--security, democracy, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, trade, etc. They are monochromatic:
Democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> judge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> on its worst behavior toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> and
ignore any good behavior, while business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s dynamism
and don't notice repression, espionage, etc. Any reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy must
separate issues of agreement and disagreement. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> can
cooperate on trade, but we'll never make common cause on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. So our policy
needs firewalls : The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business community shouldn't be able to
force the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to cave on human rights just to improve economic ties.
Nor should human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> be allowed to make trade agreements
contingent on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> kindness toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>. Until the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> can
disaggregate, its entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy will be held hostage to the most
contentious issue of the moment.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Don't
criticize without offering a sensible alternative: A key reason for
our mangled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> hawks endlessly indict <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy
without proposing their own remedy. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> whacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> bashers for their belligerent
carping over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cox</ENAMEX> report: "Where exactly do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> think you are going
with this? ... Do you want to declare war on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>? Is that what you want?" The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> bashers slam <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s economic coziness with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, but they're mum
about what they would do instead: They don't want a trade war, either. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> preach for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> independence, but then refuse to say whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> is worth fighting for.

             

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Stop seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>: Unlike the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is not expansionist, not interested in exporting communism (and
hardly interested in keeping the communism it's got), and incredibly keen about
joining the world economy. This is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is not the
implacable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> was, and we should not treat it that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>. We can do business with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. On the other hand ...

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Don't help
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> become a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> may not be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, but it's
not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX> either. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> wants to build sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and
dethrone the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s dominant military power. We don't have to
help it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should limit technology transfers, increase spying
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, strengthen our military alliances with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> (notably
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>), and stall <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s weapons development as much as we peaceably
can.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Take the long view: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy wobbles because it
is always responding to the crisis du jour--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cox</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, the latest
suppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>, etc. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relations are better considered
over a span of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>. On democracy, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> are
raging over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s recent suppression of all democratic dissent. This
suppression is an outrage, but our policy must be more sophisticated than mere
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indignation</ENAMEX>. Compare <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1999 China</ENAMEX> permits vast
economic freedom, sponsors competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> elections, allows the
establishment of nongovernmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, tolerates environmental and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights activism, and is starting to develop a reliable legal system.
This is certainly not democracy, but it's not totalitarianism either. Catharin
rights, and labor, notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> took the same preliminary steps on its
path to democracy. (Of course, taking the long view on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> also requires
taking the longer view. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> may have improved since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, but it still
has an unblemished history of authoritarianism, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> millenniums without
sustained democracy.)

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Worry a
lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>: Amid all the fretting about normal trade status,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, espionage, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, we tend to overlook <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. This is worrisome,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> is by far the hottest issue between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
"There is an increased sense of desperation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. We can
stumble into a war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> very easily," warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
Shambaugh of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are fretting about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s prosperous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> and its flirtation with independence. They are
also irked by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>--especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> plan to
deploy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Theater Missile Defense</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>. Keeping the
peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan Strait</ENAMEX> must be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' top <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> priority. It
will require immense prudence: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must nurture a democratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> while discouraging a declaration of independence, must arm Taiwan
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> invasion while promoting closer Sino-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> ties.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. And, finally, don't be so melodramatic: Our
relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> are messy partly because we worry too much about them. "We
have never been able to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> like we would look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. We
are always swept up in some idealized notion of what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is or should be,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bates Gill</ENAMEX>. "On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> issues, we have
never learned to have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">normal</TIMEX> reactions. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is not <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 feet</NUMEX> tall." Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
is an emerging power and, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> may be the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next century</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have transformed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> into an otherworldly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>,
a mysterious angel, a baffling demon.

            Here a historical analogy is illuminating: Only a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade ago</TIMEX>, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was frantic about another mysterious, ominous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> power that was not quite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, not quite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, too,
seemed antagonistic toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and bent on global domination. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
is more like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid brother</ENAMEX> than a mortal threat. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, too, is just a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> like any other, with ambitions and fears, strengths and weaknesses. And
until we recognize that, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy will be more fraught than it should
be.

         
      
   
