
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot Hooligans, Not Hoops</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paducah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonesboro</ENAMEX>. Our once-safe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have become slaughterhouses,
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> for any pot-smoking, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>-listening,
trench-coated deviant with a grievance.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> will undoubtedly exploit the tragedy of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> to push
for still more restrictions on the constitutional right to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. Any day
now, you should expect to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">lackeys</ENAMEX> proposing to expand
"gun-free school zones," the supposedly "safe" areas around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> where guns
are banned. (Given recent history, perhaps they should be called "school-free
gun zones.")

            It's time to recognize the naiveté of such legislation, a
foolishness that has turned our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> into killing grounds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX> wisely declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that the
presence of an armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> might have saved the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High School</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> pointed out that the presence of "someone who
was armed" could have "stabilized" the situation. As usual, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moses and the Body</ENAMEX>
were on target, but they didn't go far enough. As it turns out, there was a
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>, but a single, lightly armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is not
sufficient deterrence. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> don't just need several armed security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> or even armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. They need armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Immediately, before
another student fires another shot, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right To Carry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Concealed Weapons</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Classroom Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.

            There is no disputing:
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> are outlawed, only outlaws in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> calls our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> "safe zones," but this is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perverted</ENAMEX> idea of safety: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law-abiding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are defenseless while predatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juvenile delinquents</ENAMEX>, armed to the teeth, are free to roam. Why do you think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan Klebold</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High</ENAMEX> for murder? Because they
knew their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> would be unarmed! But they would not have dared to invade
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had they known they would be confronted by well-trained,
well-prepared, and well-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX>. Studies have proven that society is
safer when law-abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> carry concealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> will be,
too.

            Not every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> has to carry a concealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. It is,
of course, a matter of personal choice. But any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who is willing--whether
she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 or even 8</NUMEX>--should be free to arm herself and walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of
her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> without fear. If our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> are old enough to kill--and
the schoolyard massacres have proved that--they're certainly old enough to
defend themselves. Let's put classroom safety in the hands--and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holsters</ENAMEX>--of those who need it most.

         
      
   
