
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">219</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Not&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               The slogan in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, promulgated at government expense, is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not Me</ENAMEX>, Not
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Now</TIMEX>." Not what?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 218</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Smell Something?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           "It stinks in God's nostrils, and I
know it stinks in the law's nostrils, and it stinks to me." Who said this about
what?
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "Noted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX>, protesting a parking ticket
with his usual élan."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York City Consumer Affairs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jules Polonetsky</ENAMEX>, ever vigilant about
Passover gouging, has discovered some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fake</ENAMEX> gefilte <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> produced by the Posse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comitatus</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Oder</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>, on the suspiciously effective performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Orioles</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bullpen</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candor</ENAMEX>, gossiping about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stench</ENAMEX> at the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Concepts Potluck</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bingo Night</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Wasik</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s highest praise."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Shuger</ENAMEX>
            

             

             

             

             

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Judging by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>--and I do--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> likeliest to express nasal disdain are
film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. This is a disturbing ceding of the field
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. It is, for instance, the right of every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> to carp
about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> (I believe that's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>) and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bible</ENAMEX>). But there is a recent reluctance to fire at certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> unless one
has impressive credentials, a professionalizing of contumely. This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lamentable</ENAMEX> and unnecessary. Remember (using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginkoba</ENAMEX> if need be) what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
said about literary criticism: "You may scold a carpenter who has made you a
bad table, though you cannot make a table. It is not your trade to make
tables." Although as any trained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> can tell you, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Cham</ENAMEX>
clearly did not mean you should criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> because you're discontent
with the replies selected for Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.

            
               Really, Really
Sorry Answer
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Lyons</ENAMEX> was describing his theft of the
for swindling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $4 million</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Baptist Convention USA</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s largest black denomination, while serving as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. "I
cannot shake the feeling that I have let so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down," he added. Well,
yeah.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alma Mater</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            In the fierce struggle
for first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who can write first-class tuition checks, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> have begun advertising. Can you name the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that used the
following slogans in recent magazine ads?

            

               Slogans
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Sacrifice Nothing

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Sacrifice Nothing for Nobody Nohow

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Service, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pride</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excellence</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Write <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">... Explore ... Discover</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Dream, Think, Become

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Drink, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vomit, Repeat</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Education Creates a Lifelong Thirst for</ENAMEX>
More

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Education Creates a Lifelong Thirst for</ENAMEX>
More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Sorry About the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> Percent
Whiter

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Bennington

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>*

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University of New York</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Lawrence</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of New Rochelle</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Dartmouth*

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iona College</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business School</ENAMEX>)*

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> (political science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>)*

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>*

            *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> be
the liquor talking.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            A delightful potpourri with a faint but disturbing
note of disdain for the delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
