
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story worries that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis could
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">refreeze</ENAMEX> relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is so eager to reassert its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> that it may "gamble away its standing in the democratic world in
support of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> that has committed the most heinous human-rights abuses in
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>." ... Another editorial charts the sinking status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX>.
During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> era, Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> viewed asylum as a symbolic triumph
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> displaced by recent ethnic conflicts are
finding no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">havens</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> filmmakers. The most talented of the
lot, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who just released a penetrating movie about war and moral decay, is
now negotiating a deal to direct costume dramas and love stories for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 15, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> special
millennium issues picks "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best Ideas, Stories and Inventions</ENAMEX>" of the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,000 years</TIMEX>. The introduction defends the concept of ranking (it cuts through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 20 th -century</TIMEX> "data smog," and besides other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do it
too). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Botstein</ENAMEX> deems the human voice <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Musical Instrument</ENAMEX>, and A.S.
Byatt awards <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scheherazade Best Story</ENAMEX>. Among the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>: human
rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Idea; Celestine V for Best Pope; India for Best Revolution</ENAMEX>;
penicillin for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Invention; and Lucille Ball for Best Clown</ENAMEX>. The list is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decidedly Brit</ENAMEX>-heavy, with citations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth I</ENAMEX> (Best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Boleyn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Sex Scandal</ENAMEX>), the purchase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Suez Canal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Land</ENAMEX>
Deal), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Naval</ENAMEX>
Battle).

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Face of Evil</ENAMEX>,"
recites the now familiar story of how he co-opted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> nationalism to fuel his
own rise to power. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>," but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>

               suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> may eventually pay the
price for it during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2000</TIMEX> campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has defended the bombing-only
strategy so vehemently that he'll suffer if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> does send ground
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> prints a map of the world's ethnic and civil conflicts,
color-coded to show the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> involvement, annotated with death tolls.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               sidebar reports that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation</ENAMEX>
Army have been trafficking in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> purchases.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story on the amateur genealogy trend sweeping the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> points would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Archives</ENAMEX>, Internet
databases, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> records. The most avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormons</ENAMEX>, who
believe that ancestors can be saved through posthumous baptism and have
established <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,200</NUMEX> genealogy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> around the world to encourage
conversions.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>

               features the findings of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> who claims he can
predict with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> accuracy whether a marriage will endure or dissolve.
The piece includes a handy quiz for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> who want to diagnose their
viability. (Yes or no: "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> generally likes my personality.")

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story
debates whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s goal should be to carve up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> or
administer it as a protectorate. A caustic piece reports that war has improved life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>: There
are no traffic jams (because so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have fled), and the crime rate has
dropped (because all offenses are tried under martial law). ... A
profile says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> may be the slumbering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> of the
presidential race. He's raising cash fast and his once-derided brainy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">folksiness</ENAMEX> is earning praise.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A profile of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ochs</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulzberger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> suggests that their stewardship of the New York
Times was unduly influenced by self-consciousness about their Judaism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Sulzberger</ENAMEX> intentionally underplayed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exterminations</ENAMEX>. ... A long piece chronicles how a death row <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paris Carriger</ENAMEX> was exonerated with legal support from a small
cadre of savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. He didn't know any of them when sentenced,
but he cultivated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">epistolary friendships</ENAMEX> from his prison cell with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>,
anti-capital punishment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> he saw featured on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MacNeil-Lehrer NewsHour</ENAMEX> . ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> reveals the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nastiness</ENAMEX> inside upscale restaurant kitchens: old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, grimy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, and rivers
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The editorial lauds
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hawkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for their willingness to send ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">berates</ENAMEX> poll-wary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> for their hesitance to do so. ("Why don't they just
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> the national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> and stop the charade?")
... A piece suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are not as skittish about battle
casualties as the conventional wisdom dictates: During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Gulf War</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> backed the use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. ... The cover story likens
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> ethnic cleansing to the practices of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>. Both are a harsher
expression of the same impulse that leads to "separate academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African-American</ENAMEX> studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> studies."

         
      
   
