
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greens Back Bombing</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Party</ENAMEX>, on which the German
government's survival depends, rejected a resolution demanding a permanent,
unconditional halt to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing but approved a resolution calling for a
"limited halt" to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> withdraw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawks</ENAMEX>'
spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> are standing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> behind the bombing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doves</ENAMEX>' spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> is splintering, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> can't last. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> a "hegemonist" that uses
its power to "wantonly interfere in the internal affairs of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.''
However, he also agreed to speak with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Sinologists debated
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> is sincerely paranoid or is feigning belligerence to
appease the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> changed his spin on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkan</ENAMEX>
history. His old spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> must intervene in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> because ethnic
violence there has been awful for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. His new spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> can heal the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> because ethnic violence there has only recently become awful.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> endorsed new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> restrictions. After
killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> measure that would have required background checks on all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> at gun shows, they proposed a similar measure. They also voted to ban
sales of semiautomatic assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>, and many of them voted for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> provision that would prohibit high-capacity ammunition clips from
being imported. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s spin on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s initial vote against
background checks: "They passed up this chance to save lives." The spins from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal senators</ENAMEX> and editorialists: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are turning their backs on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX> because the public wants gun control. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are helping the NRA stave off serious gun laws by pushing weaker
restrictions riddled with loopholes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Even so, that's progress.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> filed an antitrust suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX>. The suit accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> of using short-term fare cuts
and service increases to drive away <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in order to resume charging
high fares. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s first suit over predatory pricing since
airline deregulation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s spin: We're busting illegal monopoly
tactics. The positive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> spin: We're being busted for providing
better service at lower cost. The negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> spin: We're being
busted at the behest of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' spin: We're doing
well despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s illegal monopoly tactics. The cynical spin: The suit
will help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> cautioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> may not use their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> to punish organizations
for financial transactions with political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Reports depict the
action as a response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s attempts to pressure an industry lobbying group
to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Although the
letter evidently just spells out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rules, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> said
it "chastised" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> called it a "rebuke."
Campaign-finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdogs</ENAMEX>' spin: It's an attempt to curb <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s fearsome
power and ruthlessness. DeLay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>' spin: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> has disposed of this
matter." The lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> has "sensitized" us to the importance
of hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>
and replaced him with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s internal security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.
This comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> begins prescheduled
impeachment proceedings against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> stock exchange plummeted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent, prompting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to halt trading. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> failed
to save <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s spin: Don't worry,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will continue to reform its economy and play a "constructive role" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Other spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was unhappy because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX> was failing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was jealous because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX> was succeeding. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> decided, as he
does <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month or so</TIMEX>, that it was time to fire his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Now that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> is gone, economic reform can proceed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> is gone,
the political system will collapse. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>, which liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX>,
will respond by impeaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> or forcing him to call new elections. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) Now
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is in turmoil, it can't help solve the crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) Now
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is in turmoil, it can't cause further mischief in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> is resigning. Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summers</ENAMEX> will succeed him. The official explanation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> wants to
return to "private life." The unofficial translation: He wants to resume making
boatloads of money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> hope he'll take over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> next year if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> retires. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> engineered the current
economic boom. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> did. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Neither of them did; they just got the
credit. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>.
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> lauded him as their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>.
Pessimists sold their stocks because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> is leaving. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Optimists</ENAMEX> bought the
stocks because they trust the economy he's leaving behind. (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>,
see "")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ashby</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> whose jet severed an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> ski
lift cable, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, was sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> in military
prison. He was acquitted on manslaughter charges but convicted of
obstruction for destroying a videotape of an earlier part of the flight. The
upbeat spin: The obstruction conviction makes up for the manslaughter acquittal
by reaffirming (especially to angry <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military misdeeds won't
go unpunished. The cynical spin: As with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that
was evidently mistaken for a chemical weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, the ski lift disaster
(attributed in part to government maps that failed to show the ski lift) proves
again that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military intelligence is an oxymoron.

         
      
   
