
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pissed Off About Off</ENAMEX> <EM>Piste</EM>

            The top international story
is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peace talks ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> without a signed agreement. Talks
will reconvene in mid-March, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has apparently agreed not to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>
in the interim. No agreement was reached because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> refused to
accept any plan enforced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>, on the other hand,
pledged at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX> to sign the proposed peace agreement--they will
finalize their decision after consulting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> back home. Most
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' intransigence and call the peace
talks a failure. This is in contrast to, for instance, the New York
Times , which focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>' pledge to sign the
agreement and concludes that the talks were a "limited success."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> "the undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX> summit and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
credibility "its first casualty." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s main complaint is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
faces no serious consequences for his unwillingness to compromise. If anything,
he's learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> lacks the political will to punish him. The paper
predicts that "killing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is not likely to stop." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX>
agrees, saying: "No one has gained from the chaotic 'peace conference.'... No
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>, who has been given a few more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> to kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> before there will be any more talk of unleashing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> on him."
The same editorial also says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s "humiliating climb-down" will hurt
her credibility in future international crises. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">listlessly</ENAMEX> concludes that "triumph was not on the agenda at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, only weariness and relief that the show had been kept on the road
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 days</TIMEX> of discussions at which the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> did not once
negotiate with each other directly."

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers give prominent coverage to news that
another avalanche roared through a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sixteen people</ENAMEX> were killed, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX> are missing. Recent avalanches in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. An
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> are currently stranded in snowed-in resort <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>
throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> reports
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Britons</ENAMEX> are being tried in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for recklessly endangering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX>' lives by going "off piste " (off the marked trail) at a ski
resort near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albertville</ENAMEX>. The lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Londoners</ENAMEX> contacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> on a cell
phone and were brought to safety without injuries to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skiers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX>. The
trial is attracting attention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> because some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">avalanches</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX> have been attributed to irresponsible off piste
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skiers</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astonishingly</ENAMEX>, the brief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story finds room to list each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>'s income, as in "Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairley</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, earns <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about £46,000</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for a medical equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.")

            
A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX> paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Vision</ENAMEX>, has
scored the first interview with deposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idi Amin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a decade</TIMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Audience</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Daddy Idi</ENAMEX>," reprinted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail & Guardian</ENAMEX> ). The profile
sketches "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Daddy</ENAMEX>" as a playful old duffer--e.g., "to punish the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> for running false stories that he eats <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX> a day, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amin</ENAMEX>]
refuses to have his picture taken." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> notably refrains from
asking any hard questions about, say, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandans</ENAMEX> thought to have died
under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amin</ENAMEX>'s rule. Perhaps this is because before the interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amin</ENAMEX> told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that "his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> "say they know you, the place you stay and
when you get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amin</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jeddah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> pension; he
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> satellite dishes, drives a white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX>, and enjoys fishing in the
Red <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
