
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  True
Crime
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>, in his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> st
directorial effort, is a decrepit newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> rushing to save an
innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on death row. The A-list <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who usually puff the star offer
only bland praise this time. The film is "assembled ... with loving care," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wilmington</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> . It's "a wickedly effective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thriller</ENAMEX>," writes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>. And the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> finds it a "quietly poignant ... involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thriller</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naysayers</ENAMEX> toss spit wads. The film is "a hopelessly cliched
newspaper yarn--I kept waiting for someone to scream into the phone, 'Baby, get
me re-write!' " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kaltenbach</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> ). Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> : "It's a gritty story made in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s more elegiacal mode, a confusion of style and content that is not in
the film's best interests." No one comments on the movie's most notable
feature: that here Eastwood crusades on behalf of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> he would have
summarily dispatched, vigilante style, in previous films. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Check out David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s 
                  Slate
                review ; and read a review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission Ranch Restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, here.)

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> and
I
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). This animated effort kiddifies the classic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX> musical. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX> says the
themes about defying class and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convention</ENAMEX> don't work: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't much tuned
into that." Trying to make the story interesting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creators ladle</ENAMEX> in wacky
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, an evil royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>, and a hot-air-balloon action scene--and
refuse to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> die in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>! The result is "an above-average
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-morning</TIMEX> TV show," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaltenbach</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">animation</ENAMEX> gets mixed reviews: "The cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' faces and body language
aren't doing much of an acting job," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Koehler</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX>, the animation "is a curious
hodgepodge of awkward human movement, tired nature effects and fine painterly
backgrounds and detail work." (Discuss the real version of the musical with other stage
nuts in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musicals</ENAMEX>.net.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Forces</ENAMEX> of
Nature
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks SKG</ENAMEX>). Reviews for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck-Sandra</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bullock</ENAMEX> romance are all over the place. Some like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affleck</ENAMEX>, some like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bullock</ENAMEX>,
others like neither. The soppy plot (wedding-bound strait-laced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gets
waylaid by wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>) produces severely mixed reaction as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turan</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is captivated: Besides being "smartly written" and
"directed with a lively intelligence," the film "has several surprises in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repertoire</ENAMEX>, and most--but not all--of them make this a most pleasant and
diverting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>," he says. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> isn't buying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overuptight Affleck</ENAMEX>: "You can't have screwball comedy if only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> party
desperately wants to screw," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justine Elias</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX> in
Time hates the whole thing: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, it had to come sometime: this is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> reprehensible fiasco." A subtext to the reviews is outrage at
the ending, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> try not to give away but still bridle at. "Forces
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> is less about the anarchic powers of love and sex than it is
about the bond between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nonrefundable, first-class
airline tickets," concludes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elias</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX> is beside himself: "It's not even
clever enough to give us the right happy ending. It gives us the wrong happy
ending," he writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> . (The Affleck
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Store</ENAMEX>--part of the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affleck</ENAMEX> site--has to be seen to be
believed.)

            

               Television
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>). Raspberries for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s hosting
performance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">71 st Academy Awards</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say she wasn't
funny and spent too much time congratulating herself. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Rosenberg</ENAMEX> scored her "gratuitously coarse language and
one-liners, and cheap political jokes." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX> hit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s habit of being her own best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> spent too much time
laughing at her one-liners (often, she laughed alone)." Otherwise, everyone
expressed dismay at the epic, record length (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> plus) and a dance
number strange even by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> standards (it included what were apparently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interpretive</ENAMEX> steps to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>), but marveled at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Benigni</ENAMEX>'s
irrepressible speeches and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare in Love</ENAMEX> 's upset win. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>-day
stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> let the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> lash out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> capo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Weinstein</ENAMEX>, who had the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temerity</ENAMEX> to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Picture Oscar</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>.
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinstein</ENAMEX>'s] costly promotional campaigns ... had paid off more handsomely
than expected," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernard Weinraub</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The big
spending is seen both as the roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> 's win and as
portentous of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Normandy</ENAMEX>-scale campaigns on everyone's part <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
(Everything you wanted to know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> is here.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of
Renewal
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>, who was not , gets hosannas for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> volume of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> memoirs. These were the boring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> is given credit
for masterful analysis, trenchant characterizations, and vivid storytelling. In
an almost prostrate review on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> arts
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX> writes, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s history of his own time in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is a work whose breadth, clarity of vision and historical scope amply
justify its size. It is an event, a likely classic of its genre." Kirkus
Reviews agrees: "A brilliant, masterly, even seminal book." The Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts things a bit more into perspective: " 'Years of
Renewal' is an engrossing book, truly hard to put down, at least for
aficionados of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef Joffe</ENAMEX>. (You can read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's excerpt here.)

            Find a
movie playing near you on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  
                     Movie--
                  
                  The
Deep End of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corruptor</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage: Carrie</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  Wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Death-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  Black <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hawk Down</ENAMEX>: A
Story of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Modern War</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Bowden</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Analyze This</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX>, Stock & <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> Smoking
Barrels ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Monica's Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Annie Get Your Gun</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Bright Lights</ENAMEX>, Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  8MM ;

               
                  Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> Cigarettes ;

               
                  Movie -- The 
                  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Houdini Girl</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martyn Bedford</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Perfect Murder, Perfect Town</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiller</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Nightingales</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  
                     Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jawbreaker</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Space</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Music--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Rock</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleater-Kinney</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Traveling Mercies: Some Thoughts on Faith</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Lamott</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Elegant Universe: Superstrings, Hidden Dimensions</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quest for the Ultimate Theory</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian R. Greene</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
