
   
   
      
         
             Unforgiven

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Seconds</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> not to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office, network
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> stamped the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ACQUITTED</ENAMEX>" and "NOT GUILTY" across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
television screens. "This is a real slap at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>," declared
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX>, echoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> on other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLINTON</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACQUITTED DECISIVELY</ENAMEX>," announced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s talk show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> scavenged the battlefield, pronouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>.

            Not so fast. Though the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has cast its votes, history's verdict remains in doubt. The spin war
over who was right or wrong doesn't end with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s acquittal. And the early
conventional wisdom--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has lost the fight--rests on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> erroneous
assumptions.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> fallacy is that the debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s guilt
is an up-or-down question. Actually, it's a spectrum. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX>, crippled by
short memories, focus on the public's opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment and
removal. But this was only the last stage of a gradually escalating scandal.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question, unresolved until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX> confession, was whether
he had done something immoral. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question, debated throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s inquiry, was whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had done something illegal. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> question--whether he had done
something impeachable--didn't come to the fore until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment
debate and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial.

            It's true that by the
time the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> got to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> stage, they had lost the public. But on
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question, the polls remain squarely on their side. In a
post-acquittal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> survey, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 24 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>
say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> shares their moral values. Likewise, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> a negative opinion of him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 35 percent</NUMEX> express a
positive opinion), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59 percent</NUMEX> say he has diminished the presidency's stature,
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54 percent</NUMEX> say he would "commit adultery if he knew he could get away with
it." <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 39 percent</NUMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s verdict vindicates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 percent</NUMEX>
say it does not. These numbers show how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> can rewrite the scandal: by
sliding the debate back across the spectrum to the moral question and
portraying every vote to acquit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a vote to exonerate him.

            This is why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have scrambled to avoid a fight over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s morals and to assure the public that he's been sufficiently
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">castigated</ENAMEX>. They denounce his conduct at every opportunity. Having failed to
pass a censure resolution <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, they signed it anyway and put it in the
Congressional Record . They denied that in acquitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> they had
voted to exonerate him morally. They even touted the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 to 50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> votes
to convict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--which they had unanimously opposed--as suitable punishment.
The votes for conviction "confirmed the humiliation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lautenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, observed approvingly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D.</ENAMEX>, called the verdict "a rebuke" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and asserted that
"this whole process ... has been a level of punishment that was commensurate
with the failures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to act appropriately."

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, assisted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, depicted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' failure to win
a majority vote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> as a disgraceful setback for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. This
argument reflects a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> fallacy: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are out to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and that their vindication depends on his repudiation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. In
post-acquittal comments, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> did try to portray the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
as united in its denunciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. "We're going to end up with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> either having voted to convict or to censure," Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>. "And that, I think, sends a very strong,
historic message to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> seized
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s remark, "It's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> talking point you see: that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> have voted either to convict or censure."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> is missing half the story. There are two
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. The pedagogical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, wants to unite the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior,
thereby resolving the impeachment issue. The political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, wants to divide the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and keep the issue alive for the next election. The pedagogical
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> punished and repentant. The political <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want
him un punished and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">un repentant</ENAMEX>, so the public will stay angry at
him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. They're not interested in using congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hurt Clinton</ENAMEX>. They're interested in using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> to hurt congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            The political
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> objective was to kill the censure resolution. They argued,
correctly, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> were using it for "political cover." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
decision to kill it for the same reason was no less political. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First DeLay</ENAMEX>
blocked it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX> killed it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, insisting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> render an all-or-nothing verdict. According to the New York
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX> had warned his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> that censure would muddle
the partisan rift over impeachment, making the issue less potent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, he got what he wanted. In a tone of disbelief, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schieffer</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, "The trial ended without even a verbal reprimand from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> proclaimed far and wide that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had
escaped untouched. "[It] looks as though, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> put it, a reckless,
reprehensible, and irresponsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will remain our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>. "He won. He always wins," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Children</ENAMEX> now have the lesson that lying, cheating, and breaking the law are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">permissible</ENAMEX>," moaned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Tate</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Matalin</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House of</ENAMEX>
"gloating." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s acquittal another "skirmish in the ongoing culture
war." Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> signaled his intention to pound Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential campaign for having defended
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> think they're
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> to this attack because they've got both ends of the spectrum covered: On
the removal question, the polls are on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s side, and on the moral
question, on which the polls are against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have acknowledged
and condemned his misconduct. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> fallacy: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have
overlooked the legal question in the middle. On that question, they have failed
to reconcile themselves to the polls. In a Gallup survey shortly before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> verdict, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was guilty of perjury. A
post-acquittal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> poll finds that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78 percent</NUMEX> think he's guilty, though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 32</NUMEX>
percent think his crimes merited expulsion from office. And in a post-acquittal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> survey, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> still say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should "face
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> charges at some point."

            Yet every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> voted "not guilty" last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. A few have conceded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s guilt on the perjury charge, but the rest
have either denied that the case was proved or have dodged the question by
arguing that either way, the alleged crimes wouldn't merit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
removal. And while their censure resolution may immunize them against the
charge of moral indifference, it doesn't protect them from the charge of
indifference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s apparent lawbreaking. Its language pointedly avoids
accusing him of perjury or obstruction of justice.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> smell their
opportunity. At their press conference after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> verdict, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> interrupted their sermons against "the polls" to point out where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> agreed with them. "We take great satisfaction ... that [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> poll]
showed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ... recognized that the president
had committed falsehoods under oath," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gekas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, cited the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, "by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> or more,
believes that he's committed perjury," chimed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cannon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>.
"The political cleansing that did not happen through the impeachment process"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leaves Clinton</ENAMEX> "with a great and serious burden."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> will make <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> carry that
burden into the elections. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Romer</ENAMEX> ritually expressed his "disappointment in [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s]
personal behavior," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX> shot back, "I find it
interesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Romer</ENAMEX> would say [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>] are on the high ground, when
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> lied to them, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of them
say he obstructed justice." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , political consultant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> went further, calling the scandal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s "albatross" because "he
acted as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
believe committed perjury and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 24 percent</NUMEX> think is honest and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trustworthy</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> often say
history is written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>. They think this maxim shows how clever and
cynical they are. Actually, it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of a circular argument, and their failure
to grasp this irony exposes their naiveté. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Thirty-five</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX> was a landslide loser. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the conservative
movement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winners</ENAMEX>, it turns out, are written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>. And the contest
to write the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment is just beginning.

         
      
   
