
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Please settle an ongoing dispute between my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and me. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> believes it is OK to floss his teeth while driving
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. (I am not making this up.) His teeth are very nice, but I believe this
activity should be restricted to the privacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> only. He does not
see a problem doing this in public. Please respond.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               --Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floss</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mrs.</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie hesitates to ask
what he is steering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flossing</ENAMEX> is not a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-handed maneuver. You
are correct that it is not an activity meant for public viewing but, more
important, seeing to one's dental hygiene while driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> poses a threat to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oneself</ENAMEX>, as well as to others. Do tell Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floss</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> implores him to
find <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four minutes</TIMEX> to do his admirable oral upkeep when he is outside of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">automobile</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, nervously

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I usually agree with your advice <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>,
but there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases where I'd have suggested something different. I wonder
if we actually disagree, or if my solutions just didn't occur to you.
            

            
               For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> put off by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her old</TIMEX> , I agree that
the best solution would be for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> to change her ways, but leveling
with her would more than likely end the friendship. It sounds as if things are
just fine as long as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> doesn't have to visit her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">house.</ENAMEX> So, why not just develop a convenient "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cat allergy"</ENAMEX>? The white lie is a
time-honored solution for situations like this.
            

            
               And for "," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who wants to keep weight off but can't control what's served at dinner
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, it's only good manners to eat what your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> serves you--with gusto
and gratitude. You can fast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>. (Well, OK, one bowl of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special-K</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">skim milk</ENAMEX>.) Just a thought or, rather, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
            

            

               --I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Southerner and Manners Are Our Thing</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear I'm,

            Thank you for being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> lies are,
indeed, meant for situations like this, but in the case of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nauseously Yours</ENAMEX>,"
there is the chance that straight shooting would be of real help to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> living in filth.

            As for scarfing down
whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> fare is offered, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will split the difference with you.
Granted, one can't get into terrible trouble with an indulgence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX>,
assuming one is eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conscientiously</ENAMEX>, but to inhale a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> of rich food
is counterproductive. Let's say that when at a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> where the sky's the
limit--calorie-wise--it is permissible to treat oneself to something
particularly wonderful ... which of course would involve small tastes of
everything, wouldn't it?

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, moderately

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I'd like to rely on
your unwavering good taste and style to answer a fashion question. Does the
rule of no white clothing before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX> and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> still apply?
I learned at a very young age that dressing in white clothing before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX>
Day or after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> was inappropriate. Are the standards still alive, or are
we living under the rule of the "casual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>" ilk that has pervaded the
standards of dress?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Waiting on Hat Pins and Darning Needles for Your Reply</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear Wait,

            Prudie supposes that the
calendar's rules regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">white</ENAMEX> are still operative for the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>. Even
for them, however, fashion has weighed in with a wild card: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> white. To be
perfectly candid with you though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s own style sense veers toward the
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>: Wear what is flattering and what you like. (This is why no one
has seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s knees in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eons</TIMEX>.)

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, sartorially

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Whatever happened to courtesy? When I am out and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>, whether getting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or shopping for other goods, I seem to encounter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> who equate "There you go" with "Thank you." I can't tell you how many
times I have heard "There you go" as I am handed my change, or my bag, with no
thanks given. "There you go" seems to imply "Get the hell out," whereas a
thank-you is an appreciation of my helping to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> employed.
            

            
               I am not some crotchety old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>. I have worked
retail for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> myself, and I say, "Thank you" because I realize that
if I do not act appreciatively, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> may well go on down the
road!
            

            
               Thank you for you
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courteous Carol</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Court</ENAMEX>,

            My dear, with all due respect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks you
have the wrong take on this. Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> finds "There you go" to be a
rather chipper bon voyage at the end of one's transaction. Have you
noticed how certain phrases seem to take hold? Like "Have a nice day" (which
Prudie happens to loathe). "There you go" is simply one more evolution of our
spoken language ... perhaps meant to refresh commonly said things.

            You are correct, of
course, that a thank-you is always appropriate, but that does not mean a
substitute phrase is improper. Prudie, frankly, cannot fathom how you've
decided that "There you go" is code for "Get the hell out." All you can do,
really, is not go there, yourself, when speaking.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
linguistically

         
      
   
