
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> generally uses
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointments</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, to demonstrate that he's still the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off guard. Most recently he picked, as his
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> known neither for an effective negotiating
style nor for foreign policy expertise but, rather, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of strong will,
few convictions, and a tendency to move slowly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 until 1998</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> apparatchik before that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> remains,
oddly, a cipher. To his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> is a moderate who kept the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> political machine steady for an unusually long time. To his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>,
he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who has never had a clear strategy or articulated an
unambiguous position.

            His diplomatic experience is limited. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>
was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chernomyrdin Commission</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">biannual</TIMEX> meeting
that addressed much and solved little, aside from keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s decrepit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mir</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in orbit. He also helped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> out of the hostage
crisis that occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, when a group of armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechens</ENAMEX> took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in a southern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. Federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> surrounded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shamil Basayev</ENAMEX>, the leader
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage-takers</ENAMEX>, demanded to speak with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, who was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Halifax</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> got on the phone and, in a desperate
and fragmented conversation broadcast live on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> TV, negotiated the
release of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>. In exchange, he allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> to return to
Chechnya, taking a busload of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> with them as human shields (they were
later released). The incident was initially viewed as a triumph for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>--until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national heroes</ENAMEX>, used the
incident to propel themselves to power. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> point out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s order to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> not to storm the hospital ensured the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX>' ultimate victory. Of course, had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> authorized the attack,
he would have been blamed for the deaths of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>.

            So, what was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s position on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>? Nobody knows. Although he was prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> during the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> (which has more than surface similarities
to the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>: It was a war against an ethnic minority seeking greater
autonomy, a war that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> could neither win nor negotiate its way out of for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bloody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> has yet to take a stand on it or on what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">republic</ENAMEX>'s relationship ought to be with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">federation</ENAMEX>. The agreement
that halted the war was negotiated by a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> who was not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> is remembered as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
presided over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s transition from a period of utter economic and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> desperation to one of relative stability. On the other hand, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy was on the brink
of collapse. The debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s premiership centers on whether his
policies of gradual reform helped postpone the breakdown or whether his chronic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inaction</ENAMEX> led to the stagnation that ultimately destroyed the economy. Either
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, throughout his tenure he avoided making decisions, instead deferring to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and playing different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> within his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
another.

            To the West, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who moved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> closer to the West and forged a friendship with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. It may be tempting to read in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s appointment a
message from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to the effect that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is finally
willing to behave as though loans were more important than a nationalist
foreign policy. But more likely the message was intended for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>, the confrontational, pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> who hopes to capitalize on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The night</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Allied Force</ENAMEX> began, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Primakov</ENAMEX>, en route to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for loan
negotiations, turned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> around in midair, losing the money but gaining
immense popularity at home. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> afterward, his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> and current
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> issued a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX>, anti-NATO line and decried claims of
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> atrocities as defamatory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s own public statements on the
conflict were not all that different, but now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> has arrived on
the scene, the rhetoric has become noticeably milder. In the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX>'s first
public statement on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, he ruled out the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
military involvement.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s previous appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, was another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s inspired and unexpected moves. Before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yegor Gaidar</ENAMEX>'s reformist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX>, he
had had the political profile of an apparatchik, which is to say, he didn't
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Born to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in the provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orsk</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> worked his way up through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> ranks. He was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Committee of the Communist Party</ENAMEX> and, briefly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of the oil
and gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, he lost a race for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>. He was mainly known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gaidar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for holding no views
and taking no actions, which meant he could be sold as the least of all evils
to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> in the bitter political crisis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1992</TIMEX>.

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> may seem awkward and indecisive, but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, he is said
to be ruthless. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>--the all-powerful and extremely wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>. As the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman of</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazprom</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>, he
presided over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s issuance of stock. His tax returns estimate the
worth of the stock he holds at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>, but other published reports place his
personal wealth at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX>. His position as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in charge of the
pipeline made him an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX> with post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX>, which
depend on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> for natural gas and generally have huge unpaid gas debts.
Though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> also exports gas to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, this fact seems unlikely to sway
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> any more than threats to cut off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s oil and electricity
have.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s most notorious trait is his
inarticulateness, which may stem from an ill-suppressed tendency to swear. His
bizarre pronouncements have been a source of endless joy to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. Here is what he had to say, for example, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> financial
crisis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX>: "There was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The state retained. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> began to
accumulate. Results began to be had." Speaking of his tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>,
he claimed, "If one considers what could have been done, and then what we did
do over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this long time</TIMEX>, one can conclude that something was done." Finally, his
best-known statement, which in its eloquent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ineloquence</ENAMEX> seemed to sum up
everything about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> politics, was, "We hoped for the best, but it turned
out as usual."

            In appointing the bland, seemingly slow-paced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is probably hoping that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>
will somehow pull off a settlement without really seeming to or without raising
too many hackles, and that his ultimate success will be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX>'s loss. But,
like many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s recent appointments, this one has the quality of being
surprising without being brilliant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> is not all that qualified to
succeed in his new mission, and he may not even be motivated to do so. He has
already announced that he plans to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> (the law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bans Yeltsin</ENAMEX> from taking part in that election, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX> is another likely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>). If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> succeeds in convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to accept enough
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s demands to guarantee some sort of deal, he will go down in domestic
political history as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who sold out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. If he's worried about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at home, what he should probably do is take advantage of his own personal
weaknesses, and stubbornly and laboriously fail.

         
      
   
