
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Fools</ENAMEX>

            You need to labor mightily to mess up A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midsummer Night's Dream</ENAMEX> , which is the only one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s
masterpieces to be virtually production-proof. It is the most magical of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom farces</ENAMEX>--the ur-bedroom farce, so vast in scope that a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> can't
contain it. Its boudoir is an entire forest, symbolizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> itself, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mortals</ENAMEX> and fairies, regals and bumpkins, make love and war, where passion
becomes arbitrary and paramours interchangeable; and its last act is a
riotously bungled tragedy-within-a-comedy (a celebratory performance by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">troupe</ENAMEX> of "rude mechanicals") that's an ironic comment on the trivial pursuits
that have preceded it.

            I've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midsummer</ENAMEX> in a dozen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX>--with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> at a drama <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, with high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Branagh</ENAMEX>, with contrapuntal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purcell</ENAMEX> airs and limpid
Mendelssohn strings, in settings romantic and anti-romantic--and it has never
come close to not working. Until now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hoffman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>" of the all-star movie called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midsummer Night's Dream</ENAMEX> (evidently to distinguish it from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>'s
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midsummer Night's Dream</ENAMEX> ), has wedged the play into a weirdly inapposite
setting, has stupidly cut and even more stupidly embellished it, and has
miscast it almost to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. And yet the damn thing works: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staggers</ENAMEX> through, mutilated but triumphant.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> set
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midsummer</ENAMEX> in an ancient, vaguely mythological <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> in which
intercourse between mortals and fairies is meant to be commonplace. Titania,
queen of the fairies, has already seduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theseus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, and the
struggle between her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oberon</ENAMEX>, for possession of an orphaned
changeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> has generated hurricanes, floods, and "contagious fogs." With
perverse anti-insight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> has updated the play to a sunny, atmospherically
untroubled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX> and has filled his frames
with scampering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> urchins and matrons kneading dough. The fairies that
swirl around these settings, first as Tinkerbell-ish balls of light and then as
conventional storybook sprites, belong to a different age and culture. (The
lines, mysteriously, continue to refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athenians</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman evidently</ENAMEX> thinks that he has chosen the last
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> in which a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Friel</ENAMEX>), could plausibly be
threatened with death for not obeying her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s command to marry his choice
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitors</ENAMEX>, in this case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demetrius</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Bale</ENAMEX>)--although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strathairn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theseus</ENAMEX> is such an apologetically lightweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> that the
threat seems incongruous. It doesn't help that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theseus</ENAMEX>' own erotic pas de deux
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hippolyta</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophie Marceau</ENAMEX>, divested of most of her lines along with her
Amazonian spirit) is less sexually charged than an average coffee
commercial.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> adds plenty of
meaningless cinematic bustle, then translates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s own set pieces
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soggily</ENAMEX>. The illicit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lysander</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominic West</ENAMEX>) flee "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>" on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bicycles</ENAMEX>, which are supposed to symbolize modern liberation. But once he gets
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> into the forest, where they're furiously pursued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demetrius</ENAMEX> and
his scorned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helena</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calista Flockhart</ENAMEX>), their nocturnal circlings
might as well be set in a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>--they're stage-bound. Nearly every piece of
comic business is campily extraneous to the text, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> are blithely
disregarded. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oberon</ENAMEX>'s famous barbed greeting "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ill met by moonlight</ENAMEX>, proud
Titania," makes little sense when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titania</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>) sits glowering
behind a curtain. Commanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oberon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Everett</ENAMEX>) to squeeze the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> of
an aphrodisiac flower into the eye of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Athenian</ENAMEX> garments," the impish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Tucci</ENAMEX>) falls on a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lysander</ENAMEX>. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weeds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> he doth
wear," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puck</ENAMEX>. Doth not!) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> uses nudity for laughs, to the point where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theseus</ENAMEX>' hunting party stumbles on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> in their birthday suits--a
discovery that would surely result in their arrest on the spot instead of the
genial interrogation provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>. For reasons only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>
understands, he has saddled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Bottom</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Kline</ENAMEX>), one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s
most delightfully shameless extroverts, with a nagging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and added bits in
which the braggart is poignantly humiliated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idiocy</ENAMEX>!

            I can't be sure what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX>'s languid, bare-chested Oberon
is up to--posing for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX> ad, maybe--and his relationship to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucci</ENAMEX>'s
jaded, aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frat-boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puck</ENAMEX> is that of a prissy gamekeeper to a wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chipmunk</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> comes off the worst. She can be a great movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>,
but a key to that greatness is how her dryly sardonic voice--with its edge of
neurotic insecurity--plays against her ethereal features and brings her down to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>. When she speaks Shakespearean verse, that nervy edge deserts her: She
makes her face a blank and pipes her lines arrhythmically, like a clueless
high-school thespian. Yes, she looks like a dream, with cascading blond curls
framing those exquisitely suspended cheekbones. But every time she opens her
mouth she becomes an airhead.

            The mortals fare better.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>, a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">able Brits</ENAMEX>, actually know how to speak verse,
although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bale</ENAMEX> is more at home in naturalistic parts. With her twiglike frame
and pinched features, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flockhart</ENAMEX> is a born <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermia</ENAMEX>. Cast as the discombobulated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helena</ENAMEX>, she does reasonably well: As she demonstrates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> on the dire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> , there's no one more adept at flinging herself into
mortifying situations with masochistic relish.

            Thank heaven for the rustics and for the final act, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">wedding-</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> performance of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The most Lamentable Comedy and most Cruel Death</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pyramus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thisby</ENAMEX>," which even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> can't completely screw up. At times,
he's in his element. He has devised a neat bit of business for the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>, whose speech about impersonating "the horned moon" is now a hasty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impromptu</ENAMEX>. The tongue-tied <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Irwin</ENAMEX> is so eloquent in his
inarticulateness that I never wanted him to leave the stage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Rees</ENAMEX>, under
a heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">barbershop</ENAMEX> mustache, is the sweetest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Quince</ENAMEX> imaginable--both
Bottom's biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and his most sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. And even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>'s
sentimental interpolations can't strangle the comic spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Kline</ENAMEX>. The
beauty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kline</ENAMEX>'s Bottom is its childlike straightforwardness and simplicity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kline</ENAMEX> understands that whatever happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottom</ENAMEX> remains essentially himself:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ass</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> makes him more serenely Bottom-like. His "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bottom's Dream</ENAMEX>" speech
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">joyous</ENAMEX> discovery of the dreamlike essence of life--a truth unglimpsed by
any of the play's other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. It's too bad that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> belabors the
point by giving Bottom a tender finale in which he stares moist-eyed into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moon</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> like that, you can almost see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ass</ENAMEX>'s head materialize on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
