
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica to Emigrate</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> war against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> ceased to lead the front pages of many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> were more interested in a mysterious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX>--definitely not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, said the police hastily--that injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brixton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South London</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> press was more
interested in the political machinations that led to the cancellation of a
planned referendum on electoral reform. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> press was more interested in
a crisis within an alliance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> press
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s own internal politics.

            Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadsheets</ENAMEX> stuck loyally with the nightmare in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, but the
angles were all different. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, apparently taking its cue from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had been
misled by intelligence reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "would buckle at the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> show of high-tech military might." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that "leaked documents"
included a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> assessment from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has no stomach
for a war he could not win. "After enough of a defense to sustain his honor and
assuage his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backers</ENAMEX>, he will quickly sue for peace," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> report was quoted
as saying.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> led with a startling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-column headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> must go, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>." The removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has not so far been
an official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> war aim, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claimed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have "changed tack." The basis for this assertion appeared a little
weak. It was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, speaking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> TV, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was "a
significant problem" and that it is "extremely difficult to contemplate"
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX> living in future under his rule. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> led,
rather surprisingly, with the ecological fallout from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refinery</ENAMEX>. "Poison cloud engulfs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s main
front-page headline over a warning of "an ecological disaster." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> ran the same story on an inside page, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss</ENAMEX>'
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful Blue Danube</ENAMEX>" has gone black.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a
prediction of a new wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> brutality against <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX>. Under
this was a photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>'s historic parliament <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reichstag</ENAMEX>,
which reopened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday 66 years</TIMEX> after the notorious fire that tightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s
grip on power. But the joyous reopening was marred by an acrimonious row over
its redesign by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Foster</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern</ENAMEX> magazine
complained that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> aesthetic with neon lights and metallic gray"
dominates the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>'s new interior, while <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt Sunday</ENAMEX> attacked
its "banality" and its "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">chilly</TIMEX>, almost antiseptic" atmosphere.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> was trying
to get diplomatic advantage from its acceptance of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 320,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> by demanding quick entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, overriding the usual
criteria for membership. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> dwelt on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s
anger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> for providing false evidence to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s media on the bombing of the refugee <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post of Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bliss</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX> wrote a searing condemnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war, predicting among other
things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would never again agree to lead future wars by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that does most of the fighting and pays most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> will from now on call the tune, looking to its own interests," he said.
"Whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will have a taste for the long haul in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>,
or will withdraw from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to protect its clearer national interests, hangs
in the balance."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Londoner</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> has protested
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Press Complaints Commission</ENAMEX> about media persecution, according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. In a formal complaint to the newspaper
industry's self-regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> (who has lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and calls himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>) listed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a dozen</NUMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that
have been camping on his doorstep or otherwise pestering him, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and
his east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> began. He told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCC</ENAMEX> that he wishes to "state categorically" that he is not related to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, has no links with any of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">republics</ENAMEX>, and does not want to discuss his views on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> with anyone.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCC</ENAMEX> said it would investigate.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> announced on its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is planning to
move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. Quoting "her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX>" Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McKellen</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar-</ENAMEX>nominated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said she was going to live there because the
press and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> are more sympathetic toward her in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. "She has
complained about constant harassment from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press which
characterises her as an overweight sex-crazed seductress," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
explained.

             

         
      
   
