
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe Goes Bananas</ENAMEX>

            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> government
involved in what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> called "the gravest
crisis in relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamberto Dini</ENAMEX> declared in an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the same
paper that "the alliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s loyalty to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> are
not in question." The same point was emphasized in an interview with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olviero Diliberto</ENAMEX>, who said that he would
nevertheless go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> "as soon as possible" to discuss with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> how to bring to justice those responsible for the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skiers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when a plane flown by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">U.S. Marine</ENAMEX> Capt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ashby</ENAMEX> sliced through cables carrying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gondola</ENAMEX> and sent it crashing to
the ground.

            National outrage over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashby</ENAMEX>'s acquittal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> on charges of involuntary manslaughter encouraged
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armando Cossutta</ENAMEX> to demand the removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> soil and generated an internal crisis within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s coalition
government, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> reported. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo D'Alema</ENAMEX> was
caught in cross-fire between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> loyalists, it
said.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> court decision provoked an outburst of
anti-American comment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> press that is without parallel in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Alema</ENAMEX> left for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> to meet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he was warned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ennio Caretto</ENAMEX> not
to be "too diplomatic" because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was guilty "almost of an act
of war in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>" and, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wanted the continued unconditional use
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, he must be told to stop "treating it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton-D'Alema</ENAMEX> talks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugenio Scalfari</ENAMEX>, the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Repubblica</ENAMEX> who is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> at the paper, was hardly less harsh. "Any
court that wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> would either have condemned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homicidal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> or would have shifted the focus of the trial onto the
responsibility of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>," he wrote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> "solemnly promised" by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> after the tragedy had been denied, he added, with "the
arrogant contempt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> shows toward satellite
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalfari</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> posturing, but
said that, given the transformation of the situation since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> victory in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, there was now an urgent need for a revision of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> "to construct
an international community in which there would no longer be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> but free and equal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>."

            The death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> was big front-page news in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, perhaps because he
lived there from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>, hermitlike in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country house</ENAMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, he was
generally saluted as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. Even more so in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera , a front-page comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tullio Kezich</ENAMEX>, headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shame</ENAMEX> on you,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>," complained that "this undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seventh Art</ENAMEX>" won only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>, and that only for the special effects in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> . In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> , in which his death was the main
front-page lead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Serra</ENAMEX> compared him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX>, but as a
fugitive from "another kind of fatwa, a typically Western one: condemnation to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX>, photographs and interviews, television and awards ceremonies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>; because he was, after all, the most famous and celebrated living
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the most important language of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>."

            The "banana war," another source of major tension
between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, rumbled on noisily in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press,
with the Financial Times leading its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a story
saying that, in retaliation for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s stance on the matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were threatening to renege on a treaty with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
fight drug trafficking. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caricom</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-member
regional trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, said at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were reconsidering
the drug control pact and would also not honour several economic treaties
because of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s decision to impose sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> imports," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said.

            The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in an editorial, headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> must not go <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>," that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 9 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> now came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 40</NUMEX>
percent from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiquita</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Del Monte</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. "Free trade has obvious benefits," it went on, "but the rules must take
into account the needs of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and the new world of multinational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>." Pointing out that "the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> complaint came within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> of
another big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiquita</ENAMEX> donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
Development that "trade disputes brought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> that have received
financial support from likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> should be null and void."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the looming crisis in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace process as a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>'s
failure to make even a token hand over of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to allow a new Ulster
executive to be formed. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Express</ENAMEX> reported that everything now depends on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> achieving a compromise between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unionist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> at a meeting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led its
front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> is to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, when they
meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>, to give formal support to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX> to
establish an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> without
parallel invitations to [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> are viewed
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> as an international affront to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election</TIMEX> period
and as encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s promised declaration of independence,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said.

            By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to begin an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> city book signing tour, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> seemed to have exhausted its interest in her. After massive
coverage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, her arrival was peremptorily reported, but interest will
doubtless build up during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening</ENAMEX>
Standard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, firebrand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Burchill</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a saint and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. "The sweet, sly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-pleasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> of all of
us who don't know whether to hit or hug, who gives herself in a heartbeat to
the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for all the right reasons," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burchill</ENAMEX> wrote. "Let's love her while
she's here, and be thankful that she never took that swallow dive off the roof,
for truly she has added to the gaiety of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> as no-one ever will
again."

             

         
      
   
