
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Talking
Black
            

            Is 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">racist</ENAMEX>, or is Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts Jr.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>) crazy? ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>") To paraphrase The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files</ENAMEX>, the
truth is somewhere in between there. To say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> would not have a
prominent role with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> if he were not black is not
necessarily racist. Rather, it demonstrates a rather remarkable journalistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sloppiness</ENAMEX> (employed, on occasion, by those on the right as well as on the
left) that permits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to look at a subject's basic physical traits and
ignore the many other attributes and characteristics that make the individual
worthy of being viewed, objectively, as a legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

            As a matter of full disclosure: I am
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-American</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, and I work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. I have
worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> on several projects. (The comments here, however, are
solely my own and do not necessarily reflect either <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>' viewpoint or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>'s.)

            It strikes this conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> as
bordering on liberal racism for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> to ask, as he does in this
response to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> would have been chosen to
give the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s election and to speak at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Convention</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> if he had been white and to assert that
"there's nothing racist about arguing that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>--whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>--has benefited from a desire for
diversity." The implicit insinuation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> has been given a "pass" on
that defectiveness because of the color of his skin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> doesn't find
anything even possibly racist--or at the very least, paternalistic--in
that argument?

            First, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> himself admits, the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'94</NUMEX>
was a very vocal, visible, and aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. To demonstrate how important
they were to the "revolutionary" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> change that was happening, many
were given rather attractive leadership positions not usually afforded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>) both came out of this class.
It's not too surprising that they would each assume prominent roles as public
faces of the insurgent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. They are both photogenic, both athletic, both
conservative. The post-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX> election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> results demonstrated that
a sizable percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> were ready to elevate him into a
leadership role, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>. Now, does <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> gain a slight edge because
he is black? Perhaps, but recall that the media immediately gravitated toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>, partly because he was the lone black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> in the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'94</NUMEX>. It
seems rather ironic for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> to assert that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are playing
affirmative action politics by promoting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>, when part of that promotion is
a reflection of how much the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have already elevated him as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity-politician</ENAMEX> by gravitating toward him. What came <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it is not simply a matter of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">melanin</ENAMEX>. Otherwise, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Franks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>), who was elected to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> (and served with him in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'95</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX>), would have
received the same attention and promotion from the media and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. The
different treatment afforded those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> indicates that, though both are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-American</ENAMEX>, they are substantively different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--physically,
politically, and oratorically. The media know a good story when they see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> is, simply, a better individual story than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Franks</ENAMEX>. Given
this distinction between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who are the same, isn't it presumptuous of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> to proclaim that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> has the role he does just because he is
black?

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> was chosen to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> response in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> for the same reason that he had a prominent
role at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National Convention</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> gives
a damn good speech. In fact, of all the speeches at the convention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>' was almost universally cited as one of the more memorable--up there with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>'s and (for poignancy) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>'s. Even a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>
said recently on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, "We are fortunate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C.</ENAMEX> is not [running for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>], because he is a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> and, unlike many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>,
doesn't terrify the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>." Putting aside the obvious partisan gloss
in the statement, it still clearly explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> has managed to take (or
been placed in) a leadership role within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>: He articulates a
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> agenda in a style that is straightforward, uplifting,
and non-judgmental.

            Finally, it is virtually impossible to figure out
exactly what a "white" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> would look like. It is almost as impossible
as imagining that a "white" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> would become <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> is a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>; a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>; a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (despite admitted mistakes as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teen-ager</ENAMEX>); and countless other things that have all served to mold him into a
specific unique <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Slate
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> are likely not
racist. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> is most assuredly not crazy for being
offended by some of the implications of the original "" article. Thus, I would
think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> might be waiting a while for an "apology." In the meantime,
he might think about drafting one of his own.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalitions</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Prize
Fight
            

            One thing you didn't
mention in your dead-on is that, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time to my knowledge, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> decided commentary on the biggest story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> was more
worthy of a prize than anyone's reporting on the story. Perhaps the only
adequate response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> was cynicism and pointed barbs, but you would
think a story resulting in the impeachment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would have had some
reporting worthy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s notice.

            
               --J.J.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sutherland</ENAMEX>
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>

            
               Pleading Not
Guilty
            

            I must take issue with a
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelms</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overnight Transportation Company</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wrote:

            
               As presented in the fact sheet, this is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic</ENAMEX> case of special pleading disguised as a violation of civil rights. Even
assuming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> was a double-crossing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jerk</ENAMEX> who hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, what is he
(or she) really guilty of? Failing to cut some slack!
            

            Although this paragraph is
correct as far as it goes, you make it sound like "special pleading" is a bad
thing.

            All civil rights legislation (to one way of
thinking, all legislation, period) is the result of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> successfully
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convincing Congress</ENAMEX> that its interests are more important than the freedom of
others. (This sounds more cynical than it is; one way to so convince <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
is to speak to their sense of justice as well as to their pocketbook.) An
illustration: In most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, if I were your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> I could fire you just
because I don't like you, even though there's no good reason for my dislike.
However, if I also have a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who I dislike merely because she's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, I can't fire her. In this way, current civil rights legislation requires
that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) my freedom is impaired; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) I am required to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and women
differently.

            Take a look at the
Family and Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Leave Act</ENAMEX>. Suppose again that I'm your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> and that,
due to an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, you have to take off work for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly three months</TIMEX>. If I'm
smart, I'll want to get someone else to write <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX> (which
is legal). But what if, in order to lure someone as perspicacious as you away
from her current, stable job, I have to promise to give her the gig
permanently? (Which is complicated, but basically illegal.) In this case,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has decided that your interests as an ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should trump my
interest in keeping an important feature of 
                  Slate
               
available to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and the interests of your putative replacement in
getting a long-term job with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. I agree with you that the proposed
parent-friendly legislation is a bad idea, but not because it involves special
pleading. I'm against it because, unlike the special pleading which resulted in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FMLA</ENAMEX>, the rights that are being specially pled for
are not worth the cost in freedom they will engender.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>
Pascover
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
