
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humble Pie</ENAMEX>

            As all
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> heaved a sigh of relief over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peace deal, a feast of humble
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pie</ENAMEX> was consumed in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Street</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> grudgingly
admitted that air power alone seems to have done the trick. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , the
Times , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> , which all spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war</TIMEX> urging a land invasion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, were disconcerted by the fact that a peace settlement has apparently
been achieved without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. "We take no comfort in saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing,
in crude terms, 'worked,' " said the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> in an editorial
that honorably recalled its previous insistence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> could
not be "bombed to the negotiating table." The settlement was "a victory for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and a vindication of its belief in modern air power," said the
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> --but the paper qualified this with a claim
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> only capitulated because of "the growing willingness of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX> to consider the deployment of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Independent</ENAMEX> said that "victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should also put an end to the
thoughtless assertion that 'wars cannot be won from the air.' " Thoughtless
assertion or not, this is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> had been saying all
along. Or had it? "This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> consistently called for the deployment of
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to be threatened--and to make the threat credible, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> would
have had to be prepared to go through with it," it said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. So it never
really wanted a ground invasion--just a credible threat of one! The
Times , which had been just as eager as the other broadsheets to send in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, sought to preserve its dignity by avoiding the issue altogether. In
an editorial urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> to remain wary, it said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should not suspend
its air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> "is in compliance with all its commitments" and
warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the international peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> was "a
potential bear trap." It said, "A 'unified control and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">command</ENAMEX>' should not
become cover for a semi-detached <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military presence that could permit
the creeping partition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabloid Sun</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' down-market stablemate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, has the advantage of having always campaigned against the
commitment of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and so headlined its editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> might WAS right" as vindication of its stance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , which is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s biggest-circulation paper, may have been heading for a confrontation
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> on this issue, but the peace agreement
ended any danger of that. Instead, the paper presented the deal as a personal
triumph for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, who, it said, stiffened the backbones of "wobbling alliance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>" such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s evil ambitions caused the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis," it went on. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s resolve has played the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of
ensuring he has not been allowed to succeed."

            In a
report from its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> correspondent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> said
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> agreement, if it sticks, will be a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> over
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s war, dismissed as a 'coward's war' and ridiculed
as 'immaculate coercion,' will be vindicated," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Dejevsky</ENAMEX> wrote. "His
insistence that the conflict be conducted from the air and only from the air,
and that an air war was winnable, was denounced in military circles, ever more
openly, as the irresponsible reverie of a non-military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that an international banking deal between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX> is "almost certain to unravel" following an
attack by the televangelist on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> homosexuality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Executive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Burt</ENAMEX> flew to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to confront
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> for saying on his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> TV program The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">700 Club</ENAMEX> that "in
Scotland you can't believe how strong the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> are. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>] could
go right back to the darkness very easily." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>, who claims his family
emigrated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1695</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> was founded), made a
deal with it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX> to start a telephone banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. The announcement sparked a storm of controversy over his reputed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bigotry</ENAMEX>, however, and scores of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade unions</ENAMEX>, threatened to take their business elsewhere. In a "right of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">reply"</ENAMEX> column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> wrote:
"I abhor bigots and bigotry. I denounce racists and racism. ... Discrimination
in whatever form or guise has no part in my beliefs or my life."

            The FT also
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> almost doubled last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and is expected to achieve overall household penetration of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this year</TIMEX>. A forecast due to be published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dataquest</ENAMEX>, a
market research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is beginning to close the
"technology gap" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

         
      
   
