
   
   
      
         
            <STRONG><EM>Slate </EM></STRONG><EM><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mea Culpas</ENAMEX></EM>

            
               The Shearered
Truth
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> who might enjoy parsing all the careless
errors in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX>'s silly about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cody Shearer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Matthews</ENAMEX> should stop
right here, and use your very thoughtful link to my current <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>
column. It's a longish list, I'm afraid, but most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>'s mistakes should be
obvious to anyone who can read. Just to correct the record in

                  Slate
               , here they are:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> writes: "On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8 last year</TIMEX>, shortly after
she had testified in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> reportedly had a frightening
encounter with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jogger</ENAMEX> near her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>" Fact: As I mentioned,
the alleged incident on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> testified
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case. Otherwise, what was the point of "intimidating" her?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> writes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> seemed to have a pretty
good idea who [the mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jogger</ENAMEX>] was--an idea that he got from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> ." Fact: As I noted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> picked up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jogger</ENAMEX>'s supposed identity from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> broadcast in an item posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following day</TIMEX> . That's why the column was primarily about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> writes: "The next night, chatting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Ireland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews</ENAMEX>
was less coy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> in question, he declared, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX>'s twin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cody</ENAMEX>." Fact: As I wrote, quoting the transcript of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews</ENAMEX>
identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Shearer</ENAMEX> by name <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> appeared . There are
many words to describe the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> behaved. "Coy" is not among them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> writes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> could not have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
stalker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conason</ENAMEX> declared, because he was on a transcontinental flight last
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jan. 8</ENAMEX>--a flight on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> happened to bump into his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s
"declared" was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> has documents proving he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8</TIMEX>--and that he sat next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> on a flight back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 11</TIMEX>. This mistake is a little worse than what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> did. He
had to make a phone call to get the facts. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> had to do was read
them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> writes: "According to a recent Drudge
posting, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a gun was arrested outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews' Willey</ENAMEX> segment aired." Fact: (This is exhausting) Many news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>, reported the appearance of a gun-waving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, not just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>. Those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> also made it clear that the gun nut
wasn't arrested outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, but in fact arranged voluntary
surrender to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days later</TIMEX>.

            As for my failure to
"explain" why nutty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are nuts--and why they weave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> family
conspiracies around an event that may or may not really have occurred--that is
beyond my competence. Sort of like journalism (or even reading) is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. O.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>.

            Best
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Conason</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX> replies:
                
               I thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Conason</ENAMEX> for
pointing out my errors, and I apologize to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>
                  late for my carelessness. The article as now published
reflects the corrections.
            

            

               Ticketmaster
            

            I found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s "" somewhat puzzling. First,
why would allowing the interplay of free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX>,
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, and other mass entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> would become dominated by
wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>? More specifically, why would letting the price of tickets rise
to the market clearing-level necessarily "lock out" the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>? This is an
assumption about demand. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> appears to be saying is that demand for a
given commodity will become more inelastic as one's income or wealth increases.
This is odd because it collapses the distinction between willingness to pay and
ability to pay. Just because someone can afford to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120</NUMEX> for an advanced
showing of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">game</ENAMEX> doesn't mean
he will. Why, then, conclude domination by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, even if we allow for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s assumptions
and his conclusions, it would still imply that those who pay more must also be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rabid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. Is it true that wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are bigger sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonwealthy</ENAMEX>? If not, stadium seating will always be accessible to the average
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, even if we accept the conclusions, they
don't apply to all mass entertainment venues. A particular sporting event can
be unique. Seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> do a slam-dunk right in front of your eyes
because you have courtside seats can be a singular experience. A movie, on the
other hand, is the same everywhere. Why, then, would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lucas</ENAMEX> be concerned
about alienating <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> by allowing some advanced showings at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">premium</ENAMEX> prices? The movie can air for as long as it keeps packing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>.
How is accessibility reduced?

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, money is a very flexible tool. It is
possible to shift our disposable income to any number of items. Why couldn't an
average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120</NUMEX> or so to see an advanced showing of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menace</ENAMEX> and simply forgo doing something else he obviously valued less?
Charging below market prices to make tickets "affordable" does not appear to
make any sense.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Becker</ENAMEX>'s argument
is the only one that appears to make any sense. If the value of mass
entertainment is in the social experience, then guaranteeing that the venue be
packed by charging below market prices is a rational policy. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and
clubs live and die by this principle, often giving the impression of being
"packed" by letting a long line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in at a slower rate than they
otherwise could. The strongest example of this is probably <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wrigley Field</ENAMEX>. It's
been argued that the stadium contributes enormously to the baseball experience,
which is why the place is packed even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX> have a bad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Pokorni</ENAMEX>
            

            
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Chicago</TIMEX>

            
               Defense
Defense
            

            "How exactly is it that in the land of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">childproof</ENAMEX> cap it's legal and even customary to keep a loaded unlocked gun in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?" asks the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14</TIMEX> "," citing an experiment suggesting that
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (especially ones aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 to 7</TIMEX>) will play with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> even when told
not to. Let me suggest a possible answer.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. It turns out that there are very few fatal
firearms accidents involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. This may be surprising, given that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> households own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, but it's so. According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Safety Council</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accident Facts</ENAMEX> , there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 30</NUMEX>
fatal gun deaths in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 4 to 7</TIMEX>. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> such deaths among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">kids 0</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 to 14</TIMEX>. This tells us about the age of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> , not of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>, but it's the best rough proxy I've seen in
my professional readings (I teach a seminar on firearms regulation at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA Law</ENAMEX>
School).

            To put that risk in some perspective, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 500</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 0 to 4</TIMEX> drown <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> in residential swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>, which are legal
and even customary to keep around one's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>; that's twice as many as the
fatal gun accidents for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 0 to 14</TIMEX>, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> are much less
common than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. (I know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fence their swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>, but some
don't--just like some keep their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> locked and others don't.) More generally,
the total number of fatal accidents involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0 to 14 that year</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,500</NUMEX>,
so fatal firearms accidents accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> of the total. There
were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,400</NUMEX> fatal firearms accidents involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of all ages, out of
a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93,300</NUMEX> fatal accidents from all causes.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. But doesn't it make sense to require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to
keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> locked or unloaded even if it'll save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life?
Unfortunately, the analysis can't be that simple, because such a restriction
will not only save lives, but also cost lives.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> are used quite commonly in self-defense;
estimates range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">110,000</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Crime Victimization Study</ENAMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> defensive gun uses (studies by largely pro-gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criminologist Gary Kleck</ENAMEX> and by largely anti-gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Cook</ENAMEX>).
Nobody knows what the exact count is, and how many of these uses involve saved
lives, or saved lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Nor does anyone know how many of these uses
would have been frustrated by having to fumble with unlocking the gun, often in
the dark, when one has just been waked up by an intruder breaking into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">house.</ENAMEX> It is at least possible, though, that this number of lost lifesaving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-defense</ENAMEX> uses would be greater than the number of fatal accidents
caused by having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> loaded and unlocked. Not certain, but possible.
Certainly the answer isn't certain in the other direction.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. So, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> answer to the
question "Why would a reasonable gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> believe that it should be legal and
customary to keep a loaded unlocked gun in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?" (not quite
the question <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> asked, but the only one I'm remotely qualified to
try to answer) is: "Because loaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">unlocked guns</ENAMEX> can save <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lives as
well as take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lives, and reasonable gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>--especially ones who
live in dangerous parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>--may be acting very rationally in keeping their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns maximally</ENAMEX> ready for self-defense, despite the modest risks this may
impose."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Volokh</ENAMEX>
            

            Acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA Law</ENAMEX>
School

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future Is</ENAMEX>
Now
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> writes in "": "And when they
(e-books) truly arrive, I predict that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket</ENAMEX> will be remembered as a
landmark: the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> demonstration that reading a 'book' didn't require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>,
ink, or even an overhead light."

            For the sake of
historical accuracy I hope that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket</ENAMEX> will not be so remembered. Some of
us have been reading 
                  Slate
                and other fine reading material on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">john</ENAMEX> (and wherever) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> now using our palmtop computers. I use my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psion Siena</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3C</TIMEX>. I won't bore you with the details, but it's really quite
easy to download books and other reading <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> into a palmtop computer.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>

            
               Flighty
Argument
            

            In , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> asks, "Why shouldn't big people
(not just 'fat' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>) pay more for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> tickets? After all, moving them
through the air takes more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>. Why should this argument make sense for
postage but be abandoned for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?"

            Taken to the extreme, should small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay less?
Should small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be charged more for heat since they generate <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less</NUMEX> of their
own? Should smarter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay more for school since they remember more? Should
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be charged more in taxes since they require more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>? Should city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay more in income taxes since they have more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>? How do you suggest this is administered?

            Ticket prices are based
on the bell-shaped curve that describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. This gives the average
height and weight. These "outliers" are already accounted for. Congratulations,
however: You are well on your way to being a true libertarian.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Donahue</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
