
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pronouns</ENAMEX> and Transsexuality

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Here is an odd one
for you. I am a transsexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (postoperative, many facial surgeries, voice
surgery). I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX>. Most of the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have no idea,
but in the work environment, everyone eventually knows. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are fine
with it, but a few (always <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>) choose to act out in spectacularly
inappropriate ways. The worst is in meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> where a male manager
will refer to me repeatedly as "he." This, of course, makes no sense to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, who has no idea why the professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> across the table is being
referred to as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Things I have tried include taking the offender aside to
ask that he use my given name (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jess</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica</ENAMEX>, as he wishes) instead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pronouns</ENAMEX>. If we're not in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> meeting and I have the clout, I sometimes
take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> down on the spot--in the nicest way I can. Any cool suggestions
or ideas?
            

            

               --Jess
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Madame</ENAMEX>,

            If anyone has earned the
right to the feminine title, it is you. Prudie offers the following ideas to
eliminate the insensitive hostility: You could send a memo, in-house, stating
that if the pronoun problem persists, you will take your gussied-up self, along
with your skills, to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. If it is a practical impossibility to leave,
you might consider going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX> and registering a formal
complaint. If you have the figurative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> for it, you might respond to the
digs made in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with a remark such as, "You have to make
allowances for (so-and-so). <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> can be so confusing."
In other words, throw the discomfort on the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>" will not
know what to make of the byplay, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> guesses the needler will clam up.
Maybe with the head-on sparring you can train these jerks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, supportively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My 24-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">girlfriend</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>, also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> has lived in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apartment</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 br/1</NUMEX> bath) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX>. He is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gainfully</ENAMEX> employed (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Price</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waterhouse</ENAMEX>), and pays no rent. Not a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>, not a thank-you. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> is: He is my BF and stays in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. How do you collect rent due? And
how much?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concerned</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Con</ENAMEX>,

            Who wants to know? You
have no standing in this deal. If , however, you have been deputized to
ask on behalf of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GF</ENAMEX>, she's in a bit of a bind, unless the lease stipulates
how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may occupy the flat. Her only hope, if she is unhappy with the
perpetual houseguest, is to advise the (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">threesome</ENAMEX> is not a comfortable arrangement for her, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) the guest is a de
facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> and should share the expenses--to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX>. She
might also consider moving.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, practically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am a Ph.D.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> who does consulting at a local psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. While most of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> there call me Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, there are some who call me by my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name.
I wouldn't mind this so much in private, but it's not good in front of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Much of my work is with severely disturbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and requires that I
testify in court to request civil commitment. For reasons of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ego</ENAMEX> and
personal safety, I would prefer to be called by my title, particularly in front
of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. I can't think of a way to request this without seeming overly
impressed with myself and my degrees. Keep in mind that none of them would ever
call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> by their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names. How do I request this politely and
without appearing to be a snob?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>
yours,
            

            

               Stymied
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Sty</ENAMEX>,

            You request it in a memo
and with an explanation. It is quite likely that those calling you "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe"</ENAMEX> are
unaware of your reasons for wishing to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not grasp,
however, how use of your last name provides greater safety than your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. It
is the last name, after all, that is listed in a phone book. Perhaps your
concern is that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are hearing both names used?) In any case,
good luck. It should not be too difficult to get things your way.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, honorifically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is being
married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> is not invited, because she is my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s. I did not feel it was appropriate to invite her, due to
the limitations placed on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> with respect to the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> invited. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have been very much a part of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s
life are livid that I did not insist on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> being invited. I feel any
pressure I can take off these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is in their best interest. What do you
think? Also, I wondered, when having a wedding shower, if it's appropriate to
invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are out of state and obviously aren't going to come to a
shower. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> say it's fine; I feel it's soliciting a gift. I'd be
interested in your feedback.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Wan</ENAMEX>,

            As to the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yours</ENAMEX> who doesn't
particularly have any relationship with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> understands the
constraints when putting on a wedding. But she also thinks there's got
to be a way to squeeze in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> more. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> in mind that all those invited
surely will not come. And of course both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>'s and groom's side can keep
expanding the "just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more" ploy, but if it's really just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks it is doable. If you are close to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, she ought to be
there. As for the shower invitations to out-of-state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees
with you that such invitations are really invoices.

            Though the happy day is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some months</TIMEX> away, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> sends best wishes and congratulations to the young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> and tranquil thoughts to both sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
matrimonially

         
      
   
