
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soft-Core Tai Chi</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Entrapment
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). A few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> like this old-fashioned heist flick starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX> despite its unoriginality: "It works because it is made stylishly,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX> are enormously attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, and because of
the romantic tension between them" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ).
A slew of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> finds the whole thing a bit off: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connery</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>, and the highlight of the film is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>' spandex-clad
"demi-soft-core tai chi" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ) as
she attempts to evade an optical security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in the process of ripping off
a priceless gold mask. 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> says
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Entrapment</ENAMEX> is an A-list production, but despite ... a bevy of
state-of-the-art sensors, cybergizmos, and digital readouts, it can't manage to
brush off its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-movie</ENAMEX> cobwebs." (Read the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review .)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslow Boy</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>
directs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-</ENAMEX>rated family drama, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rattigan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX> play about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">schoolboy</ENAMEX> accused of petty theft and the legal battle that blossoms in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accusation</ENAMEX>'s wake. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX>'s departure from his trademark profane
and sharp-edged films, but the reviews have a dutiful air about them: "a
pointed examination of the price of seeking justice" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) ... a "handsome, stately adaptation" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the consensus view by

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beat by beat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX> turns
out an immaculately staged, crisply paced, and elegantly acted movie. It's also
a tad bloodless, but you can't have everything.")

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>).
Though the premiere is still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> away, hype for the Star Wars
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prequel</ENAMEX> is at full throttle. The soundtrack has been released, tie-in toys have
gone on sale (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> showed up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAO Schwarz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> store on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of Web sites have cropped up, and lines have formed
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. The backlash has also arrived: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> complains in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "When a film becomes the nexus of such a complex
marketing juggernaut, inevitable consequences include weariness and even déjà
vu. Nobody on this planet will be able to approach the Star Wars
prequel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> , with a sense of discovery. So much commerce
rides on this product, so much advance flogging has been necessary, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s own innate appeal is compromised." (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two well</NUMEX>-maintained fan sites,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>.net and
Countdown to
Star Wars , present detailed information on the film as well as
photos and news on upcoming commercials. The film's official site offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX>
and an online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Like a Secret</ENAMEX>
               , by Built to Spill (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bros.</ENAMEX>). Excellent reviews for the latest album from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>-based indie rock
band. Reviewers praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> and lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guitarist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Martsch</ENAMEX> as the locus of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s appeal: His "particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> ... is the vivid tension he generates
between earnest romanticism and howling discord" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Fricke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> ). Reviews compare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s sound with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> as diverse as
Wire, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hüsker Dü</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Reed</ENAMEX>, and several mark the similarity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martsch</ENAMEX>'s
voice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Young</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Fusilli</ENAMEX> writes that
it's "the kind of disk you replay when it rolls to a close, just to delight in
all that cleverness once again." (For more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, check out this site, which has
photographs, lyrics, and a list of tour dates.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olive Tree</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas L. Friedman</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Early</ENAMEX> reviews lavished praise on the New York
Times "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>'s study of globalization: "The author
uses his skills as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> to conduct a breathtaking tour, one
that possesses the exhilarating qualities of flight and the stomach-hollowing
ones of free fall" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Recent reviews
have been considerably cooler. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gripes: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s belief in global economics
and American-style capitalism's ability to solve the world's ills reads more
like cheerleading than analysis: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>]nly a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> could write a book so relentlessly upbeat about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>'s
prospects in an ever more tightly integrated world without being accused of
unsophisticated boosterism" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David J. Lynch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Some of his
theories have already been disproved: His "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Golden Arches</ENAMEX>" theory of
international relations held that no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that both had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>
have ever gone to war. This "was proved false even before his book's
publication date by the war between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> (where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> were promptly vandalized)." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>,

                  Slate
               ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> is blind to the negative aspects of a world
dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: "The lack of skepticism toward
business--the tendency to adopt its view of the world--has had a deeper effect
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> than just causing him on occasion to strike a tonally false note,"
writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , because "in the era of
globalization business can constrict freedom and innovation just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
did during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s review in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Movie
            

            

               
                  Idle Hands
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). Another campy teen
horror flick. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shocker</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say it's trite and unoriginal (it follows a boy
with a demonically possessed hand). It's also "undeniably kinetic," and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman Flender</ENAMEX> (yet another WB alum) manages to generate "watchable
levels of splatter-happy delirium" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ).

            

               Offspring
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bechet Dumaine Allen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Soon-Yi Previn</ENAMEX> are in
possession of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bechet Dumaine Allen</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are dying to know:
Is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-month</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> adopted or not? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Previn</ENAMEX> "didn't appear pregnant in
recent photos" (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shauna Snow</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). The name comes from
legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soprano saxophonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Bechet</ENAMEX>. 

         
      
   
