
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Time To Clear</ENAMEX> out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurotrash&quot</ENAMEX>;

            The mass resignation early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> of all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX>--universally
characterized as the most serious institutional crisis in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 42-year</TIMEX> history
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> community--dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> is responsible for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> affairs of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> and enforces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> law. An investigation into charges of
fraud, corruption, and cronyism found evidence of incompetence, mismanagement,
and loss of political control. Although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Cresson</ENAMEX>, was singled out for particularly strong criticism,
commission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Santer</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> chose "by unanimity to resign
collectively."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Soir</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> supported the
dramatic gesture of unity since "it is too late for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-measures or for soft,
evasive answers" and claimed the resignations were needed because the
commission "suffers from a democracy deficit and therefore a lack of
legitimacy. ... To counterbalance this [it] has to be perfect, spotless." In
contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro-skeptic Times of London</ENAMEX> speculated that the collective action might,
in fact, represent a further avoidance of individual responsibility, and
worried about the possible "renomination" of the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> (an idea
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">floated by Santer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>): "This supposedly cathartic drama could end up as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Japanese</ENAMEX>' purge, in which heads roll only to ensure that things continue much
as before, with much the same discredited cast. That would be an outrage."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s Le Monde
                saw a silver lining in the crisis and
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> had to seize this opportunity to
"clean up its administrative and financial habits, improve its decision-making
process and, most of all, rediscover the inspiration and drive it has lost.
This might even mean increasing its funding and staffing levels." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> pointed out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s problems were partly caused by
the expansion of its responsibilities as it "found itself taking on ever more
grandiose tasks, largely on the demand of member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, with progressively
more limited resources. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s report shows they did not know how to
cope."

            Meanwhile, there is no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> in sight. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> want to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santer</ENAMEX> as soon as
possible, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> would prefer him to remain as a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX>" until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31, 1999</TIMEX>--the end of his term. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> made its
position clear in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>: "It is time to clear out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurotrash</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s reopening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, after a week
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">government-ordered</TIMEX> closure, put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, as depositors
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">queued</ENAMEX> to withdraw their funds and striking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>
blocked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> to protest a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">165 percent</NUMEX> increase in the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quito</ENAMEX> faced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its third day</TIMEX> of roadblocks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diario Hoy</ENAMEX> reported
that the capital was in a state of paralysis with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> closed and provisions
in short supply. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telégrafo of Guayaquil</ENAMEX> blamed the uncertainty gripping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>'
failure to discuss possible solutions to the crisis. "There has to be an
opening and communication on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. If it wants to achieve a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> accord, it's logical that it must display an openness to
reconciliation."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">state-run China</ENAMEX>
Daily pooh-poohed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> media reports about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> nuclear espionage at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claimed, "The 'lab-theft' story is
bound to follow in the footsteps of the 'political donations' and 'satellite
secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leakage</ENAMEX>' reports--to be forgotten within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> after the claims
cannot be substantiated."

            
A story in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun of Japan</ENAMEX> revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aum Shinrikyo</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> that attacked
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarin</ENAMEX> nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, is enjoying a resurgence based
in part on the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">security</ENAMEX> provided by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of successful computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>' prosperity
stems from their cheap prices, which are possible because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> work for
next to nothing. A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> that
"Aum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> work there, and the job is considered part of religious
training. Their salaries are therefore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>." A "public security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>"
quoted by the paper speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aum</ENAMEX> will "grow into a stronger and bigger
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> with ironclad solidarity" when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fumihiro Joyu</ENAMEX>, a senior cult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, is released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.

             

         
      
   
