
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS Capitalism</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writers</ENAMEX> have long sought
metaphors to capture the conflict of new and old worlds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Adams</ENAMEX> posited an
antithesis between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamo</ENAMEX> and the Virgin--the mysterious electrical
generators he saw at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Exhibition of 1900</ENAMEX> and the religious devotion
that built <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chartres Cathedral</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> saw the new technological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century ago</TIMEX> as awe-inspiring, destructive, and almost beyond comprehension. His
opposition has been revised many times since. Recently, for instance, the
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Barber</ENAMEX> described the contest as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jihad</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McWorld</ENAMEX>." As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> may gather from his terms, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barber</ENAMEX> is hardly enamored of either
globalism or tribalism, the modernizing principle or the medievalizing one.
Both, in his view, undermine the viability of participatory democracy.

            The newest entrant in
this contest of symbols is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas L. Friedman</ENAMEX>, the foreign affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , who offers a somewhat sunnier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> in his new book,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olive Tree</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX>, a luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> made mostly by
robots in a state-of-the-art <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>, stands for progress--"all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anonymous</ENAMEX>, transnational, homogenizing, standardizing market forces and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> that make up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s globalizing economic system," as he puts it.
The olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, which grows in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> was stationed
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , stands for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalism</ENAMEX>, religion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>, community--gnarled, rooted things that cling to
the soil. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> believes that the clash between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> principles defines
the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> era in international relations. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> and olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>
[are] wrestling with each other in the new system of globalization," as he puts
it, energetically compounding his metaphor.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> himself--he lets it be known that
he drives one of these sublime <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedans</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> where he
lives, when he's not trading Internet stocks on the Internet, communicating
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> by cell phone, or eating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX> in some far-flung capital. He
avers that he respects olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and aspires to preserve as many as possible
but that there's no stopping, or even slowing, technological advancement,
market integration, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cultural hegemony.

            His point of view is that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davos World Economic Forum</ENAMEX>. Capital
now moves swiftly and freely around the globe--a phenomenon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> calls, in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his catchier coinages, an "electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX>." Because this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX> can
stampede at will, if not at whim, developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, now known as "emerging
markets," no longer have much discretion about which economic policies to
pursue. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> lacks a capitalist-friendly financial structure with a
convertible currency, "transparency" of information, and protections for
private property, First World investment money will simply go elsewhere. As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, you can choose to conform to international economic norms
or you can choose to be poor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> makes this point various ways, saying
it, quoting others saying it, and quoting himself saying it to others. He calls
this dilemma "the golden straightjacket."

            But rather than consider
whether we should be altogether pleased that the entire world seems to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">converging</ENAMEX> upon the same economic model, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> simply declares it a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonissue</ENAMEX>. The integrated world market is coming, no one can do anything about
it, so the question of how we like it is irrelevant. You might call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s
foreign policy market realism. Capitalism, not liberal democracy, emerged
triumphant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. And though a free economy tends to open up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> over time, growth and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> aren't necessarily connected in the
short term. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s way of thinking, the question of whether a government
has elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> or respects human rights has far less effect on its
immediate prosperity than the question of whether it listens to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, which have something resembling
free elections, are stagnating because they refuse to liberalize their
economies. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, which has a thriving capitalist economy but doesn't have free
elections, survived the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis largely unscathed.

            The problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s book is not that he's wrong
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> economics or international relations. I think he's largely right, though
as I'll argue in a minute, he overstates the ease with which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> and the
olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> can happily coexist. The problem is that he has distilled the
conventional wisdom of the enlightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> without adding much
thinking of his own. Financial metaphors running away with him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>
describes his journalistic method as "information arbitrage." He sees himself
acquiring knowledge at wholesale from the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>, hedge fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>,
and central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> to whom his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> column grants him access, and
selling at retail to general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. Reporting on things seen and heard while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX>-trotting, with a bit of opinion thrown in, works well in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biweekly Times</ENAMEX> column, but a book needs to do more than endorse the
wisdom of others--especially if the wisdom is as familiar and widely accepted
as that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hormats</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Summers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> agrees with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> is no excuse for
neglecting challenges from such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Sachs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Krugman, or the aforementioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barber</ENAMEX>, none of whose views he considers.

            A subsidiary fault is
rhetorical hyperventilation. The less <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frieidman</ENAMEX> has to say of his own, the more
he relies on slogans and strained neologisms. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Countries</ENAMEX>, he tells us, have
economic operating systems of different degrees of sophistication, which he
dubs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DOScaptial 1.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>, etc. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globalution</ENAMEX>" is the way the "electronic herd"
creates pressure for democracy. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glocalism</ENAMEX>" is a culture's ability to profit
from what's good about other cultures without soaking up what's bad. Backward
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> suffer from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Microchip Immune Deficiency"</ENAMEX> or MIDS. At
times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> manages to sound like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> at a rally. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> can destroy you by dropping bombs and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supermarkets</ENAMEX> can destroy you
by downgrading your bonds," he writes.

            This penchant for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toffleresque</ENAMEX> gimmickry finally gets the
better of him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Golden Arches Theory of Conflict</ENAMEX>
Prevention." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s "insight," as he calls it, is that "no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
that both had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> had fought a war against each other since each got its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>." A variation on the theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX> don't go to war with
each other, the golden arches hypothesis was proved false even before his
book's publication date by the war between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> (where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> were promptly vandalized). An ethnic and territorial
conflict that doesn't have much to do with globalization at all, the war in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> defies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s notion that international relations is now an
extension of international economics.

            As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelist</ENAMEX> for globalization, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> is
intent on demonstrating that it's compatible with a respect for identity and
tradition, that olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> can grow next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexi</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> instincts
tell him that any difficult choice must be a false choice. His happy-go-yuppie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensibility</ENAMEX> tells him that we can have our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and eat it too, that technology
can uphold tradition instead of undermining it. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> spills over with
hopeful juxtapositions garnered on his travels. He describes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> on a
flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahrain</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s global positioning system to pray toward
Mecca, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> in veils and on the Internet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kayapo Indians</ENAMEX> in a hut
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> rain forest watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> and monitoring the value of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>-extraction rights on a satellite TV. This last example <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> describes
as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> and olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> in healthy balance."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> is almost certainly correct in his belief
that globalization is likely to make life better for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in remote places.
But it won't do it while preserving their local cultures. It will do it by
partially or completely obliterating them. That's what market capitalism does.
It uproots and homogenizes as it enriches--like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ronco</ENAMEX> appliance, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>
might say. I don't know anything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kayapos</ENAMEX>, but I'd wager that if they
keep watching that satellite TV, they won't be in loin cloths and huts the next
time the foreign affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> in
for a visit.

         
      
   
