
   
   
      
         
             Thank Heaven for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Boys</ENAMEX>

            It is, of course, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s fantasy to
discover that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> molests <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But since such pedarastic
revelations are (surprisingly) rare, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> sometimes must settle for the next
best thing: pretending that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> coddles child molesters.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a spectacular example from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election.)

            The political benefits of pedophilia have not been
lost on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who have ginned up not one but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> child
molestation controversies during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>. These tempests do not
arise from any actual disagreement over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pedophilia</TIMEX>. Rather, they are perfect
case studies in how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> fabricate, then profit from, an inflammatory
issue. (See also: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>)

            The first controversy begins with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psychological Bulletin</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychological Association</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rind</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
Tromovitch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bauserman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> re-examined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> studies in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> sexual abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> had been
surveyed as college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. They concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>,
typically do not suffer "intense psychological harm" from childhood sexual
abuse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> also recommended changing the terminology of sexual
abuse: An encounter between a "willing" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> should be called
"adult-child sex," not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> sexual abuse."

            The study and its
revolting linguistic suggestion moldered away in the great bibliographic
graveyard until it was brought to the attention of radio nag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlessinger</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. The article was an easy and deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: It
promoted the notion that an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> could consent to sex. Author
Bauserman, it turned out, had published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paidika</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of</ENAMEX>
Pedophilia , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> that favors the legalization of sex with
trumpeting the article on its Web site.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>'s crusade against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> study enlisted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dobson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Values</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> distanced itself from the study, noting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>'s
long record of fighting pedophilia and insisting that the article does not
mitigate the illegality and immorality of pedophilia.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early May</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> deployed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> article as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. Led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> have
introduced a resolution to condemn the article and to demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> do the same. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is expected to vote on the measure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-June</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of the resolution say congressional condemnation will discourage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child molesters</ENAMEX> from citing the article in their legal defenses--not that
there's any evidence that anyone has done that.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> saw its opportunity on
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> skirted a question about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> study by saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had not reviewed it. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has,
of course, denounced pedophilia.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week later</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockhart</ENAMEX> still had not
commented on the study, the RNC blast-faxed a press release congratulating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> for its brave stand and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slamming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Its headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Still
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spinning 'Sexual Relations</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--As GOP Protects Minors From Pedophiles</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>'s
political exploitation of the APA squabble ranges from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Values</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>'s criticism of "liberal political advocacy ... laying the groundwork
for the permissibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molestation" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>'s
loopy accusation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is fronting for pro-pedarasty gay-rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>. "There is an eerie silence from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. I think they are
afraid of offending their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual ranks</ENAMEX>, since there is a
strong element of support among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual activists</ENAMEX> for lowering the age of
consent," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRC</ENAMEX> Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cultural Studies Robert Knight</ENAMEX>.

            The mainstream press has ignored the pedophilia flap, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>, other talk radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> publications have all
trumpeted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s courage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s conservative base.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have
managed to cast themselves as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> of pedophiles, insinuate that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is soft on pedophilia, and link <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub rosa campaign</ENAMEX> to
lower the age of consent--and all this is based on a report that no one noticed
until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX> uncovered it, that no one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> seems to
have read, and that no one remotely linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has ever endorsed.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> pedophilia scare has served a more pragmatic
purpose: legislative blackmail. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> has been considering a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.3 billion</NUMEX> bill for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Customs</ENAMEX>
Service. Federal employee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
strongly opposed a provision that would limit certain kinds of overtime pay for
customs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. In the face of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> played the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">molester</ENAMEX> card. They added <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> to the legislation for customs to
investigate Internet kiddie <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX>. They also added money for drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interdiction</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> endorsed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-porn and drug funding but voted against the bill
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> because of the overtime provision. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Subcommittee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Crane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, immediately accused the minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of giving aid and
comfort to molesters. "This bill protects our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and
pedophiles, and it's unfortunate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have put special interest
pressures ahead of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s safety," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX> said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, unwilling to take another beating, folded,
voting unanimously for the bill in full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. It passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">410</NUMEX>-2.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> gripes, "There is not a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> who objects to the funding to fight child porn, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> constructed the vote in such a way that a vote against the bill can
be framed as a vote to say <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> favor pornography. They added on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child-porn</ENAMEX> provision and the drug provision simply to force us to vote for
them. And we had to."

            (Which raises an
intriguing notion: Why aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> attaching
anti-pedophile measures to every bill? What are they afraid of?)

            Now that they have conquered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> with bogus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pedophile</ENAMEX> charges, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are siccing the tactic against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, which still objects to the overtime provision. "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are under
attack by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child pornographers</ENAMEX> who prey on them over the Internet. Couple that
with the constant peddling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and you have a deadly
combination that we must do everything we can to stop. This is not a time for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partisanship</ENAMEX> or special interest influence," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who doesn't want to be called
squishy on molesters, will probably cave. Once he does, perhaps the two parties
can abandon this imaginary controversy and tackle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> that actually
plagues <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--not child sexual abuse, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> sexual abuse abuse.

         
      
   
