
   
   
      
         
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> passed legislation to build a national missile defense system .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> persuaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, to insert a clause
saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> won't be deployed until it's "technologically possible,"
which could allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> to postpone it. If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> accepts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> language, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will support their joint bill. If
not, he'll veto it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The system violates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">anti-ballistic missile</ENAMEX> treaty with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It will anger the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and
kill arms reduction, which is more important. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It's too expensive. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It
won't work. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> caved as usual. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> just want a campaign
issue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The conservative spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New</ENAMEX> threats from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> justify building the system. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> is vindicated. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The
system can work. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ABM treaty</ENAMEX> is defunct. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s
weasel words to postpone the system indefinitely. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) It's a great campaign
issue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
peace talks collapsed . The ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> signed the peace deal proposed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavs</ENAMEX> (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>) refused,
principally because they can't stand having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
enforce it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX>' spin: The ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> are good, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are
bad, and now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> may have to bomb the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. The ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>' spin: Now
that we signed the deal to end the violence and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> didn't, please bomb
them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' spin: The deal was a sham concocted by the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>
and "their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>," and we don't believe you'll bomb us. The public
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government spin: Now we're really going to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> you. The private <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bombing</ENAMEX> will be harder than we thought, so first let's try
begging again. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
A government
study endorsed medical marijuana . The study was commissioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry McCaffrey</ENAMEX> and conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy of Sciences</ENAMEX>. It
says: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) pot can reduce pain, anxiety, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX> in chemotherapy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) its medical use would not increase casual pot smoking
or more serious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy people</ENAMEX>; but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) since pot smoke is toxic,
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose long-term health is moot (i.e., terminally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>) should
use it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCaffrey</ENAMEX> said little about the report, leading everyone to conclude
that he'll ignore it. The anti-pot spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The report shows pot isn't
medicine. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It shows pot is toxic. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Medical pot is a slippery slope to
legalization. The pro-pot spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX> can help. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arresting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> is not
right." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Legal pain-killing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> (e.g., morphine) are worse. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Politicians
are just afraid of being called soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Recent ballot measures show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> want medical pot. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) It's not a slippery slope to legalization. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) Let's
legalize it. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> announced his presidential
candidacy on the Internet. He portrayed the new medium as a symbol of his
emphasis on individualism, growth, and opportunity, in contrast to old-style
centralized government programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. Old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>:
pro-choice flat-taxer. New <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>: no-new-taxes pro-lifer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' spin on
his wealth: wacky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' spin: He's "not beholden" to interest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Old spin on his experience: He's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. New spin: He can win
because he's been campaigning nonstop since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. Old spin on his significance:
He can't win. New spin: He'll destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> again.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/17/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Paula 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> separated from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , "The split followed disagreements over strategy
in her sexual harassment case ... how to spend the money they received from
their settlement and where to live in the post-lawsuit era." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
presented himself as the voice of practicality, saying, "My idea is you don't
spend money until you know what you're going to have." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
says now that he's been fired as an airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>, he "will pursue an acting
career and work on a book." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> will accept a job
offer as a manicurist while weighing "paid media offers." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/17/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Lyons</ENAMEX> resigned as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the largest black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> religious
body, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Baptist Convention USA</ENAMEX> . He had been convicted of
racketeering and grand theft for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) selling bogus membership lists to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
that sought access to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) stealing donations intended to
rebuild burned black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>. The sunny spin, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>: He's
"remorseful" and resigned with "dignity." The cautious spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> are
losing their tolerance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who exploit them. The pessimistic spin, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX>' possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Butts</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leaders</ENAMEX> will always be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fallible</ENAMEX>, so structural reforms are needed to make them more accountable.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/17/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware</ENAMEX> lawyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Capano</ENAMEX> was sentenced to death for murdering his ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capano</ENAMEX>'s trial had drawn national attention because he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> and because, contrary to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' advice, he took the
stand and confessed to getting rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> but asserted that
another of his ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX> had committed the murder. After being convicted,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capano</ENAMEX> expressed no remorse but asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to consider his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s feelings
in choosing his sentence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> chose death, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> agreed, calling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capano</ENAMEX>'s invocation of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> further evidence of his selfishness,
ruthlessness, and contempt. Headline and caption <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> alluded to the irony
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capano</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, being sentenced to death. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/17/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Chess Federation</ENAMEX> anointed its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black grandmaster .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Ashley</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, earned
his place among the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">470</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmasters</ENAMEX> through superior tournament play.
He stopped coaching <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in chess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> in order to train
himself for tournaments and achieve his dream. The sunny spin: Anyone can
succeed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and hard work. The cynical spin: Anyone can succeed if he
stops wasting his energy on others. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/17/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D-Mo.</ENAMEX>, endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and joined him on the campaign trail. Previously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> had
downgraded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s stock, arguing that he already trails <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, in polls; that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sleaze is rubbing off on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>; that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s attempt to make suburban traffic jams a presidential campaign issue is
frivolous; and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> shot himself in the foot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by claiming to have
taken "the initiative in creating the Internet." The spins on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">endorsement: 1</ENAMEX>) It's a much-needed boost for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's mutual back
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scratching</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will simultaneously campaign to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> unity will scare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) On the contrary,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are uniting because they're scared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s early unity behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Cinderella 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">victors</ENAMEX> shook up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s
basketball tournament . In the West, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> -seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonzaga</ENAMEX>, which
has already taken out <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>-seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>, has
a good chance of becoming the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> double-digit seed ever to reach the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quarterfinals</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> -seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> reached the
round of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> by knocking off <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>-seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--behind a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-point
onslaught from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wally Szczerbiak</ENAMEX>--and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12 th</NUMEX> -seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Missouri State</ENAMEX> held <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>-seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> points--the lowest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> tournament score since the inception of the shot
clock--and then trounced <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>-seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s round of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> boast
the highest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in the tournament's history.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Boxing officials
ordered a rematch of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13</TIMEX> heavyweight championship fight between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evander Holyfield</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lennox Lewis</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> and sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are in an
uproar because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> called the fight a draw--despite a huge disparity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">punches in Lewis</ENAMEX>' favor and the widespread perception of spectators that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX>
won. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, said he will ask the state athletic commission
to investigate the fight. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The fight was rigged, probably by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">promoter Don King</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The disputed outcome only shows that judging fights is a
subjective art. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Even so, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' fault for failing to put the outcome
beyond question by going for the kill. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Who cares whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are
honest? The real outrage is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> is barbaric. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) The real outrage is
that the fight was boring. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) The real outrage is that boxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> won't
be able to raise enough money to pay the exorbitant sums the boxers are
demanding for a rematch. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
