
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">233</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Courtly&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "I couldn't do my current job without them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> as he waved something in the air. What?
            

             

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 232</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summoning DiMaggio's Ghost":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  The list includes whistling, making certain hand gestures, and
carrying bottles, baseball bats, or flashlights. List of
what?
               
            

            
"Telltale signs that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> might be troubled. That and having a bomb
factory in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Kickertz</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jenkinson</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "Things
I'm not allowed to do within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 yards</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dame Judi Dench</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            "Why,
West <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Side Story</ENAMEX> dance steps, of course."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Lyle</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways</ENAMEX>
to ward off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lorre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Carla</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Been in a Coma</ENAMEX> Since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michaels</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX> headings in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Shalit</ENAMEX>'s new book, When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modesty</ENAMEX>
Fails ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>
            

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX>'s
Question Critique
            

            Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>, this is one of
those questions where you taunt us with the open arms of the obvious.
You--sitting in a well-upholstered recliner, casually sipping something
top-shelf and free of little umbrellas, poking lackadaisically at a morsel of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">takeout</ENAMEX>--have only to dance your fingertips across the keyboard to condemn us
as we fall prey to writing "things prohibited in high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>" or "new ways to
pick up interns." We are so weak, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>. Pity us.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            "The whole system should be blown up." No, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan Klebold</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metaphorically</ENAMEX>? Wadda ya, an idiot? It's just an
expression. "I can understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would pick on it. Because they want to
deliberately misunderstand it," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. "And if anybody misunderstands
it, they're honestly doing it on purpose. To get me," he added, except for
those last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> words.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
mostly associate the activities in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s question with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> locales that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seems unable to connect, even when his
hand-wringing about teen violence runs on the same front pages that report <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> suffering. It's a violent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Who knew? I'm no fancy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> but maybe, just maybe, the whole system should be blown up.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metaphorically</ENAMEX>. Don't pretend not to understand me, the way those robots do
when they follow me around. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Idiots</ENAMEX>.

            
               There's No Such
Thing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Association</ENAMEX> Answer
            

            All are illegal under the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> statutes of
various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Loren-Maltese</ENAMEX>, town
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, wants to fight even harder; she proposes exiling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang members</ENAMEX>--banishing them from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX>--and coming down hard if they ever
return, even to visit their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly
supported a nonbinding referendum on her plan.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: How
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will Betty Loren-Maltese</ENAMEX> identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang members</ENAMEX>?
A: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> "known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang members</ENAMEX>" including several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>.
They'd have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX> to get out of town.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
Loren-Maltese propose to round up these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>?

            A: She
might consider gating neighborhoods and establishing police <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> has a reputation
for racism and government corruption. What did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>
call it?

            A: The
Selma of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Q: Does Betty Loren-Maltese</ENAMEX>
think her law should apply to convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> like her late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and to
those in organized crime?

            A: "If
they get involved in drive-by shootings."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
Loren-Maltese respond when constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Tushnet</ENAMEX> notes: "You can
punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for what they do; you can't punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for what that are."

            A: "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang members</ENAMEX> have rights. How about our civil rights?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Is there something else
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Loren-Maltese</ENAMEX> kind of calls her proposal?

            A: "I
kind of call it tough love."

            
               Prelude to a Kick
Extra
            

            

               "This is an all-out war on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do bad things," said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Brown</ENAMEX>, just before strangling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> with the entrails of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>. Or perhaps he was planning to arrest some more jaywalkers.

               "Any visit-and-search <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, of course, has to have the appropriate rules
of engagement," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX>, just before rummaging through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>' lingerie drawer. Or perhaps he was clarifying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> plans to board
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>-bound oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tankers</ENAMEX>.

               "There's still a lot of old equipment out there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mick Mack</ENAMEX>, just
before using a laser pointer to highlight surprising features of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anatomy</ENAMEX>. Or perhaps he was commenting on dangerously outmoded playground
apparatus.

               "I want to make a plea to everybody who is waiting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next deer season</TIMEX>
in my home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, just before telling newly mobilized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air National Guardsmen</ENAMEX> that bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> would be a lot like shooting
ruminants, only safer. Or perhaps he was about to announce a new gun control
package.

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
