
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Gratuitous
Meritocracy
            

            It seemed too much to hope for that the list of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>'s 100 greatest pieces of journalism--produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX> journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, at no one's urgent
request--would actually include The Fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> . But there it was
at No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Schell</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> argument against having a nuclear war may be
the silliest book ever taken seriously by serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> ? See "" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' suggestions.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schell</ENAMEX> set out, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, to prove that nuclear war really
would be a really, really bad thing that should be avoided if at all possible.
He succeeded, declaring at every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> that vast resources of courage and
imagination were required to make this point. He went on to argue that
virtually all aspects of life as we know it--including "say, liberty"--"have
become inimical to life and must be swept away" as the only hope of avoiding
nuclear cataclysm. At this he was less successful.

            You won't believe,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, what a literary-intellectual event this overheated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX> of the
obvious and the idiotic became. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> actually took up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schell</ENAMEX>'s recommendation of nuclear monomania. As long as nuclear weapons
existed, he declared, to even think about anything else was deeply immoral. And
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> agreed. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schell</ENAMEX>'s manifesto is even sillier in hindsight. Not so
much because of the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schell</ENAMEX> was not alone in failing
to predict), but because even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Schell</ENAMEX>, it turns out, cannot panic full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> about nuclear war. Lately he's been expressing alarm about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of
the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. Threat to liberty or something like that.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fuss Over The Fate</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> was the last gasp of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> buzz machine of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shawn</ENAMEX> era. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX> buzz machine was just as powerful as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">much-criticized Tina Brown</ENAMEX> model that came after, and hypocritical to boot,
since it denied its own existence. Literary devices did most of the work. There
was the bullying portentous tone, which said, "This is unbelievably
important--so you, shut up." Then there was the pretense of simply presenting
the facts, which put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> on a pedestal beyond the reach of quarrel and
made his or her conclusion seem inexorable.

            Actually, the last gasp of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> may be
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> list, which is laughably heavy on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> golden oldies. (In
truth, the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> is a much better publication.) How could
anyone think that the pointless pointillism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McPhee</ENAMEX>, at No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>, should
rank higher than No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>, a great book that happens to be by my best friend
in journalism?

            But quarreling with an
exercise like this, while enjoyable, misses the point. Such quarreling buys
into the premise that there is something socially useful about inventing
reasons to decide that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are better than others. Call it gratuitous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meritocracy</ENAMEX>. I wouldn't say that the ever-growing profusion of prizes and
awards and lists of the best this or that are "inimical to life" or anything,
but they are a minor blot on our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>.

            What's wrong with them? Well, of course they're
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pseudoscientific</ENAMEX> or, to put it another way, dishonest. There's no objective
measure, and no hope of broad general agreement, that No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> is superior to No.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> (though any sane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can see that No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> should be much, much higher).
This is generally true of gratuitous meritocracy, whether it takes the form of
a glossy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s "best-dressed" list, or a glitzy prize like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>, or the employee ratings of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, or the endless
variety of hierarchical opportunities held out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and college
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. All of these pretend to a precision that doesn't exist. But that's
not the real problem. Even if it were possible to determine scientifically
whose performance as a supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was better than anyone
else's, why should you want to do that?

            Human inequality is both
part of the condition of our species and a specific necessity of the
free-market economic system, which relies on incentives and differential
rewards to motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Some inequality is inevitable, in other words, and
more of it is a price worth paying for a prosperity that benefits all, to one
degree or another. Looking back on the experience of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have concluded that attempts to eliminate inequality
wholesale end in tears. But we still argue about the relationship between
greater equality and greater prosperity within a capitalist economy. Will a tax
cut have a huge productivity payoff or just line the pockets of the already
well-to-do? Will a government benefit program lift <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up or just sap the
poor and sock the rich? And so on.

            But a list of who's better than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in some aspect
or another is not inevitable and does not make the economy any more prosperous
or society any richer in other ways. I suppose you could argue that a
best-dressed list encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to dress more beautifully or that a list of
the greatest works of journalism of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> will motivate
those who didn't make it to try a bit harder during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 100 years</TIMEX>. It's a
hard sell, though. What actually inspires such lists is a love of
distinction-making for its own sake, which sits oddly with our alleged
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> principles.

            Of course, more banal
commercial considerations are also at work, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Law of Award</ENAMEX>
Entropy, which holds that awards tend to subdivide and multiply until they are
worthless. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> begat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmys</ENAMEX>, which begat the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cable Ace Awards</ENAMEX>, of
which there are so many that any cable TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who actually attends the
ceremony is entitled to leave in a snit if he or she doesn't win <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
Meanwhile, on your television are the gala <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bulgarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press Association</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Syndicated Sitcom Excellence Awards</ENAMEX>, hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Henderson</ENAMEX> ...

            In principle, there is nothing tackier about an award given
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association of Right-Wing Radio Blowhards</ENAMEX> than one given by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish Royal Academy</ENAMEX>. In practice, awards seem to gain legitimacy with the
patina of age. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prizes</ENAMEX>, for example, go to books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> but not
to magazines. So, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of decades ago</TIMEX>, the magazine industry created the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Magazine Awards</ENAMEX> ("the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enema</ENAMEX>," as occasional

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX> calls them). A totally artificial and
unnecessary addition to civilization. And yet by relentlessly treating them as
a big deal over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have succeeded in making them a
reasonably big deal. Not as big a deal as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulitzers</ENAMEX> yet, but in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ballpark</ENAMEX>. (And yes, we'd like one, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX> that we are, thank you very
much.)

            Inevitably, come now the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Webby Awards</ENAMEX>, given by something we are asked to believe is the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Academy of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Arts and Sciences</ENAMEX> ." For a medium that prides itself on its
insurgent spirit, this is a comically egregious exercise in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">faux-establishmentarianism.</ENAMEX> But like all such operations, this one traps its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in a conspiracy of mutual hype. They hype you by giving you an award.
You hype them by bragging about it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'acad√©mie Internationale des Arts et des</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciences Num√</ENAMEX>©riques have innovated a clever variant on this trick. They
give a separate set of awards based on how many votes your site gets in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> poll they're running on their site. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is now littered
with links to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Webby</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Voice</ENAMEX>" page. (Why, what a coincidence: Here's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right here .) Despite some press-release malarkey about
democracy in action, the true spirit of the Web, and blah, blah, the connection
between this and any valid expression or measurement of Web popularity is about
as close as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die internationale Akademie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">digitaler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K√</ENAMEX>ºnste und
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wissenschaften</ENAMEX> is to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy of Sciences</ENAMEX>.

            Small type at the bottom of the home page confesses
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'accademia Internazionale degli Arti e delle Scienze Digitali</ENAMEX> is
"an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDG Conference Management Company</ENAMEX>." Said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> seems to have
copyrighted all the materials, so I think it's clear what's going on. But
everyone is pretending this is some sort of real industry honor. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> is
throwing a cocktail party to celebrate the fact that its Web site was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominated</ENAMEX> !) And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> it will probably be just as real as all
the others. And just as pointless.

            On behalf of all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at

                  Slate
               , thank goodness we don't have the strength to resist.

         
      
   
