
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> runs for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, she'll have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> crucial advantages. One
is that her last name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The other is that her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name isn't Bill.
The emerging spin behind her candidacy is that she's her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s moral
opposite: She's been his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, she's been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>, and now it's "her turn."
But that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> dimension in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> differ. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oppose Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s candidacy are gearing up to exploit another
difference: her comparative liberalism on matters of policy.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Filegate</ENAMEX> might have
hurt her. But nowadays talking about those scandals reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> less of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' suspicious behavior than of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s impeachment jihad. Indeed, part
of the logic behind her candidacy is to ride the anti-impeachment backlash.
"Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would serve as a constant reminder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> effort to oust her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>," observes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . She "could help drive
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to the polls," sweeping several of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> out of office. A scandal-based <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> attack would only make
things worse. "If their campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> is to simply be
an extension of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Torricelli</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, warned on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , "they're
going to take a sizable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> lead and make it into a rout."

            It's true that the public remains angry at Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. But the genius of her candidacy is that she gets to ride that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">backlash</ENAMEX>, too. Her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>" told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that she's "very
enticed by the idea of at last having an independent voice, particularly after
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> ... publicly humiliated her" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. This story line plays to
moralists as well as to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>. If you're mad at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the argument
goes, support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he cheated on.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have fallen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> over heels for this spin. "Her Turn," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover. "A
Race of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Her Own</ENAMEX>," agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial says
her candidacy "could allow her to untangle herself from the political side of
her marriage and compete for a power base that is all her own. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> might
ante up a campaign contribution just in the hopes of seeing Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sworn
in on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> becomes unemployed. ... If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
announces that it is now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s turn to shine, and his to take on the jobs
of campaign cheerleader and family breadwinner, even many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> would agree it is about time."

            The pose of the wronged but ever-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful wife</ENAMEX> also helps
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other ways. It raises her to an even higher pedestal,
prompting the media to ask not whether she's up to the job of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> but
whether she's too good for it. Meanwhile, the pedestal lifts her above the
charge of carpetbagging. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> says she "would be part of a great
tradition" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">icons</ENAMEX> who have used <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seats as a "platform" from
which to "enlighten the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s likely
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, understands the peril of the
impeachment mess and is wisely steering clear of it. "I was one who didn't
believe that [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>] should have been impeached, so no, I would not
bring it up," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> declared on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> . Instead, he vowed to
confront his likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> on "issues" such as taxes, welfare reform, national
health insurance, and her advocacy of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Superficially,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s argument is that she's too liberal. But he has added a clever twist
to the argument, turning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s strategy on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. She's
different from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, all right, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. The difference is that
she's out of the mainstream.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> twice likened his own views
to those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and contrasted them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s more radical
views. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, "I'm in the same position as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is out there much more heavily favoring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>." Later, when asked about his initiative to require homeless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get jobs or leave their homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> said the
initiative "emerges from the mandates of the welfare reform bill that was
signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. And what it says is that when you seek shelter ...
we will engage you in a process of trying to find work for you as opposed to
letting you become dependent." As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> allowed, "She
may be in a different position."

            Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> worry openly about this
line of attack. "Let's say she disagrees with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> on trade policy," one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . "It will be trumpeted as a big deal."
In a mock strategy memo published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> asked her, "What if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> undercuts your most
effective campaign issue by making a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on partial
privatization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and tax cuts? Will you take a stand or stand
by your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therein</ENAMEX> lies her dilemma.
On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Safire</ENAMEX> explained how she
could beat the extremism rap. "She can do what her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has done over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and that is reassess things. ... She can make a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, be
embraced, get a lot of pictures over there, and move from the left [toward] the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>," talking more "about getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off welfare and balancing budgets."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> is already working on this script, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "would make very
clear that she supports this peace process ... from the perspective of an
administration that has probably been more helpful to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and its security
than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> step to the left, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> steps to the
right. That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> love about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s politics--and what they hate
about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
