
   
   
      
         
            Wild <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>

            Commenting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s capture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX>, the press across
western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> principal demands: that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> should not be executed,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> law allows, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> should seize this opportunity to reach a
peaceful settlement of its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> problem. It was also generally accepted in
both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence was deeply involved in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s mysterious delivery from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, where he
had been sheltering, to an island <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> ran
a front-page story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s "kidnapping,"
quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> as saying that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> secret
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> alerted us to his whereabouts." The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> carried an exclusive
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulent Ecevit</ENAMEX>, who said it
is entirely up to the judiciary to decide if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> should receive a death
sentence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> led its front page with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ecevit</ENAMEX> saying that he
hopes there will now be a solution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> problem, though in the
interview he spoke of achieving this not through greater political autonomy, as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> demand, but through economic improvements in the southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> where they live. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in the English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ilnur Cevik</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecevit</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Aziz</ENAMEX> recently agreed to a resumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> sales and border
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> between southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, which had been interrupted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> bombing campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cevik</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> should now press for a
lifting of sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and called on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> "to utilize our unique
position as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to be able to integrate back into the
international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammad Noureddin</ENAMEX>, a
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> affairs, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mideast Mirror</ENAMEX>
news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s "handover to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> may be poised for a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in which it needs to enlist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX>." Reporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
denial that it had been in any way involved, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the denial was in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurd</ENAMEX> suspicions based, in part, on
a column written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
Safire, who had said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> intelligence and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>" were
helping to track down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>.

            The rioting of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, with burnings
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX>-takings at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>, alarmed European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and generated countless pages of comment and analysis. These
included much self-criticism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in a front-page
editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, which has a large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant population</ENAMEX>, has
damaged both its own constitution and international agreements on terrorism by
refusing to request <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s extradition from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, when it had an
international arrest warrant out on him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also warned of the influence
the affair will have on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s highly charged debate about the integration
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> society.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> of breaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> accords, with the result that "the
whole territory of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> is in a state of siege by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurd</ENAMEX> intifada." The
editorial went on to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> should take a common position toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, "clarifying that its aspirations to membership of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> will be
strictly dependent on the way it manages <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s destiny. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that
doesn't respect the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> and which practices the death penalty
doesn't have the right to be part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX>
should "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX> with all the guarantees due to him, to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
is a state founded on the law." It added, "This is an essential condition for
any settlement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurd</ENAMEX> question." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libération</ENAMEX> called for "a political solution that
necessarily requires a radical decentralization. ... It is here that the role
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, which played a big part in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s arrest and which for
the moment can only see him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX>, could be decisive."

            
In an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> youth magazine
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supermodel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Moss</ENAMEX> revealed that she hadn't walked sober
down the runway for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moss</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> checked into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
rehabilitation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>, said that she and her fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> drank <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> from
early in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and smoked pot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>.

             

         
      
   
