
   
   
      
         
             Geek Love

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> will change the
world. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> will do my homework, my dishes, my laundry. The hype reminds me of
similar hype <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX>, which never did floss my teeth.
But, setting out to demystify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX>, I fell in love. Geek love, I hasten to
add. It's not for everyone.

            Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s OS<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacOS</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX> was written by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, not a faceless
monolith like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> I work for. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linus Torvalds</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is
also different because it is based on the founding principles and software of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Software Foundation</ENAMEX>, whose name describes its mission. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is
derived from an operating system developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSF</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU</ENAMEX>. The proper name
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU/Linux</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU</ENAMEX> is a variation on the Unix operating system and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acronym GNU</ENAMEX> stands--disconcertingly--for " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU</ENAMEX>'s not Unix." Are you still with
me?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> preaches that all software should be "Open
Source," by which they mean that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> should be able to view and change the
underlying code, be it for the operating system or for applications.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> consider their code top secret.) Open
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sourcers</ENAMEX> also advocate free distribution of software. To the FSF the issues of
free software are at the very foundation of creating a "cooperative society." I
am a wee bit skeptical. I enjoy getting paid to write software, and I suspect
that many, if not most, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> are being paid by someone to write
software. It's nice that they can play with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> for free, but if all software
were free, how would they eat?

            When pushed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Software Foundation</ENAMEX> defines "free" as a matter of liberty, not of price. Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNU/Linux</ENAMEX>, but the underlying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> are freely available to
anyone who wants them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> that sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> offer the support and
maintenance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have come to expect--and charge for them.

            But software development religions aside, what is an
operating system like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> doing? As the name suggests, it controls the
fundamental operation of your computer: things like how to read documents from
a disk and send them to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>. As you may have heard, the demarcation of
what is and isn't "in the operating system" can be a touchy question. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> maintain that an operating system contains any goddamn thing they
want to put in it, thank you very much. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> say that an operating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is just the core functionality (or in computer parlance, the kernel)
necessary to run the chips in your machine.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is definitely the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> model. When you turn on a computer using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Linux</ENAMEX> you get no bells,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whistles</ENAMEX>, or windows. You just see some lines of text and then a blinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cursor</ENAMEX>. So are we just back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX>? Well, no: You can add a graphical interface
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xwindows</ENAMEX>, which looks amazingly like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX>, complete with a Start
button. Once you start <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xwindows</ENAMEX>, you're back in familiar territory. You can use
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> to open documents and applications (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX>). I even ran
a Web browser. A big practical disadvantage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is that there isn't much
application software for it. But that's because so few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use it. It
wouldn't be fair to count this as a negative in weighing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>'s intrinsic
merits. And so, of course, I won't.

            To begin my experiment I had to get a machine running
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>. So I started searching the Web for information. After getting lost on a
few Web sites, I completely wimped out and went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>. The
software may be free, but there's big money in books on how to use it. I made a
scientific decision based on weight and purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red Hat Linux Secrets</ENAMEX>
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39.95</NUMEX>, which included <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Hat</ENAMEX> software's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.1</NUMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> on a
CD-ROM.

            Back at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> I did
the hard stuff. I hijacked a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentium</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">133</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> megs of memory and
repartitioned its hard drive into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repartitioned</ENAMEX>" is a fancy way of
saying "divided." Thus, instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big hard drive I now have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little
ones using the same physical disk. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> has a utility program that helped me
do this (because it knows you're going to want to keep running Windows too). It
did involve some complicated thinking about disk cylinders, but it worked.

            I then fruitlessly tried to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX> to boot up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First I</ENAMEX>
tried to get it to load directly from the CD that came with the book. Then I
spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another hour</TIMEX> trying to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> boot disk I had created to
acknowledge the existence of the CD drive. Finally, I copied the entire CD onto
my hard drive and started the install process. I had to create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more floppy
boot disks.

            I had to repartition my
drive again within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> to create swap space for the operating system (for
those keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> I now have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> partitions on my hard drive). I had to
format both drives. I then had to remember where on my hard drive I had put the
install files. Then it got started. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> found my various devices, such as my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and graphics card. It configured both relatively painlessly. It wasn't
complete plug and pray. I still had to select my items from lists, and it was
good that I generally knew what types of hardware I was running, but it worked.
Finally I got a blinking cursor at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> prompt. I then launched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xwindows</ENAMEX>.
To complete the setup, I got the browser configured and read

                  Slate
               ! After installing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corel</ENAMEX>'s WordPerfect I was even able to
write this column on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Linux</ENAMEX>. (Lexicographical curiosity: The word Linux
is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> spell-check dictionary but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word's</ENAMEX>.)

            After spending a day with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>, I concluded that it runs
great. It helped that I know Unix, but the system does work. I have basic Web
browsing capabilities and a word processor. I also configured and set up the
Web server, so I could, in theory, power all of 
                  Slate
                off this
machine. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is definitely cool as a server. But if you want to
replace your desktop machine, forget it.

            What makes Linux
enthralling from a tech-head's point of view is that it is based on Unix
standards that have been around for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsystems</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Graphics</ENAMEX> have produced varieties of
Unix for their business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. While these varieties are generally
incompatible with one another, all this code-writing has resulted in a
far-flung <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that understands the Unix <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>. Linux <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> stand on
the shoulders of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>, thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> has a lot of intrinsic testing behind
it. That makes it what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">techies</ENAMEX> call "robust," meaning resistant to breaking
down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enthusiasts</ENAMEX> claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> can run for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> without requiring you to
restart your system. On my machine I can claim only a week of running without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">restarting</ENAMEX>, but that is pretty darn good. It also has a solid multithreading
and multitasking model, meaning that one errant program can't bring the whole
computer to its knees. (This is a feature <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> shares with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows NT</ENAMEX>, but not
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95/98</ENAMEX>.)

            In terms of performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX> ran about as quickly as
Windows <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">95/98</NUMEX> (though much faster than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows NT Server</ENAMEX>) on my low-end Pentium
machine. For a completely unscientific example, there was little difference in
basic file <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> such as copying and pasting, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> ran just as
fast as it did on a comparable Windows machine.

            Should you switch to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>? In my opinion, if you are a typical computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>, there is no practical
reason to do so. The best reason is psychological. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is a workable
alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX>, and thus it allows you to vote with your PC. If you
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hate Microsoft</ENAMEX>, you can use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>. It has all the basics necessary to get you
through your computing life, if you are willing to ignore some rough edges here
and there. For instance, you won't have much trouble importing data from word
processing and spreadsheet files. But if you crave a huge variety of software
application--games, personal information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, graphics programs, financial
software, reference works--you'd be better off buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mac or a Windows</ENAMEX> PC.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> predict that the dawning of the Web means that your operating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> may be less and less important anyway. Many of you have used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Linux</ENAMEX> and
don't even know it, because many of the Web sites you frequent to check the
weather or buy airplane tickets are powered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>.

            Now I must confess my doubts about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Source</ENAMEX>
movement. Do all those software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> writing open source code for Linux
have the incentive to fix problems as they arise and--more important--to help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> upgrade and keep old code running? Perhaps the greatest technological
feature that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX> possesses is that it can handle programs as old as the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> DOS applications. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> will never do that.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> will fracture into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> different incompatible versions, just as Unix
did. Linux <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> insists that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> will prevent such a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tower of</ENAMEX>
Babel disaster. I suspect that a schism will eventually divide the happy Linux
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, as equally creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innovators</ENAMEX> disagree on the operating system's
future.

            Furthermore, as in 
                  Slate
               , software companies
spend a surprising fraction of their resources testing software, not writing
it. In my experience, this is the ultimate problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Source</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>: not enough formal engaged testing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Developers</ENAMEX> want to write code,
they don't want to solve all the niggling little problems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> come up
with.

            But if the thought of a free operating system is so
exciting that you're willing to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39.95</NUMEX> and invest <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for the privilege,
by all means give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> a try.

         
      
   
