
   
   
      
         
            A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year ago</TIMEX>, with the Dow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> industrial average at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,700</NUMEX>, financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Glassman</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Hassett</ENAMEX> wrote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> that the price
of stocks was still way too low. By their logic, they said, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> should be
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX>--and would be, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> caught on.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, as the Dow
hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hassett</ENAMEX> repeat their argument in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> .
They admit that the "financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>" has reacted with guffaws. They do
not mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Siegel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharton</ENAMEX> finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> whose research is
central to their case, wrote to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> that "their analysis
contains a serious flaw [and] vastly overstates the value of stocks."

                  Slate
                also published a "" between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clive Crook</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crook</ENAMEX> explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glassman</ENAMEX> was
"wrong, plain wrong ... in the same way that it's wrong to say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> plus <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
equals <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glassman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassett</ENAMEX> (henceforth, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Glassman</ENAMEX>") remain unbowed.
In fact, they've upped the ante. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This fall</TIMEX> they're bringing out a book titled
Dow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,000</NUMEX> .

            It would make a wonderful tale if these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX>, a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>) had discovered what the entire finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> had missed,
and written the next <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Wealth of Nations</ENAMEX> . The true tale, sadly, is
somewhat less inspiring. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX>'s analysis suffers from a plain conceptual
mistake, described below, which he simply refuses to admit, no matter how many
times it is pointed out to him. Here is his argument, and why it is wrong.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX> begins by asking
whether you'd rather have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> in a savings account that pays <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>
interest or a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> share of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> per share <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The
answer is simple, right? The savings account pays you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> per year, while the
stock pays only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>--and even that only if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s entire earnings are
paid out in dividends.

            But why would a stock that pays out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $1</NUMEX> be trading at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> can get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> in a savings account? Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> tend to
grow over time and so do their earnings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Firms</ENAMEX> can grow for any number of
reasons, but only one is mathematically certain, and that is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX>'s
argument depends on: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that earns <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> can use it to expand, and thus
increase its earnings, expand even more, and so on. For instance, a typical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> of earnings per share might earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.05</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.11</NUMEX> the
following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, and so on. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX>, earnings per share will pass <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> and
continue to increase. You can show mathematically that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year forever</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.05</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> and so on are equal amounts. So it's not
illogical that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> would be willing to pay the same <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> for either
income stream.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Glassman</NUMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are not
paying the same amount for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these two</TIMEX> income streams. To get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> account costs you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but you can buy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> of corporate
earnings on the stock market for an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $25</NUMEX>! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason is that
stocks are considered riskier. Even if the average return on the stocks is the
same as the certain return on the savings account, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will pay extra for
the certainty itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glassman</ENAMEX> thinks this is the only reason for the
difference--although it's not.

            But Glassman
argues--citing historical studies by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>--that stocks held for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>
are not actually riskier. And when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize this, they'll be willing to
pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> of corporate earnings, and stock prices will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quadruple</ENAMEX>. That's where he gets his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times the current level.
(Maybe it's not too late to call the book Dow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> .)

            So where's the flaw? Assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX> is right about
the long-term risk of stocks, and assume he's right that average corporate
earnings will grow at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. The problem is that he is
double-counting. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> you get from a savings account is yours to spend
on anything you please. The corporate earnings are yours to spend only if they
are paid out in dividends. But if they are paid out in dividends, they aren't
available to expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, and so the delightful progression from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.05 to $1.11</NUMEX> and so on won't occur.

            Another way to see the flaw is to apply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX>'s
logic to the savings account. Sure, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> investment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will only get you
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. But those earnings will allow the savings account to grow, and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s earnings will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.36</NUMEX>, and then <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.74</NUMEX>, and so on. So according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX>'s theory, you should be willing to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> savings
account.

            The key point is that earnings cannot be
simultaneously paid out in dividends and invested in future profits.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX> would be right, however, if you could buy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> of dividends for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>. But it turns out that to buy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> of dividends costs you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$72</NUMEX> (among Dow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> industrial average stocks). Which suggests that if you really believe
that stocks are actually no riskier than a savings account--or, rather, if you
believe that everyone else will come to believe this--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> may still have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,888 or so</NUMEX> points to go. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> 14,000 anyone?

         
      
   
