
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> serves as both whipping boy and ghost for the dispirited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is blamed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s sinking popularity, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> still
practice his brand of antagonistic, moralistic politicking. ... New
physiological research into fear has found it surprisingly and unfashionably
reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Freudian</ENAMEX> notions of the unconscious. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Irrational anxiety</ENAMEX>,
suggests the research, is learned, permanent, involuntary, and inaccessible to
the conscious mind. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> visits rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polygamy</ENAMEX> has long been officially outlawed but is quietly tolerated. Now angry
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> are organizing outreach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and vast polygamous clans are
facing charges of pedophilia and sexual abuse.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                
               and

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> is flirting with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> run, and
the newsweeklies flirt right back with cover stories and ample advice.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's ebullient cover story calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> "the hottest commodity in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public life," urging her to run because: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She has sacrificed enough
of her own ambitions for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s career; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) she's a born policy wonk; and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) it would strengthen the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' marriage. In a sidebar , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> dissents: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> press
will eat her alive, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s a grind ("you won't fly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX> or
ride in escorted motorcades"), and she'd eventually make an even better
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story is more restrained: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>
("makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> look like a patsy") would rip her to shreds, and it's not
clear she even wants to run. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> may be floating the idea simply to
dissipate the last whiffs of the impeachment scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sidebar</ENAMEX> advice from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>: Wait
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> race in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chronicles Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s evolution from wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scion</ENAMEX> to hunted terrorist/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> fundamentalist icon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> first
formulated his doctrinaire philosophy of jihad at a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>,
refined it among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, and
used an international, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>-based terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> to launch it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>.
... Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> or merely a competent one? A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> article suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> will be a litmus test for the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright Doctrine</ENAMEX>," which consists of carefully nursed personal relationships
backed up by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military might.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The world is aging,
frets the cover story . Life expectancy is climbing, fertility is
sliding, and the cost of supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> could cause a global recession.
The first casualty is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, whose fat public pension program is eating up
government resources. ... A piece suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> aren't seduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
offers of a generous federal tax cut. Polls show that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are willing to
shun instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gratification</ENAMEX> to accomplish long-term goals such as repaying the
federal debt or revamping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. ... The magazine reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ouija</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> are passé; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s teen-age girl
turns to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch handbook</ENAMEX> for spiritual advice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> popular version includes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Bus Driver spell, the Un-Ground Me spell</ENAMEX>, and the Just-Say-No
spell.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story asserts
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> is a seasoned, ideologically consistent, genuinely religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who could restitch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of economic and social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. Even his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown</ENAMEX> speech has aged well: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> will
see that her sitcom has been canceled and that he's back on the scene," insists
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> may be a formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, but the subsequent article
explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> has already been anointed the inevitable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. His
ideological and geographic support is wide, his fiscal support is deep, and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> is already cooking up policy. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 227</ENAMEX>, which replaced bilingual education with
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>-only instruction, insists that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant voters</ENAMEX> will shun feel-good
appeals to diversity and tolerance. Instead, they're attracted by unabashed,
ideologically strict insistence on assimilation through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> education.

            
               
                  The
Nation
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            An editorial reports what first motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> to
consider a bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>: the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> would be on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ballot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Reluctant to cede the precious gender gap to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> initially wanted to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s running mate.
... A liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> fantasizes about the conservative party he'd like
to debate: Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>, it would be sober, earnestly religious,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX>. ... A piece argues that the impeachment process was driven by big
business in general and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> in particular. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> had
represented the industry while in private practice and was appointed on the
advice of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>-indebted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
