
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Gringo</ENAMEX>

            The hot news in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>? The escalators at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Managua</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> are besieged
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, who, enthralled by this new technology, go up the down staircase. Then
there's the saga of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the dozen</NUMEX> crummy border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> that tried to secede and
join <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> is cheaper. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thanks</ENAMEX>, but no thanks, said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Costa Ricans</ENAMEX>.) Or political dirty tricks, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan</ENAMEX>-style: Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX>
really sic a swarm of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">killer bees</ENAMEX> on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> campaign rally?

            If these stories didn't
make your newspaper's front page, it's probably because there's hardly anyone
left here to report them. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade ago</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contras</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX> were
willing proxies for the final great showdown of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ortega</ENAMEX>
press conference could easily draw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>--double that if he had
a captured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> or some other bauble to show off. Everybody had
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> here. I remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> identifying herself as the bureau
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> as she asked a question at a press conference.
I guess she was checking out reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> were using <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> as a
base to smuggle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bolshoi</ENAMEX> ballerinas to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX>.

            Today, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Herald</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>,
I'm practically the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gringo journalist</ENAMEX> left in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Managua</ENAMEX>. (The only other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , with
an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.) Sometimes the isolation makes me feel like I'm trapped
in one of those post-holocaust movies from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>, where the lead character
wakes up to discover that everyone else has been wiped out by killer robots
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX>.

            Not that there aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consolations</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> begged in vain for interviews with the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinista</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">comandantes</ENAMEX> . And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> who wrote
unflattering stories about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandies</ENAMEX>--I was one--could find themselves tossed
aboard a plane bound for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan</ENAMEX>
official would stand on his head and eat a bug if that would entice a foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> to do an interview. My fax machine fairly hums with offers of
briefings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> who can't quite believe their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is no
longer the lead item on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> daily briefing. They are inevitably
surprised that I don't want to drive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to see the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shovel of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> turned for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> linking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Managua</ENAMEX> have never heard of, much less anyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.

            In part, my popularity may stem from the dread officials
feel at dealing with the newly unchained local press. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>,
muzzled under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four decades</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Somoza</ENAMEX> dynasty and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX>, have become the most aggressive in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>. They take the
freedom to ask any question they want with a disconcerting literalness.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomas Borge</ENAMEX>, the sole surviving founder
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandinista Party</ENAMEX>, was being interviewed on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Managua</ENAMEX> radio station.
After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borge</ENAMEX> droned on for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> about the world economy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
broke in: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comandante</ENAMEX> , what everyone really wants to know is if the
rumors all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> are true: Do you just have one ball?"

            "What are you talking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borge</ENAMEX> replied. "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> just had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> . Here, you want to see
them?" He wasn't talking about his newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>. As I tuned to another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> was still pleading with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borge</ENAMEX> to keep his pants on.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Testicular</ENAMEX> journalism still isn't part of my beat. But I
have covered:

            

               The opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Managua</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> actually came out to dedicate it, pronouncing the occasion as
nothing less than the attainment of civilization: "When foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> see
that big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>, they know we're not running around in loincloths.")

               The controversy that led to a fistfight at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Nicaragua</ENAMEX>
pageant--"right in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Congeniality</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>," as one scandalized
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> put it. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> was a blue-eyed blonde, naturally provoking
protest that she was a gringa <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ringer</ENAMEX>.)

               The resurgence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>'s movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, which practically croaked
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX> made them show an endless parade of odes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ortega</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> deserve some credit
for a censorship policy that prevented their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> from being exposed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story</ENAMEX> , which they saw as an example of class betrayal (a heroic
working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> takes a place in the ruling class) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Hall</ENAMEX>
(too occupied with the trivial problems of the petite bourgeoisie).

            

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, you never traveled alone in the countryside
if you could possibly help it--you wanted help handy if you blundered into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firefight</ENAMEX> or a minefield. Not that many of us would have known what to do in
either situation--our attempts at self-protection were mostly laughable.

            One regular precaution
before driving out into the boonies used to be marking a giant "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TV</ENAMEX>" with
adhesive tape on the back and side windows, which we believed was easy-to-spot
shorthand for "don't shoot, I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Kinzer</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> encountered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contra patrol</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>,
chatted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> amicably for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or so, and then got ready to leave.
"Could I ask you a question before you go?" asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contra commander</ENAMEX>. "What
the hell does 'TV' mean, anyway<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            Lately, the only time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> banded together to travel
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Managua</ENAMEX> was during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Mitch</ENAMEX>, and that had as much to do with
crying on each other's shoulders as it did with self-protection. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> complain about having to call up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of
murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, but try interviewing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who just saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his
family swallowed in a mudslide.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happily</ENAMEX>, the memory of the hurricane is starting to
fade--though it was rekindled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> came through
Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, scattering relief programs in his wake like victorious GIs
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tossing chocolate bars</ENAMEX> to school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. As the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gringo reporter</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>, I naturally put in my bid for an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, which was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">politely</ENAMEX> declined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX>. "All <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> care
about is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and we're trying to get away from that," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
official told me. I wonder if he'd heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomas Borge</ENAMEX>'s radio interview.

         
      
   
