
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Source</ENAMEX>

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Source</ENAMEX>," click .

            There
in the fringe of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> between
the upper field and the edge of the one
below it that runs above the valley
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time I heard in the early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days of summer</TIMEX> the clear ringing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX> notes that I knew were the opening
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fingal's Cave</ENAMEX> Overture
I heard them again and again that year
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next summer</TIMEX> and the year
afterward those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> descending
notes the same for all the changing
in my own life since the last time
I had heard them fall past me from
the bright air <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the morning</TIMEX> of a bird
and I believed that what I had heard
would always be there if I came again
to be overtaken by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that season</TIMEX>
in that place after the winter
and I would wonder again whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mendelssohn</ENAMEX> really had heard them somewhere
far to the north that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>
looking up from his youth to listen to
those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> notes of an ancestor
spilling over from a presence neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">water</ENAMEX> nor human that led to the cave
in his mind the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluted cliffs</ENAMEX> and the wave
going out and the falling water
he thought those notes could be the music for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mendelssohn</ENAMEX> is gone and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fingal</ENAMEX> is gone
all but his name for a cave and for one
piece of music and the black-capped warbler
as we called that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> that I remember
singing there those notes descending
from the age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> dripping
I have not heard again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> can it
be gone then will I not hear it
from now on will the overture begin
for a time and all those who listen
feel that falling in them but as always
without knowing what they recognize

         
      
   
