
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Judge <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me by My</ENAMEX>
Actions
            

            I write to you about the comments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>
in a to a recent column of his in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don't Blame It on Rio ... Or</ENAMEX>
Brasilia Either"). In it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> states that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> prior to my being
offered the central bank presidency by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardoso</ENAMEX>, I "was negotiating
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>" and that meant I knew nothing bad was going to happen to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. At the same time, he goes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soros</ENAMEX> was "buying up large quantities of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> debt at deep discounts."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>, perhaps the best
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, however, he was careless, and I happened to
be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlucky victim</ENAMEX>. His accusation is false. He did not bother checking with
me. I did meet with senior government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>), but I
was not offered any government job, not the least the central bank presidency.
I did not have access to any privileged information either. As it turned out,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was a chaotic day in the markets, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> I did get the
invitation, which I was honored to accept. These are the facts.

            Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> has
written <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> notes on the episode, both available on his Web site. In them he
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that he does not believe that I am corrupt (thanks, but in my worst
nightmares I never dreamed my name and the word corruption would appear on the
same page) and that he did not treat me unfairly. I beg to disagree. Whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> thinks it is right or wrong for someone with market experience to take
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> post is immaterial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> should be judged by their actions and
their record, not by labels of any kind, not by rumors.

            

               --Arminio Fraga
            

            

               Commentary
            

            I suppose you think you
are being iconoclastic by publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Podhoretz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midge Decter</ENAMEX>'s nasty
musings on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of his funeral (see ""). You are wrong. It
is never iconoclastic or even interesting to read the predictable
chauvinism-driven propaganda of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> (the right-wing ones,
anyway) are always right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> are always wrong. It is so very tired. Too
bad that the kind of thinking these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> represent has led to so many dead
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>) over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 50 years</TIMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rosenberg</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               And
Dissent
            

            Why are you subjecting your loyal and (usually)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enthusiastic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> to the reactionary, bigoted, and sexist drivel of Midge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Podhoretz</ENAMEX> in ? We don't subscribe to 
                  Slate
                in
order to expose ourselves to the ramblings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Bryant</ENAMEX>'s spiritual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podhoretz</ENAMEX> may be correct in his opinion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
Sharpton, his comments regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> possess a thinly
disguised undertone of racism: As he castigates "white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>" for assuming
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Negroes</ENAMEX>" could do no wrong, his discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpton</ENAMEX>'s actions seem to
say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, what can you expect? We told those white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> that
you couldn't expect more from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Negroes</ENAMEX>." Podhoretz implies that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpton</ENAMEX>'s
behavior is both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of and entirely in keeping with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>"
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> in general.

            Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decter</ENAMEX>'s comments, the less said the better.
While we may deplore that sex has become the dominating factor in many young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives, the goal should be to expand and emphasize the nonsexual means
of personal expression ("liberation") available to them, not to return to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repressive</ENAMEX> and contaminating moral hypocrisies of a previous age.

            The best thing that may
be said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podhoretz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decter</ENAMEX> is that their biological clocks can't have many
more <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> left on them. And that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
                will
never see fit to subject their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> to them again.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Milazzo
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>

            
               Straight
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shooter</ENAMEX>
            

            In his "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Chait</ENAMEX> says it's misleading to
focus on the ratio of tax revenues to GDP. Why? Because the boom in stock
prices has led to a big jump in federal tax receipts but isn't counted as an
addition to GDP. But why should it be? The price of a stock reflects the
present value of expected future earnings; these earnings will be counted as
income when--and if--they're achieved. It would surely be silly to count the
expected earnings implicit in the stock price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> as income earned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chait</ENAMEX> also errs when he
criticizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Foundation</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, he says, "assumes that the average
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> pays <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an average</NUMEX> share of estate and capital gains taxes, which is
absurd." In fact, it isn't absurd at all. The median or modal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> may not
pay the average, but the average <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> obviously does.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Carnahan</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

            

               Taxonomy
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Chait</ENAMEX> may be correct that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of
income does not go to the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but he is wrong if he
thinks that we don't pay around that in taxes overall. Does he include the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> "non-taxes" in his calculations of tax burdens?
State, local, sales, property, and gasoline taxes? Does he count the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>
percent of one's salary that goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> in his tax burden number?

            Back of the envelope, it seems that every working
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> pays a flat <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of salary, plus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 5 percent to 10 percent</NUMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and sales taxes on every dollar earned or spent, respectively, plus
some unknown amount in property taxes (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX> get screwed the most here,
since rent of course includes prorated property tax pass-throughs), plus
gasoline taxes, plus some special local taxes (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s extra taxes on
restaurant meals, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, and other "sin" taxes). All told this seems to add up
to a total tax burden for a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 40 percent</NUMEX>.

            The typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pays a greater percentage of
total income to taxes than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> who would have to pay estate or capital
gains taxes. This is true because the vast majority of tax revenue that is
collected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is regressive: sales taxes, property taxes
(which are passed on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX>, so paid by everyone), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, etc.
And poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more likely to spend money on things like cigarettes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, and so on, making their total percentage tax burden even larger.
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> tops out at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $70,000</NUMEX>, making it a smaller
percentage tax burden for the rich than the poor.

            Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chait</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buddies</ENAMEX> should donate more to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric M.</ENAMEX>
Eisenstein
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> 

            
               Notes on
Groove
            

            Almost everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cullen Murphy</ENAMEX> states about the
word "groovy" in "" is accurate, except for its original meaning. Jazz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> did indeed use the term to indicate being "in the zone," but it
didn't necessarily refer to the grooves of a record. It referred more to the
sense of swing derived from the rhythmic variation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their playing</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>
notes. While classical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> tended to interpret their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> notes
strictly and evenly, jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> provided a little bounce in theirs, a
slightly uneven distribution of rhythm achieved by placing them slightly behind
the beat, and/or by making the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first eighth</NUMEX> note slightly longer than the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. This heightened the sense of groove, by playing against the beat rather
than on top of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Musicians</ENAMEX> often refer to a great rhythm section with terms
like "grooving," "popping," and "killing."

            All great jazz musicians
have an original approach to playing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> notes, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis Armstrong</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman Hawkins</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester Young</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Parker</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Evans</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX>
and on and on. They all play <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> notes in a unique way. They all have their
own "grooves." Jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> also experimented with several mood-altering
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>, and this also plays into a sense of "feeling groovy."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre White</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
