
   
   
      
         
             Account Overwrought

            Banking regulatory issues do not normally spark
interest, let alone outrage. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a quarter of a million</NUMEX> furious
comments flooded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Deposit Insurance Corp.</ENAMEX> to protest the "Know Your
Customer" regulations proposed by banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>. The regs
would have required that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> determine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of funds, create
client profiles based on transaction patterns, monitor accounts for deviations,
investigate irregularities, and report unexplained activities to federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>.

            "Tyrannical" and "Gestapo-like," declared the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. Also fanning the public outrage were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>
decried the invasion of privacy posed by the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">KYC</ENAMEX>" regs, as they came to be
known. Of all the correspondence, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 100</NUMEX> positive comments were
recorded, with "Go for it, and I'll see you in the place where there is no
darkness" counted as a laudatory sentiment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDIC</ENAMEX>.

            Heeding the outcry,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> introduced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> measures by late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> to kill the initiative. Also
running for cover were the plan's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDIC</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Comptroller of the Currency</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Thrift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supervision</ENAMEX>--which withdrew the proposal. Today, as the bank regulators
mop up the damage, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions need to be asked: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) What made the government
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> would stand for such gross intrusions into their privacy; and,
more important, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) doesn't the public know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> already have KYC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX>?

            By law, all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> snitch on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, reporting
to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> every currency transaction greater than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>. Between
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 million and 12 million</NUMEX> such reports are filled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. Against a backdrop
of fines and sanctions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> must also report all transactions greater than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> whenever a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> believes that the information is
"relevant to a possible violation of law or regulation." This includes
unexplained transactions that are "not the sort in which the particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> would normally be expected to engage" or that have no "apparent lawful
purpose." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 50,000</NUMEX> of these reports are filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. The federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</ENAMEX> aggregates the reports and makes them
available to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and to all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. This databank of
unsubstantiated allegations can be maintained indefinitely and is routinely
accessed by law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, who often go fishing for financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>. The information, however, only flows one way: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX> are prohibited from
disclosing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> that they tattled to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and an act of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> shields <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">financial institutions</ENAMEX> from liability suits. There is no
penalty for overreporting.

            Law enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> describe these detailed reports as essential in their battle
against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX>, and embezzlers, as well
as international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">money launderers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,613</NUMEX>
convictions for financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> fraud won in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> were initiated or
enhanced by suspicious activity reports.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> howled about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> and damned the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> for snooping, surely the fury was mock. Federal and state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> have passed new bank surveillance laws with an almost biennial
frequency since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bank Secrecy Act of 1970</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Legislators</ENAMEX> even boast about the
new laws at election time to prove that they're tough on crime. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> prodded federal banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to require
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> surveillance by overwhelmingly passing a bill that would have
forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to issue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> rules for comment within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 days</TIMEX>

            Taking the hint, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> composed the model KYC
regulations on its own initiative <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of research. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> innovations would have required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to develop programs to
verify the identities of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. It suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> make visual
checks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and corroborate phone numbers by calling new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> under
the guise of thanking them for their business.

            After completing a preliminary draft of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> rallied the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to follow its lead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDIC</ENAMEX>
now says that it had serious reservations about the proposal, the very proposal
that it nearly shepherded into law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> insists that it published the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> for comment--which is the way of all new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> regulations--to accommodate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> and to standardize the banking
regulations.

            Ordinarily, new financial regulations generate a
few comments from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the financial community, the odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, and the occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> touched off protests across
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bankers Association</ENAMEX> complained about "a new, vastly
more expansive burden of investigating all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to determine if anything
illegal has taken place." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Banking Association</ENAMEX> argued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> would
deter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> from opening bank accounts. Privacy groups
protested that they had not been invited to help design the new regs.

            But it was the
grass-roots opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX>, sparked in part by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian Party</ENAMEX>, whose
protest Web site steered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">171,268</NUMEX> e-mail complaints from netizens to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDIC</ENAMEX>,
that elevated the subject to the national agenda. Acknowledging that they had
lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KYC</ENAMEX> battle but won the regulatory war, the sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> made
this joint statement when they withdrew the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> regulations at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> hearings: "Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 15 years</TIMEX> banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and law
enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have forged a vital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> to fight financial
crime."

            To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> would have encroached on financial privacy
just as sensitivities about the Internet and other new technologies have
increased demands for privacy. Now that financial data are compiled and stored
digitally, it is cheap, easy, and tempting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to cast a wider
and wider financial dragnet to build increasingly intrusive computer profiles
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Attention must be paid lest the government further encroach on the
privacy of our data streams.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KYC</ENAMEX> flap is less about the loss of financial
privacy than it is about the public's loss of naiveté regarding the myth
of financial privacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want to believe that checking accounts are
sacrosanct, even though they haven't been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This spring</TIMEX>, the
government bolstered the myth of financial privacy by cynically folding its KYC
hand when its regulatory methods and practices were noisily scrutinized.

            In fact, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KYC</ENAMEX> was dying a very public death it
was thriving in the shadows. Thanks to current banking regulations, more than
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> currently maintain KYC programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Secrecy Act Examination Manual</ENAMEX> all but requires the adoption of "Know Your
Customer" programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> not heeding this "imperative" are subject to cease
and desist orders and to financial penalties of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of</NUMEX>
dollars.

         
      
   
