
   
   
      
         
            Hard <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Core Goes Soft</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, when
debates over the fate of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Civ</ENAMEX>" requirements raged at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> and
elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX> often pointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> as the
school where the old ideals of liberal education remained the most intact. Now
that bastion of tradition is itself under attack, not by deconstructionists and
postmodernists but by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>.

            The turmoil is over a
proposal to transform the old "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Core</ENAMEX>" curriculum, some version of which
has been in place since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, into the so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> Plan." The
university <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> wants to reduce the number of required courses in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humanities</ENAMEX>, sciences, and social sciences from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 to 15</TIMEX> and to remove a
longstanding foreign language requirement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> who
object to this change are also up in arms about a plan to expand the size of
the undergraduate student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX>, to 4,500.They further
object to efforts to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s image from superintellectual to smart
but fun. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way this makeover is to be accomplished is by changing the
school's handle from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> to just "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>" (to identify
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with the hit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> musical, perhaps).

            I should probably start by declaring my own hypocritical
feelings in the matter. I grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>) and thought seriously
about attending "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>" as it was known in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, before deciding
that it was a bit too cloistered and socially claustrophobic for my taste.
Instead, I went to a big-name Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. I suspect that I would
have got a superior education at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, but I'm still glad I didn't go there,
both because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is partly about leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and because I think it would
have been too hard and not enjoyable enough. Having rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX> in part
for the reasons that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are worried about, I can't easily argue that
they're being absurd.

            On the other hand, my
instinctive sympathies are entirely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> who are withholding
contributions until their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX> quits threatening to loosen up. What was
best about the undergraduate education I subsequently got at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> was what was
done in imitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">freshman year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Books</ENAMEX> program, structured
around discussion in small seminars. I think it's important that the beacon of
that kind of liberal education continue to exist, even though I didn't--and
still probably wouldn't--choose that education for myself. My old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty Peretz</ENAMEX>, used to say he wanted to found an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> for Hard-Line Christianity. Mine would be Nonalumni
Against Changing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>.

            As reports about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> culture wars go, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
story is refreshingly man-bites-dog. Instead of being driven by a bunch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenured radicals</ENAMEX>, the dumbing down of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s curriculum is being pushed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Trustees</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Sonnenschein</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> who casts the need to change as a simple issue of competition.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> wants to attract the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are offered more
"choice" about what to study by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of
his plans think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonnenschein</ENAMEX>, who came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, misunderstands the
culture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> he runs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> sign was his hiring as one of his vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> a marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> who said cringe-making things about
making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> more "fun" until he was driven out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>. The
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of reducing the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX>, physics, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
composition in the curriculum are liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, who
reject the consumer-market model of education.

            The best argument for
change is that it's the only cure for a looming financial problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion</ENAMEX> endowment is puny compared to the big Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>', and it
has run a small deficit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX>. The main reason its financial situation
is weaker than that of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> (though hardly desperate) is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
has a much higher proportion of unprofitable graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Undergraduates
are the cash <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> of higher education, both because they pay tuition and
because they later contribute money when they become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>. The unstated logic
of the changes is roughly as follows: To produce more revenue you need more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undergraduates</ENAMEX>. To get more high-quality undergraduates--meaning those with
high <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT scores</ENAMEX>--you need easier course requirements and a more appealing
atmosphere.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s revenues also suffer from the way undergraduates
are taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>--in small, participatory seminars led by full faculty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. It's retail rather than wholesale education and requires more faculty
than a lecture-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> has been holding
larger seminars and using more graduate teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>. Those protesting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Plan</ENAMEX> are really objecting as much to what has already happened in
this regard as to what's promised.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX> hopes to attract
more smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> by becoming an easier school that offers its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> less
individual attention? This isn't necessarily as nutty at is sounds. Consider
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, whose undergraduates have a higher average <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> score than those at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, and which gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as many applications precisely because it
has a reputation for being a blast and lacks any real requirements. The problem
with this logic in this situation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s whole history, tradition,
and reputation are on the other side of this divide. Intellectual intensity is
its great--and perhaps sole--selling point. Rebranding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> as a "fun" school deserves a place in the annals of marketing lunacy,
alongside "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weyerhaeuser</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> growing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Coke</ENAMEX>. It's like
trying to sell spinach as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious dessert</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> will never be fun,
except insofar as intellectual stimulation is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of pleasure.

            That does not, however, condemn it to an inexorable
decline. It's not clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s financial problem is all that serious.
But if it does need to woo more undergraduates, it would probably have better
luck emulating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> that has the
toughest core requirements after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s, is as trendy as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>--it admits
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 17 percent</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>, versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. Of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> has the advantage of being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> instead of in an isolated
enclave on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Side</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. But it also markets the strength of its
curriculum. It boasts about its set menu instead of apologizing for not being a
cafeteria.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> ought to do the same. What's valuable about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> isn't just that it's a high-caliber, difficult <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. It's that, in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of confusion about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ends</ENAMEX> and means of higher education, it has the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clearest</ENAMEX> and best notion of what constitutes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. This is isn't simply reading
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Books</ENAMEX> chosen by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Maynard Hutchins</ENAMEX>
and his sidekick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortimer Adler</ENAMEX>. It's a commitment to general education--a
sequence of courses intended to develop critical thinking in a wide variety of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disciplines</ENAMEX>--in opposition to early specialization. And it's the pedagogic
method that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> largely invented: small seminars based on original texts
and the examination of original works.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> not being as selective as its Ivy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> are, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> should quit worrying about it. Part of
what's appealing about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> is that it's more open and democratic than other
comparable elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Unconventionally gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, who didn't get top
grades in high school or who don't have perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores, stand a better
chance than they do elsewhere of getting in--and of being presented with the
highest level of intellectual challenge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> like to say that
it's harder to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> but harder to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. This makes it
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the few possible end runs around the meritocratic-credentialing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>,
whereby standardized test scores determine future opportunities. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> has
resisted institutional peer pressure for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>. It would be a shame to see
it finally give in and become more like everywhere else.

         
      
   
