
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Litigation Lover</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has spent
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> on legal fees; has been forced to answer repellent, invasive
questions under oath; has had every private embarrassment announced to the
world in the guise of "court documents"; and has watched helplessly as his
closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> have been barbecued and bankrupted by hostile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Anyone who had been stretched on this legal rack for so long would do
anything to prevent the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from being similarly tortured.

            So it's not surprising
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> just announced its opposition to the renewal of
the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> statute. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> believes that the president
and his top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> should not be subjected to the kind of endless,
borderless, remorseless investigation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has inflicted on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. And indeed, they should not be.

            Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> have said not one word about the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX>, borderless, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">remorseless</ENAMEX> lawsuits that afflict everyone else .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has learned a selfish lesson from Flytrap: I, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
should not have to suffer through a barrage of litigation and investigation.
But he has missed the real lesson: No one should have to endure what he
endured. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> as a parable of how the law,
misapplied, can undermine the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. In fact, it is a parable of how the
law, properly applied, can undermine anyone.

            "The case, with its
invasive, irrelevant discovery, with its incredible legal fees, with the way it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drew</ENAMEX> in innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystanders</ENAMEX> and ruined their lives, is exactly typical
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> legal system," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Olson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Excuse Factory</ENAMEX> .

            Even so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is not advocating any legal reform
larger than protecting himself. He continues to act as though lawsuits are
government by other means. From the beginning of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
favored policies that made litigation more invasive and expanded the right to
sue. And he still seems to believe that litigation is a substitute for
regulation and legislation.

            There is, as has been
widely noted, one pungent irony about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policies. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, he supported
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence Against Women Act</ENAMEX> at the behest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The act permits
much more expansive discovery into the sexual history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> in sexual
harassment and sex crimes cases. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> and legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> warned that the new
rules would be intrusive and prejudicial, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed the bill into law
anyway. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years later</TIMEX>, he found himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of the sort of voyeuristic,
nasty snooping that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">law</ENAMEX> authorizes.

            In most other matters, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has protected or
expanded the right to sue and the power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX> to make life miserable
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>. He has presided over the enlargement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Disabilities Act</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> successfully
petitioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designate asymptomatic</ENAMEX> HIV-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a
protected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADA</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, he and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> defeated
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> bill to penalize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> for frivolous lawsuits and to
impose "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> pays" rules. Also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> delighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> by vetoing a bill to limit punitive damages in product liability
cases.

            Since the scandal, the
administration has been no less enthusiastic about lawsuits. The administration
continues to push a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s bill of rights" that would guarantee the right
to sue your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is also trying to use lawsuits to make public policy.
In his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address, he announced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> would sue cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to recover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>, a
backdoor way to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> increase federal tobacco revenues without going
through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is lending tacit support to cities
suing gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, a backdoor way to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> make gun policy
without going through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            The result of this reliance on lawsuits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, his
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> calls "microgovernment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> are abdicating their duty
to write well-defined laws, leaving it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to make the rules
case-by-case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> end up deciding how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> treat their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, how
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> treat their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Microgovernment</ENAMEX> makes easy populist
politics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can take credit for giving people
"rights," then leave the actual work of making sense of those rights to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s bill of rights, for example, would deliver a poll-tested
victory to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> would absorb the responsibility of
handling the lawsuits spawned by the new rights.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s support for
better living through litigation is also based on interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> politics.
Trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> courted him and his party with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,
civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naderites</ENAMEX>--all avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> in
litigation--constitute a huge chunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s base. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> may also
be a true believer in government by lawsuit. He came of age when the civil
rights movement and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naderites</ENAMEX> were using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to challenge unjust
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and arrogant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. His intentions are honorable:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> shouldn't discriminate in hiring, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> shouldn't
deny care to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who need it. But he never asks whether lawsuits and
rights are the only way to prevent these bad things.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microgovernment</ENAMEX> does not seem to cost anything--no new
budget lines, no new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>--but of course it does. Financially, it
shuffles expenses from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to someone else, usually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being
sued. Politically, it's anti-democratic, replacing congressional and executive
branch decision-making. "It is a kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-card monte," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX>. "You
shift the responsibility to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> can't do
anything about." And it makes an already litigious society more so, afflicting
more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with onerous discovery, bottomless legal expenses, and
grotesque but legal invasions of privacy. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX> notes, has
far laxer discovery rules than any other developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is reluctant to challenge the law's tyranny.
During <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> conveniently abandoned their objections to
wide-ranging sex harassment litigation, endorsing broad discovery in order to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nail Clinton</ENAMEX>. But even those who insist that the legal system is out of control
are afraid to challenge it: Every time they have done so, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have trounced them, depicting them (with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>) as shills for
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that don't want to be accountable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.

            Can anything change <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s mind? After all, he
has suffered through legal hell once and has emerged unaffected. Maybe, just
maybe, if he were sued again ...

         
      
   
