
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Pushing
Tin
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of this film
offers an exhilarating peek into the high-pressure world of air traffic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controllers</ENAMEX>, but despite the best efforts of a choice ensemble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Cusack, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cate Blanchett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Bob Thornton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angelina Jolie</ENAMEX>), the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> by
the end. "[F]or a while, at least, the sheer journalistic energy of what we're
seeing grips us in a casually exotic way" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ). The trouble: The plot is horrendous and ends up with an
"obligatory traffic control emergency crisis" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ) that takes all the spice out of what had been an unusual study of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group dynamics</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> the trailer and clips from the film here [requires free registration].)

            

               
                  Election
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> rave: "The
best and brightest high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> since the groundbreaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heathers</ENAMEX> ... a nearly flawless little film" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese Witherspoon</ENAMEX> turns in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a spectacular</TIMEX> performance as a
ferociously ambitious goody-goody go-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">getter</ENAMEX> who's running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> council
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Broderick</ENAMEX> is the genial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who becomes irritated with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese</ENAMEX>'s smugness and tries to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the election. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> runoff that
results is a loose parody of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX> presidential election, which makes for "a
moral fable with rare comic bite" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Travers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ).
(
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> the film "exuberantly caustic." Visit
this site dedicated to the expecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witherspoon</ENAMEX> and her fiance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillippe</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lovers</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic Circle</ENAMEX>
                (Fine Line Features). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have a hard time
explaining just what it is they like so much about this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> of fate
and love, but they like it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maslin</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> "needn't really articulate what
makes it so haunting. The evidence is on the screen" (the New York
Times ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lest I</ENAMEX>, too, go round in circles trying to
convey the dense texture of this exquisite film, I'll simply say that [it]
seizes your mind and stays in your heart" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). The
story follows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> who meet at the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> and cycle in and out of each
other's lives through adulthood. Peppered with wordplay, startling visual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imagery</ENAMEX>, and near misses by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, the film has only one flaw,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, namely that all the fancy footwork verges on becoming too
self-conscious. (Visit the film's official site for a sample of the film's
peculiarities.)

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  Mule
Variations
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Waits</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epitaph</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Waits</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> album in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, which ditches the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">junkyard</ENAMEX> noise experimentation of his previous
releases for a blues approach, gets passable reviews from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Sone</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waits</ENAMEX> seems to have peaked as a songwriter with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rain Dogs</ENAMEX> ," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Ratliff</ENAMEX>, "and he's still writing outtakes from
that record" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ). Spin 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Vowell</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Waits</ENAMEX>'
coolie raps often feel a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fake</ENAMEX>, like he's working at having a good time."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hilburn</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> dissents, calling Mule
Variations "personal and accessible"; as does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billboard</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waits</ENAMEX> digs
deep and wide into his song psyche and pulls up material rooted in blues,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gospel</ENAMEX>, and cabaret music but delivered with the utmost originality." (Listen
to a track from the album here.)

            

               Event
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">100 th Birthday</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23, 1999</TIMEX>). The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centennial</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s birth is marked by the appearance of a biography of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">V</ENAMEX>쯴a
(Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Nabokov</ENAMEX>) ; a reissue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speak</ENAMEX>, Memory ; and a
celebration staged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vintage</ENAMEX> books, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">V</ENAMEX>쯴a for the details it reveals about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokovs</ENAMEX>' intense marriage--she was his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, typist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chauffeur</ENAMEX>, nursemaid, go-between, buffer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX>-catching
companion" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). But when you get down
to it, "this is really a potted biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Nabokov</ENAMEX>, told from an
unusual angle" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dirda</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">PEN</ENAMEX> celebration
featured readings by and about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokovs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Carol Oates</ENAMEX>, Dimitri
Nabokov, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">V</ENAMEX>쯴a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacy Schiff</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library</ENAMEX> is also getting in on the action with an exhibit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manuscripts</ENAMEX> and personal effects, such as his glasses and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX> net. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
to read a discussion on Speak, Memory and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">V</ENAMEX>쯴a in

                  Slate
               . This multimedia exhibit on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' Web site
includes recordings of him reading his work and a series of photos [free
registration required].)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passion, Fool of Fame</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benita Eisler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX> puts forth no new theories on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> or on his times as it retells
the juicy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of his life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Schulman</ENAMEX> complains in the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> that despite the excellent material, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisler</ENAMEX> "cannot capture" the
essence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX>'s power "because her earnestness misses his seductive
combination of modesty, irony, self-doubt and self-confidence." (For more on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX>, visit this site which includes a portrait <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> and links to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poets</ENAMEX>'
sites.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Lost &
Found
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). A "rancid little nothing of a movie"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) that's a grim, gross wannabe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers flick</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Spade</ENAMEX>. Thumbs down from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. 

                  eXistenZ
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dimension Films</ENAMEX>). Good reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Cronenberg</ENAMEX>'s
virtual reality flick that covers the same ground as the more popular The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Jason Leigh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> as a video game <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> who hides in a
game of her own devising. Features a device called a "gristle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>."

            

               Magazine
            

            

               
                  Nylon
               . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supermodel Helena Christensen</ENAMEX> starts her own
magazine; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are mildly interested. It boasts interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike D</ENAMEX> and a layout far funkier than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s mag, but critics
agree creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christensen</ENAMEX> is "without a doubt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s biggest
selling point" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Week</ENAMEX> ).

            Find a
movie playing near you on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hideous Kinky</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Goodbye, Lover</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLC Punk</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girl Who Loved Tom Gordon</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Prayer for the Dying</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Nan</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Go ;

               
                  Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dreamlife of Angels</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Never Been Kissed</ENAMEX>;
               

               
                  
                     Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metroland</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ground Beneath Her Feet</ENAMEX> , by Salman
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iceman Cometh</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Neill</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX>
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>
               

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Things I Hate About You</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Walk on the Moon</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie- - <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Out-of-Towners</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Financier</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strouse</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Life and My Life With the</ENAMEX>

                  Times , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Frankel</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mod Squad</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EdTV</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dates</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Futurama</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- All Too Human: A Political Education</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief of Unbearable Urges</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englander</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
