
   
   
      
         
             The Wages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>

            A seemingly honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>,
partially backed by circumstantial evidence, accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of having
raped her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> denies it but refuses to say where he
was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> believes her but seems not to care. The opposition
party declines to press the issue, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> concede it will go away. How
has such cynicism come to pass?

            This is a lesson in the
consequences of spin. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and enemies
played a game. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> conspired to drive him from office. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
conspired to protect him. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> did and said whatever it deemed necessary
to capture public opinion. The game ended, but the spins remain engraved in our
consciousness. Now they are clouding our perception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accusation</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. It's just more politics.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX>, care more
about politics than about truth. Together, they have ruined his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX>'
credibility. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> have dismissed every charge against him as the
product of a right-wing propaganda machine, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> have done
everything possible to prove that theory right. Rather than let each woman
decide whether to come forward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> dragged her onstage.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> said nothing about sexual harassment until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> outed her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years later</TIMEX>. Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> financed and
managed her lawsuit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> taped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, tricked her into saving
the stained dress, and ultimately fed her to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and to
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>.

            Likewise, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> didn't start pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> onstage until he ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Eventually, they fed her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, who sent private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to her home, subpoenaed her, and dumped her name and story into
the public record based on hearsay, disregarding her denials. Even after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
chose not to pursue her story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> used her secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
interview--which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had been given no chance to rebut--to persuade their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to vote for impeachment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
to air its interview with her. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Channel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> pushed the story into the public record, and the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page blew it open. To prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
had used Broaddrick against her will, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> used her against her will.
Why did she finally tell her story? Because "all of these stories are floating
around," she said, "and I was tired of everybody putting their own spin on
it."

            With equal cynicism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s surrogates used these
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> to distract the public from his treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
They dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> as a right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stooge</ENAMEX> and discredited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
investigation as a political "war." While <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> discounted impeachment as a
partisan jihad, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> locked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to prove them right. In so doing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> squandered their credibility. Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stands accused of
rape, they sit helplessly mute.

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are burying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story under the usual political dirt. On
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Organization for Women</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> scoffed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> wouldn't heed attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, who's been married <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and lied under oath." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ,
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bimbo-leak plumber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> argued, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>
starts out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> [in] the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>, and now this on the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page. ... We have a history of right-wing pressure
tactics to push these into play without verification."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. It's just more sex.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged sexual offenses have progressed
along a spectrum of violence, from consensual adultery (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>) to unwanted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solicitation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>) to unwanted groping (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>) to rape
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>). But his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, intent on proving a pattern of behavior and
destroying him with whichever scandal was at hand, lumped them together and
overplayed the lesser charges. Their latest gaffe was to spend a year
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecuting Clinton</ENAMEX> for lying about consensual adultery, while the Willey
investigation remained offstage.

            The point of the rape
charge is that it's different. Yet once again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are lumping it
into a "pattern." "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story is believable because of its wretched
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">familiarity</ENAMEX>," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX>, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "piggish
behavior" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as evidence that he could be a "brute." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>-fisted moralist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> huffed, "How many times does this
kind of thing have to come up? ... We have heard, seen this pattern before."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> chimed in, "Is this out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>? Please." On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> touted a poll showing that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
"think the allegations represent a pattern of behavior."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> are content to subsume the allegation
of violence into a pattern of sex and thereby dismiss it as immaterial.
Stephanopoulos rephrased the rape charge as a question about the relevance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' private lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Jeffords</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>, dismissed the story as
"a private matter," though he later apologized. "I'd like to see us get on to
the issues," replied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D.</ENAMEX>, when asked
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s allegation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Wellstone</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, used the same dodge on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> : "Can't we focus on
issues that are important to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?"

            Already, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissolving Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story into a pattern of philandering. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> called it another allegation of "boorish and immoral sexual
behavior." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> Late Edition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> cited its "uneasy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">familiarity</ENAMEX>." And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> worried that in
pursuing it, the press would again be accused "of asking too many questions ...
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s life." Framed this way, the story is dying.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. It can't be proved.
            

            Not content to disgrace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> morally, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adversaries</ENAMEX> tried to inflate his cover-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair into crimes
and impeachable offenses. Not only did this weak poison fail to kill him, it
strengthened his immune system. It raised the threshold for inquiring into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal behavior and for obliging him to answer questions. If an
offense can't be prosecuted and proved in court, it no longer matters.

            This mindset has crippled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> ways. First, it has induced a sense of helplessness
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> charges that can't be legally proved. "There is no way we'll ever know
what all the facts are," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> argued on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> . "What we have to
do now is move on." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crossfire co-host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Press</ENAMEX> agreed: "There's no way
to prove she's telling the truth. ... We'll never know." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Keller</ENAMEX> added: "The merits of the allegations are probably
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unknowable</ENAMEX>. Legally, it doesn't seem to go anywhere." This notion that the
charge "doesn't go anywhere" legalizes and objectifies the investigative
process, absolving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of responsibility to pursue the question.

            Likewise, the word "unknowable" disguises the fact that the
merits of the charges are not only knowable; they are known by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> has now spoken. Shouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? When asked this question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>
replied: "I don't think you're going to hear anything from him, nor do I think
it's going to lend any new information. Let's move on." Thus the passive
prediction that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will successfully lie, stonewall, or evade the question
glosses over whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have a duty to ask it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has a duty to
answer it.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the legal
framework shifts the burden from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX>. When asked on Late
Edition whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was obliged to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s allegation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, said that was "up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>" and called the
charge "effectively unprovable." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> fumed
that those who dared to pursue the question would "tear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives apart
based on a plausible allegation." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Estrich</ENAMEX> demanded "a higher standard" for such
an inquiry. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX> defended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s silence
as a legal tactic to avoid a libel suit.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, this framework lends a high-minded legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> to a
low-minded excuse for ignoring the story. Instead of admitting to scandal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fatigue</ENAMEX> and fear of exasperating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> observe
that the "statute of limitations" on the rape charge has expired. A legitimate
reason not to prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thus becomes a bogus reason not to question
him. "It's not that we're tired, and it's not that we're lacking in moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outrage</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrich</ENAMEX> asserted. But "unless you're ready to reopen the impeachment
process ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> wants to move on." The bipartisan movement to kill the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> law provides additional legal cover for this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX>. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> has come for us to close the books," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> argued.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, the notion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are responsible
for all inquiry lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> pass the buck. Upon leaving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "will be subject to criminal prosecution just as any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> would be," observed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wellstone</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, refused to say whether anything should be done about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s
story: "I'm really not involved in that at all. ... The proper authorities
ought to handle it." Conversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> predicted that the story would
die "because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> don't want to touch" it, and fellow Late
Edition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> added, "There's no legal process continuing
with it. There's no impeachment process. I don't see what keeps this story
alive."

            Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was
never in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>. Maybe they had consensual sex.
Maybe what seemed coercive to her seemed merely rough to him. Maybe he lost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and has regretted it ever since. But the bottom line is that he's
giving no answers, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> jaded by spin is giving him a pass. It's less
and less clear that actions have consequences. And it's more and more clear
that ideas do.

         
      
   
