
   
   
      
         
            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With the Show</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the pleasures of
working in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> or film is hanging out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and sundry showbiz
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exhibitionists</ENAMEX>. True, they tend to have the emotional autonomy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-olds</TIMEX>,
but they're less of a labor to "read" than ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mortals</ENAMEX>: It's their
business--you might say their existential orientation--to communicate their
thoughts and feelings in an engaging fashion every millisecond . I
mention this because the first thing that struck me about the much-hyped
satirical comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EdTV</ENAMEX> , which purports to show the effect of TV cameras
brought into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, is that almost no one on-screen seems
ever to have met a real (i.e., nonshowbiz) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, let alone to be able to
embody <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Howard</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> have
spent much of their lives in the business, and I'd trust them to depict the
anxieties of TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and the madness of network board meetings. I'd trust
them to skewer the vanity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>. What I don't
trust is their ability to convey what it's like simply to have a meal with a
loved one or to walk across a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> or to wake up from a sound sleep without
the self-consciousness that comes from a constant proximity to media. When they
project their particular self-consciousness onto society as a whole, the upshot
is a sour, self-congratulatory muddle.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EdTV</ENAMEX> is based
on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> that no one I know has seen called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XIX</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airwaves</ENAMEX> . (The mock imperial title alone suggests more wit than
the whole of its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EdTV</ENAMEX> takes off from the
increasingly less outlandish idea that a cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> might, in the face of
declining ratings, decide to have its cameras traipse around after an
"ordinary" person <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> a day--a scenario somewhat different from last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX> , in which the cameras were hidden, the universe
manufactured, and the TV protagonist unwitting. There is already something like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EdTV</ENAMEX>--albeit with one camera--on the Internet, and the number of auditioners
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real World</ENAMEX> and for a spot on various "trash" talk shows
suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has no shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exhibitionists</ENAMEX> who'd love to
be "validated" by TV cameras. (On these terms, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is the most
valid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> on the planet.) Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of a gung-ho <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Topping</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen DeGeneres</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> holds auditions in public places
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and comes up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Pekurny</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew McConaughey</ENAMEX>), a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> video store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> who is cute and unthreatening and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unformed</ENAMEX>. ("I have a dream, I just don't know what it is yet.")

            The problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EdTV</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>'s life looks and
sounds like a tedious sitcom before the TV cameras ever show up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConaughey</ENAMEX>'s
manner is TV-talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bashful</ENAMEX>. (Is this supposed to be the point? That he's
deformed by television before he's ever on television? I don't think so.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>'s
rambunctious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> is played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Harrelson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>,
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Kirkland</ENAMEX>, who could never be anything but an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>.
His wheelchair-bound stepdad is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Landau</ENAMEX>, who makes sitcom-style, raunchy
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> wisecracks. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s squeeze--and, later, his own--is Jenna
Elfman, of television's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX> . At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, the door swings
open and there stands <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hopper</ENAMEX>. "What an inspired touch!" I thought. "A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lazy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> shows up to explain to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> the secrets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Strasberg</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Method"</ENAMEX>--how to be "private in public"--just like on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bravo's Inside the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Actors Studio</ENAMEX> !" It turned out that this wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hopper</ENAMEX>, however, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hopper</ENAMEX> in the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>'s long-lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--and few things can dispel
the illusion of watching real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than a hack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> feigning naturalness via
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mannerisms</ENAMEX> recycled from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery Clift</ENAMEX>.

            Before the movie even gets going (it doesn't seem to
begin for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX>), it's clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> and his frequent collaborators
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell Ganz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babaloo Mandel</ENAMEX> are too deep inside the mentality that they're
trying to satirize to come up with anything fresh. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EdTV</ENAMEX> has none of the
edge of such "mockumentaries" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Life</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>) or
This Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinal Tap</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>) or even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX> ,
all of which exploit in hilarious fashion the tension between just being and
performing for a camera. Where the filmmakers are most comfortable is back in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, so they throw in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RuPaul</ENAMEX>, and a panel of repugnant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pundits</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Plimpton</ENAMEX>, and Arianna
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffington</ENAMEX>--to discuss the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> phenomenon." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are so in
love with their own hip self-consciousness that it's a wonder they don't
feature film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> discussing their movie.

            As it turns out,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EdTV</ENAMEX> isn't really about the impact of television on ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
It's about the problems of being famous--like how you can never get any
privacy. In common with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX> , the film eventually evolves
into a melodramatic revolt against a repressive corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX>, here an
executive (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Reiner</ENAMEX>) who doesn't want to turn off the cameras and leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed</ENAMEX>
alone when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>'s life is in a shambles but his ratings are high. ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
Show took a higher, more metaphorical route; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EdTV</ENAMEX> , liberation
comes down to exposing the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> has a penile implant.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reiner</ENAMEX> has the
fatted, self-centered TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exec</ENAMEX>'s demeanor down pat, but the movie degrades him
while holding the same attitude toward human beings that he has. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>'s
unconvincing life runs its increasingly public course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> cuts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Couple, a Gay Couple</ENAMEX>, an Old Couple, a bunch of Single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX>--who wince at him cutting his toenails or cheer on his conquests. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> polls show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The People</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly prefer a flagrantly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insincere</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hurley</ENAMEX>) to the sweet and awkward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elfman</ENAMEX>)
with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> has found love, you have to ask<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Are The People</ENAMEX> supposed to be
shallow boobs? Or is this just how the world looks from certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>
ZIP codes?

            A more true-to-life--alas--version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EdTV</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
Dates , a microbudget documentary directed by and starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myles Berkowitz</ENAMEX>.
At the beginning of the film, now in wide release, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkowitz</ENAMEX>--thirtyish and
divorced and unable to get his directing career off the ground--explains that
he has received a sum of money from a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> (heard cursing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> via a hidden tape recorder) to go on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> dates with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> attractive women
and thereby capture something unglimpsed in commercial movies about the single
life, the nature of love, etc., etc., ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nauseam</ENAMEX>. All that is captured, of
course, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berkowitz</ENAMEX>'s ambition to put himself in your face: He comes out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">20 Dates</ENAMEX> with a trophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> and a feature film in major release, but
absolutely no insight into dating, love, or human chemistry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, ends up cringing and squirming on behalf of his dates, some of whom
are appalled to the point of violence and litigation by the revelation of a
hidden camera. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> had the camera concealed from them--both
sued.) The masochistic fascination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dates</ENAMEX> is something that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EdTV</ENAMEX> can only dream about, but I wouldn't exactly call it
entertainment; I found myself wanting to apologize on behalf of obnoxious
heterosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> the world over. I also wondered: What about those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, some of them pretty, bright, and articulate, who admirably recoiled from
this clown when they discovered they were fodder for his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> ambitions?
When they saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berkowitz</ENAMEX> on the big screen with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>
logo behind him, did they think, "Wow, I really missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> on this one. I
should never have let him get away"?

            The best reason for seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces of</ENAMEX>
Nature --a sporadically funny but uneasily revisionist screwball comedy in
which straight-arrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX> is tempted from his imminent nuptials by free
spirit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock</ENAMEX> and assorted natural disasters--is a scene in which the
heartsick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock ex-boyfriend</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Strickland</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affleck</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> (Maura
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tierney</ENAMEX>) sings an a cappella version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Collins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Against All Odds</ENAMEX> (Take a
Look <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">At Me Now</ENAMEX>)" into her ear in the middle of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. The gesture is as
embarrassing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> as anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EdTV</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dates</ENAMEX> ,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strickland</ENAMEX> sings with such quavering soulfulness that the bit lifts up and
floats out of the movie like a weird but beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX>. I was going to
mention this scene anyway, as the picture's highlight; I dwell on it because
word comes that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strickland</ENAMEX>, a regular on the sitcom Suddenly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> , has been found dead in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, apparently having hanged himself.
It's no consolation, but he has left behind an exquisite moment in film.

         
      
   
