
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Refugee Showdown</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> engaged
in name-calling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> over the handling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> crisis. In
an exclusive interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solana</ENAMEX> said that after much debate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> had agreed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> should be airlifted to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>
reported on its front page that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> are "at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loggerheads</ENAMEX>" on the issue and insist that they can absorb no more than a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX> ousted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are heading for a showdown over which of them will accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>,
how many, at what cost, and on what terms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> 's
op-ed page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polly Toynbee</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> government policy, saying
"it's not body bags the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> fears at the moment, it's live Kosovan
bodies swamping our shores." In another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
was condemned for its initial refusal, subsequently reversed, to accept any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, with reference to the "similar attitude struck during the Bosnian
war," and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> was attacked for "drastically reducing the numbers it had
been expected to take."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s leading newspaper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> , said in an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has "good and solid reasons" for
not wanting to accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>--that to do so would be to condone "ethnic
cleansing" and to play <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s game. But it
added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lionel Jospin</ENAMEX>'s position would be clearer and less
subject to the suspicion that he was only worried about reopening the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
immigration debate, if he carried his argument to its logical conclusion. This
being that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> can only be returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> if there is some kind of
intervention on the ground. "The defence of the right of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to return
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is a slogan empty of meaning if one continues to exclude categorically the
committal of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>," the editorial concluded.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solana</ENAMEX> in his
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> ,<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> stand united
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s outright rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s cease-fire offer, and the idea
of sending in ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> seems to be gathering ever stronger support. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secretary-General Solana</ENAMEX> stressed the limitations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> offensive. "One
can't do miracles with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> who belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have
parliaments," he said. "One has to go forward step by step. General [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Wesley</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, furthermore, has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> constrictions: to safeguard the lives of the pilots
and to guarantee that there is no collateral damage. So this is not a war in
the classic sense but a military campaign." The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s promised respite from "hounding,
killing and raping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovars</ENAMEX> does not begin to meet alliance requirements." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> should keep in mind the "infamy of what is happening and hold true to
the principles of democracy, individual liberty and the rule of law which its
founding treaty proclaims."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> papers continued to wrestle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> (they were
not published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>) with the analogies between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s wartime debt to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. "As a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, I am sure it
is my obligation to come to the aid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elie</ENAMEX>
the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> . "Some say that when we, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, needed the world's intervention, no one came to our help. But does that
mean we must be indifferent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? On the contrary. What the world did not do
then, it is doing now." Yet he dismissed comparisons between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX>: "What is happening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> is a
genocidal plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is committing grave crimes, but the comparison of
other disasters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> has led to the diminution of its significance.
Every disaster has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> and every criminal a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>."

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> gave top billing
to domestic stories, especially the arrest warrant for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX> on charges of money laundering, they
covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> crisis in a manner often strongly critical of the
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestia</ENAMEX> said the West was losing its image as a
"wise, democratic, and civilized collective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rather</ENAMEX>, as represented by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, the West is doing insane things, contrary to the fundamental principles
of democracy." "Allegedly for the sake of their own salvation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> are being crushed from the air along with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montenegrans</ENAMEX>.
Trying to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>' mass exodus to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> did nothing but
provoke it by its air strikes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>'s civilizing role seems to involve the
destruction, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s most beautiful
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. ... A game with no rules has started in the world, and one beyond the
limits of law, too. There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> step from this to the apocalypse," it
said.

            Finally, an apology: In
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, I mistakenly referred to an article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Globe and Mail</ENAMEX>
attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> air strikes as an editorial, when it was in fact a signed
piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Gee</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
