
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Students Have Always Been Violent</ENAMEX>

            Judging by the histrionic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> massacre
coverage you'd think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are by nature innocent, free of violent or
sexual thoughts until corrupted by our culture. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have traditionally
been safe. That the recent spate of killings is unprecedented.

            History says otherwise. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every era</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX>--especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>--have been unruly and destructive. As
late as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th century</TIMEX>, those "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>" we now call teen-agers
were considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. And preteens swore, drank, had sex, even dueled with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. If school violence wasn't a problem back then, it's only because few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.

            In colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, most young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were
taught at home. Those who attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> were just as prone to be disorderly
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teachers</ENAMEX> kept problem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in line with corporal
punishments that seem positively barbaric <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: They tied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to whipping
posts and beat them or branded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for their crimes--a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">T</ENAMEX>" for thievery, a
"B" for blasphemy. Occasionally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were put to death.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branding</ENAMEX> fell from favor
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the18 th century</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were still flogged or tied to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">chairs</ENAMEX> (for more on corporal punishment, click ). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 19</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Mann</ENAMEX> reported that he saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">328</NUMEX> floggings in one
school during the course of a week. As the principles of humanitarianism spread
and the era of mass schooling arrived, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> and others replaced or supplemented
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> academies with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>-supported "common <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>," which admitted
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from all walks of life. (Later, attendance become compulsory.)
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilded Age</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX> flooded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, public
elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> proliferated. Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressives</ENAMEX> championed the view
of adolescence as a stage of childhood, and high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of which
opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1820s</TIMEX>) multiplied as well.

            It appears that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> meant more violence. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1837</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> noted that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> had to be shut down
because of disciplinary problems. In most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, keeping order took
precedence over teaching. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1851</TIMEX> likened the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
school to "the despotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of a military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, where
the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were bigger and less docile, violence was even worse.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton University</ENAMEX>, to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> example, witnessed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> major riots
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1800 and 1830</TIMEX>, including the burning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1802</TIMEX> and a rash
of campus explosions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1823</TIMEX> that caused <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to be expelled.

            School violence persisted
into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20 th century</TIMEX>, taking different forms according to the
climate of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. In politically charged times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> became violent in
the name of political causes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, for example, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
introduced a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon</ENAMEX>" system to deal with an influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rebelled</ENAMEX>--literally. Between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000 and 3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren picketed</ENAMEX> and stoned
P.S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">171</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> and attacked nonstriking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX>. Similar riots
erupted across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, resulting in furious battles between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> mobs and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. Likewise, the civil rights movement and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> protests
brought different forms of "political" violence to places ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Central High</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> to Kent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>.

            More politically sedate times didn't translate into student
acquiescence, however. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, urban strife and
suburban anomie gave rise to school violence of the sorts broadly rendered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> films Rebel Without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cause</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackboard</ENAMEX>
Jungle . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> waxed hysterical over "juvenile delinquency," as the
vogue phrase had it--alienated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> unaccountably sullen in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bountiful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Though history had recorded public concern over
bands of violent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> ever since the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>, the fear
of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>" (a term coined in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>) caught the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s fancy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
magazine headlined a story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teen-agers on the Rampage</ENAMEX>," which detailed a
weeklong outbreak of violence in high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> held hearings on the delinquency epidemic, calling comic-book artists
to testify about whether their drawings inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to violence.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth</ENAMEX> rebelliousness
surged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. While crime grew overall, juvenile crime grew faster.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sociologists</ENAMEX>, social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and policy wonks turned their attention en masse
to offenses ranging from vandalism to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>-related crime, from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use to
student-upon-student assaults. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> implemented safety plans, bringing in
adult hall monitors and setting up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> for hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> grievances. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> hired professional security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>--and later adopted the surveillance
cameras, metal detectors, locker searches, and other measures more commonly
seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>. But a major study conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> confirmed what experience
had been teaching. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teen-agers</ENAMEX> were more likely to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of crime at school
than anywhere else.

            If student violence has now been a major concern for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades now</TIMEX>, what seems to distinguish '90s violence is the suburban- or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural-school</ENAMEX> massacre. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Paducah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonesboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>; and now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>--in each case, young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, armed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, committed multiple murders in or near the school
itself. To be sure, similar atrocities have occurred in the past. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>, a
55-year-old school-board <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> detonated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> bombs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>,
schoolhouse, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. And to be sure, the string of recent killings
in fact reveals nothing, statistically speaking, about our society. Yet they
remind us that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> skyrocketed in the '80s
and while tailing off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> remains far higher than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> past.
According to , the growing trend of violent altercations ending in death is
attributable "almost entirely" to the proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            History makes it clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>
are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> to violent impulses. There have always been, and always will
be, maladjusted or deranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who unleash those impulses. That they do
so is inevitable. How they do so may be within our control.

         
      
   
