
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Guns Stun</ENAMEX> Europeans

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> massacre near
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> supplanted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> as the lead story in the late editions of almost all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, which carried the usual expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
bewilderment over the lack of serious gun control in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> said that even the mass murder at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High School</ENAMEX> was
unlikely to lead to any change in the law. "[S]o extravagant is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
concept of 'freedom,' and so deep-rooted is the pollution of firearms of all
kinds throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, that there is little prospect that even this
latest monstrosity will provoke a meaningful shift in public attitudes," the
paper said. It noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had "mouthed the necessary words of
horror and condolence," but commented that it was "hard for the rest of the
world to take these entirely seriously, when repetition seems almost
inevitable." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Standard</ENAMEX> splashed the story on its front page
with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">They Did It for Hitler's Birthday</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> observed
in a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are "frankly disbelieving" when told
how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> outlawed hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the wake of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> massacre in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dunblane</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. "They argue, rightly, that no such sweeping legislation could be
passed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," it said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also noted that the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rifle Association</ENAMEX> faced "the considerable embarrassment" of holding its annual
convention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, very close to the scene of the tragedy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> remains the other main story
around the world. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s coverage included an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shimon Peres</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, to mark his arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
for the first informal annual meeting of past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>.
He wrote that he had been asked to be available to mediate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
conflict but had replied that he would only do so "if and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are
truly determined to seek a political solution." He said, "It doesn't seem to me
that this is the mood at the moment, but it might be very soon." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peres</ENAMEX> called
the war an "absurd" one that should never have started, but added, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> can't
deny that its purpose is fundamentally of a moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. It is not a
political or a power game. The civilized world is simply tired of racism,
discrimination and atrocities."

            In an interview in
Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo D'Alema</ENAMEX> offered
rather qualified praise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. He is "an intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Alema</ENAMEX>
said, but "I don't know if he saw all the traps that had been set for him in
the war." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, whose coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is divided about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, said that once the war was over there should be reflection about "the
criteria for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> intervention. ... The right of humanitarian interference is
legitimate, but we must ask ourselves about its limits."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX>'s L a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa</ENAMEX>
                led its front page with an appeal for
peace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Orthodox Patriarch Alexis</ENAMEX> II. It said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patriarch</ENAMEX> has criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> but has asked "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, like
those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>, to halt military operations." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> has expressed the hope that the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> hierarchy "may lead to peace and the end of aggression."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> complained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
in its main front-page story that in western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> is keeping its
promises toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. "Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,824</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> who had arrived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,937</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two-thirds</NUMEX> of the total--have come
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>," it said. In an accompanying front-page comment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said:
"Typically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX> the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> said it would take
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>--and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> they are here. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> generosity? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>
efficiency? Or stupidity, a continuing feeling of anticipated guilt that other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> quietly smile at and exploit<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> led its front page with a question: "A month
of war, with what results?" Its answer, in summary, was that the offensive has
weakened <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s military potential but has failed to deter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> or
prevent "ethnic cleansing" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has been
driven out, and diplomatic initiatives are at a dead end," it said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
press focused again on the prospects of a ground war, with the conservative
tabloid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX> splashing the claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> is now planning for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. It said that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since the
bombing began <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX> "held out the prospect of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> going into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> before a ceasefire has been agreed with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>." But it added the rider that "this will only happen when the back of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> has been broken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>'s air power."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> condemned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> for its ecological effects.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial: "There is
nothing humanitarian or liberating about the intense bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>,
which has created even more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> and resulted in widespread ecocide." The
paper devoted its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> editorial
to the diplomatic significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s jewelry. Under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lapel Diplomacy</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that "her sparklers--the brooches
she wears while negotiating knotty issues of geo-politics--are as much a
statement as the press releases after various meetings with, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>." It went on: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The American eagle brooch</ENAMEX> says
without a word being exchanged that she is in hawkish, combative mood; the
cherub brooch betokens the spirit of innocent accommodation; and the red and
gold balloon brooch denotes a festive moment. On all other counts, Ms <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>
is thought prone to tough-talk, but her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brooches</ENAMEX> seem to tell a different, more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nuanced</ENAMEX> story."

             

         
      
   
