
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Losers</ENAMEX>

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> filled their front pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> with what now appear
to be premature post-mortems on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> compiled a list of the war's winners and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> ("[His] reputation as a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> on the international
stage will be enhanced. And his commitment to the morality of the conflict will
win him several saintly points."); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Shea</ENAMEX> ("<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockney</ENAMEX> accent has been forced to explain away an array of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> mistakes--in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. While his rhetorical denunciations of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> got more extreme, ... he rarely lost his temper."); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> ("The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> owes it a debt of gratitude and it stands to gain economically from
long-term international commitment to the area."); and construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> ("Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobo</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> may emulate
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, who both committed suicide."); <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Apache</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim Rugova</ENAMEX>
("How can the bookish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s independence movement live down the
shame of being shown on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> TV with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>? ... [H]e could be bumped off
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>."); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> ("It has suffered from loss of trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>,
and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> are unlikely to leave for some time."); and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> ("The costs of putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> on the ground will be a major
drain on resources. Then there is the cost of reconstruction: like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>,
most of the money will have to come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. Ultimately, that
means from our pockets."). No mention was made of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">estimated 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> killed in the conflict nor of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,200</NUMEX> civilian
fatalities.

            Others
given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX>'s laurels included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Observer</ENAMEX> as having "saved its reputation and credibility,
gaining time to improve its effectiveness as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guarantor</ENAMEX> of peace"; and the new
world order celebrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Marr</ENAMEX>'s column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
has happened is a decisive and perhaps terminal defeat for an older <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, a
place of tribal hatreds, double-headed eagles, flaming swords and obscure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">martyrs</ENAMEX>. A better world order survives, symbolised by those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> faces looking after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>."

            An
op-ed
column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> drew parallels between the plight of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> displaced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> ... in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>." The lessons learned from these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are that "[t]he <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> must begin reconstructing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> society now,
without delay, even before they make or find their way into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> itself and
face the immense task of rebuilding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>'s decimated infrastructure and
housing stock. ... The most important goals are to encourage self-help and to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heal</ENAMEX> shattered identities. Both are crucial for preventing dependency and
building self-confidence." (See 
                  Slate
               's on how the
Kosovar/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> parallel disturbs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.)

            
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> expressed disappointment at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s failure to play a significant
role in international diplomacy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he development has served
as a sobering reminder of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s inability to play a meaningful political role
in the ethnic dispute." A foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> attempted to save face by
claiming, "There is no reason to feel belittled because I don't think, for
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has played a major role, either."

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s voting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, the first free elections in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>, got an optimistic boost from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>. "Despite predictions of chaos, the
campaign period has been festive and relatively free of violence. And the mass
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, remarkably free to report on shortcomings in election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>,
have been reasonably effective in their role as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdogs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> ...
is not obviously trying to manipulate the electoral results, and the military
appears to be acting in a neutral manner. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hundreds</ENAMEX> of social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are
actively involved in voter education and election monitoring, an unprecedented
mobilisation of civil society."

            The
multiculti redesign of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane fleet</ENAMEX> has been scrapped. Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> commissioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> from around the world to provide
abstract "world images" for the rudders to replace the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> flag. The
designs (click here for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>), which included images based on Delft
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pottery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">calligraphy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> waves, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cockerel</ENAMEX> (but not
British <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and chips--a design glorifying the national <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> was rejected by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BA</ENAMEX>), were popular with everybody except the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at home, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
Times . "[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>]esign changes need to be introduced sensitively. Most
travellers have a keen instinct for survival when it comes to flying and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BA</ENAMEX>'s
traditional image helped to underline its reputation for reliability," said a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial. "The flag signalled that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s reputation
was on the line, that the wings would stay attached to the fuselage and there
would be enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> to complete the journey. The ethnic tails suggested an
altogether trendier image." The rebranding campaign, which cost BA more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$95 million</NUMEX>, will be scrapped and the tail fins repainted with a design based
on the original "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Jack</ENAMEX>" flag used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horatio Nelson</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trafalgar</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1805</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
