
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Mod
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Squad</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM-UA</ENAMEX>). Vicious pans for this remake of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968-73</TIMEX> TV
show <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delinquents</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Danes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Epps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giovanni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ribisi</ENAMEX>) pushed into police undercover work. "It could be the capper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> prime-time special on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World's Most Inept Movies "</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Corliss, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) ... "really, really dumb" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who
"miraculously 'solve' the crime with a tape recorder and a lot of bad driving"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kridler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> ) ... "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the lamest films [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>]
ever has foisted upon the world" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ) ...
"torturously boring" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Van Gelder</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) ...
"almost unreleasable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). And to add insult to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">injury</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> uses the expression
"rumpy-pumpy" in his review for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Gave At First Sight a Good Review</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, correctly
foreseeing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> would be desperate for advertising blurbs on this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, pumps the thing up: It's "a great-looking picture that zips along with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX>, light on its feet." (Check
out this archive of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Danes</ENAMEX> photos.)

            

               
                  EdTV
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). Mainly positive reviews
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Howard Truman Show -ish</ENAMEX> comedy. In this one, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew McConaughey</ENAMEX>), knows what's going on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say it's not as subtle as
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Truman Show</ENAMEX> , but it's funnier: "There's a nice overlay of goofiness
in the satire" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> calls it "a grab bag that's both amusing and frustrating.
Simultaneously inspired and contrived, clever and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> self-consciousness about stardom and the price of fame a tad too
navel-gazing; most find the movie pretty charming, especially the twangy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConaughey</ENAMEX>'s performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>
this interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConaughey</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in

                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">20 Dates</ENAMEX>
               
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are unanimously repulsed by Myles
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkowitz's</ENAMEX> documentary about his attempts to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>. He films a
series of dates, sometimes secretly. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> identify with the one who
stabs him in the hand when she finds out what's going on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee Graham</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> calls the film "excruciating," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkowitz</ENAMEX> "the biggest
jerk you're likely to see in a movie this year." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justine Elias</ENAMEX> of the
Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> compares him to "an obnoxious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year-old</TIMEX> who believes
everything he does is fascinating and adorable." Somehow in the course of the
film he manages to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who'll continue the relationship, and the two
are allegedly now engaged. 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Edelstein</ENAMEX> says of the film: "I
found myself wanting to apologize on behalf of obnoxious heterosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> the world over." (Read the rest of his review .)

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  Futurama
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 p.m.</TIMEX>; starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6, Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 p.m.</TIMEX>). Mainly nice,
loyal reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Groening</ENAMEX>'s new animated sitcom; a few "this ain't no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> " complaints. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the sci-fi spoof set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 3000</TIMEX>
is more visually interesting but that it lacks the "bite" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Wertheimer</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) and the "snappy rhythm and the kind of far-reaching
humor" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginia Bellafante</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) that make The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> so good.
On the positive side, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> calls it
"another satiric triumph," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> turned out in force--its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX>
rating was higher than both The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Simpsons and The X-Files</ENAMEX> .
(Find out more
about the show at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s Web site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Human: A</ENAMEX>
Political Education
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little, Brown</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Idealist</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>? Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> revealed in this memoir
more the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>' lethal piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
Review blasts the book: "The self-importance underneath the self-criticism
is breathtaking." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wills</ENAMEX> calls the memoir as a whole "tiresomely moralizing" and
knocks the quality of the advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> did for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, noting that
it was after he left that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency really took off. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Economist</ENAMEX> praises the book ("impressively honest and hugely enjoyable")
but doesn't have much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Ullmann</ENAMEX> writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> that
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX>]erhaps the book should be renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Too Ambitious</ENAMEX> ." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Caldwell</ENAMEX>'s discussion of the book in

                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unbearable Urges</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Englander</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). This story collection
draws praise, along with raised eyebrows in regard to some extra-artistic
issues. The reviews are wonderful: "graceful and remarkably self-assured ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unpretentious</ENAMEX> and powerful stories" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The oohs and
aahs come over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englander's</ENAMEX> reported <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX> advance, an unheard-of sum for a
debut short story collection. His stories mostly hinge on matters of faith. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Mobilio</ENAMEX> writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice Literary Supplement</ENAMEX> ,
"the questions with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flannery O'Connor</ENAMEX> pried at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
doctrine he now aims at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox Judaism</ENAMEX>." (Read an excerpt from the book
here.)

            Find a
movie playing near you on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  True Crime ;

               
                  Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> and I ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces of Nature</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Years of Renewal</ENAMEX>
                  , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  
                     Movie--
                  
                  The
Deep End of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corruptor</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage: Carrie</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  Wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Death-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  Black <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hawk Down</ENAMEX>: A
Story of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Modern War</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Bowden</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Analyze This</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX>, Stock & <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> Smoking
Barrels ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Monica's Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Annie Get Your Gun</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Bright Lights</ENAMEX>, Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  8MM ;

               
                  Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> Cigarettes ;

               
                  Movie -- The 
                  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Houdini Girl</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martyn Bedford</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Perfect Murder, Perfect Town</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiller</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Nightingales</ENAMEX> .

            

         
      
   
