
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Kills</ENAMEX>

            The massacre at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>
High School prompted op-ed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> across the land to diagnose a shocking "lack
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>" as the cause of the madness. As if! There is no public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that works harder to forge a sense of belonging than the
suburban public high school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assemblies</ENAMEX>, homecoming week festivities, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">car wash</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>, pep rallies, proms, graduation ceremonies--these rituals instill
in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> the "school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>" that persuades many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> to return
to town <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every five years</TIMEX> for reunions to celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>'s glory
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>.

            Representing the "lack
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>" position were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX>
Gabler, writing separately in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opinion</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> took the standard communitarian tack, arguing
that newly landscaped suburbs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> produce deracinated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> who
can't become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> because they lack a sense of community: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ou</ENAMEX> cannot
become an individual without a strong sense of 'we,' " he writes. Gabler
combined a squishier communitarian criticism ("it may be too simple to say that
rootless malleable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> ... give rise to rootless malleable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
with little identity of their own, save the identity borrowed from mass
culture, but it may not be too far off, either") with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> monism:
Identitiless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> play "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doom</ENAMEX>" on the PC, then try it out in the enhanced 3-D
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> of real life.

            But neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabler</ENAMEX> nor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> appear to have attended a suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>. If they had, they
would know that such high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> suffer from an overdose of community,
not a deficit. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> killed.

            Columbine evidently overflowed with this sort of school
spirit, most of which revolves around student athletics. The latest consensus
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> is that rage directed at student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> and their perceived
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protectors</ENAMEX>, the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, drove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan Klebold</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meticulously</ENAMEX> prepare and then execute the killings. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> and suburban
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> elsewhere, athletics are the biggest tool in creating the sense of
"we" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> extols. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>--both on and off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>--worships the
basketball and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football gods</ENAMEX>, and favoritism for the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institutionalized</ENAMEX> in the name of fostering a sense of community. It's more than
curious that at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> supposedly dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectator</ENAMEX>-friendly athletic competitions are the only activities considered to
be worthy of regular praise and attention. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gabler</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">closed-circuit TV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> played sports highlights regularly. Can one imagine
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain News</ENAMEX> , or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, replacing high-school
sports coverage with debate team transcripts?

            The skewed community
values created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and the media exacerbate
the natural volatility of high-school social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Just as rape and other
felonies committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star athletes</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouses</ENAMEX> are tolerated with
wearying predictability, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> will allow the
barely controllable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> from the gridiron free rein to commit verbal and
physical aggro upon the castes below. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the harassment and
ostracism survive. Some drop out of school or transfer. In my day, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hassled
student ended his life by hanging himself from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> rim. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klebold</ENAMEX>'s case, the endgame was a spasm of violence.

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klebold</ENAMEX> have established--one hopes--the
extreme end of inappropriate response to high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hazing</ENAMEX>, their crimes were
anticipated by popular culture. It's particularly strange that the supposedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>-savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabler</ENAMEX> didn't acknowledge in his piece the popular-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> killing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic Heathers</ENAMEX> and its less acute echo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jawbreaker</ENAMEX> . Even the
mild snarkiness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daria</ENAMEX> should have put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabler</ENAMEX>, for whom mass
entertainment is the only important reality, on notice that high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that are hardly tolerant, accepting, or even rational. Are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX> vows to rebuild <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> also a vow to resurrect the very community
that shaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klebold</ENAMEX>?

            You can't feel like an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> if you don't want
to get inside. Viewed from this angle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klebold</ENAMEX>'s rampage can be
interpreted as an extreme desire to join a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> whose values they had
bought into. By embracing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> sloganeering, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klebold</ENAMEX> may have
thought that they had cast out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>'s influence. But they absorbed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> community values--aggression, planning, cohesion, and
physical sacrifice for the goal--in the methodical planning and execution of
their atrocity. Yet right up to their donning black trench coats for the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, they would probably have preferred being honored at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> pep rally
than at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> rally.

         
      
   
