
   
   
      
         
             War of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wills</ENAMEX>

            Amid the saturation
coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> point of view is nowhere
to be seen. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This weekend</TIMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military and foreign policy officials
made the rounds of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk shows, the only air time a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> spokesman
could get was a brief interview on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>. It looks as though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are
helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> win the war for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> hearts and minds. But the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> war
isn't about which side is right. It's about which side is choosing the course
of the conflict, and which side is imposing the consequences. And in that war
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>.

            Virtually the first
question posed on every talk show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> was the same. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the unfortunate
consequences of our bombing seems to have been to unleash a bloodbath, where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, military, paramilitary, are storming into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and driving people
away," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> declared on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . "Some are suggesting that
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase of the air campaign has only intensified the alleged ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleansing</ENAMEX>, the atrocities being committed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> added on
Late Edition . On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX> suggested that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing "has simply backfired."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> disputed these suggestions, but the
underlying damage was done: The ethnic cleansing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> was framed as a
"consequence" of the bombing. This is the opposite of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
envisioned the story: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> was imposing the consequences. It's "an upside-down argument to think that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> or we have made this get worse," sputtered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> when confronted on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> with the charge
that the bombing had backfired. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is the one that is to blame. He is
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that is making it worse. And what we were trying to do is to make sure
that he pays the heaviest price for what he is doing."

            The bombing can make
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> pay a price, but it can't necessarily break his will. The longer he
holds out at home and escalates the genocide in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, the more the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> pronounce the bombing a failure. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Action</ENAMEX> Fails to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stop Serb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brutality</ENAMEX>," says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> front page. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times raises the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s defiance shows the bombing
strategy was "fatally flawed" and adds that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> here are on the
defensive, insisting day after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> that it was not their bombing that sparked
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> attacks or the huge civilian forced exodus from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>."

            The bombing was supposed to force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to accept a
peace plan that would grant limited autonomy to the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has shredded the peace plan by fomenting so much hatred between
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> that coexistence is impossible. Instead, having
driven the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> from their homes, he's offering to let them
return--and even to remove "some" of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> halts its
bombing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. By framing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enforcers</ENAMEX> of
consequences, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> gets to define the options and their costs. Rather than
play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s game--autonomy or bombing--he's creating a new game: ethnic
cleansing or bombing. In the new game, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> gets for backing off is what it
had in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is making
steady progress in turning the game upside down. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have
stopped demanding that he sign the peace plan and have started demanding merely
that he "stop his repression." "We are going to continue the bombing until we
can guarantee that the killings stop and will not restart," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secretary-General Javier Solana</ENAMEX> declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. The new offer implicitly
emerging from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> is: Stop the cleansing and we'll stop the
bombing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Milosevic</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s game or vice versa? That depends
on which side's will breaks <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, which in turn depends on each side's
assessment of the strength of the other's will, which in turn depends on how
the media portray their morale. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorializes on Page
A28 that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> must muster all the air power it can and use it against Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s murderous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>," its front-page headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On 7 th Day</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serb Resilience Gives NATO Leaders Pause</ENAMEX>"--gives him a huge lift. The media
also help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> by playing up cracks within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> over how far each member
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is willing to pursue the bombing. Knowing the limits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bolsters Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s confidence and helps him dictate the terms of the
game.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did his
best <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to reframe the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s terms. The ethnic cleansing isn't a
consequence of the bombing but was planned long beforehand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> argued. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' terms for ending the bombing are "unacceptable," he added, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is
"united" and "determined to stay with our policy." If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> continues the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleansing</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he will suffer further costs: the devastation of his
military and the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> sovereignty over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. And by
accelerating the bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is warning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> that it is willing to match
him escalation for escalation. Eventually, the consequences will become
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unbearable</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side or the other. It's a head game. War always is.

            

               For more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> coverage, click .
            

         
      
   
