
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">204</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Stay</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Who said this to whom about what: "Keep on doing what you're doing, and
don't call us, we'll call you."
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 203</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gloat, Little Gloat Worm":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seafood Restaurants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruel</ENAMEX>
Intentions can all make the same boast. What?
               

               "All
can be purchased in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ballard</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

               "They
are each based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> novel. (I could be wrong about Cruel
Intentions .)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Silow-Carroll</ENAMEX>
               

               "Four
things that drove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> into self-imposed exile."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
               

               "Each
would have had more effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> peace process than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>
did."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lengieza</ENAMEX>
               

               "One
makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skipper</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wakes Tipper</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bakes Flipper</ENAMEX>. And one ... to take a guess
at what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Travers</ENAMEX> said in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> , is 'like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Liaisons</ENAMEX>
Dangereuses , but much, much hipper!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Wolitzer</ENAMEX>
               

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

               Ah, the smell of it. Many
of you wallowed in the olfactory, particularly in the odor of corruption and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. (If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> were played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, what a merry romp that would be!
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX>, hey? I give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>; you give the scent.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX> alludes to fish aroma when he says, "Something is rotten in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>." His was another example of the bisexual symbolism of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>; it is one of the few things used to represent both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and female
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genitalia</ENAMEX>. "Stinking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>" was a derogatory <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Elizabethan</ENAMEX> reference to vaginal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">odor</ENAMEX>; and cod--as in cod piece--was slang for penis. Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> is such a
flexible metaphor because the general shape of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is phallic, while its
open mouth suggests the vagina. So, who's hungry? Anybody up for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX>?

               
                  Inductive,
Funductive Answer
               

               As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Weishaar</ENAMEX> knew (click for more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pamela</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weishaar</ENAMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We're No. 2</ENAMEX>!"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s No. 1 toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will become
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest consumer software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, when it
completes its purchase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Learning Company</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.8 billion</NUMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> requires no explanation except, perhaps, for
his astonishing physical grace. The man moves like a young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">panther</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX>'s is No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in what the restaurant industry
calls the "casual seafood" category. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX>'s agreed to buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consolidated Restaurants</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84 million</NUMEX> in stock and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million</NUMEX> in assumed
debt, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX>'s control over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Spaghetti Warehouse</ENAMEX>. For my money,
nothing says good eating like "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>."

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX>
was No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> at the box office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> in what the movie industry calls
the "dim-witted teen remake" category. ( Analyze This was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX>.)

               
                  You Be the MBA
Extra
               

               I give the revealing
detail; you give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revealing Detail</ENAMEX>
               

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> operating earnings fell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
percent.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Laying off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of the lowest-paid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s pay for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-chairmen</ENAMEX> exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> each.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> says linchpin of
long-term strategic development is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>,
talent."

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> of directors
damned to hell for all eternity.

               
                  Answers
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-3</ENAMEX>. All refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX>.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quotes Charlotte Beers</ENAMEX>, new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairwoman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Thompson</ENAMEX> advertising.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Is conjectural; check
with your spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

               
                  Common
Denominators
               

               Plastic parts and fish
fragrance.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
