
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in the Doghouse

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has been barred from
some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s top-secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> plans because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> fears they
will be passed on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, quoting "a senior
Western military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has started cutting
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> out of the loop on some operations because of the worry of information
being handed either to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> direct or indirectly through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>." In
an editorial headlined "Send in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said that, with an impetus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s advantage, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> "should seize this moment to announce a new goal and new means to
achieve it. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the independence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is the
commitment of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, a move that senior military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> consider
essential to success."

            The deployment of ground
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> has been gathering ever-greater support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> since it
became clear that the bombing is strengthening rather than weakening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s resolve to complete the "ethnic cleansing" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. A majority of
papers, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>, have now come out in favor of it, with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> important exception: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
largest-circulation paper. While the upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> papers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
Times now support ground intervention, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> backs Prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> in his promise not to send in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. While it
bursts with aggression against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clobba Slobba</ENAMEX>" being its rallying
cry--the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun</ENAMEX> threatened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to withdraw its support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> if he
changed his mind. "Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Send Our Troops off To Die</ENAMEX>" was its front-page
headline.

            The weightiest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of the war remains the
Times ' op-ed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Jenkins</ENAMEX>, who, writing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, said that "the misreading of Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> deserves to
rank with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallipoli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> in the annals of military incompetence."
He wrote, "It is grimly intriguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pro-war lobby is made up
of mostly younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do not remember (or have forgotten) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">escalation</ENAMEX>. The issue, once again, is not the plausibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> but
the esteem of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> and confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s military omnipotence. As
for whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovan</ENAMEX> war will be anything but an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> one, you can hear,
read and talk about this subject from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn to dusk</TIMEX> and not hear a word about
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> involvement--beyond the complaint that 'America is having to rescue
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> from another of its messes.' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
contained reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> by a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who spent time
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combatants</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> reported that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> claims to control "just <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>" and to be in close
contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, from which it could call in air support at any time.
It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florin Kulaj</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">850</NUMEX>-strong
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Brigade</ENAMEX>, as saying that he had identified ground targets for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> attacks, such as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, which had been bombed on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kulaj</ENAMEX> also admitted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> was surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and short of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. "New <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> hardly get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalashnikov</ENAMEX> between
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them," he said. "We don't ask the West to send ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. If our men
are given the means to fight, we will be able to defend the civilian population
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is
still reluctant to arm the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> because it doubts its democratic
credentials.

            According to Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monde</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are "deaf and
blind" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> refugee crisis. "After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of conflict, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> continue to see it only as a showdown between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, confused with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and considered the 'aggressor,' and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>,' " it reported. "Accordingly, not a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX> has devoted a front-page story, or even a headline, to the exodus of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of [ethnic] <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> press
comments from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>, selected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, included the following: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vremia</ENAMEX> said, "The horrible
descriptions of massacres of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX> in the West are wrong and
exaggerated"; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Izvestiya</ENAMEX> offered, "While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unites</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> plays golf, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are fleeing from the
hell unleashed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>"; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavissimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> said that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> was conducting "barbaric bombardments ... under the false pretext of a
humanitarian catastrophe."

            While Le Figaro
in a front-page editorial said that the tide is now turning in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s favor and
marveled at the "astonishing unity" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> so far, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera berated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo D'Alema</ENAMEX> for condoning open
revolt against the war within his coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armando Cossutta</ENAMEX> was seeking a meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> and that
another coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was calling on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to distance itself from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> "while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> is at war and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airmen</ENAMEX> running the risk of being shot
down," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergio Romano</ENAMEX> wrote in a front-page comment, "I have tried to find a
precedent that would allow me to justify these initiatives and the prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>'s silence, but I cannot find one."

             

         
      
   
