
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Listomania
            

            

               
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> name the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>'s silliest books.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>'s
journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> recently bade adieu to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> by picking the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>'s 100 greatest pieces of
journalism . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX>'s ranking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Schell</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fate of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> --an overheated and self-edifying prophesy of nuclear disaster--at
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>, inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> to 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> in naming the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100 Silliest Books Taken Seriously</ENAMEX> (By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serious People</ENAMEX>).

            Although we received a wide variety of entries,
consensus emerged around these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> books and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, in this order:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greening of America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reich</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Earth in the Balance , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Das Kapital</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population Bomb</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Ehrlich</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of History</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolph Hitler</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Various works of Ayn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rand</ENAMEX>

            What makes a book silly? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> selected books that
state the obvious: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Road Ahead</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computers</ENAMEX> will be
important in the future--gosh!" writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Evans</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in the
Balance was accused of both fuzzy thinking and naked political promotion.
Others nominated titles whose silliness was revealed by time, public debunking,
or both. The easy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>--and easy target--in this category is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlich</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population Bomb</ENAMEX> , a neo-Malthusian tract, which predicted a
population explosion that would cause global shortages, raise prices, poison
the environment, and lower life expectancy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlich</ENAMEX>'s theories lost steam after
he lost a famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> bet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Simon</ENAMEX>, who wagered that any
basket of resources <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlich</ENAMEX> might name would be cheaper at any date in the
future. Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlich</ENAMEX>'s book was treated to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> st
anniversary reprinting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

            Our more aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, excited to nail
entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of work in one go, bypassed books and went straight for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayn Rand</ENAMEX> garnered the most votes for any single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. A
sampling of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX> ("I can think of
no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> I'd rather unilaterally disarm," fumes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Mazmanian</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> ("the consummate
pseudo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who disguises his bilious prejudices as profound insight,"
writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Greenberg</ENAMEX>);

            and the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Foucault canon</ENAMEX> ("or should I say oeuvre ?" asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Baker</ENAMEX>).

            Others took a more literal approach to silliness. "I
suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice in Wonderland</ENAMEX> is not exactly what you meant," writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Solovay</ENAMEX>. Maybe not, but you illustrate beautifully our point about
interpreting standards.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, what did we mean by seriousness? Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> measured it by amount of attention devoted by the chattering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> on
the pages of prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Greening of America</ENAMEX> --a
celebration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> ethos--debuted around the same time as the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed page and dominated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. Other answers
interpreted seriousness--well, more seriously, mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Das Kapital</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Red Book</ENAMEX> for their enormous impacts
relative to their shaky intellectual foundations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reader Jeff Staiman</ENAMEX> argues,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> devoted their lives to [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Das Kapital</ENAMEX> ], set up national economies
and whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> based on it. Of course, only a minority believed in it
deeply, but many of them were serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." He adds, "if any group is more
shrilly serious than the few hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> I met at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, I hope
never to meet them."

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX>'s list, 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'slist</ENAMEX> has only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> discernible effects: It validates already popular opinions (Did you already
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s book deserved a comeuppance? Well, others did too.), and it makes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> feel very bad (or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> list's case, very good) about their
work.

            Actually, our list does
provide <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more, far more practical, service: It should serve as grave warning
to anyone who is even remotely contemplating writing a book on the fate of the
environment.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi Kantor</ENAMEX>
            

            
               More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fellas</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven days ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> should date if she and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ever split (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"). Chatterbox suggested, among others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Wieseltier</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX>, but his e-mail inbox overflowed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> picks.
Herewith, a sampler (and please don't send any more!):

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Geoghegan</ENAMEX> (winsome lefty
labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret Lives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens</ENAMEX> (click

here to buy the book)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesia</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Banderas</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed al-Fayed</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX>
Templesman
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
