
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">193</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Whoa, Canada&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poitras Report</ENAMEX>,
recently released in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>, describes an inept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that routinely
broke the law, lacked ethics and professionalism, and embraced a code of
silence that thwarted whistle-blowers. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>?
            

            

               ( Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 192</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where It's At":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     Fill in the blank in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville Gilbert Brim</ENAMEX>'s report on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> study funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthur Foundation</ENAMEX>: "On balance, the sense we all
have is that ________ is the best place to be."
                  
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthur Foundation</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Krause</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jon</ENAMEX>
Delfin , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael Roche</ENAMEX>
               

               "During
a showing of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Message in a Bottle</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
Hotchkiss
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starbucks</ENAMEX>. (Is this a trick question or something?)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Schoenberg</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

               "New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. (The study centered on where you are likely to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> starting
new careers after being publicly humiliated by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX>
Saucier
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance Florence</ENAMEX>. Now would one of those fucking geniuses we keep funding
build us a time machine<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Smith</ENAMEX>
               

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to judge a grant
program is to count the number of projects that but for that grant would not
have come to fruition. By this measure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthur</ENAMEX> "genius grants" are a
failure. Awarding much of their money to established <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, the MacArthurs
tend to fund those happy in their work, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who simply continue what they've
been doing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, but in more stylish clothes. Another way to judge a grant
program is to count the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> houses the grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> have
bought; by this measure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthurs</ENAMEX> are a triumph.

            
               AARParific
Answer
            

            Middle age is the best place to be.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> found
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years between 40 and 60</TIMEX> to be a time of well-being for most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> they studied, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 23 percent</NUMEX> reporting a midlife crisis. Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">menopause</ENAMEX> emerged as a less traumatic transition than is usually reported. Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Rossi</ENAMEX>, who analyzed that data, said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Sheehy</ENAMEX> image of the
menopausal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with sweat running down her face is just not true."

            
               All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gall</ENAMEX>'s
Extra
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> last romp through the
catalog of "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> to public safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>." Can you match the trademark
to the product?

            
               Brand
Name
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAT TRAP</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">SUPER</ENAMEX> STINGER

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STREET HAWK</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. THE ADVANTAGE <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MIAMI CLASSIC</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. ELIMINATOR

            
               Item
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Gas</ENAMEX> mask (also available: The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Phalanx Alpha</ENAMEX>
Plus)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Holster</ENAMEX> (also available: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tornado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grabber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
Lightning)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Socks</ENAMEX> (also available: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional</ENAMEX>)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Pocket</ENAMEX>-sized spikes to flatten car tires at road
blocks (also available: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Checkpoint Charlie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MetroSpike</ENAMEX>)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Flashlight</ENAMEX> (also available: Wow, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TopSpot</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surefire</ENAMEX>)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F. Light</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> for patrol
car roof (also available: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excalibur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code 3</ENAMEX>)

            

               Answers
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-D,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3-F</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-A</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-B, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-C</NUMEX>.
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years</TIMEX>?!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
