
   
   
      
         
            Endgame Over

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> approved a peace deal proposed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The plan mandates a withdrawal of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, to be followed by a halt in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing and the return of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dispossessed Kosovars</ENAMEX> under the supervision of a unified, allied-led
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX> will be "demilitarized," and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> will eventually become autonomous but not independent. Click here to read the text of the agreement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taciturn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> reaction: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bombing</ENAMEX> won't stop until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavs</ENAMEX> actually
withdraw. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s jubilant unofficial reaction: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victory</ENAMEX> is ours. The consensus
political spin from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> both and domestic : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s capitulation vindicates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s bombing-only strategy. The counterspins to all the huzzahs:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> will never agree to its own emasculation or abandon its goal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> independence. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) By bowing out now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> will retain his hold on
power.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> suppressed commemoration of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> anniversary of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> uprising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>,
disbanded a public memorial service, and excised all mention of the anniversary
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> made no mention of the
date's significance but stressed the importance of "stability above all else."
To survey the current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> spins on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX> column by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> legalized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pill</ENAMEX>. Health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> approved birth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> pills after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several decades</TIMEX> of debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> asked why it has
taken so long. Answer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is hostile to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
concerns. Answer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is hostile to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tylenol</ENAMEX> isn't on the market yet. Answer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: Then why was <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>
legalized after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only six months</TIMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> playoffs news: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Ewing</ENAMEX> will
miss the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> playoffs because of a torn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX>' tendon. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana Pacers</ENAMEX> have split the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> games of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">semifinals</ENAMEX> series. The injury deprives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX> of his last best chance to play
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> championship, which he has never won during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year</TIMEX> career. The
sentimental spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> can't afford to lose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX>'s fire and courage.
(He's been playing hurt for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.) The realistic spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> are
younger, faster, and better without him. The cynical spin: This is the first
interesting story of the playoffs.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> held its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> free elections. The unsurprising
news: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African National Congress</ENAMEX> will win handily and will appoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thabo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mbeki</ENAMEX>, the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>'s successor-designate,
to the presidency. The more surprising news: The election was free of the
racial violence that accompanied the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> all-race elections in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. Read the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part overview of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> here .

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will investigate the marketing of violent
entertainment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said the study will
explore whether or not media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> intentionally lure young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> with
violent imagery. Why the study won't be useful: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> protects
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> from being legally forced to tone down their pitches. Why the study
will be useful: It will give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> a reply to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> accusations that the
administration is soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX> will introduce an online discount trading
operation . Traditional trades through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> currently cost up to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of dollars; the online fee will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.95</NUMEX>. Previously, the brokerage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> had loudly vowed to stay off-line and boasted that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> would
cough up fat commissions in exchange for handholding and top-flight financial
analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spin 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>'s move proves that the Internet is transforming Wall
Street. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spin 2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>'s late arrival proves how slowly the Internet is
transforming Wall Street. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spin 3</ENAMEX>) By the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> is up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> will already have lost out to scrappier, more nimble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. Spin
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> has already lost out to scrappier, more nimble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spin 5</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> will revolt at the prospect of reduced commissions.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackers</ENAMEX> hijacked several government Web sites--including those of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>--freezing or replacing official content.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>' mischief posted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
home page.) Reportedly, the vandalism was in retaliation for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> raids on
suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker community</ENAMEX>'s reaction to the press: vigorous
denial of wrongdoing. The reaction within hacking circles: vigorous jockeying
for credit.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will abandon its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mir</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> space
program is broke. Set on cruise control, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> will eventually burn up
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">re-entry</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> reaction: dejection and wounded pride. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s
reaction: relief that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> won't drain financing from the international space
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>, along with the usual orbital traffic worries about a large abandoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
