
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">220</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Sticks and Stones&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               The list includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>, fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX>,
and hordes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>. List of what?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 219</ENAMEX>)--"Not":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              The slogan in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>,
promulgated at government expense, is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not Me, Not Now</ENAMEX>." Not
what?
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "Not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillel</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Rickey</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
Silow-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carroll</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "Not a
new law that requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in labor to serve jury duty."-- Adrianne
Tolsch
            

            "Not a
chance in hell former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canadians</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kennebunkport summer</TIMEX> manse
... unless they are to be used as game."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
            

            "Oh,
this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>'s tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lamely</ENAMEX> responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>'s campaign,
'Wouldn't You Rather Be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>?' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuger</ENAMEX> )

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX>? What's that noise? You're not having sex with that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster</ENAMEX>, are
you?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

             

             

             

             

             

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>, which is basically <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyannis Port</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, but with unattractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who aren't having much fun or killing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in drunken driving incidents, so I guess it's a trade-off. It is cold
there. And they grow lobsters in the rocky soil, between the rows of blueberry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that form such an attractive backdrop to Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Lansbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of
television's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baywatch</ENAMEX> , although you'd think they'd shoot a show like
that someplace warmer. The state seal shows a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> and a seaman and a moose,
who seems faintly disapproving of the lifestyle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seaman</ENAMEX>,
which strikes me as impertinent coming from a ruminant. If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
happy, where's the harm, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oh-So-Judgmental Moose</ENAMEX>! The seal includes a pine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree symbolizing</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pine trees</ENAMEX>--does that still count as symbolism?--along
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Star</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirigo</ENAMEX>," which actually means "I
direct," but if you imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> saying it, sounds like "Dir I Go eating
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster</ENAMEX> which is not even slightly kosher! Like some big dumb moose!"

            
               Abstinent
Answer
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not Me, Not Now</ENAMEX>"--not sex. Particularly not teen
sex, particularly not nonmarital sex.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> have opted out--spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the $50 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> allocates
for abstinence education, with every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> of federal money matched with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> of
state funds.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> now has an official state sex act:
"mutually faithful monogamous heterosexual relationships in the context of
marriage." The state bird is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX>; the state flower is dogwood; they're
not even dating.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>'s theme is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sex and Reading Can Wait</ENAMEX>"
(except for the part about the reading).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, with its own view of the erotic, uses the
money to sponsor a hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are playing hockey or basketball,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nan Streeter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s reproductive health program, "it's hard
for them to get involved in risky behavior."

            Not to drag in my
personal life, but one thing that's always given me real erotic contentment is
knowing that, while having sex, it's hard for me to get involved in playing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hockey</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Benelux</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            A bloated promotional
supplement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> touts the lowlands as a great place
to make a buck. Match the advertised attribute with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.

            
               National
Characteristic
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>'s" make it a great place to do
business.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX> would find it just the right size.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ... live below sea level."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "One <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thousand Years Young</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. National capital transformed "from dour <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> into a magnet for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">multinationals</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Times They Are a' Changing</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "You're constantly
among attractive and amusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who find you fascinating."

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>'s are place, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, price,
pro-business, pot-smoking, pouty, pert<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'n'sassy</ENAMEX>, and promiscuous. Is that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>. The ad notes other attractive, small
things--microchips, squirrels, country music great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Lee</ENAMEX> (except for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">squirrels</ENAMEX> and Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>).

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. Say no more. I'm sold.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. And, coincidentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>. And thank goodness all those
dull <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> have been displaced by witty, playful multinational corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. Let the revels commence.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>, apparently, was the old tambourine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s inspiration. Although oughtn't it be "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">a-changin</ENAMEX>' "? Maybe it's different
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walloon</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Randyland</ENAMEX>. No, it's
not on any map of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Benelux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>; you have to find it in your heart. OK,
everybody, let's recite the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>'s.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
