
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">242</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Reading Is Fundamentalism&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Kicking off a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> ad campaign, gospel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelists</ENAMEX> poured out of a
giant copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book</ENAMEX> , an updated, "cool" version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>. But,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Book</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>, televangelist and former presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>, "Our goal is not to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibles</ENAMEX>. It is to make
Bible-reading cool and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to devise other ways
to achieve that goal.
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 241</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Very Special ...":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               A recent episode of a popular TV series was postponed because it was
frighteningly like an actual, front-page event. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> says it will go
ahead and broadcast the show's season finale, although it too is disturbingly
reminiscent of that same event. How will the listing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX>
describe the big show?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dharma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dharma</ENAMEX> gets her toe stuck in a bowling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ball</ENAMEX> and shoots <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> newscaster <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Dando</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>): A puffy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">besotted</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> dissolves his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>--again! Also: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoebe</ENAMEX> decides to learn to ski."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Wasik</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rothman</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Charlton</ENAMEX> makes an ass of himself at the convention."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
Ringle
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> : A horrific school shooting provokes discussion and
soul-searching among the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally</ENAMEX> frets over
her uncertain love life and her biological clock."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Ananda "Hear, Hear</ENAMEX>!
Death to the Autoreplies!" <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gupta</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Buffy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head cheerleader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andie Pamerson</ENAMEX> decides to
remove her breast implants because they're possessed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
Kiefer
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            "Map <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, map <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, make me a map.
Find me a find, catch me a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>.
Map <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, map <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, make up your mind,
and make me a perfect map!"

            
--from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> musical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fiddler Somewhere in the General Vicinity of the</ENAMEX>
Roof
            

            The news event most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> played with was, of course, the bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX>.
This story contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sure-fire comic ingredients (at least for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>): incompetence and destruction. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roadrunner</ENAMEX> . Thus, the string
of successes on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Night With David Letterman</ENAMEX> involving the dimwitted
demolition of culturally evocative objects<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Running Stuff Over With a Steam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roller</ENAMEX>, Dropping Stuff off a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>-Story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crushing Stuff in a Hydraulic</ENAMEX>
Press, Dropping a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000-Pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weight Onto Stuff, Crashing Into Stuff With a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locomotive</ENAMEX>. With one fleeting exception, when he shot up, and later blew up,
his own cue cards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> shunned firearms and explosions. Just not funny. If he
were alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, he'd never get a show on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>.

            
               Buffy the Vampire
Answer
            

            I don't have a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> around, but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s episode this way: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cordelia</ENAMEX> likes
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> pulled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earshot</ENAMEX>,'' an episode of
Buffy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Michelle Gellar</ENAMEX> stumbles onto a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX>-murder plan by fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> announced
that it would run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part finale, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Graduation Day</ENAMEX>," chockablock with
gun-toting high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

            "We are airing the
episodes. There are no plans to pull them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Kingsdale</ENAMEX>, a WB
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner Inc.</ENAMEX> No, wait: It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> and not Kingsdale
that is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>. Under current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law, human beings cannot be
owned and must instead be rented.

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Tribute</ENAMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>
            

            To the shame of my
closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, I am now hooked on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy</ENAMEX>. Been watching since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. My
favorite episode so far was the one where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armageddon</ENAMEX> was the "B" story. Last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">night</ENAMEX>'s best moment (which I suspect won't travel well out of context) was when
the prom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emcee</ENAMEX> thanked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffy</ENAMEX> for saving so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' lives that "our class
has the lowest mortality rate in the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>!"

            
               Augmented
Quotations Extra
            

            (Each final sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.)

            

               "If you do the procedure correctly, it's very
safe. And right after surgery, I take the fat I sucked out and fry up a couple
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Kling</ENAMEX> defends liposuction, despite a few regrettable
deaths.

               "This product is made with fur from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> that
may have been killed by electrocution, gassing, neck breaking, poisoning,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clubbing</ENAMEX>, stomping or drowning, and may have been trapped in steel-jawed
leghold traps. Or by improperly performed liposuction."--Warning label that
would have appeared on fur coats had <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> approved <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition</ENAMEX> A.

               "Instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s 'talk softly and
carry a big stick,' we have yelled and carried a toothpick. And so I announce
my intention to undergo penile enlargement, and as long as you're down there,
let's go for the scrotum enhancement."--Retired but not retiring, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
assesses our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> policy.

               "Supposedly everybody
was watching, and in reality no one was watching. But then again, who wants to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> get his penis stretched?"--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanche Lambert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> assesses security failings at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               Tech
Talk
            

            

               
                  Slate
                has ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">autoreply</ENAMEX> shut off. There is,
however, little they can do about the fawning farewells to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> takeout.

         
      
   
