
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Samaranch Hand&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               As it prepares to convene in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> has invited a well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> to join its reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>.
Who and why? (Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 206</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Do You Take It?</ENAMEX>":
               

               

                  
                     
                        
                           It happens in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> a day, and
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Cohen</ENAMEX> calls it "the oddest kaffeeklatsch in the
history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> civilization." What goes
on?
                        
                     
                  
               

               "The
trees talk about how to kill another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> get together to try and solve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> case."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Schoenberg</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norm Oder et al.</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coors</ENAMEX> studies for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> mitzvah."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Snow</ENAMEX> (similarly, but rappers
not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brewers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh Bardugo</ENAMEX> )

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meredith Vieira</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy Behar</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> at the taping of
their TV show The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Parallax View</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Wolitzer</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finally</ENAMEX>, a question to which I know the answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Murderers yell</ENAMEX> at each
other."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Smith</ENAMEX>
               

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

               To play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
requires the willful suspension not of disbelief but of genuine knowledge: An
awareness of the actual answer so easily eclipses the inspiration for a comic
response. And, clearly, everyone knew the facts of the matter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But
there's more about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> you might not know. To condense from (but not
otherwise alter) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960</TIMEX> edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Book Encyclopedia</ENAMEX>: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thirds</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> live no more. ... Streams tumbling down from
the snowy peaks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockies</ENAMEX> form ... cantaloupes. ...The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherokee Indians</ENAMEX>
found <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> on ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>, who became a leading ... <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brandy</ENAMEX>.
... He surveyed friendly relations." In this context, it's hard to know what
makes a kaffeeklatsch odd. Or a klatsch.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fresh Air</ENAMEX>
Answer
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Felipe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin Kings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> convicted of
murder and racketeering, is about to join <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bomber <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bomber <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Ahmed Yousef</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unabomber Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX> for
conversation in the exercise yard at the federal "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Super Max</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>

               Kept in solitary confinement <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23 hours a day</TIMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-by</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> cells, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> can not even look into the eyes of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>.
They are permitted to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> per day in separate cages in the exercise
yard, where they can speak to each other through mesh fences.

               Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe</ENAMEX> is believed to have ordered murders
from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, he has been kept even more isolated, but a
ruling by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Martin</ENAMEX> allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe</ENAMEX> into the exercise yard.

               The conversation? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Klienman</ENAMEX>,
said, "They talk about innocuous things like the movies. They don't talk about
anything they shouldn't be talking about."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Cohen</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Latin Kings</ENAMEX> case.

               
                  Infectious
Extra
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Epidemic</ENAMEX>!," the
wonderful new exhibit at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Museum of Natural History</ENAMEX>, must
have presented a challenge to the gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop managers</ENAMEX>, but they rose to it. Some
actual items for sale in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum shops</ENAMEX>:

               

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rat Hand Puppet</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plague</ENAMEX>-infested <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fleas</ENAMEX> not included.

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cockroach Earrings</ENAMEX>, part of a series that includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mosquitoes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX>--It's a formal affair: Should I go with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hantavirus</ENAMEX>?

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biohazard Martini Glass</ENAMEX>, "playfully reminds us of the effects of
overindulgence on our immune system", <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>--Remind me: What's the difference
between "playful" and "heartless"?

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Virus Coaster Set</ENAMEX> (includes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Influenza A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hepatitis B</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Adenovirus</ENAMEX>, T4
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bacteriophage</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX>--How many times must I tell you: Don't put your glass on
the table, put it on something that will give you searing abdominal
cramps.

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Influenza A Squishy Rubber Ball</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.50</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, catch ... a dose of this!

                  "Transfusion™ fruity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and hairwash gel" sold in a realistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> bag,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12.50</NUMEX>--From the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who brought <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">you the Body Bag poncho</ENAMEX>.

               

               
                  Common
Denominator
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
