
   
   
      
         
            Bibi, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bye</ENAMEX>-Bye

            "There
have never been elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> that focused so explicitly on the
personality and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent prime minister</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. B. Yihoshua</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">distinguished Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and sometime political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>, wrote Monday
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> . "The main issue that got this
campaign going was not the final status agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> ... but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s problematic personality." In the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emuna Elon</ENAMEX>
wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> could not trust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> wants
change, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> cannot settle for a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX> was said, even by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, to be 'not taking off' until
he was suddenly reinforced by a battalion of expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> who
taught him to recite some slogans convincingly."

            As
opinion polls showed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> likely to lose in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s national
elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the liberal daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> urged a large
turnout by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> opposed to him, so as to ensure his defeat. It described his
statements in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final days</TIMEX> of the campaign as "further proof of his lack of
responsibility." The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> said a pall had been cast over the campaign by
the death on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX> during an altercation with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> who had been trying to deface a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> poster and replace it with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> of both parties deplored the incident and
described it as murder. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in a
front-page comment as "the worst of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
state has had in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half-century</TIMEX> of existence."

            A
flurry of diplomatic activity within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to reassess its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> strategy
dominated war coverage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> led its
front page with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> warning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war cannot be won without the use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. In
an editorial, it continued to bang the drum for ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> must "convince a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to take
those steps that might render plausible an integrated air-ground campaign in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. ... Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who memorably 'smoked but did not inhale'
is for now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> who 'bombed but would not fight,' " the
editorial said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> must now convince
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> that his reputation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s future credibility, rests upon a
willingness to use the tools at his disposal."

            A day
earlier, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>
is feeling "a deep sense of frustration" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> after failing to persuade
him to commit ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. But in another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> paper, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> dismissed claims of a divide between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and himself. "The vast bulk of this military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> is being
carried out by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is a very long way from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>," he
said in an interview. "Their commitment and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is something for which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should be praised, rather than the sneers he receives from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

            The
Independent
led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the angle that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> is isolated on the ground war issue. It
quoted a "senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>" as saying that not only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but
also <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> is still against committing ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> because it could lead to
"unknown repercussions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>" and "cause <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to fall in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX>." It quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> as saying
there is "no threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX> relationship" but that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> wants
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> "to get a move on" and "face up to the decision." In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, a "hawk
without wings," has been allowed to become isolated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
reluctance to commit ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> has hardened rather than softened and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has followed the line of least resistance."

            The
moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim Rugova</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the joint declaration he signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> was "without meaning." It demanded, among
other things, an immediate end to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rugova</ENAMEX>, who was recently
allowed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, said in an
interview that he had only signed to give his family some space, since he was
effectively a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>. He said he wanted the air offensive to
continue until <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and are replaced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-led
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            The
main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s rejection of a proposal by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo D'Alema</ENAMEX> that the bombing should stop if there is agreement in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> resolution supported by both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shea</ENAMEX> has reiterated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> must accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s conditions before
the offensive can be halted. D<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'Alema</ENAMEX> discussed his proposal with German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> at a meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bari</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s peace initiatives have also been cold-shouldered by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s leading newspaper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Daily</ENAMEX> , ran an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
headed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stopping Bombing--Precondition for Any Political Solution</ENAMEX>." The
government organ said that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> in
Belgrade provoked widespread indignation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, instead of changing
their stand, "have continued the barbaric raids on an even larger scale against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>." It said, "It is well known that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> issue is an internal
affair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Republic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> involving complex ethnic and
religious contradictions. ... Events over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 50 days</TIMEX> have demonstrated
that the lunatic bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has not solved the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis. Instead, it has caused a larger exodus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> and seriously
devastated stability and peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> and even <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>."

            On the
failed impeachment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Duma</ENAMEX>, the daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> said that the "hearings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX> have proved beyond doubt
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> hardly has a match among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>." But other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">papers</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has little to be proud of. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> noted
that "not a word in support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has been said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three days</TIMEX> of
parliamentary hearings." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moskovsky Komsomolets</ENAMEX> said that "even those who
opposed the impeachment could not find a good word to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and
spoke against the impeachment solely in the interests of preserving a semblance
of stability in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
