
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Easy
Answers
            

            It is often said that there are no easy answers,
but in fact there are. In a former life I used to interrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> on
television, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> there was never a subject on which they were
unable to come up with an easy answer. Not necessarily a correct answer--or
honest or heartfelt or logically coherent--but easy.

            What is an easy answer?
An easy answer, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, is one that assures you will never be proved
wrong. Or at least that if you seem to have been wrong, another easy answer
will be available to explain why you weren't. "There are no easy answers" is
itself an easy answer--if you can get away with it. Often, you not only can get
away with it, but you can also enhance your reputation for being "thoughtful"
(high praise that in the culture of politics means indecisive in a classy way,
rather than kindly or considerate of others or anything like that). Sometimes,
though, you have to do better, and this is when easy answers become hard
work.

            War and peace issues are the worst. A famous joke among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">academics</ENAMEX> is that scholarly disputes are especially passionate because the
stakes are so low. By contrast, when the stakes are as high as they can get,
there is a special need for elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to avoid having a forthright
opinion. Easy answers to the rescue!

            The current issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military involvement
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, for example, seems to be a yes-or-no question to which either
conventional answer--call them "yes" and "no"--is decidedly uneasy. "Yes" means
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">risking American</ENAMEX> lives in a faraway land that has no apparent connection to the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing that really matters, which is the Dow Jones industrial average. "No"
means doing nothing, as the world's only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>, while a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> government
commits daily televised atrocities against white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> (not just
some unmediated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX>). Unless you're extraordinarily lucky, the outcome of
making either choice will leave you morally implicated in some dead bodies
(with larger raw numbers making up for lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> in the case
of a "no").

            Fortunately, even for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> there are answers available besides yes and no. They will be familiar
from intervention disputes dating back at least to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, but they are
especially useful for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer-squall</TIMEX>-style military actions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, in
which we all agree to be frenzied about the occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">drug-smuggling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> or genocide in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
on the strict understanding that we will be allowed to forget all about these
matters and places in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>, max. Here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>-tested
easy answers on issues like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>."Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cokie</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is that if we go into [INSERT
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOCATION</ENAMEX>], we should do so with the resources necessary to get the job done.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airstrikes</ENAMEX> alone [or 'only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>' or 'a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> hydrogen
bombs' or whatever is on the menu] just aren't enough. It is immoral to put
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> at risk without a guarantee of overwhelming superiority for a
certain and speedy victory."

            This is perhaps the most
prestigious dodge: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell Doctrine</ENAMEX>, named for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> (who is
responsible for the doctrine but not its use as a dodge). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell Doctrine</ENAMEX>
holds that the lesson of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> is do it right or not at all. Go in full force
from the beginning rather than escalate yourself into a quagmire. Or don't go
in at all. Finish quickly before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> loses patience (or ideally, as in
the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>, before the public has even heard of the place). Or, of
course, don't start at all. As to which of these alternatives--all or nothing
at all--is the right one in any situation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell Doctrine</ENAMEX> does not say. So
this is a great way to sound tough and sophisticated without actually
committing yourself. Since any actual military engagement is not going to
involve every last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing nut</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s "miscellaneous screws" jar, you
are well positioned to say "I told you so" if things go badly. Yet you never
actually opposed the action, so you're OK if things go well. And no one can
accuse you of wimping out if the military action doesn't take place: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, you
wanted to go in with more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>."Where is our exit strategy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>? That is what I'd like
to know."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Exit</ENAMEX> strategy" became a
fashionable term during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. It really sounds like you know what
you're talking about. And what does it mean? As I understand it, an exit
strategy is a sort of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> Doctrine. It does not demand certain
and prompt victory. It merely demands a certain and prompt conclusion to the
exercise that is acceptable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. When invoking this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>,
it is not necessary to specify--and indeed it is hard to imagine--what
conclusion short of victory a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> like you, who flings around terms like "exit
strategy," would find minimally satisfactory. And no military action (except
for actual movies) can be fully scripted in advance. So you're golden. If
things go wrong: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>, I pleaded with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to make sure we had an exit
strategy." And if the action goes well or disaster occurs because we didn't
intervene: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>, I was behind this all the way. I've always said that victory
is the best exit strategy."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>."<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>, I support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> credibility is at
stake. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX> has made a commitment on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must honor that commitment."

            This is the sneakiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dodge</ENAMEX> and probably the most popular--especially among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. You get to
be patriotic and hawkish. And if things go well, you were behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>
in chief all the way. But if things go badly, it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s fault for
making the commitment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tragically</ENAMEX>, you had no choice but to support him once
the commitment was made, but of course making it was irresponsible folly.
Please note that, like a reheated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX>, this dodge works even better after a
military action has begun. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>, we never should have got into this quagmire,
but now we have no choice but to ..."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>."I'm not persuaded this is so important, so vital to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s interests that we ought to intervene."

            That's an almost exact quote from a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, and illustrates a nifty linguistic evasion. You don't
say you're against it, you say you're "not persuaded" to be for it. Not only do
you evade the tough choice, you also evade responsibility for your decision.
It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s fault, even if he's right, because he didn't persuade
you.

            You can also say (like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Baucus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>) that there are "unanswered questions." Being
undecided and wanting ever more information is another great way to be
designated as "thoughtful." And with a bit of skill and a bit of luck, you can
keep taking your own temperature until it doesn't matter any more. Meanwhile,
you're OK no matter what happens. "Not persuaded" can be spun as a yes or a no.
A nice variant is to say, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> must be persuaded this is the
right thing, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> hasn't made the case." Not only is whatever
happens not your fault (unless it's good), it's not even the public's fault.
It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s fault, either because we did what he wanted or--if we
didn't--because he didn't convince us to do so.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>."I don't think we should begin bombing unless and until
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> really begin a very significant massacre against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>."

            That is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> (where most of these quotes
come from). In a way, this is not a dodge. It is a sort of madcap <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomonic</ENAMEX>
approach. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickles</ENAMEX> is saying: "Why must we guess whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is going
to kill a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>? Let's wait and see if he does it! And why must we
choose between saving a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> and saving none? Let's split the
difference and save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of them." As a bonus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickles</ENAMEX> retains a valuable fudge
factor in the question of what qualifies as "a very significant massacre."
Depending on what happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickles</ENAMEX> is in a position to accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
failing to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interests and values, or of recklessly endangering
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lives on the basis of a massacre that was merely "significant" but not
"very significant."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>."What's happening in [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WHEREVER</ENAMEX>] is a tragedy and an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outrage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>. Intervention to stop the bloodshed is absolutely essential. But
it's a job for [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INSERT NAME OF CLOSER COUNTRY AND/OR REGIONAL GROUP</ENAMEX>], not for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>."

            This final dodge is slightly different. You're
claiming credit for sharing whatever humanitarian or geostrategic concern
dictates military action, while opposing the use of the only military power you
yourself bear responsibility for. I once interviewed an especially moronic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, since defeated, who declared that some worthy military action was "a
job for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>." I asked him why other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> should risk their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' lives if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> wouldn't, and he replied, "I didn't say
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'other</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>,' I said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>." When it was pointed out to
him that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> don't come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>, he was stymied. That point had never
occurred to him.

            But exposing the logical flaw here does not depend
on any huffing and puffing about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s leadership role. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX>
going on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> television to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> should tidy up the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> without our help is like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> running (as has
been known to happen) a stuffy editorial saying that a corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> in some
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should resign. Of course he should. And the sun should
shine in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. But even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> 's opinion cannot
affect these matters. When an answer moves beyond difficult to completely
impossible, it becomes easy once again.

            Watch for these easy
answers on the TV talk shows and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. Practice on your own. Soon
you too can be ducking responsibility like a real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            
               For more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">coverage,</ENAMEX> click .
            

         
      
   
