
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">201</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;No-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stick Finish&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fill in the blank. Ending her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> was disappointed with that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s position on human rights
but has few ways to alter it, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lardy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> has got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carrot</ENAMEX>--that is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">_____________</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 200</ENAMEX>)--
                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boyish or Goyish":</ENAMEX>
               

            

            

               In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> it happened to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's down
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX>, and a policy just announced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pediatrics</ENAMEX> is meant to make it happen even less. What?
            

            "Having
sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Ginsberg</ENAMEX>. (As for the precipitous drop-off, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsberg</ENAMEX> said, 'Come
on, I'm dead. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Sixty percent</NUMEX> still ain't bad.')"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Getting through elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> without a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ritalin</ENAMEX>
prescription."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Connelly</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Circumlocution</ENAMEX>. From now on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> will be obligated to get to the point.
Immediately."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter Miller</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lois C. Ambash</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            
"Circumcising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newborns</ENAMEX> by having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> shoot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreskin</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rakoff</ENAMEX>
            

            "Being
covered by health insurance."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Barth</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers. 

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            There was a sweet and
goofy nostalgia in many of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s responses, recalling boyish sexual stirrings
in a nonexistent time without <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s easy access to pornography. In those
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, a trembling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who yearned to see a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had to see her on the
radio, and that took imagination. If he lacked imagination, he'd need an older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> slept over, plus a homemade periscope, assembled at a
scout meeting during those interludes when he wasn't being fondled by the scout
master, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Finian</ENAMEX>. Such were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX>. Or perhaps they weren't. Wasn't
nostalgia one of the things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pandora</ENAMEX>'s box? What about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlboros</ENAMEX>, handguns,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">malt liquor</ENAMEX>? Were they in there? And a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>? In the box? I
remember.

            
               Abbreviated
Answer
            

            Circumcision, as you all knew.

            Announcing its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penile</ENAMEX> policy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as many decades</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55,000</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAP</ENAMEX> says there is no
"medical indication" for the routine circumcision of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>. While the group
does not oppose the procedure for religious or cultural reasons, the new policy
calls for the use of pain reducing creams or injections.

            
               Augmented
Quotations Extra
            

            Each final sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.

            

               "I am truly grateful that we are able to bestow this priceless gift on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> to come. And so I proudly dedicate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>'s Sequoia
Casino!"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, not discontent with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$480 million</NUMEX> plan to protect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX> redwoods from giant lumber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

               "There are several inaccuracies in what was printed, and that's of more
concern than what it might do to the ratings. And another thing: I can
fly!"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eileen Murphy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>, not convinced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> maintains the high standards of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> interview.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> was a wartime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>. We were in a culture war
then. And we're in a, oh, call it a haircut war now, so die, you shaggy
bastard, die!"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Taylor</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon Library</ENAMEX>, not
criticizing the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for trampling the constitution.

               "We are absolutely serious about making this a terrific place to work for a
variety of diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, pink curtains!"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Steffens</ENAMEX>, vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX>, not encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women employees</ENAMEX> to join a
class-action sex discrimination suit against the brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly a third</NUMEX>
of those eligible have joined the case, far more than the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> response
typical in similar actions.

               "We have heard that only one percent of the
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 5 feet 10 inches</NUMEX> with over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1400</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S.A.</ENAMEX>T. scores. And
we'd like to welcome each of you to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fashion Model University</ENAMEX> , a major
motion picture from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miramax</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene Pinkerton</ENAMEX>, not embarrassed to have
placed an ad on behalf of an infertile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> to a leggy,
brainy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Youthful erotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">awakening</ENAMEX>.

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
