
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 10, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s redesign brings with it a new Web site and a slick,
decidedly un-wonkish new look. ... The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column argues that the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> should use its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cold War-era</ENAMEX> spying apparatus to monitor human rights abuses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Spooks</ENAMEX> have
generally shied away from such missions because of the moral and political
dilemmas created when an intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> atrocities. ... A
piece describes wartime propaganda on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> TV. The
programming includes nationalistic music videos, scornful exposés of Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> is gay, as is most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>), and
repeated showings of the film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> endorses the deployment of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
But a separate editorial says that partial defeat (concessions to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbs</ENAMEX>, failure to repatriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>) will be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s "price of going to war
without the will to do the job properly." The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> neglected to anticipate the
refugee crisis, and the subsequent dispersal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovars</ENAMEX> across the
already shaky <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan region</ENAMEX> could cause "a potential collapse of terrifying
proportions." ... A piece bemoans <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s inert tourism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>.
Government and industry are squabbling over whether to promote the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as
the modern, hip "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cool Britannia"</ENAMEX> or as the tradition-soaked land of high tea
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 8, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> visits two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> uprising who have moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
and become evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>. Both believe that "the root of democracy is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">spirit of Christ</ENAMEX>" and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> will only come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> through mass
religious awakening. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles public radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira</ENAMEX>
Glass, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This American Life</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> exploration of odd corners
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture. Glass is considering launching a TV version of the show,
but not on public television, which he deems too influenced by its corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                
               and

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The newsweeklies slam the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's caustic cover story ("<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>, we are shocked to discover, is not a video
game") derides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s apparently unshaken faith in air power.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               lambastes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for "diplomatic errors and missed
opportunities": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> originally told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to offer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> a face-saving compromise; when action became
inevitable, they recommended strengthening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s military threat; finally, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airstrikes</ENAMEX> began, they urged planning for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> crisis sure to come. At
every turn, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> failed to heed. A sidebar reports that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> nixed a plot
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s inner circle to overthrow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>

               piece crudely indicts the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> (they "didn't
need to load <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> into boxcars to look bad"). Since losing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1389</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have been "seasoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haters</ENAMEX> raised on self-pity." Both
magazines print huge, heart-rending photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> explains why the anti-sweatshop
movement is growing on college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> has jump-started the
protests by lavishing student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> with internships and trips to countries
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> working conditions.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>

               writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>'s soon-to-be published final
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">True</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Light</ENAMEX> , a fictionalized account of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">safari</ENAMEX>, contains some of his funniest and most complex work.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story opines that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should have offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> a
better deal at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX>. A sidebar suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s lingering anger over
impeachment has colored his approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis. Another sidebar , titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Talking Casualties</ENAMEX>," scopes out what it
would take for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to win a ground war (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
setup time). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX> is a "born-again advocate" of an
invasion. ... A story forecasts country music's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Big Thing: African-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crooners</ENAMEX>. Country originated in gospel and blues, but since the civil rights
era <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> have associated country music with white prejudice. Now record
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are hoping that black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> acts will boost lagging sales.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               The 
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yorker</ENAMEX> excerpts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX>'s posthumous novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> , the
story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> of mixed race who denies his black heritage and becomes a racist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>. It will be published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles a
controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> "what if" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> whose work examines <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> history
as it might have been. He has deemed that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
fault and that allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> a partial victory then would have prevented
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bolshevik Revolution, World War II</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. ... A writer
recounts the colorful rise and fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Charles Jessup</ENAMEX>, the "the
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preachable preacher</ENAMEX> that ever preached preachable preaching." The star
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> healer built <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s first evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> by
broadcasting his tent revival act on the radio. After collecting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $10</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in "faith donations," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessup</ENAMEX> was locked up for mail fraud.

            
               
                  The
Nation
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            Much condemnation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s air campaign. An editorial says the bombing encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> nationalism,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enables Milosevic</ENAMEX> to crack down on dissent, destabilizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, undermines the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, and violates the principle that foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> should not
intervene in civil wars. ... A scathing article says the administration
is acting to make the world safe for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economic imperialism as much as
to avert a humanitarian disaster. Given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> brutality in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> and its
failure to stop other horrors (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>, etc.), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> "has no
moral ground to stand on" in condemning and attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
