
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Your reply to "" 
               regarding his
distress over his accent was insufficient, in that you more or less dismissed
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is real: In too much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> it does not
pay to be perceived as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX>--and the single biggest giveaway is an
accent.
            

            
               What should our young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> do? For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing,
recognize that he came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> past puberty--when a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
voice changes, so do his chances for assuming a "native" accent. But all is not
lost! Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> should buy a set of blank videotapes and set his VCR for one
or more of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk shows. Why? Because all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> shows offer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcripts</ENAMEX> (typically from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burrelle's of Livingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>), so he can have a
tape of the show as well as the exact transcript of what each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is
saying.
            

            
               Our young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> should select a particular
accent he wishes to emulate. (I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
has notably round, melodious tones.) Then read the transcript and repeat
the statement into a tape recorder. Repeat again and again until the recording
sounds exactly like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> in tone, inflection, and cadence.
            

            
               Does this work? Yes. I learned the technique
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> who is routinely mistaken for a native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> (on the
telephone). It is how I learned to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Japanese</ENAMEX> fluently at the age of
35.
            

            
               Sign me,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheering Him On</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Cheer</ENAMEX>,

            What a fascinating and generous letter. Prudie must
confess that your advice is a tad more constructive than her own. And you have
made other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> happy, as well. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, the charming Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX> who owns
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burrelle's</ENAMEX> and also the astute Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> of the round, melodious tones.

            We must only hope that
our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> does not get to sound too much like the aforementioned Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX>--or any of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sabbath</ENAMEX> gasbags, to use the phrase that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonderful Frank Rich</ENAMEX> has popularized. We must also hope that he does not weight
his conversation to talk of impeachment and partisan politics.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, thankfully

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               With current events
being what they are, I've been in several social situations where politics was
the topic of conversation. Since I am a very principled (and yes, opinionated)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, I eagerly take part. Knowing that politics and religion can lead to
arguments, I try not to be the instigator. It seems that lately, however, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with whom I get into these conversations are not well informed. They
don't usually understand legal and ethical principles, and they don't know much
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> history. Most of the time they're only going along with popular opinion
and haven't thought out their ideas. The flaws in their reasoning are easily
exposed, and I find that no matter how gently I state my case, I make
compelling arguments that frustrate and intimidate my talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. My
question is, what should I do?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Terry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stamford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Bru</ENAMEX>,

            It must be murder to be
smarter than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you find yourself with. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you find more
informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, join a study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, or forswear serious conversations where
you will not have to sit on your principles and opinions and your superior
knowledge of history. When all else fails, you can always launch into Gwyneth
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, conversationally

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am interested in a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-worker</ENAMEX> who left
to go back to school but who still lives in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as me. The chemistry
between us is palpable, and we truly enjoy many things together in what is
currently a platonic friendship. After she left I was in a dilemma, wanting to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX> the divide between friendship and a relationship.
            

            
               Not wanting to get my hopes up, or embarrass
her with untoward advances, I found myself--after she had already quit her
job--standing in front of her cubicle. I noticed that her computer was still
connected and that her e-mail program was open. No one was around so I sat down
and started reading the titles of her e-mail. Needless to say, it wasn't too
long before I found an e-mail she had sent to a mysterious mf50 (not the real
handle) in her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>. The message was one line, and it hit me in the solar
plexus: "Just wanted to say I love you."
            

            
               Was I wrong to read
her e-mail? Is this bad manners? (I found out, later, going back to her
computer, that "mf50" was actually her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.) Should I pursue the
relationship?
            

            
               --
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Pollard</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear J</ENAMEX>,

            Yes, you were wrong to
read her e-mail. It is really no different, in the integrity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, than
opening someone's letter. And, yes, it's bad manners. And, oh hell, pursue the
relationship, or at least give it a try. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels slightly ambivalent about
the cloak-and-dagger underpinnings involved. You might be "rewarded" with a
lovely romance. But on the other hand, if it hadn't been her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> knows you would have backed off. Complicated, this, but romance ranks
high in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s book, so go for it and snoop no more.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, tolerantly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I recently
interviewed for a position as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Software Development</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
produces shrink-wrapped packages for the corporate market. This is a small but
growing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> was voted "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Young Entrepreneur of the Year</ENAMEX>."
My experience in the job interviews with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exec</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> was the most
obnoxious I have had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36 years</TIMEX> in the business. They came on as if I was a
suspect in a major crime rather than an experienced professional interviewing
for a key position. The specifics included squeezing my hand in a viselike grip
during the handshake and asking questions such as, "Why do you want to work
here?" and saying with a serious demeanor, "Tell us about yourself." My
response to all this was quietly but pointedly to let them know that I
considered their manner to be amateurish at best and downright insulting at
worst. I did not get an offer. Thank God for small favors. However, I am
wondering if this is the new style of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gen X Wunderkind</ENAMEX> , or might
it have been an isolated case? What happened to social skills, or maybe I am
too old at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> to understand that it has all been "deconstructed" with the rest
of Western Civilization.
            

            
               --
Call <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me a Crank</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Call</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would not label
your experience a battle in the generational war, but a skirmish, perhaps.
"Tell me about yourself" in a job interview is regrettable and somewhat
imprecise, but might have played better with someone in their age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. As for
your age, you are on the shady side of the actuarial table for new
employment. Perhaps a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with a different outlook might fill the bill.
Young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> are not always looking for a graybeard. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> just knows you are
feeling like everything's gone to hell in a handbasket but hopes you will
philosophically come to terms with things the way they are.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, solicitously

         
      
   
