
   
   
      
         
            Heads Up! 

            With the millennium
looming, the list-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> seem to have inherited the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film Institute</ENAMEX> drew up a register of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> greatest American
films ever made. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Library</ENAMEX> chased the idea a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX> with its own list of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> best works of fiction of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> it
promises to name the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> best works of nonfiction . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Forum</ENAMEX>'s
Newseum compiled a roster of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> top stories of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> , and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> pegged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s 100 best works of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism .

            Not to be left behind, we've plundered the
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX> account, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>' new best-selling book to assemble a
more compelling--and concise--look at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 high</NUMEX> points of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>.

            Your mileage may vary, so if you've come across an
important headline that we've overlooked, please send it to 100TopHeds@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Click to read
the best of the nominations.
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>:
Near-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sighted Teddy Roosevelt Bags President McKinley</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safari</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright Brothers Announce</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3-Second</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meal Service</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12-Second</TIMEX> Flights

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taft Calls</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Legislation To Enlarge Doorways</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Railway</ENAMEX>
Seats, Bathtubs

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Albania Lapses Into Anarchy 85 Years Too Soon</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shipping Magnate Declares Titanic -Iceberg Merger Successful</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> Creates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Unite Nation Against Common Enemy</ENAMEX>"

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canal Opens New Era of Global Trade</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama Hats</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>:
Fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breaks Out Between War Correspondents</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German Submarine</ENAMEX> Fires <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Warning Torpedo Into</ENAMEX> Lusitania
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Physicians Laud Mustard Gas</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Inhalable</ENAMEX>
Condiment

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vows To Make World Safe for Robber Barons</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lenin Orders Pictures of Czar's Family Put on Milk Cartons</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeymoon Antics Give Gandhi Idea</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive Resistance</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Votes</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Celebrates With First Toast</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
Speakeasy

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rejects</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty of Versailles</ENAMEX> for Having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suspicious Foreign-Sounding</ENAMEX>
Name

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Women Experience Futility of Voting Firsthand</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Humane Loophole in Immigration Quotas Lets Some Foreigners Enter U.S. as</ENAMEX>
Livestock

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>:
Heisenberg Says Uncertainty Principle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> or May Not Be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greatest Discovery</ENAMEX>
Ever

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian Hijacker Forces Charles Lindbergh To Make Nonstop Transatlantic</ENAMEX> Flight
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunpoint</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> Rules <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Films Do Not Have Right To Remain</ENAMEX>
Silent

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Seldom Gets</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First, Admits Wife</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>:
Stock <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Market Crash Linked</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radicals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreigners</ENAMEX>, and
Anyone <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Looks Funny</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capone Denies Murder for Profit Allegations, Insists Gangland Slayings "Purely</ENAMEX>
for Fun"

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Goes off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold Standard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adopts Moldy Crust of Bread Standard</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Only Thing We Have To Fear Is Eleanor" Speech Calms Nation</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1933: New</ENAMEX>
Deal, Same Deck

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Woman Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Perkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrates by Getting Coffee</ENAMEX> for
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet Members</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newborn Ralph Nader Files Suit</ENAMEX> Against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ejecting Him Into Hostile</ENAMEX>,
Unsafe Environment

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcoholics Anonymous Sells First Mailing List</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smirnoff</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Labor Relations Act Recognizes Workers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right To Be Fired</ENAMEX>
Collectively

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Remaining Chinese Communists Receive</ENAMEX> "I Survived the
Long <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>" T-Shirts

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show Trials Notably Lacking in Good Show Tunes</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Civil War Erupts</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bullfighters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flamenco Dancers Clash Over Limited</ENAMEX>
Supply of Tights

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jobless Rate Tops 110 Percent With Many Unemployed at More Than One</ENAMEX>
Occupation

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>:
Over<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-Excited Hindenburg Announcer Explodes</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chamberlain Calls Hitler</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Nicest Totalitarian Maniac I've Ever</ENAMEX>
Appeased"

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland Invades Itself</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Gehrig Has Lou Gehrig's Disease</ENAMEX>; "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With My Name, I Figured It Was Only a Matter</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>," Says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee First Baseman</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women Enter Work Force</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower Pay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Longer Hours; "It's the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greatest Thing Since Slavery</ENAMEX>!" Say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry Leaders</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Trotsky</ENAMEX> Dies in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Ice Pick-Assisted Suicide</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Neither a Borrower Nor a Lender Be" Clause Added to Lend-Lease Act</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Stir-Fry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Resistance Waiters Bravely Refuse</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Refill Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffee</ENAMEX>
Cups

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>! Admitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sprightly Musical To Replace Boring Actual</ENAMEX>
State

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Soldiers Hear of Nude French Sunbathing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Storm Normandy Beaches</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Genuinely Touched" by Gift</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potsdam</ENAMEX> Surprise
Party

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
Charges <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drunken UFO Pilot in Roswell Crash</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Defeats Dewey</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Louie Have Yet To Concede</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Blamed for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Starting Hopeless Asian Land War 15 Years Too Soon</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>: Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TV Couples May Be Sleeping Together, Say Insiders</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R. Asks Hungary</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Has Parking Spaces for</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> Tanks

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Innocent Soviet Corpses Thrilled</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posthumous Rehabilitation</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>:
First <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hospice Allows Patients To Die in Homelike Setting--Surrounded by Greedy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hateful Relatives</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>:
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quiz Show Investigators Stunned by Revelation That Not Everything</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TV Is Real</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-2
Shot Down Over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Infant Bono Unhurt</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
Markets <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bay of Pigs Blooper</ENAMEX> Reel

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Innocent Trees Die To Make Silent Spring a Best Seller</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>: JFK
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accidentally Struck</ENAMEX> Down by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flying Zapruder Lens Cap</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>:
Rockefellers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys Conscientiously Object</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall McLuhan</ENAMEX> Caught Reading

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McNamara Commended</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA</ENAMEX> for Applying New Math to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Casualty</ENAMEX>
Figures

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFK Assassinated</ENAMEX> Separately but Equally

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>:
Hippies, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beatniks Sign Historic Personal Hygiene Ban</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nonproliferation Treaty Strictly Limits Nuclear Weapons</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nations That Can</ENAMEX>
Afford Them

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Kennedy</ENAMEX> Charged With "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leaving the Scene of a Successful Cover-Up</ENAMEX>"

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Near-Perfect Neil Young Guitar Solo Ruined by Addition of Second Note</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Hoover Buried</ENAMEX> in Simple but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elegant Black Dress</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor Will</ENAMEX> Use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Bar Code Technology To Track Husbands</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>:
Entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Product Safety Commission</ENAMEX> Dies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pinto</ENAMEX> Explosion

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pardons Nixon</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plaid Trousers</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News: Smelly Ozone Layer</ENAMEX> Disappearing

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monopoly Threatens Free Market, Warns Head of Tiny Start-Up Microsoft</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Management</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>
Brings Western Civilization to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Official Halt</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan Shot En Route</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA Fund-Raiser</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Day O'Connor Receives Congratulatory Pat</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind From Fellow</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale Fever</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweeps Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
Are the World" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gives Hope</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Has-Beens Starving</ENAMEX> for a Hit

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ollie North Wins Daytime Emmy</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Democratic Platform Not High Enough To Make Dukakis</ENAMEX>
Visible

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Authorities Kick Off</ENAMEX> "Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square Clean</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week With Special</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tank Sweepers</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scientist Achieves Cold Fusion on Honeymoon</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi Army</ENAMEX> Stages Spirited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/8</NUMEX>-of-a<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-Second</TIMEX> Counteroffensive

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">For</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God's Sake, Use a Decent Camera</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pleads Extraterrestrial</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Abstinence TV Spots Boost Teen Celibacy</ENAMEX> to a Record <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.0002 percent</NUMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>:
Desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Postmaster General Tries To Hand Deliver</ENAMEX> E-Mail

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>: AOL
Offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hours of Free Downtime</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>: Wave
of 1970s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nostalgia Drives</ENAMEX> up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Oil</ENAMEX> Prices

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primitive Amazon Tribe Still Using Apple</ENAMEX> IIs

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa To Assume National Debt</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.9 percent</NUMEX>, No Annual
Fee

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hair Club</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Men Must Admit Women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Court Rules</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Luck Gene" Identified</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Abacuses Still Reeling From Year 2000 B.C. Problem</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>:
Internet Fills up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Terrifying Void of Existence</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU Targets Lactose Intolerance</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard To</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accept Mortal Kombat Scores</ENAMEX> in Place of SATs

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Union Introduces Singing</ENAMEX> Mammogram

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Approves Nicotine Eye Patch</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> Win <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Drug War</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Turnout for Apocalypse Lighter Than Expected; Most</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prefer To Be Elsewhere When World</ENAMEX> Ends

            Is there an important headline that we've
overlooked? Please send your nominations to 100TopHeds@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Click to read the best of the
nominations.
            

         
      
   
