
   
   
      
         
             Double Take

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> began bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX> and doves have agreed on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration have "miscalculated." "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> completely
miscalculated when it launched the air campaign," declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
Murkowski, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>. "They assumed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> would immediately
retreat when the bombs began to descend."

            This critique is well founded, but it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dimension of the story. In war, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, and each can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">miscalculate</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, war has a psychological dimension, in which each
side's morale is undermined by its mere belief that it has
miscalculated. To win the practical war, you don't have to calculate perfectly.
All you have to do is outcalculate your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. Likewise, to win the
psychological war, all you have to do is make your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> second-guess his
belligerence more than he thinks you're second-guessing yours. The surest way
to lose the psychological war is to fret that you have misjudged your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>'s
resolve, while failing to entertain the possibility that he will decide he has
misjudged yours.

            The "miscalculation" critique permeated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
war debate on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor. "It appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> mistakenly thought that bombing specified military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> would send a message to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> that
would cause him to quickly embrace the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> peace plan. It is obvious this was
a gross miscalculation," charged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCollum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Smith</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, denounced "the tragic miscalculation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> would back down if we bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>."

            Since this way of framing the conflict treats <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
but not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> as a rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> susceptible to threats, punishment,
failure, and re-evaluation, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> is happy to encourage it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zivadin Jovanovic</ENAMEX> warned that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> ground invasion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> "would be yet another miscalculation by those who have already been
proved wrong so far," posing "dangers to the whole continent" and drawing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> into a quagmire that would make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> look like "nothing."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>, Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX>, decided he had heard enough of this critique. Wrapping up his
opening remarks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> turned the miscalculation
argument on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, "may have thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> really
wouldn't launch the airstrikes. But he was wrong. He may have believed they
wouldn't last after they were started. Wrong. He may have thought that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> would be afraid of his bluster and intimidation, they would withdraw
the use of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> or buckle under his intimidation. He was wrong. He
thought that other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> might rush to his aid. Wrong again."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> went on: "He thought that taking prisoners
and mistreating them and humiliating them publicly would weaken our resolve.
Wrong again. He thought his air defense would be effective against our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>. Wrong. He thought his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would stay loyal. Increasingly he's
wrong about that. There are more desertions. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> are under arrest.
Dissent is growing louder and louder. Military press censorship has been
imposed. He thought he could hide the truth from his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, I suppose, and
increasingly he's wrong in that. We're winning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is losing, and he
knows it. He should face up to this and he should face up to it now."

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reinforced Clark</ENAMEX>'s campaign to counterframe the miscalculation thesis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Shea</ENAMEX> suggested that the assignment of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> "demonstrates yet again <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s miscalculations. He thought he could
defeat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> in a short, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-to-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX>' operation. ... [This] was
completely wrong and is further testimony to the success of the air campaign."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, contended that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "counted, at the outset
of this, when he moved his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> breaking up quickly--and
quite the opposite has happened." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Press Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX>
predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "will change his calculation" as his apparatus of
power is progressively destroyed.

            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misjudge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s efficacy and resolve?
Absolutely. But to debate that question by itself is already a loaded
proposition, because it overlooks the corresponding question of whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has misjudged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s efficacy and resolve--and whether he,
accordingly, can be humbled into reconsidering his belligerence before we
reconsider ours. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> understands that in war, morale is both vital and
relative. He has heard enough pessimism from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> on the
subject of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has miscalculated. He is not interested in changing the
answer. He is interested in changing the question.

         
      
   
