
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">241</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;A Very Special ...&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               A recent episode
of a popular TV series was postponed because it was frighteningly like an
actual, front-page event. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> says it will go ahead and broadcast
the show's season finale, although it too is disturbingly reminiscent of that
same event. How will the listing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> describe the big
show?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 240</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So Stop and Ask Directions":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     Fill in the blank on this thoroughly satisfying
explanation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>: "None of those maps indicated
that it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> that was being targeted. It was not a human
error or mechanical error--it was a(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX>) __________
error."
                  
               
            

            "
'Humechanical error?' offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> after an uncomfortably long
pause."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Shuger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duncan</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

            "
'Hilarious error.' (This contributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s angry reaction.)"--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
            

            "
'Typographical error.' 'Chinese <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX>' was mistakenly typed 'aspirin factory'
on the map, so the spell-checker missed it."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Novak</ENAMEX> )

            "
'Cartoon error.' Just try this little trick to defuse the tragedy of the
situation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missiles</ENAMEX> through window. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> flattened. Staccato violins pluck
out stereotypical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> music. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> run around, backsides aflame. Cut to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> positioning boulder on cliff."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M Pesca</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in my boyhood when the world seemed full of possibility. I and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
would take our fishing poles down to the pond and dip our toes in the water and
... oh, I'm sorry--are we out of time? I deeply regret the error."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Please Stop Sending Me Those Autoreplies" Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            It is a terrible thing to be dragged in front of
the TV cameras and forced to admit that your own dreadful ineptitude led to
horrible suffering, which is why I pray that none of you will ever have your
divorce hearing televised. But if you do, may you be blessed with the wiliness
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX>, the agility of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, and the creepy ingenuity of a defense secretary
in concocting a dazzling non-acknowledgement: It was nobody's fault. It's the
new heartlessness.

            Whatever happened to the
military's traditional heartless approach of finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX>? In Stanley
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1957 Paths of Glory</ENAMEX> , when those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> failed to go
over the top and take the anthill, the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> arbitrarily picked three
poor, dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bastards</ENAMEX> to be tried and executed for cowardice. In the remake, the
general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> will arbitrarily select <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saps</ENAMEX> who will be tried and found
delightfully not guilty. The movie will be called ... oh, pick it--anything
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tailhook</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviano</ENAMEX> . No, wait. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was found responsible
for that last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, not for the deaths themselves, but for destroying a
videotape. Patton, I think it was.

            
               Always Check Your
Answer
            

            "It was an institutional error."

            Some ways of cross-checking a map the institution
decided not to try:

            

               Have an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> on the ground confirm the location.

               Have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> on the ground confirm the location.

               Ask an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who'd recently been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>.

               Ask a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.

               Look it up in the phonebook.

               Call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav Federal Directorate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supply</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Procurement</ENAMEX> and ask for
its address.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartographic Fun</ENAMEX>
Fact
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Imagery</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mapping Agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> that made the map of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, also made
the map of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviano</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> without the ski lift. Coincidentally, it was also
nobody's fault that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> jet severed the cable and killed those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skiers</ENAMEX>.

            
               Let Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fingers</ENAMEX>
Do the Extra
            

            The just-arrived
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Yellow Pages</ENAMEX> is sprinkled with chirpy public-service ads. As every
professional knows, placement is as important as the ad itself. That is, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> an ad in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is read is affected by the other information on the
page. Below, actual phone book public service messages, the actual paid ads
that accompany them on the page, and the presumed meaning of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">juxtaposition</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Ad</ENAMEX>: "Encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to write and
share original stories."

            Paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity signatures</ENAMEX> and sports
memorabilia."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Message</ENAMEX>: Get
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to sign lots of stuff, so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years from now</TIMEX>, when they're famous, you
can sell it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer</ENAMEX> to read to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>."

            Paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">She-Male Escorts, The Alternative to the</ENAMEX>
Routine."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Message</ENAMEX>:
Something about reading pornography to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>? I'm as appalled as anyone.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Ad</ENAMEX>: "Hold family storytelling
sessions."

            Paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Oldest Private Drug and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcohol Treatment Center</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Message</ENAMEX>: Hold
family storytelling sessions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Milt</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX> benders in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Healthy Advice</ENAMEX>. Consult your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> before beginning an exercise program."

            Paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sizzle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Escorts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feel the Heat</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presumed Message: Ever</ENAMEX>
since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> died during sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so cautious. It's like they're
afraid of being sued or something.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Ad</ENAMEX>: "Household safety. Make sure
everyone in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> knows what to do in the event of a fire."

            Paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Accident Victims</ENAMEX>. You Need an Experienced
Law Firm ... fire and explosion injuries."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Message</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
the fire, then the lawsuit.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Ad</ENAMEX>: "New in town? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shop the Bell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Yellow Pages</ENAMEX>."

            Paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Asian Club Escorts to Excite You</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Message</ENAMEX>: Don't
know where to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hooker</ENAMEX>? Here.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Ad</ENAMEX>: "Start your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX>."

            Paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold Shield Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Investigations</ENAMEX>.
Private and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corporate Investigations</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presumed Message: Make</ENAMEX>
big money writing books <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will pay you not to publish. Start with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milt</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> error.

         
      
   
