
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musa</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ake&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musashimaru</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akebono</ENAMEX> to become the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">67 th yokozuna</NUMEX>. Why is
this noteworthy?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 249</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cam Com Can Gal":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  The list includes cameras, laptop computers, canvas bags of
tools, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">665 gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. List of what?
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Award</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inducements</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who are ready to switch to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> local
service."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Things used as stand-ins for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> while Star Wars was being
filmed."--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin Warner</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To</ENAMEX>
the horror of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>, soon the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yangtze River</ENAMEX> will be composed
entirely of these items."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Once-hidden details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Da Vinci</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Supper</ENAMEX> , now clearly visible
beneath the table."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robot</ENAMEX>
punch. Serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Large
Intestine Wrap-Up
            

            Although many of you submitted enema jokes, I ran
none--an aesthetic not a political decision, if such a distinction is possible.
Some laugh at colonic humor, some don't. I have no doubt that several entries
were particularly fine examples of rectal comedy. These I have passed along to
my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> counterpart, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophie Rhys-Cohen</ENAMEX>, who plans to run them in "Naughty
Scamp," the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>, along with many comical pictures of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothing and a terrific photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>'s left
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX>. (At least they said it was hers when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sophie R-C</ENAMEX> handed over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">£100,000</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' money.)

            Incidentally, Naughty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scamp</ENAMEX> is still encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to suggest better things to do with
fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> than eat them.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Russian Walk Into an Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            All are packed in the cargo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bay</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Shuttle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Columbia</ENAMEX> for a scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> launch.

            And if it does take place, that launch will end a
string of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> consecutive failures. The unmanned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-failure record was broken
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thaad</ENAMEX> anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX> that was to serve as
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>, in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Bacon</ENAMEX>,
"tumbled chaotically out of control." I guess we've all done that. The Thaad
project, incidentally, has already cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $3 billion</NUMEX>. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> is discouraged by its unbroken record of failure. I
call that plucky.

            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> does get off the ground, its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> will transfer those supplies
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, in one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">160</ENAMEX> space walks on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">86</NUMEX>
flights needed to complete the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>--and no doubt worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">every penny</NUMEX>.

            Canvas? Can that be
right--canvas tool bags in outer space? Shouldn't the tools be stowed in
something spectacularly light and strong and expensive--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevlar</ENAMEX> or woven <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tang</ENAMEX> or
something? But that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Dickey</ENAMEX> reports in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and that's good enough for me.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>'s
Medical Extra
            

            I don't know if this
counts as an "extra" or anything, but what the hell is going on with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>' neck? I mean, you'd think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with all that high-tech know-how could
do something about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX>. It's less like a wattle and more like a Siamese
twin. Maybe he could computer-animate some paisleys on it and claim it's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scarf</ENAMEX>. Am I the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> this unsettles? Am I just jealous?

            
               Headline
Haiku
            

            Local Press Looking
human experimentation lab
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promote Good Citizenship</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
Waugh
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ex-Cons</ENAMEX> Find
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drag Racer</ENAMEX>
Touching and Fondling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Favorite Hobbyhorse</ENAMEX>

            
               Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25, 1999</TIMEX>

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Colonic discomfort.

         
      
   
