
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dress To Thrill</ENAMEX>

            Coming to work on the bus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>, I sat
across the aisle from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was probably in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50s</TIMEX>. She was plain
looking and plainly dressed. I guessed her to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household worker</ENAMEX>. Her slip
was showing. That is not unusual. What struck me was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hem</ENAMEX> of her slip
was lace.

            I spontaneously said to myself, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What a pitiful</ENAMEX>
attempt at elegance!" But when I got off the bus and ruminated on it, I
realized that was a condescending and stupid reaction. She was saying
something. She was saying; "I'm not just a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-legged vacuum cleaner or
dishwasher. I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who deserves to be respected and loved."

            That bit of lace made a big difference to her. It
was the difference between a work uniform and private, personal dress. Wearing
the lace was a decision she had made for herself, beyond the requirements of
her working life. She was expressing her membership in a class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
have a life beyond work and who have some bit of "fancy" in their dress to show
it.

            To whom was she making this statement? To herself,
of course. There may have been someone else--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>. But
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all she was making it for herself, to make herself feel good.

            How do I know this,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX>? I have not interviewed her nor spoken any word to her. But I imagine
that is the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are. I imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to think of themselves
as belonging to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that they admire or respect and dress as they think a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> dresses. Their object is not to display their
individuality, except that they want to choose their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. I don't believe
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> were happy all wearing the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> jackets, because that
did not express membership in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that they had chosen. I understand that
under those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> jackets there were frequently bits of colorful clothing that
reflected more private choices.

            The message of the clothing is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all to the wearer.
I think of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Side Story singing "I Feel Pretty</ENAMEX>!" They
didn't sing "I'm So Pretty." The important thing for them was to feel
pretty, and they associated the way they dressed with the feeling of being
pretty.

            We see all the young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--and some not-so-young--walking around in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> district in short,
black dresses and shoes with built-up, chunky heels. For many of them, that is
not the most becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> they could wear. That depends on how good their
legs are. And they are surely not expressing individuality. They are expressing
their membership in a class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are smart, professional, liberated,
and also feminine and sexy. They are expressing it to themselves and to
whomever may be looking.

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street corner</ENAMEX> there is a group of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with
exceedingly droopy trousers and black, high shoes. The laces flopping loosely.
They are imitating prison dress. In their way--which may be entirely peaceful
and law-abiding--they are showing their solidarity with those who thumb their
noses at the mores of bourgeois society.

            What about all those men
you see in gray slacks and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy blue blazers</ENAMEX> with brass buttons? They are
ever-young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>--or want to feel they are. They are proud
to be "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarsdale Galahads</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks Brothers</ENAMEX> types," despite the disdain with
which those words are used in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolls</ENAMEX> .

            Of course, the extreme in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s dress is the dinner jacket.
All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--at least, the ones I know--say they hate to have to get into that
monkey suit. They curse as they struggle with the bow tie. But is there a man
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> so dead, or a waist so big, that he does not smile and say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX>," when he looks at himself in the mirror fully attired?

            When I was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
administration, we were all very buttoned-down during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX>,
however, when only the "responsible" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX>, came
to work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Office Building</ENAMEX>, casual dress was
the uniform. That was our way of showing, to ourselves especially, that we were
intimates of those eminent locations.

            And what about me now? On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> I go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, I
wear a flannel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> with no necktie if the weather is cool. In warm weather, I
wear an open-necked sport shirt with no jacket. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have said that I
dress "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> style," but that isn't really it. I am asserting my membership
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Geezers</ENAMEX>." We have paid our dues. We are free of
obligations, including the obligation to dress like everyone else. We know that
our dress is only a trivial sign of our liberation, but it is a sign we
enjoy.

            So, hail to you, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lace-bedecked bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>! May you
always be elegant to yourself, as you will always be to me.

         
      
   
