
   
   
      
         
            Free Movies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers seem
to be trying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> into sending ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The
Daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph of London</ENAMEX>, very keen on ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> itself, led its front
page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hints at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> invasion," based on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> having dispatched his leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> TV shows "to
suggest a possible escalation of the conflict." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>
led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with news of the growing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> popular support for a land
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invasion</ENAMEX> and the increasing pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to embark on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by both
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            The war continued to
lead practically every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s mass-circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , which splashed
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wills In Hospital Drama</ENAMEX>" on its front page. The story told how <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>' eldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, had had a broken finger reset after a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> attempt
to fix it failed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> also considered this story worthy
of its front page, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> gave greater prominence to a story about the queen's sister: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> recovers after
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">scalding feet</NUMEX> in bath." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> explained that "any
serious burn to the feet, hands, face or genitalia is considered of great
medical importance and is usually treated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
has warned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> about some of its planned airstrikes in order
to minimize civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simpson</ENAMEX>, diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>,
wrote for the paper from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> that the clearest example of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> had been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kragujevac</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at a car factory
had been ordered to end a sit-in protest against the airstrikes because the
factory was about to be targeted. "The only problem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> faced was in
persuading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> that their information was genuine," he reported. The same
paper reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British SAS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandos</ENAMEX> had been sent deep into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to
target the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> Special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, find and mark
massacre sites, locate the hideouts of death <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad leaders</ENAMEX>, and find secret
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Serb</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arsenals</ENAMEX>.

            Another Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">José Comas of Spain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa</ENAMEX> í
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">s</ENAMEX> ,
contributed a special article to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday-Monday</TIMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> describing the
mounting anger and defiance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>: Many young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including sworn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>, were saying they would
fight to the death over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> had reconciled
themselves to every shortage except that of cigarettes, he reported, quoting a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> as saying that this could be the first thing to destabilize
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> because "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> can't live without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>." But Comas
said the war had also brought positive changes to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>. "Crime has
completely disappeared," he wrote. "Before the bombs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> tried to
cheat their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Today, they charge the correct fares." He added that
nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> had stopped charging for tickets, and that those that still
did charge something were giving the proceeds to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L e Monde</ENAMEX> also devoted a front-page article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
to a mysterious journey by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavle Bulatovic</ENAMEX>, who,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bulgarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trud</ENAMEX> , turned up unexpectedly last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bulgarian</ENAMEX> border post of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalotina</ENAMEX> and was kept waiting there
for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> before being taken to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sofia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bulgarian</ENAMEX>
capital. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trud</ENAMEX> , he then took a flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have since denied his presence there. It was believed he might have
gone arms-shopping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> before reappearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said.

            In an editorial, Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s saber rattling on television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> as
"both pathetic and disturbing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> were a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, it said, and
"to see them represented by a valetudinarian buffoon and exploited by a corrupt
regime after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">totalitarianism</ENAMEX> fills one with deep sadness." The
paper said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s past greatness and her continuing possession of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>
nuclear warheads explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> continue
to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to her, but added: "If it is wise not to marginalize the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>,
it is also perhaps imprudent to take their bragging seriously, thus encouraging
them to be even more intransigent--and more demanding when they ask for
loans."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that the West would be wrong to ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s warnings,
however "insolent and demagogic" they might be. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is still the world's
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> nuclear power, and we cannot further humiliate her with impunity in her
present state of prostration," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> said. "Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> nor the
world should forget the lesson of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles</ENAMEX>: A humiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> hatched the
seeds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX>." But "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don't Fear the Bear</ENAMEX>" was the headline of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's editorial.

            The lead story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> of forcing an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Platt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARE</ENAMEX>, into making a "preposterous" televised confession
of spying for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> of
putting words into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Platt</ENAMEX>'s mouth and demanded his immediate release.

             

         
      
   
