
   
   
      
         
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> finally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aired Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s accusation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> forced himself
on her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years ago</TIMEX>. The segment examined problems in her story: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She said
"no" at first but later stopped resisting; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) she didn't report the crime; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
she can't remember when it happened; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) she filed an affidavit in the Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case denying she had been assaulted. Her explanations: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) she was
"panicky"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) she was "in denial"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) she thought "it was my fault"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) "I
didn't think anyone would believe me." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> denies the allegation,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> refuses to say where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> in question.
The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> has no motive to lie. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) But she ruined her
credibility by changing her story twice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Her credibility can't be as bad as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) What's scary is that the allegation is plausible. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowards</ENAMEX> for ignoring it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowards</ENAMEX> for secretly using it
as a basis for their impeachment votes. (For more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> spins, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s ".") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> received the death penalty for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chaining</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> Byrd
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> to a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and dragging him to his death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> would be the first
white executed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for killing a black since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1850s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black rejected the defense's argument that poor conditions in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> had served time had caused his racism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Optimists</ENAMEX> and pessimists debated whether the case showed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the persistence of
racial violence or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) a growing resolve to prosecute it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> debated
whether the sentence was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) bad because the death penalty is always wrong or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>)
good because the death penalty has been applied in a racially discriminatory
manner. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Tracht</ENAMEX> (a k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Greaseman</ENAMEX>") was fired for joking
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> racial murder . Shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracht</ENAMEX> played a song by a black
hip-hop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and then joked, "No wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drag them behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Listeners</ENAMEX> and black radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> protested and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tracht</ENAMEX> apologized, but his
station fired him, saying it "cannot be associated with the trivialization of
an unspeakable act of violence." The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> who made a "slip
of the tongue." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He's a racist who joked on the air in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>'s birthday, "Kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more and we can take a whole week off."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The scandal is that only a comment this offensive can get a shock jock
fired. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Radical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feminist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Daly</ENAMEX> refused to let <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male students</ENAMEX> enroll in
her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston College</ENAMEX> introductory course on feminist ethics. She says <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) she has
offered to teach male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> separately, but having them in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would dampen debate among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) one of the male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> who was just trying to score a political point. The college
administration, citing gender equality law, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daly</ENAMEX> to admit the male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> or stop teaching. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daly</ENAMEX> is taking a leave of absence in the hope that
the dispute will blow over. She accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> of "caving in to right-wing
pressure and depriving me of my right to teach freely and depriving [female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>] of the opportunity to study with me." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> agreed to work together in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. To
recap: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> decided to launch an inquiry into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s conduct in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case. Then a conservative legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> asked the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who had
appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to intervene. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to file briefs
on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> had authority to launch the inquiry. The conservative spin:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is conspiring with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. The liberal spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is
conspiring with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and the conservative legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to hide their
conspiracy to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The cynical spin: Let's get rid of the independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counsel</ENAMEX> law so we don't have to listen to any more of this garbage.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
peace talks made progress . The ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX>, which is seeking
independence from ethnically <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, agreed to the peace deal in
principle but asked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> to convince its armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> to abandon their
rebellion against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in exchange for limited self-rule. The talks
recessed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX>. The scenarios, in order of ascending cynicism: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The
ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> will approve the deal, enabling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> with bombing unless he goes along. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
will use the recess to attack the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hard-liners</ENAMEX> will use the recess to attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in the hope of persuading
the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to back the war instead of the peace talks. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> will attack the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in the hope of persuading them to
back the war, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> would win, instead of the peace talks, which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> would lose. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) The ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> will approve the deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">threaten Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> will ignore the threat, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will once again
do nothing. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/24/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Twelve</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> threw their support behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> ,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> expect at least three
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> to add their support soon. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX>
announced that he would publicly castigate any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who "sowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> by attacking other candidates
personally. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicholson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> translate this as a warning against further
attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. This comes amid news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is taking another leave
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> to explore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> presidential bid. The pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
spin: It's amazing how early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are uniting behind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.
The anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> spin: It's not surprising that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> are backing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
their own. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are in deep trouble and are
desperately hoping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> can save them. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/24/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Election news:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Daley</ENAMEX> won re-election with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 70 percent</NUMEX>
of the vote. Several black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> backed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> despite assertions by his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Rush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Black Panther</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> had
neglected poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The rosy spin: It's a victory for racial unity. The
cynical spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Daley</ENAMEX> machine lives on. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Isakson</ENAMEX>, a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>, won the special election for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> seat . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> had a field day contrasting the "moderate" Isakson
with the "combative" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> "see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isakson</ENAMEX> as a pleasant
change" and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isakson</ENAMEX> thrashed second-place finisher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Jeffrey</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> had fired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> over her comments on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/24/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran</ENAMEX> said he will assemble a dream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> "accountable" for the death of
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peddler</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou Diallo</ENAMEX>, died after
plainclothes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> fired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> at him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vestibule</ENAMEX> of his
apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, hitting him <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> times. The racial controversy has consumed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> examines the case. At the same rally at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran</ENAMEX> spoke, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpton</ENAMEX> said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> itself is on trial before the world."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Movie critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Siskel</ENAMEX> died at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> . He had been recuperating from surgery to remove
a brain tumor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obituaries</ENAMEX> fondly recalled his on-air debates and "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> thumbs
up" salutes with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> on their eponymous syndicated TV
show. Siskel was the skinny <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The pessimistic spin: There's only one thumb
left. The optimistic spin: There's still one thumb left. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> signed agreements to reduce their tensions.
They pledged to alert each other to nuclear weapons tests or accidents. They
also promised to try to solve their border dispute over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. This comes
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> after both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> showed off their nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arsenals</ENAMEX> by
detonating bombs underground. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) They've agreed to give peace a
chance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) What agreement? They've only agreed to keep talking. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Coming from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, that's nothing to sneeze at. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It's amazing that they've
relaxed their enmity after showing each other their nuclear weapons. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) They've
relaxed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enmity</ENAMEX> precisely because they've shown each other their nuclear
weapons. (For more on the meeting, see ".") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
