
   
   
      
         
            Dark <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Side</ENAMEX> Lite

            Those poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who've been camping out in front
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX>: Who can blame them for saying, "To hell with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, we know it will be great!"? The doors will open, and they'll race to
grab the best seats and feel a surge of triumph as their butts sink down. We've
made it: Yeeehaww!! They'll cheer when the familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Williams</ENAMEX>
fanfare erupts and the title-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars Episode 1: The Phantom</ENAMEX>
Menace --rises out of the screen and the backward-slanted opening "crawl"
begins: "A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away ..." Yaaahhhhhhh!!!
Then, their hearts pounding, they'll settle back to read the rest of the
routes to outlying star systems is in dispute." Taxation of trade routes:
Waaahoooo!!!!
            

            How long will they go with it? At what point will
they realize that what they've heard is, alas, true, that the picture really is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stiff</ENAMEX>? Maybe they never will. Maybe they'll want to love The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> so much--because they have so much emotional energy
invested in loving it, and in buying the books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, dolls, cards,
clothes, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX>, fast food, etc.--that the realization will never sink in. In
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypnosis</ENAMEX>, the subject works to enter a state of heightened
susceptibility, to surrender to a higher power. Maybe they'll conclude that
common sense is the enemy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> and fight it to the death.

            Look, I wanted to love
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> , too. I was an adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and would enjoy being
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> again for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX>. But the movie has a way of deflating all but
the most delusional of hopes. If someone had given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Wood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115 million</NUMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">remake Plan Nine From Outer Space</ENAMEX> it might have looked like this,
although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX>'s dialogue would surely have been more memorable.

            The first thing that will strike you is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX>,
who wrote and directed the movie, has forgotten how to write and direct a
movie. Having spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two decades</TIMEX> since the original Star Wars (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>)
concocting skeletons of screenplays that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> flesh out, and overseeing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX> that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people storyboard</ENAMEX> and stage, he has come to lack what
one might Michelangelistically term "the spark of life." If the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars was a box of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cracker Jacks</ENAMEX> that was all prizes, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menace</ENAMEX> is a box of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cracker Jacks</ENAMEX> that's all diagrams of prizes. It's there
on paper, but it's waiting to be filled in and jazzed up.

            Advance word has been
cruel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, but advance word has it only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> right. Yes, they're
terrible, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewan McGregor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Portman</ENAMEX> are not terrible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, they've just been given scenes that no human could be expected to play.
As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage Jedi Master</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Qui-Gon Jinn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neeson</ENAMEX> must maintain a Zen-like
detachment from the universe around him--probably not a challenge when that
universe will be added in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> by computers. "I don't sense anything," he
tells his uneasy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apprentice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obi-Wan Kenobi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGregor</ENAMEX>), as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sit
waiting to conduct trade negotiations with a bunch of gray, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>-faced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> who talk like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> in a samurai movie. McGregor furrows
his brow. "There's something ... elusive," he says, working to enunciate like a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Guinness</ENAMEX> but succeeding only in nullifying his natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Scots</ENAMEX> charm.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>," he adds, "you said I should be mindful of the future." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neeson</ENAMEX> thinks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> dispute."

            A hologram of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Sidious</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dark Lord</ENAMEX> of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sith</ENAMEX>,"
commands the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX> to sic its battle droids on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi ambassadors</ENAMEX> before
they can apprise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Amidala</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portman</ENAMEX>) of the imminent invasion of the
peaceful planet of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naboo</ENAMEX>. In come the battle droids and out come the light
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sabers</ENAMEX>, which still hum like faulty fluorescents. Clack, clack, clack. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>
can't edit fight scenes so that they're fluid--he cuts on the clack. You get
the gist, though. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX> make their getaway, but with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and tolls and droid
destroyers, it takes them over an hour to land on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naboo</ENAMEX>, by which time the
queen and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galactic Senate</ENAMEX> have already got the grim message. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> have been disrupted: "A communications disruption can mean only
one thing," says someone. "Invasion."

            Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amidala</ENAMEX>, done up
like a white-faced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">empress</ENAMEX> in hanging beads and glass balls and a hat
with curly horns, speaks in tones from which emotion has been expunged, perhaps
on the theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> won't argue with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> who puts them to sleep: "I
will ... lead ... us ... to ... war," she drones. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi whiz</ENAMEX>
through the underwater core of a planet in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-of-warlike submersible pursued
by 3-D <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dragony beasties</ENAMEX> and a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> with extra movable parts.
Potentially thrilling stuff, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neeson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGregor</ENAMEX> remain peculiarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unruffled</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> will guide us," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neeson</ENAMEX> blandly, and the director
seems to share his lack of urgency. There's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> detachment and there's Quaalude
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detachment</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom</ENAMEX> 
               Menace falls into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>: It
really does take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX>, in a galaxy far, far away. When R2-D2
showed up, I thought: At last, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> with the potential for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimacy</ENAMEX>!
            

            Say this for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>, he doesn't whip up a lot of bogus
energy, the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of such blockbusters as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Mummy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>) do. It's as if he conceived <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX>
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> No pageant and has purposely deadened his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, directing them
to stand stiffly in the dead center of the screen against matte paintings of
space or some futuristic metropolis and deliver lines alternately formal or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bemusing</ENAMEX>. ("This is an odd move for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Federation</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> considers
himself an "independent" filmmaker and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> of integrity. Had he not been
such a pretentious overlord, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> would doubtless have
been engaged to rewrite him and make the movie halfway human. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> would have punched up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Qui-Gon Jinn/Obi-Wan Kenobi</ENAMEX> badinage, and
a black dialogue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> would have given the comic-relief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar Binks</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-size <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> with pop eyes and a vaguely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">patois</ENAMEX>,
something fresher than "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ex-squeeze me</ENAMEX>!" and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butterfly McQueen</ENAMEX>-style
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">simpering</ENAMEX> and running away from battles. Those of us who complain about the
assembly-line production of "blockbuster" scripts need an occasional reminder
that assembly lines can do much to make empty thrill machines more lively.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menace</ENAMEX> didn't need to be barren of feeling, but it took a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Kasdan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Big Chill</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>), to draft the best and most
inspiring of the Star Wars movies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Empire Strikes Back</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>), and a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irvin Kershner</ENAMEX>, to breathe Wagnerian grandeur into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>' cartoonish fantasies. Having lived with the saga for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was prepared to set aside some of its narrative expectations here to
plumb the origins of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>' universe. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> , however,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX> already exist and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> is taken for granted--we're still
in the middle of the damn story. The only dramatic interest comes from a young
Tatooine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anakin Skywalker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Lloyd</ENAMEX>), whom we know will grow up
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Skywalker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Hamill</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Fisher</ENAMEX>) and
then surrender to the dark side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> and become <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX>. But that
transformation won't happen until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> episode; meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anakin</ENAMEX> is a
conventionally industrious juvenile with a penchant for building droids from
scratch and "pod racing"--an activity that he demonstrates in one of the
movie's most impressive but irrelevant special effects set pieces, a whiplash
hyperdrive permutation of the chariot race in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Hur</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>).

            Later in the film, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anakin</ENAMEX> goes before something called
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jedi Council</ENAMEX> and meets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel L. Jackson</ENAMEX> (together again!), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>
dramatizes the interrogation so ineptly that you either have to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoda</ENAMEX>'s
word that there's something wrong with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> ("Clouded this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s future is")
or to conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoda</ENAMEX>, like us, is moving backward through time and has
already seen Episodes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Anakin, he says smugly, has fear in him, and
fear leads to anger and anger to the dark side--which would mean, as I
interpret it, that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without fear (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't exist) are
suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi knighthood</ENAMEX> (perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoda</ENAMEX> will enlarge his
definition of fear in subsequent episodes). There's also some quasireligious,
quasiscientific blather to the effect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was conceived without a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> by "metachorians"--symbiont, microscopic life forms that will speak to
you if you "quiet your mind." In other words, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>. So, it's not nebulous,
after all! It can be measured. It can be quantified. It can even, perhaps, be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">merchandised</ENAMEX>.

            Yes, the effects are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">first-rate</ENAMEX>, occasionally breathtaking. But the floating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galactic Senate</ENAMEX> do little to distract you from parliamentary machinations that
play like an especially dull day on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek: Deep Space Nine</ENAMEX> . The
final military engagement, in which long-headed attack droids are rolled onto
the field as the spokes of a giant wheel, would be awesome if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> didn't
routinely cut away from the battle just when he seems on the verge of actually
thrilling you. The chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villain</ENAMEX>, bombastically named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Maul</ENAMEX>, is a horned,
red, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kabuki</ENAMEX>-style snake demon with orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pingpong</ENAMEX>-ball eyes who challenges the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX> to a couple of clackety light-saber battles. His appearances are
underscored by demonic chants; he might as well wear a neon beanie that flashes
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Guy</ENAMEX>." Like all revisionist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> cheats like mad. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vader</ENAMEX> had built <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-3PO</ENAMEX> as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, how come he never paid much attention to
him in the other movies--and vice versa? As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoda</ENAMEX> himself puts it, in another
context, "See through you we can."

            
Still, it's worth reprinting a blistering
e-mail sent to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> by a relative, after she'd let him know that I hated
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Phantom Menace :</ENAMEX>

            
               Surprise, Surprise. Star Wars was
never reviewed well by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. Sometimes a basic story that rests on great
special effects and stupid dialogue can be very entertaining--it's called a
cult movie, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> can have an effect on the obvious outcome that this
is going to be the highest grossing movie ever. I myself stood in line for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and already have tickets to see it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times, and I know I'll enjoy it.
Why? Because it plays on my childhood imagination. And I'm sure it's not as bad
as Return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX> , which was the weakest one--but I still liked it
and saw it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> times. I get tired of being told I'm not going to like it
because it doesn't adhere to certain basic critic criteria. I say bpthhhh
(sticking my tongue out to review)--don't be sending me anything dissing my
movie:):):)
            

            I'll be curious to know whether he sees The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> times, or even the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> for which he has paid. (I
could imagine seeing it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times only if they sold adrenaline shots at the
concession stand.) Or maybe he'll come out of the movie and say: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, you
didn't get it, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snot-Nosed-Criteria Critic Person</ENAMEX>. It's not supposed to be
exciting. It's laying the foundation for the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anakin</ENAMEX> and
Obi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wan</ENAMEX> defeat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandalorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clone Wars and Anakin</ENAMEX> marries
Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amidala</ENAMEX>. And listen, I'm getting in line even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> for tickets to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Episode 2</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> is with me, butt-head."

         
      
   
