
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Masks</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press was
softening up public opinion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for airstrikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> with gung-ho
editorials and grueling eyewitness accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> atrocities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
Even a liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> ran an editorial headlined "The time has come to show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>'s
threats aren't empty." The bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> was "a grim duty, but as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>,
it must be done," it said. Another liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , led its
front page with a story beginning: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> did not want us to see it, but
there was no mistaking the hellish fires raging in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> as ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> were torched by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>."

            All the world's major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> seemed to have reporters on the spot. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> carried
a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masked</ENAMEX> boogiemen drive children
into the snow." The report began, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wailing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> stumbled alone out of
Srbica, wearing only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumpers</ENAMEX> in the wind-whipped cold, not knowing which way to
turn on the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. Shoes lay scattered along the road as if their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>
had just stepped out of them, together with scraps of clothing. Fleeing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">civilians</ENAMEX> spoke of summary executions on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. ... The international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>'s worst fears have been realised."

            The image of monsters in masks was common to the reporting
both from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borneo</ENAMEX> where, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> , "masked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, some in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military uniforms, attacked the
village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritabou</ENAMEX>, looting and vandalising <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and firing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>."
Describing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Kalimantan</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>-controlled territory on the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo</ENAMEX> plagued by ethnic and
religious conflict, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that "armed mobs paraded the severed heads
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>" and that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> had been
hung with the dismembered parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>." It explained, "The
fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Kalimantan</ENAMEX> was sparked by a local dispute over a bus
fare."

            The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> led
the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> under the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-column
headline "Cannibal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">warriors feast</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> on the spot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lloyd Parry</ENAMEX>, wrote that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> carrying
spears, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machetes</ENAMEX> displayed a severed ear and a human arm and offered
me lumps of hearts and livers torn from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Madurese</ENAMEX>, who have
become the target of a large-scale ethnic purge. ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> displayed and then
ate a piece of cooked flesh, which he claimed to have cut from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of a
murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            A more pleasant story was the first successful
circumnavigation of the world by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in a balloon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breitling Orbiter</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Their achievement was generally received with enthusiasm--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> should rejoice and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> that it had been the world's last great
adventure--but there were also dissenting voices. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> said
that "travelling around the world by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> does not herald any wonderful
technological breakthrough to benefit humankind," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph of London</ENAMEX>
gloated over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Branson</ENAMEX>'s failure to achieve this ballooning
record after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> attempts. It said that the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> could now perhaps
focus on the bigger challenge of getting his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> train service to run on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. "If you did that, Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX>, you would have broken all your own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>," it said. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> evening paper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soir</ENAMEX> , a direct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jules Verne</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Around the World in 80 Days fame</ENAMEX>,
complained about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s dream had finally been
realized. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Michel Verne</ENAMEX> wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s vision had nothing in
common with this technological and commercially sponsored feat.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press was
also much preoccupied with the choice of a successor to disgraced Luxemburger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Santer</ENAMEX> as head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>. A consensus
seems to be building around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romano Prodi</ENAMEX>, the centrist former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die</ENAMEX>
Welt coming out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in his support. "The name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romano Prodi</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synonym</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Italian</TIMEX> for integrity and economic competence," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. It
claimed in its main front-page story that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schr√∂der</ENAMEX>
has also pledged Prodi his support.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> came too late for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
papers, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Walker</ENAMEX>, veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film critic</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening Standard</ENAMEX> , wrote
in an op-ed piece that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overheated</ENAMEX>, overhyped obsession with blockbusters, which is strangling the
creative spirit. He also criticized "the collusive relationship of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>." The volume of movie advertising has never been so high, he
said, and there is also "an unprecedented plethora of news about movies and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moviemakers</ENAMEX>. Most of it is uncritical, otherwise journalistic access to the big
names in the casts and the films with big numbers in their budgets is denied by
the gatekeeper publicists." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's front page carried a photo of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weeping Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> under the banner headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> Cleaneth Up." In
a similar Shakespearean wordplay, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
captioned a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paltrow</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth</ENAMEX> winneth."

            In an interview with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> broadcasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> insisted he bears
no grudge against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>, who won a long and bitter custody battle against
him. "I had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year</TIMEX> relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mia</ENAMEX> and found her to be very bright,
beautiful and a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>," he said. "She's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>. She has many
positive qualities, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in crises do desperate things. I wouldn't define
her personality or her life by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that dark</TIMEX> period." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> said that he always
books <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> when he checks into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> with his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soon-Yi</ENAMEX>, so
that he can have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> to himself. He also said he is mystified by his
films' lack of success in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in comparison with their reception
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. "It's a big mystery to me why my work isn't popular [in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>],"
he said. "I'm typically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>: born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, go to
basketball, play jazz. It doesn't depress me, but I'm bewildered."

             

         
      
   
