
   
   
      
         
             A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxing Woman</ENAMEX>

            Do taxes really drive
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> crazy? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amity Shlaes</ENAMEX> thinks so. Her new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Greedy Hand: How</ENAMEX>
Taxes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drive Americans Crazy and What To Do About It</ENAMEX> , argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is
on the verge of a civic tax revolt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX>, she writes, "cry out for tax
relief," and when tax breaks are given to them they "discover the puny size of
the break" and "turn angry." But the book demonstrates only that taxes have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driven Shlaes</ENAMEX> crazy. The notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> must pay some price for
government has rendered her incoherent, irrational, and convinced that
everybody else shares her obsession.

            This kind of pathology
is a job requirement for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX>, who writes on tax policy for the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX>' book is a longer exposition of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's supply-side theology, which holds that tax cuts for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upper-income earners</ENAMEX> can produce almost magical economic results. The book
preaches this now familiar creed to the multitudes; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX> uses folksy lingo
and homespun anecdotes to give her message a warmly populist glow.

            The problem, of course, is that the ever-rising tax burden
is not driving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> crazy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason for this disappointing stoicism may
be that for the middle class the tax burden isn't in fact rising. All credible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> (the nonpartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX>, for instance) agree that
the median tax burden has fallen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>--that is, middle-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> are paying less. And opinion poll after opinion poll shows that only
a tiny minority supports using the budget surplus for tax cuts. So, like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial dogma it recycles, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Greedy Hand</ENAMEX> must resort
to distortion, hypocrisy, and illogic to create the illusion of incipient tax
revolt.

            To do so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX> trots out
the same phony numbers used by anti-tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The book relies on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dodgy</ENAMEX> statistics from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Foundation</ENAMEX> that supposedly show a rising average
tax burden but are based on inflated estimates and miscounting (to review the
many egregious flaws in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Foundation</ENAMEX> study, see a previous ).

            In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX> cites <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> nonphony piece of
evidence--but even that doesn't mean what she thinks it does. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
suffering, she writes, from "real bracket creep." Bracket creep used to be a
problem: Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, tax brackets were based on fixed income thresholds
that didn't account for inflation. So when prices and wages rose quickly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> were pushed into higher tax brackets even though their real wages
weren't rising at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> fixed this by indexing tax brackets for
inflation.

            So bracket creep doesn't exist anymore. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX>
tries to resurrect it by discussing "real bracket creep"--the process of people
shifting into higher tax brackets as their real income climbs. This has
happened recently; the strong economy and booming stock market have produced
big gains in income and, hence, in income taxes. To dramatize this point,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX> recounts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> song "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taxman</ENAMEX>," written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, just as the group
was beginning to enjoy its greatest success. Their financial situation is a
representative sample--"we are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> now," she writes mournfully.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX> doesn't
explain why this is a problem . Yes, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> sold a skillion
albums <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, they paid higher taxes than they did when they struggled in
anonymity. And yes, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are paying tax rates they "never expected would
apply" to them, but only because they're earning more money than they ever
expected. Tax rates are marginal. When higher income moves you into a higher
tax bracket, you pay the higher rate only on the extra income. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accidentally</ENAMEX> added a few extra zeroes to the end of my paycheck, I would end up
paying a higher tax rate than I had anticipated, but you wouldn't hear me
complaining about it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX>' analysis is also full of astonishing omissions. She
denounces the payroll tax as regressive, which it is. But she doesn't mention
that its effect is partly offset by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>, a tax rebate
for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Indeed, she takes several swipes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>, writing,
for instance, that it "has morphed into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> project that shapes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' lives." It has shaped their lives by reducing or
eliminating their taxes. Amity, this is what you're supposed to be for ,
remember? Unless, of course, she is for reducing taxes on the rich but not on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX> and near <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> who benefit from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX> claims that the
entire notion of a progressive tax code is a fraud. "Progressivity," she
maintains, "doesn't do what it says it does: tax the rich." This is because the
wealthy use loopholes to avoid their nominal rates. For instance, she notes,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-rich</ENAMEX> can take their salary in the form of stock options, which are
taxed at a lower capital gains rate. Technically, she's wrong about that. In
most circumstances, employee stock option profits are taxed as ordinary income.
But her broad point that special breaks for things such as capital gains
undermine the tax code's progressivity is true enough.

            This is hardly a sincere indictment of the current system,
however. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX> for lower
capital gains rates on an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost daily</TIMEX> basis and has been doing so for more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have long championed the loopholes
that have compromised the tax code's progressive structure. Despite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's best efforts, though, the tax code is progressive. That
is, the effective rates--the actual taxes paid as a proportion of income--on
the rich are higher than those on the middle class.

            What explains the stunning logical inconsistencies
and misrepresentations in this book? Is it hypocrisy? Confusion? Or just a
philosophy of "any weapon to hand"? Probably a bit of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>. Shlaes hates
progressivity not because it fails but because it succeeds. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlaes</ENAMEX>
could honestly argue what she really believes: Making the rich pay higher tax
rates than the poor is just not fair, dammit. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't agree,
and that is what really drives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amity Shlaes</ENAMEX> crazy.

         
      
   
