
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">230</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Whoooo's Johnny</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> has been such an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> for us because he truly
believes in the power of our products," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Electronics</ENAMEX>. Who is endorsing what?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 229</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don't Think So":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Fill in the blank in this quote from cognitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
Bagemihl: "We shouldn't have to look to __________ to see what's normal or
ethical."
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story of O</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Hoover</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
gun control laws of the world's civilized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>
            

            "Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX>, or family. 'We should be able to get all our ethical input
from television, movies, and popular music,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bagemihl</ENAMEX> added. 'Can I get you
anything? <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Coffee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>?' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuger</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giraffes</ENAMEX>. Likewise, there's really not much point in turning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Crisp</ENAMEX>
for advice on browsing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> canopy of wooded grasslands."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>. 'But now that she's back to a C cup we can,' continued a smiling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bagemihl</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Self-Reference Wrap-Up
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s question, a cunning trap set by guest host
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>, forces me to acknowledge authorship of a column in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ethicist</ENAMEX>," a sort of jumped-up "Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abby</ENAMEX>,"
responding to ethical queries from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. I'm meant to analyze each question
and extract a general ethical principle, a rule--i.e., to apply the skills of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. This, of course, is the least interesting approach. We all know you
shouldn't shoot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. It would be more entertaining to consider mixed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motives</ENAMEX>, mitigating circumstances, conflicting social pressures, complicated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">histories</ENAMEX>, and then find that in this unique situation you really should shoot
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. It's the difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and the dramatist, between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> and the particular. (That, and the fact that show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have it all
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> when it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and shoes.)

            What compels the lawyerly approach is not
priggishness on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> (well, not entirely) but
limitations of space. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> needs only a brief summary of the case,
the dramatist needs a richly detailed scenario. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the column permits only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> words for each letter and response, so I necessarily take an approach that
might generously be called concise but is frequently called (via <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> e-mail)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cursory</ENAMEX> (actually, "cursory, you idiot").

            The oddest thing about the job is not its
limitations but the curious caricature that illustrates each column. This
sketch of a pensive moralist, the personification of the column, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Ben</ENAMEX>
of ethics, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Crocker</ENAMEX> of morals, looks not at all like me. It does,
however, bear a striking resemblance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>. Is that ethical?

            (Send questions to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ethicist</ENAMEX>@nytimes.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Don't Tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "We shouldn't have to look to the animal
world to see what's normal or ethical."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bagemihl</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Biological</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exuberance</ENAMEX> , a new book about homosexual behavior among <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, in which he
writes that same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shenanigans</ENAMEX> have been documented in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 450</NUMEX>
different species, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>, and bonobo apes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penguins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geese</ENAMEX> maintain same-sex matings for life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homosexual bears</ENAMEX> raise
offspring together. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Gay male trout</ENAMEX> move in with their straight female best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and then the fun begins.

            But in the current issue
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bagemihl</ENAMEX> warns that beyond a vague statement that "diversity is
part of human heritage," it's inappropriate to make claims about human behavior
based on his findings. And yet, just look at that adorable picture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> boy
giraffes with their necks entwined, and tell me you're not dying to turn it
into a movie starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Everett</ENAMEX> as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the left and anybody but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Lane</ENAMEX> as the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Return
Extra
            

            Everybody's got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty story, so I won't go on
and on about mine except to mention <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> highlights--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Meara</ENAMEX> and a bomb
scare. You'd have thought it would discourage her but, jeez, she just kept
coming back. Of course, you'd have thought she'd discourage us, but we kept
coming back, too. State law.

            I'm grateful to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh for filling in with disconcerting skill and to all of you for
attenuating the pranks while he was the substitute. Now I'm going to leave the
room for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>, and while I'm gone I expect whomever took it to return
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radosh</ENAMEX>'s prosthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Just put it on my desk, and we'll say no more
about it.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Preachy cognitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
