
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smell of a Deal</ENAMEX>

            The new flurry of efforts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> a diplomatic
solution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis alarmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> conservative newspapers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> all urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to stand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and intensify the war. "The smell of a deal is in the air," said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , disapprovingly. In an editorial headlined "Dealing with the
devil," the paper reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s peace conditions "run counter to
everything that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> stands for." "Having
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foolishly</ENAMEX> tied his hands behind his back by eschewing ground action, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may be looking for an easy way out," it warned. "It is up to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, in particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, to stiffen his resolve that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s demands be
met in full. ... The current whirl of diplomatic activity calls for especial
vigilance on the West's part."

            An editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said it was time
for the "listening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>" to speak with a firmer voice. "The strong <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>
public support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s intervention could weaken in the face of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indecisiveness</ENAMEX>," it said. "If Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is to avoid a groundswell of get out,
he must show that he is prepared to go in with whatever force it takes, and
stay in until the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovans</ENAMEX>, like
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX>, can go home again." The Financial Times
said that the only way out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s conditions in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX>. "He must do so clearly, addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> directly," it said.
"Nothing less will do."

            The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> and the
Independent , carried no war editorials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> ran one in praise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, whose triumph in
getting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> released has been greeted with cynicism by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> political establishment. Saying it was time for such cynicism to stop, the
paper claimed, that for all his "media grandstanding" and his repeated failure
to see major projects through, "he remains an inspiration for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, not least in motivating them to vote." "Moreover, he continues to
advocate the integrationist ideal of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>," it said.
The picture of him linking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> with the white and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> "will
exert great power in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> should be applauded
for making it happen," it added.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> ran a bitter commentary by
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fisk</ENAMEX> comparing the attention paid to the
release of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> to that of the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> attack that destroyed a bus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>. Noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
only comment on the latter event was the passive phrase, "it is regretted,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisk</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> wants us to believe that it has reserved its sorrow for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. But personally he didn't believe "that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> feels this sense of outrage as strongly as it claims." He compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
attitude to that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who crosses a city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> to help an innocent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> who is being attacked. "What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has done--faced with the atrocities
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--has been to stay on the other side of the road, to make a note of
the criminal's address, and to throw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> through the window of his home
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later that</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>," he wrote. "Not a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> life has been lost in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of war in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>--because we do not regard the catastrophe of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> as worth a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> life. It's as simple as that."

            In an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Journal du Dimanche</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> would be willing to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> command to enforce a peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">accord</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Once again, he called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing campaign "a tragic
mistake" and said: "There are no good chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>.
... Before moving a pawn, you have to assess all the possible strategies of
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversary</ENAMEX>." In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said that, by contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
has shown great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> as a chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. By moving the war to the terrain of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public opinion with his release of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, he was
attempting a final maneuver. "Having been put in check, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> can always
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">castle</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> explained. "He knows he has lost the game, but he still
isn't naked." By freeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has opened a crack in the door
on the eve of the meeting between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>. "He knows he is in check, but he wants to avoid check-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libération</ENAMEX> , in its main front-page headline, called the
release of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> "a diplomatic ambush by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belgrade</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Politika</ENAMEX> , the most widely read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, has maintained its circulation during the war despite being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">despised</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> mouthpiece. This was entirely due to its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
pages of death announcements, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biljana Sbrljanovic</ENAMEX>, wrote,
although the number of these announcements has not grown since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing
started. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, these illustrated death notices were "more important
than death itself, because if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politika</ENAMEX> doesn't publish your photograph,
it is as if you haven't died." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> is now censoring the death
announcements in order to conceal the number and the identities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombs, she wrote; but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> one notice slipped past the censors: a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman employee</ENAMEX> of the bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> TV station whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> had only just
been found. The announcement said, enigmatically, that she had been "a victim
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassins</ENAMEX> who came from the sky and of those who came from the
ground."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Evening News</ENAMEX>
marked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keizo Obuchi</ENAMEX>'s visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by publishing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup Poll</ENAMEX>, commissioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Ministry</ENAMEX>, showing that a
record <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> consider <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to be a trustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. The
poll, conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, also found that, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since
the question was first asked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> is very important to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national security. However, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris Poll</ENAMEX>
conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> showed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> in order to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> from becoming
a military threat, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported
prominently <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> studying criminology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar-Ilan University</ENAMEX>
were being required to read a textbook describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>."
The book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Making of a</ENAMEX> Criminal by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar-Ilan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe Adar</ENAMEX>,
asserted: "An honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> tends to see others as being honest as well; the
evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> sees evilness in others. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> tends to blame his victim
for seducing him. ... The cheating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX> will worry that all the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> are cheats and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX> will accuse everyone of thievery."
The book was listed as required reading for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Criminology</ENAMEX> and
Introduction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psychopathology</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. Third-year social science
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar-Ilan</ENAMEX> said they would be tested on it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks</TIMEX>.
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Weinberg</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adar</ENAMEX> was "considered an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>, and has an international reputation," and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> was
standing by him.

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers
carried a report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket chain</ENAMEX> has
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX> to supply it with smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">melons</ENAMEX> after research indicated
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX> subconsciously compared them to the size of their breasts.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tesco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> has been told by a
psychologist "that the current preference for smaller busts--epitomized by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">model Kate Moss</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>--was the reason why the
traditional big, fleshy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">melons</ENAMEX> were remaining unsold."

         
      
   
