
   
   
      
         
             Speeding While Sober

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stokes</ENAMEX> piloted his
tractor-trailer in front of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> at a rail crossing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bourbonnais</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX> In the ensuing collision, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were killed. His commercial license
was suspended for all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>. His right to drive his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for
noncommercial purposes was unaffected. Even this wrist slap only happened after
it came out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stokes</ENAMEX> had had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least nine</NUMEX> moving violations since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            So why is he allowed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> at all? Answer:
because he broke the law while stone cold sober. Had Stokes been cited even
once for driving drunk--even without an accident, even without violating any
traffic rule--he automatically would have lost his right to drive for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> would have cost him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s driving, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
would have sent him to jail.

            Why the difference? <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> is the leading cause of
traffic fatalities, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Highway Traffic Safety</ENAMEX>
Administration, contributing to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 16,000</NUMEX> deaths <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, making up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
percent of all fatalities on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. But speed comes in a very respectable
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.

            Today, drunken drivers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rank</ENAMEX> as one notch above <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molesters in the popular mind. But attitudes
about driving while intoxicated were not always so negative. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years ago</TIMEX>,
it was still widely accepted as harmless high jinks. Only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, thanks
to campaigns by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mothers Against Drunk Driving</ENAMEX>, did <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> come to recognize
the vast toll of drunks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. As a result, we've stiffened penalties,
raised the drinking age from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 to 21</TIMEX>, mandated license revocation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>
caught driving after drinking any amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
tightened the blood-alcohol standard for drunkenness. Deaths in alcohol-related
crashes fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1982 and 1997</TIMEX>.

            When it comes to speed, though, the attitude is: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> on!
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> dropped all federal restrictions on highway speed limits
(<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> imposed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> energy crisis), letting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> set the maximum
wherever they pleased. Radar detectors, whose sole purpose is to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorists</ENAMEX>
break the law with impunity, are legal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> is the
exception.) How long would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> tolerate the sale of a device to foil a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breathalyzer</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insurance Institute</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Safety</ENAMEX> reports that after the repeal of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55-mph</NUMEX> speed limits,
fatalities rose by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> on interstate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> where the limit was
raised. More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> driving faster means more slaughter on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. But the
bloodshed by speeders doesn't evoke the same emotional revulsion as the
bloodshed by drunks.

            Why not? One explanation is that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't ever
drive while intoxicated, while most do exceed the speed limit from time to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. Any movement for social reform is more effective if it pillories a small
minority and leaves the majority unaccused and unaffected.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> don't believe that excessive speed is as
risky as excessive drink. They think it is possible for an experienced and
competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> (such as themselves) to go fast without hurting anyone. This
is, in fact, possible. It is also possible to drive drunk without causing an
accident. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Every night</TIMEX> the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">drunken</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> get home safely. But
we don't accept that as a defense. We understand that however able the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>,
the risk of this type of behavior is serious and intolerable. We treat the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">culprits</ENAMEX> as potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> who need to be restrained from endangering the
innocent.

            Our attitudes about serious speeding have yet to
come to grips with simple reality. Car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and auto commercials continue
to not merely excuse but celebrate behavior that kills almost as many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
annually as died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> during its bloodiest year, while maiming
and injuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> more. If we were to crack down on speeding as vigorously
as we did on drunken driving--by mandating license suspensions for repeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>, imposing jail time on incorrigibles, and outlawing radar
detectors--we could make the roads far safer. The drunken driving crusade
reduced alcohol-related deaths by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>. A comparable commitment on speed
could save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 4,000</NUMEX> lives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
