
   
   
      
         
            Paper Swoon

            As a striving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-lancer</ENAMEX>,
I believe in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> note theory of success: i.e., send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> flattering
missives to the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>, and you'll be at the top in no time. It
doesn't really matter what you write--but what you write on does matter.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stationery</ENAMEX> has always been important, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s cachet as a cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signifier</ENAMEX> has increased dramatically in the age of e-mail. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> don't
care if you send them letters on recycled grocery bags, those who don't know
you will scrutinize the note--the paper, the letterhead--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> you.

            Cognizant of the perils
of purchasing stationery, I start at the top, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartier</ENAMEX>--arguably the snootiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stationer</ENAMEX> around. At the desk of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">52 nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Street</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>,
I find a stern saleswoman at the desk taking an order from "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX>" on
the phone. She hangs up, looks at her watch, and says she can give me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>--until the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>, I guess. The first stationery she shows me
is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">32 pound</NUMEX> (meaning that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> stacked sheets of it will weigh that much). The
sheet is thick enough to choke a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>, which is the point, of
course. It's the preferred weight for writing paper, the maximum recommended
for laser printers is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">28 pound</NUMEX>.

            Before we discuss paper price, she informs me that the name
and address die to engrave the stationery will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130</NUMEX>. A little steep, I
suggest. A die that includes a family crest is closer to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>, she says
crisply, "and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> enjoy leaving their address dies to others in their
wills."

            We whip through some
options--envelopes lined with tissue, beveling or indenting the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet</ENAMEX> around
the edge to create a border, stamping the family crest in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>--before we
return to paper prices: Fifty ecru, note-sized sheets and matching envelopes go
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$254</NUMEX>, engraving included. (That's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $5</NUMEX> a note.) The price for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
business-sized sheets and envelopes is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$259.50</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 6 inch by 4 inch</NUMEX> note
cards and envelopes cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$256</NUMEX>.

            My fingers glide across the soft <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> like skates on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pond</ENAMEX>. And then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">saleswoman</ENAMEX> lets it slip: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartier</ENAMEX>'s paper is actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">32 pound</NUMEX> paper.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Crane</ENAMEX> made the paper for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> colonial
bank notes back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX> did the engraving. Those new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">20s</ENAMEX> in your
wallet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX> watermark are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane & Co.</ENAMEX>'s handiwork. In
addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mint</ENAMEX> and the treasuries of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX>
supplies paper for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3,000</NUMEX> retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stationers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The
locations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane & Co.</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> can be found on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
Web site, and another page lets you search by ZIP code or international region for other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
(A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">calligrapher</ENAMEX> tells me that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany & Co.</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repackages Crane</ENAMEX>'s paper.)

            "Most of our social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stationery</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">32 pound</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> cotton rag," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Reed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of personal products. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cotton</ENAMEX>'s long <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> are what make paper soft. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, all paper was made of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton rags</ENAMEX>, hence the name. Today, most
writing paper is made of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> cotton and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> wood pulp. The
problem with wood pulp is that paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> have to use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> to break it
down--and the chemical never quits working. This explains why recently printed,
cheaply made books are self-immolating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, while
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutenberg Bibles</ENAMEX> are OK.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paperphiles</ENAMEX> buy foreign stationery made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smythson</ENAMEX> of
Bond Street, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, or by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineider</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smythsons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> can
be traced via a toll-free number, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">345-6839</TIMEX>. The saleswoman at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blacker</ENAMEX> and
Kooby, on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">87 th</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, shows me some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smythson</ENAMEX> sheets and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">envelopes</ENAMEX>, offering that it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of choice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
Beautiful and very "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Mitford</ENAMEX> would say, but almost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> in that hounds
and blood sausage way. A little rumply--the cards don't quite match the
envelopes.

            Then she opens a green
leather case, revealing Pineider samples. It made me believe, as some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> contend, that the beauty response is hard-wired. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">languid</ENAMEX> and luminous, and it feels denser than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX>'s. But the 225-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stationers</ENAMEX> don't bother with weight standards, used for currency and
book paper, because this stuff is strictly for letter writing. It is, they say,
the smoothest possible writing surface you can find. It would be a crime to use
anything other than a good fountain pen on it. But which pen? That's a research
project unto itself.

            The sheets are creamy white and the tissue lining in the
envelope a bluer white. The saleswoman didn't have to drop names (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Wonder</ENAMEX>) to justify the price of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75</TIMEX> note-sized sheets and envelopes. At
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$144</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.92</NUMEX> per note), this stationery is a steal. But the engraving cost is a
steep <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175 and $42</NUMEX> for the die plate. You can find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pineider</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> by calling
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">616-9111</ENAMEX>.

            I stop by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Printers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> rd
Street, an address generated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX> Web site. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanter</ENAMEX>'s price for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
note-sized sheets and envelopes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX>'s paper is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$166</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.66</NUMEX> a note!), about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> if I use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strathmore</ENAMEX>, a competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, which is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 25 percent</NUMEX> cotton
rag.

            To get the stationery
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">engraved</ENAMEX>, the die plate will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$56</NUMEX>, about average. It is a onetime charge,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanter's</ENAMEX>--and most other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>--let you keep the plates. But if I forego
the luxury of engraving, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> will sell me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500 24</NUMEX> pound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strathmore</ENAMEX> sheets
and envelopes, flat printed, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$167</NUMEX>. (That's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33 cents</NUMEX> a note. Now we're
really talking.) Turnaround time for printing is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> faster
than either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Smythson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pineider</ENAMEX>.

            If you're not going <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Europaper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and pop operations
are definitely the best value. Is engraved paper really worth it? I ask the
printer. "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caddy</ENAMEX> and others want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX>," he shrugs. "Does
anyone use colored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>?" "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hairdressers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discos</ENAMEX>."

            After choosing paper, you
must pick a size. Business-sized sheets are a mistake for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) it's
difficult to write enough to fill that much space; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) that much flattery
might be misinterpreted as stalking. The note-sized sheets look insubstantial
and girlie. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> cards are best because they make a few scribbles look
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weighty</ENAMEX> and dignified.

            Luckily, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> sizes of fine stationery,
because there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of typefaces from which to compose your letterhead.
At stationery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> agonizing over whether they're really more
Helvetica than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Old Roman</ENAMEX>. The sample books don't help much because you want to
see how it looks in your name on the size sheet you've chosen. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> let you test drive a sample of typefaces on a computer. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Levenger</ENAMEX> Web site, which sells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane's</ENAMEX>, limits you to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
sensible choices, so you can't go too far wrong. Most professional printers
will do a proof of your letterhead for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12-$25</NUMEX>.

            Let me offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece of advice: Avoid monograms.
Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> initials may look aristocratic, but that's because they were first
used by drunken, illiterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">royals</ENAMEX> who couldn't write their whole names. I
wonder if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> knows that? His writing paper has a large blue, diamond
shaped monogram at the top. But then, he doesn't need to observe the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> note
theory anymore.

         
      
   
