
   
   
      
         
            Rape and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s re-emergence as a
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis was a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, with
papers giving contrasting interpretations of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX>
ran a front-page headline reading "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rapprochement</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>"
and stressed their commitment to future cooperation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers, by
contrast, generally pronounced the negotiations a failure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> said
that peace is now more remote, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> that the meeting produced no result, and
Corriere della
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> is resisting
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s efforts at a diplomatic solution. There was much uncertainty, too,
about the significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vuk Draskovic</ENAMEX>'s
statement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> would accept a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. "What does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Draskovic</ENAMEX> stand for? Who stands behind <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Draskovic?</ENAMEX>" asked the Frankfurter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> in an editorial that didn't provide answers.

            Rapprochement or not,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> that vehement opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s actions in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> is "the most consensual issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> politics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers gave prominence to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Solzhenitsyn</ENAMEX>'s saying that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX> has entered a new era of lawlessness and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s disregard for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> was comparable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s contempt for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Nations</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> carried an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>, who said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> will never surrender. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> would
have to send in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, and who's to say that even they would be
sufficient. There would follow a long war, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> since
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, that would cause many, many dead and even more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>."
Answering the accusation that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> hasn't done enough to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> said it could have done more if it hadn't been excluded from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rambouillet</ENAMEX> conference.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> conflict has undermined his
efforts to democratize <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, combat corruption, guarantee free
expression, and bring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, because it has reopened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religious</ENAMEX>, political, and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> and, above all, revived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
hatred of the West. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> were to become an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asiatic</ENAMEX> power again, world
equilibrium would be at risk," he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> added that he had tried in
vain to understand the logic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s actions, but they had served only to
consolidate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> and eliminate all political opposition in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s attacks were initially directed at military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, "they
are now ruining the economy of rather a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> cross
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> border, they will find nothing but graves and hatred. With what
advantages? To what purpose?"

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
conflict has been squeezed off the front pages of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> by
extensive coverage of the murder <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Dando</ENAMEX>, a popular TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX>,
who was shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> on her front doorstep in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west London</ENAMEX>.
But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX> managed to link even this event to
the war with front-page speculation that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> might be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>
seeking revenge for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> TV station <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> carried a rare, perhaps unique, interview
with a volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleanser</ENAMEX>," a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan Petrovic</ENAMEX>, who recently spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> helping to drive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petrovic</ENAMEX> said that the cleansers are
under orders not to kill, beat, or mutilate their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and that most obeyed.
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX>, I'd say, did raping or killing or that kind of thing--not
more," he said. While claiming that the cleansers generally "respected human
rights," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petrovic</ENAMEX> didn't attempt to conceal his racial prejudice. "They're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cowards</ENAMEX>, those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, they run like rabbits," he said. The rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>--"all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> you know, with satellite TVs and big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>"--are
tougher to move than the others, "but if you push hard enough, they all go in
the end."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petrovic</ENAMEX> claimed to feel
sorry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> he expelled from their homes, but said that, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, they had no right to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. "I had to follow my orders, and
anyway, I knew there would always be someone to meet those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,"
he said. As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>," he would have liked to kill them and
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> on the spot, but his orders had been to hand them over to the
army. "I don't know what they did to them--they're probably holding them as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> of war." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petrovic</ENAMEX> said he had signed up as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleanser</ENAMEX> when the war
started to show his disgust for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. He was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> who
assembled in the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nis</ENAMEX> before leaving there to start
cleansing operations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silovo</ENAMEX>. He said he saw little of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s war, "We heard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> way up above us, but I think they were
concentrating on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> so they didn't give us any trouble."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Express</ENAMEX>
reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kukes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> gave the same account to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNICEF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> of how they had been repeatedly stripped, sprayed with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perfume</ENAMEX>, and then raped by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who held them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> houses
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>. The subject of rape also cropped up in an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of the suspected war criminal and
former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ljiljiana Karadzic</ENAMEX>, who like
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>, said that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herzegovina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
had been accused of raping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. "If we compare this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> with the
number of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, it means that every one of them must have raped three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," she said. "So when did they find the time to fight?" Referring to one
claim by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> had been forced to rape
her at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karadzic</ENAMEX> commented: "I am also a sexologist. To think that
I could have cured my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> of impotence by pointing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> at their
temples!"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> satirical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine Private Eye</ENAMEX> had an exceptionally tasteless cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> photographed in intimate conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Foreign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX> under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ground War Latest</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
is saying, "I'm not going in--it's too risky." "I expect you say that to all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>," replies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
