
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2 stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> had
barely touched down after its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever combat mission <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
its most loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> staged a press conference to claim vindication. Standing
before one of the sleek black <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> on the tarmac at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Force Base</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reps.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike Skelton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Dicks</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scorned skeptics</ENAMEX> who had doubted the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> (each!) airplane.
"We have seen this type of criticism on every major weapons system," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dicks</ENAMEX>, "and when they go to war, they work."

            Inside the same media
moment, footage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX> frolicking beside the wreckage of a downed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117 stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> punctured the technology's invincibility--and rekindled
the debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> reliance on high-tech weaponry. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, at the dawn of
the stealth era, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX> warned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Defense</ENAMEX> that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> have grown too complex, expensive and
delicate to be useful in warfare or credible for deterrent purposes." Fallows
argued in vain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should instead spend its defense budget
on cheap and simple armaments, and the military pumped <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $50 billion</NUMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> programs alone. Then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, as the military redefined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> from an H-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb taxi</ENAMEX> to a deliverer of conventional bombs, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> articulated the silliness of the concept: "It's the
equivalent of saying we're going to send a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls-Royce</ENAMEX> down into a combat zone
to pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX>." Today, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> sends the
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> out on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> runs.

            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2 stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX>, manufactured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grumman Corp.</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117 stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>, are
based on different underlying technologies, their names conceal a
little-appreciated similarity: They're both 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombers</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117</ENAMEX>
was originally imagined as an invisible dogfighter, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> reframed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s mission when the geniuses at the aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">skunkworks</ENAMEX> failed to push
the technology far enough. While not a fighter, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117</ENAMEX> ain't no
sissy, either. It carries a pair of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000-pound</NUMEX> bombs into combat, but it's
slow and hard to maneuver. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane fleet</ENAMEX> only flies at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> (which
explains why it's painted black) because it has no air-to-air combat
capabilities. If an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> fighter spots and engages the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117</ENAMEX>, it's toast. Very
expensive black toast.

            At least the stealth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomber</ENAMEX> begins to live up to its name. Designed as a long-range <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> that
would penetrate deep into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> to wage nuclear war, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it
subsists on a no-nukes diet, carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">16</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX>-guided, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one-ton</NUMEX> bombs (or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight 5,000</NUMEX>-pounders) into battle. Editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> love to note that, ounce
for ounce, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times pricier than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. Its incredible cost stems
from endless development snafus and such mind-bending design features as a
surface smoothness measurable to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/10,000 th</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> defends the cost by saying that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX>, with its heavy payload, can do
the work of several conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>--risking fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> in a safer
plane. But even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX> who considered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX>'s sticker price a bargain when
the game was nuclear deterrence grudgingly admit that nobody would ever build
such a device to drop conventional bombs on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>.

            With its subtle curves, smooth surface, and intimidating
bat wings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX> is the cooler big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. But the smaller
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117</ENAMEX>'s boxy and angular look gives it a nerdy cachet. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> designs
represent different strategies for evading radar: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX> absorbs enemy radar
waves; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117</ENAMEX>'s awkward geometry mostly scatters them.

            Neither design is
flawless. It's commonly assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> are invisible to radar.
They're not--they're just very difficult to see. And sometimes they're not hard
to see at all. Stealth technology is vulnerable to older, long-wave radars and
well-coordinated radar systems. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> are exponentially easier to
spot when they open their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-bay doors, even during simple bank turns. For
those reasons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> has abandoned its original boasts that stealth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> would be truly "invisible."

            
The previous watershed for stealth technology
was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117</ENAMEX> pounded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> with impunity and
apparent precision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, however, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> downgraded by
half the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> had scored an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> success rate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Naysayers</ENAMEX> continue to heap scorn on the two stealth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombers</ENAMEX>, insisting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> have yet to be truly battle-tested because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqis</ENAMEX> who have faced the technology have put up no more than
a token resistance.

            Even so, the anecdotal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> has refueled the high-tech crusade. Despite
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX>'s piddling role over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> so far--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> missions involving a total of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> thumbed his nose last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who had opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX>, cracking wise about "B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>"
and suggesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> could use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> more of the machines. The stealth war
news comes at a critical moment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, which is pushing for the
production of a new-generation <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22 Raptor</ENAMEX>. (This one
really is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>.) The cost: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">About $60 billion</NUMEX> to build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22s</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$187 million</NUMEX> apiece. That's nowhere near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>'s weight
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, but still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times dearer than an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX>.

            The national love affair with stealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> will endure
for several reasons. Although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades old</TIMEX>, the technology is perennially
futuristic--it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romulans of Star Trek</ENAMEX> , after all, who first
invented "cloaking"--and it advances the ethos of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> can-doism. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planes</ENAMEX>
acquire an added allure whenever they're developed in secret: The military
didn't even confirm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117</ENAMEX>'s existence until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> were built and
flying.) And then there's something perversely sexy about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX>-tech black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheen</ENAMEX>, something peeping-tom kinky about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>' advertised
invisibility, something magical about striking without being struck back.

            Despite their technological limitations, stealth
weapons appeal to us because they indulge our fear of commitment. And this is
what ultimately makes them pose their own kind of stealthy threat to us. As
we've seen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> weapons blind the risk-averse public and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> to
the genuine perils of combat in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the opening</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of any military engagement,
turning war into an "out of sight, out of mind" proposition. They encourage the
view that there's nothing--from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> germ weapons programs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
atrocities--that a few invisible <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> can't fix. Enticing us into believing
that wars can be won with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Futurama</ENAMEX> technology and without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> blood
being shed, the seductive charms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> ultimately evaporate into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nothingness</ENAMEX>. We are left unfulfilled by their limitations and cheated by their
costs.

         
      
   
