
   
   
      
         
             Point and Clique

            Gaze around the sprawling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington High</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lunchtime</ENAMEX>, and the social geography is clear. High on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jocks</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poms</ENAMEX> are eating in style, elbows up on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linen tablecloths</ENAMEX>. "You wouldn't
dare come here if you didn't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chirps</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Martha Corinne</ENAMEX>
"Cokie" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the pompom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> (hence: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poms</ENAMEX>) and a leading contender
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prom queen</ENAMEX>. "Once you're in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, everyone
is really nice. Once I made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, it was like I was just in ."

            One table over, her close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>--nicknamed the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>" for his aggressiveness on the football
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>--echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>' sentiments. "All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jocks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poms</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> together, and
everyone cares what we think about stuff. It may be unfair, but that just the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way Washington</ENAMEX> is."

            But down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, deep in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement cafeteria</ENAMEX>,
the tables are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Formica</ENAMEX>, the eyeglasses are thick, the ties are clip-ons, and
the hair isn't quite coiffed. Here's where you'll find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Badgers</ENAMEX>, who
are--and there's no nice way to say this--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s losers. "We have nothing
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillies</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacklyn</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GS-11</ENAMEX>, as she taps her ubiquitous
identity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">badge</ENAMEX> nervously on the table. "But they have something
against us. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> they pass a law that says raise <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed-corn</ENAMEX> allowances. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> they pass a law that says lower <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed-corn</ENAMEX> allowances. Then, no matter
what we do, they make fun of us and call us names like 'bureaucrats' and 'paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX>.' It's not fair. It really hurts."

            Never have such social divides seemed so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unbridgeable</ENAMEX>--and so alarming--as they have since the tragedy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> has focused the public's attention on just how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bewildering</ENAMEX> and even dangerous this maze of social hierarchy can be. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
are realizing that our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are fraught, filled with feuding social groups
and organized according to unforgiving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> principles. Beneath the
gleaming surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> is a seething mass--the anti-social, the alienated,
and the exploited.

            Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
High, a wealthy, self-important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>. It's like any
high school anywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days</TIMEX>' wandering its marble
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">halls</ENAMEX> reveals homogeneity on the surface--where did they find so many identical
dark suits?--but alarming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> below.

            "After <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>, I immediately thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,"
says pompom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timmy Russert</ENAMEX>. "We have outcasts like the Badgers
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wingers</ENAMEX>. A lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> were in popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. I'm
kind of scared that popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> here might get targeted."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> isn't immune to the pressures that have
spoiled the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," says longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> High civics teacher
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Strauss</ENAMEX>--"Old Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss</ENAMEX>," as everyone calls him. "Of course everything
was better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> listened to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> and helped
each other out."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington High</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>, has an absolute social hierarchy. The apex of the pyramid--a world
away from the lowly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Badgers</ENAMEX>--is student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, a
fun-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>. He and his
sidekicks, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Rubin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasurer</ENAMEX>, math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX>, and "Most
Likely to Succeed"), mix easily with almost everyone. (Because they hang out
smoking and whistling at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s white administration
building, they're called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Housers</ENAMEX>.)

            Besides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Housers</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other leading cliques
are the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jocks and the Poms</ENAMEX>, who have a friendly rivalry about which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is
more important. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jocks</ENAMEX>--aka the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Players</ENAMEX>--include "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>. They're <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stars</ENAMEX> on the field in the only sport that matters
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, political football. They lay down the social law. "We rule!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shouts Lott</ENAMEX>, gleefully. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poms</ENAMEX>, by contrast, are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX>.
They tell everyone else about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jocks</ENAMEX> have done and why:
"Everyone knows who we are," gloats <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Kristol</ENAMEX>.

            There are two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX> to these top <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. One is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band</ENAMEX>, sometimes called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. They play and talk in unison. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band</ENAMEX> socialize
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jocks</ENAMEX>--before he was expelled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Band leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton Gingrich</ENAMEX>
briefly challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular</ENAMEX>--but rank-and-file <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bandits</ENAMEX> detest
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jocks and Poms</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> has been replaced as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Band leader</ENAMEX> by percussionist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy DeLay</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> also calls himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goth</ENAMEX>, in honor of his historical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>.)

            The other challenger is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Townies</ENAMEX>, who loathe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Townies</ENAMEX> have been going to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> forever, and they hate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomer</ENAMEX> who has displaced them in prestige. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is just
so tacky. Have you seen the way he hits on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>? Did you hear about
him and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>? It's gross," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Quinn</ENAMEX>, as she loiters in the
parking lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons</ENAMEX> with her longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jocks, the Band</ENAMEX>, the
Townies, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> don't agree on much, but they all love the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulchers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulchers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Boggs</ENAMEX>--are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington High</ENAMEX>'s most successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>. They work on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Street</ENAMEX>, but drop by
the old school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> to cruise the parking lot, pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, tell
shaggy-dog stories, and deal tobacco, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
They drive fabulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and pick up every check. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jocks</ENAMEX> say they rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. But we own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gulcher Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>,
flashing a smile and a wad of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Franklins</ENAMEX>.

            But for those who aren't so popular, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington High</ENAMEX> is a
forbidding place. The popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, for example, mock the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wannabes</ENAMEX>, the mobs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sophomores</ENAMEX> who aspire desperately to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jocks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wannabes</ENAMEX>
will do anything for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jocks, and the Jocks</ENAMEX> exploit them mercilessly, forcing
them to write briefing papers, answer mail, field phone calls, fetch dry
cleaning, and play <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX>. In exchange for this drudgery, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jocks</ENAMEX>
occasionally deign to nod in their general direction. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wannabe</ENAMEX> gets paid a
small stipend for this work, she belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Staffers</ENAMEX>. If she's not paid,
she's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intern</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Staffers</ENAMEX> are cooler than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interns</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nerds</ENAMEX>, who hole up
in the economics and computer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>, have an even more hopeless position.
They're entirely ignored by the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Washingtonians</ENAMEX>--except when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jocks</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Housers</ENAMEX> need someone to do their homework for them. Then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nerds</ENAMEX> do
what they're told. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Lew</ENAMEX>, who runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget Club</ENAMEX>, sighs
about this injustice. "I mean, it's totally unfair. I spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> figuring out
exactly how much money they have and what they can spend. I'm the one who does
all the work, and what do I get in return? They laugh at my charts, and they
don't even know my name." ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Lew</ENAMEX>? Who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Lew</ENAMEX>?" asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.)

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Washingtonians</ENAMEX> try to disappear from the social
hierarchy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Badgers</ENAMEX> hide in their cafeterias. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drama Club</ENAMEX> meets in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dupont</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>, far from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. Led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arty kids</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris</ENAMEX>
Hitchens, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo" Dowd</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Wieseltier</ENAMEX>--who also edits the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">literary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dramatists</ENAMEX> profess disgust with everyone on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gulch</ENAMEX>. "They're so stupid and hypocritical and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fake</ENAMEX>," snorts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>. "We
keep our distance from their pointless little world." 

            The debate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, likewise, avoids social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intercourse</ENAMEX>. "We choose not to consort with others," declares team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>, known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>. "Frankly, it would just waste our time and
embarrass them."

            No matter where you go on
this beautiful but troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timmy Russert</ENAMEX>'s question echoes: Is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>? Nowhere does it resonate more than on the edge of
campus, in a dark corner of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> known as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Courthouse</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courthouse</ENAMEX> is the home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s proudest outcasts: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wingers</ENAMEX>. "They
think we're freaky. They harass us because they think we're
freaky," mutters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence "Larry" Klayman</ENAMEX>, the most garrulous of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wingers</ENAMEX>.
"They harass us. Well, we'll show them what harassment really is. Does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Rubin</ENAMEX> know what a deposition is? 'Cause I'm gonna show him ..."

         
      
   
