
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">update: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, having voted down (on a tie vote) a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> expressing support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing campaign, then voted to add
several <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX> in defense spending to the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
requested for the bombing. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of hypocrisy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disloyalty</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> of squandering military resources on
a foolish war. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> brought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> of religious
to release <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> captured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s army <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and interior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> strayed
into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX> but killed nobody because it didn't explode. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> apologized. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
The top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> for killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and
making itself "the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of what is or is not acceptable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/30/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>
high-school massacre is spawning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">copycats</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> shot
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to death in a manner similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> tragedy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> were charged with conspiring to blow up their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> was found with a bomb-making <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> with
which he evidently planned to destroy his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe bomb</ENAMEX> was found in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. In various places around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> suspended
classes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were questioned or even arrested due to bomb threats and
rumors of grudge-bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with hit lists. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have reportedly
banned dark trench coats. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) School violence has become a national
crisis. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) School violence is declining and has been absurdly overhyped. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overhyping</ENAMEX> is good because it is cathartic and encourages vigilance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overhyping</ENAMEX> is encouraging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">copycats</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Psychopathic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in the grip of
violent fantasies. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hysterical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are in the grip of violent fantasies.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/30/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Council</ENAMEX> agreed not to declare a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process was supposed to conclude <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, but rocky
negotiations and new elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> (scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>) have delayed
the process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> editorial spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> held off because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> asked them to do so and promised to
support eventual statehood. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> spin: We held off to avoid scaring
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, which might have helped re-elect right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, whom we despise for sabotaging the peace process.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s spin: They held off because I'm strong and vigilant, so re-elect
me. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/30/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
New evidence
supports the theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> once resembled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> . A magnetic pattern
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> indicates that it had dynamic, internal heat similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s,
increasing the likelihood that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> had a warm atmosphere, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and
elementary life. The trumpeted spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> had life! The buried spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>
faces death. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/30/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The
environmental panic over deformed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX> was deflated. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have been finding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with deformed,
missing, or extra limbs. The old theory: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX> are a harbinger of a
"poisoned environment," possibly caused by industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> or erosion of
the ozone layer. The new theory, based on subsequent studies: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> was screwed up by parasites that infected them. The new version of
the old theory: The parasites are a harbinger of a poisoned environment.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/30/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Update 
               on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> high school massacre : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
The local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fatigues</ENAMEX> who knew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> and
waited outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> during the shooting are "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of our
investigation." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> determined that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">killers</ENAMEX> bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> they used. It is not yet clear whether she knew
what they planned to do with the arms. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) A security camera reportedly captured
the shootings that took place in the school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> says
that just before the massacre it rejected an application from one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> on "medical" grounds--evidently he had been seeing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shrink</ENAMEX> and taking
psychiatric medication. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX> canceled the rest of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> tour,
explaining that there's "not a great atmosphere" for his music after the
shootings. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> said he blames ignorance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hatred</ENAMEX>, and access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> for the tragedy." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/28/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposed new federal gun control legislation . It would raise the
legal age for handgun possession to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>, prohibit juvenile possession of
semiautomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, require trigger locks, make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents criminally</ENAMEX> liable
for "knowingly or recklessly" giving their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> used to kill or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">injure</ENAMEX>, and extend background checks to gun show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who try to
buy explosives. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> proposed a national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and culture." The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is cynically exploiting
public unease about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> tragedy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courageously</ENAMEX> exploiting public unease about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>
tragedy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> is simple-minded and would not have stopped
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> tragedy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s focus on "culture" is simple-minded and
would not have stopped the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> tragedy. (For further analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
new spin on gun control, see "" in 
                  Slate
               .) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/28/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> have agreed to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in bad public school districts
state-funded vouchers to attend private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> . It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> state voucher program. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> already have vouchers, and some states
are considering similar proposals. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> will rate districts by standardized
test scores and will let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the lowest-scoring districts switch to any
school that will accept them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> will transfer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> from the school
each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> leaves to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where he or she enrolls. The arguments pro: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It
gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> a choice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It breaks the stranglehold of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It puts bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> on notice that they must shape up
or lose their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The arguments con: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will yank their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out of bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, making these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> worse and leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with
indifferent or helpless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> trapped in them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Using state money for
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is unconstitutional. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The vouchers are too small to give
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a real shot at a good private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/28/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Elway</ENAMEX> is retiring . He won the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowls</ENAMEX> and
holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football League</ENAMEX> records for games won (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">148</ENAMEX>) and game-winning
or game-tying drives in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">47</NUMEX>). He is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> to throw for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50,000 yards</NUMEX> and is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> to throw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">touchdown</ENAMEX> passes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elway</ENAMEX> said he is retiring because his knee is damaged, he has
accomplished what he sought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, and he wants to spend more time with
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The sunny spin: He's going out on top, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> did.
The sad spin: He won't get a chance to try for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>. The cynical
spin: He's shrewdly getting out before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> collapse.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
