
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">254</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Too True To Be Good&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               I give the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> headline; you give a one-sentence summary of the story:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidential Hopeful Displays Humanity</ENAMEX>."
            

            
               
                  (A tip of the
Hatlo hat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 253</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pesca Milagrosa":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  "It is terrible that something so frightening should be given
the name of something so pure and beautiful," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luz Marlene Sierra Mayorga</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogotá</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>, referring to "miraculous fishing"--which is
what?
               
            

            "Wow,
the pro-choice movement has topped itself in the euphemism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> with this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Changing lepers into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">loaves</ENAMEX> and fishes."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh Bardugo</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX>'s day in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Wolfe</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Reaching down the front of the pants of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> standing next to you on the
subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> just for the hell of it."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
Makah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>'s new strategy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> hunting with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plutonium</ENAMEX>-tipped
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harpoons</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quiz Regular M</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pesca's Nominal Torment Wrap-Up</ENAMEX>
            

            I have noticed that nearly every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-syllable first
name is a homonym for an actual word. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> being
exceptions--and therefore unfortunately discriminated against during Zoom
casting calls.) If my name were the translation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pesca</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish</ENAMEX>) it would be
punnable but would preclude my moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>.

            I have long maintained that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> and early
'80s the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> acquired and promoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> based on how their names worked
in headlines. How else to explain the mysterious presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar Gamble</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Rivers</ENAMEX>?

            All the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jacksons</ENAMEX> (like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reliever</ENAMEX>) now go by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>, simply because of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> androgynously desiccated freak.
The exception is beer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>, the explanation being <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) he had
the name <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) he's too drunk to realize; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) no one would mistake a fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretentious</ENAMEX> hop-head for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of pop.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> I have gauged the popularity
of hockey by the fact that no one has linked my name to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Peca</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo Sabres</ENAMEX>. This may speak more to the popularity of all
things <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>, but now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabes</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">cup</ENAMEX> final, I still expect no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to mention it. But maybe I'll catch a double take if I'm ever in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niagara Falls</ENAMEX> region.

            If this miraculous
phrase to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pesca</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> becomes ubiquitous, I will join the ranks of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">punnable</ENAMEX> and will forever be able to step forth from the shadows of my maternal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ancestors Philip</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sylvia Lipshitz</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fishin' Magician</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> kidnappings.

            Here's how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Rohter</ENAMEX> describes it in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> : "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> appears out of nowhere, sets up a
roadblock on a main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>, stops every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> that happens along, takes
away all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who seem likely to have a good job or a prominent name,
and holds them captive until a hefty ransom is paid."

            The practice takes its name from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> party
game where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> reach into a barrel with a hook or with bare hands and pull out
a surprise gift.

            Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1996</TIMEX>, at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,925</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been abducted.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloated Indulgence</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> sought a
published sentence exemplifying conspicuous consumption <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, like this from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>, the urinal has taken its stand alongside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bidet</ENAMEX> and the working fireplace as the latest must-have in the well-appointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom suite</ENAMEX>."

            "When did you first notice
you had become quietly wealthy<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> ad

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX>
            

            
               --Tamara
Glenny
            

            " 'There are all these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there who have made all this money and don't know what the best
sheet is or what the best cufflinks are,' said Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross</ENAMEX>, who intends to help
them learn."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hammett</ENAMEX>
            

            "[H]er favorite item in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> is a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone spaniels</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9,000</NUMEX>). 'They're <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">happy dogs</ENAMEX>--they look
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> I'd like to own.' "

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
            

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>
            

            "When, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Course</ENAMEX> of
Human Events, it becomes necessary for one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> to rise up against such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tyranny</ENAMEX>, we offer our own modest proposal: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Diners</ENAMEX>' bill of rights, one
designed to inspire a new dialogue between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>-goers and restaurateurs
and to make the dining experience as pleasant as it always promises to be."

            
               
                  Slate
               's own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zagat</ENAMEX> diary
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 1999</TIMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz</ENAMEX>
Rounsavall
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that is for
sale is located in the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s burgeoning wine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and this
property could be converted into a small destination <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vineyard</ENAMEX>."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX> "I Think
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opening Up the Vineyard to Anyone Other Than the Servants Is Really Tasteless</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            "Explaining why
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephania Lo Gatto</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000</NUMEX> over new sticker for a used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>
CLK320 convertible, instead of getting on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX> waiting list: 'If I waited
that long, I would be sick of it.' Now, wherever she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> drive
around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, 'Everybody looks at us, which is what we wanted to achieve.' "

            
               Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Madden</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            Doors at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> school
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">buildings</ENAMEX>
Face back-to-back crises:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> trap rabid <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>;
Business goes belly-up.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>

               Inquirer , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 1999</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Jersey Metro</ENAMEX> section only)

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, and dynamite--it's going to be
the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Reynolds</ENAMEX> comeback movie ever.

         
      
   
