
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shattered Illusions</ENAMEX>

            The humanitarian disaster
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and the downing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">stealth bomber</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> dominated world
coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The scale of "ethnic
cleansing" in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> air attacks caused widespread alarm in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and the loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F117-A attack</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was seen as
further evidence that an air war is not enough to secure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s objectives. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the main western <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> destination for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> gave far greater prominence to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> estimate that more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX> have been forced to leave their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
repression began.

            Reports from the front
were emotive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> began its front-page report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Djankovic</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> border as follows: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> executions, psychological and
physical torture, rapes, devastation, sackings, and extermination <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
is living through a nightmare of the greatest ethnic cleansing that has ever
been attempted. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in flight, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> completely cut out of the world without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, electricity, telephone,
or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. A humanitarian catastrophe without precedent."

            Condemnations of the air war, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> air
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> has now been ordered not to participate, were multiplying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
press. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX> carried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> front-page comments <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> demanding the air strikes be
ended. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Biancheri</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, wrote that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX> could now only be restored "on a field of
rubble." He wrote, "Let's end this war. But let's be careful in future not to
promise what we are not willing to carry out, not to proclaim rights if we
don't have the strength, the will, or what might be called the recklessness to
punish those who have violated them."

            The other comment in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gianni Vattimo</ENAMEX>, said it would not be dishonorable to
admit--as in other cases like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>--than an error might have been
made. "Perhaps the best we can do now is to use the resources that would be
wasted in war in an agreed humanitarian action of evacuation and assistance to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vattimo</ENAMEX> said. While this would risk helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>
to achieve his objectives, it was perhaps what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> now dying
of hunger and cold would want us to do, he added. On the front page of
Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Ronchey</ENAMEX> supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> 's conclusion
that "the West has embarked on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its riskiest adventures since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
II."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> gave prominence to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX>'s efforts to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> back the negotiating
table, and an editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√©ration</ENAMEX> suggested this should be done by greatly
reducing the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> destined to become autonomous under the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX>
proposals. This could save the face of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, he wrote. The
air war had already had the opposite of its intended effect, he added. It
revealed "a terrible impotence" against ethnic cleansing that risked becoming a
sinister example not only for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> but for the rest of the world.

            The question of what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, given the current Western resistance to the committal of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>,
would do if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 days</TIMEX> of bombing failed to bow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was raised in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s Frankfurter
Allgemeine , and an editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> concluded that the crisis is getting ever
more complicated and that we are now in a "thick fog."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers continue to be generally more gung-ho
than those on the Continent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, urging "an immediate intensification
of military activities aimed directly at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, said in
an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that it is not so evident that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Somalia Syndrome</ENAMEX>"
"really affects ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as much as it distracts their nervous
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>." It said that "the ironic outcome is a set of aircraft
[the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>] that are so dependent on extremely sophisticated computer
equipment designed to deceive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> that they are extraordinarily difficult
to fly."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> (which led Monday
with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP Amoco</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, was about to
take over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Richfield</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in an all-stock deal worth
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 billion</NUMEX>) carried a front-page headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s illusions crash with
downed stealth" and said that TV images of the wreckage have shattered "the
illusion enjoyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> military's technologically
superlative weaponry meant it could destroy unseen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> with little or no
danger to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life or property." The mass-circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> was committed to this war because "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butcher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> cannot
be allowed to continue his massacre of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX>," while the London
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Standard</ENAMEX> said that "having come so far, and having
got ourselves into this mess--and it is a terrible and bloody mess--we must see
it through."

            

               For more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> coverage, click .
            

             

         
      
   
