
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Let Us Now Praise Famous Me&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You like me</ENAMEX>! You really like me!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Field</ENAMEX>
               
            

            

               "I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the world and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">lord of Monkey Island</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cameron</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               Every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Awards broadcast yields <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> perfect remark. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to predict
the comment from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> that will be most quoted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
papers.
            

            

               ( Topic courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>. )
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 209</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Noise Is Off":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    The whistle, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clanging</ENAMEX>, it's a good noise," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Brady</ENAMEX>, "a noise that's supposed to be
there."
Where?
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>, trying to spin the hacking fouls and awful shooting that have dominated
play."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
               

               
"Emanating from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s new, souped-up prostate."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rakoff</ENAMEX>
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mir</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wilde</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAL</ENAMEX>'s
shiva <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gosh</ENAMEX>,
I hope nobody made any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> jokes. Remember, comedy is tragedy PLUS time.
Such jokes wouldn't be appropriate until, oh, let's say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX> around
noon."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nell Scovell</ENAMEX>
               

                

                

                

                

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

            

            Remember the grotesque
defense-spending boondoggles of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s and '60s</TIMEX> meant to bridge the "missile
gap" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> and the "swimming pool and redwood deck gap" at the
summer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>? Well, it's back, and it's called
the anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, an unworkable solution to an imaginary problem. It's
the perfect program for a time when the best delivery system for a small
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">warhead</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>. Not only will the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ABM</ENAMEX> program absorb money from
programs that might actually benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but by taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> away from real work, it will skew technological progress for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>.
(Wait, wait, I'm about to tie this into the actual topic.) The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tiny moment
of happiness to come from this occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>; at the exact moment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s utter moral collapse, I distinctly heard a whistle and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clang</ENAMEX>. Thank you. And now let's bring out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Orsini</ENAMEX> and his amazing
orangutans!

            
               Romance of the
Rails Answer
            

            The sound belongs at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroad</ENAMEX> crossing in
Kankakee, near the fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> crash in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bourbonnais</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, said a local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX>.

            Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Department</ENAMEX> has reduced the number of these crossings from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">290,000 to 257,000</NUMEX> and intends to close <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 30,000</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> there were
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">422</NUMEX> deaths at crossings, down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years earlier</TIMEX>. The remaining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crossings</ENAMEX> will get upgraded warning systems including, in some cases, gates
that block <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> involved in the Bourbonnais
crash is suspected of veering around the gates in an attempt to beat the train
through the crossing.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spring Cleaning Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            If amusing but ultimately unusable newspaper
clippings are the dust bunnies of a free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humorist</ENAMEX>'s living room, then the
News <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quiz Spring Cleaning Extra</ENAMEX> is the rug under which to sweep them.

            

               "There's a certain value in being overly courteous, even when it's to the
point of being somewhat sarcastic."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, admitting that police
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> should call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> "sir," as long as it's clear they don't mean any
actual respect by it.
               

               "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> thing would be worse than the status quo. And that would be for
the status quo to become the norm."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>, craftily stealing
rhetoric from rival <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>.
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Young children</ENAMEX> who are enchanted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies and Barney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> want to participate in a nurturing experience. Unfortunately, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are toppling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVs</ENAMEX> down on themselves causing head traumas and other
crushing injuries."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Crain</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobi Medical Center</ENAMEX>, warning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> not to let their little ones hug the television. Especially the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX>. Especially the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the purse.
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> shows are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Williams</ENAMEX>, responding
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crain</ENAMEX>, and generating the most ambivalent network slogan since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s "If
you haven't seen it, it's new to you."
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loads of pot</ENAMEX>!"-- From an ad for a two-family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in the New York
Times "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Estate</ENAMEX>" section. I'm holding out for "tons of crack" down the
street.
               

               "A picture caption in 'Weekend' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> ... misidentified a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lone Ranger</ENAMEX> mask standing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clayton Moore</ENAMEX>, one of several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> who have portrayed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lone Ranger</ENAMEX>, it had not yet determined his identity."-- A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times correction, barely concealing the urge to shout, "Who was that masked
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">man?</ENAMEX>"
               

               "But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, I finally did come out. I joined a teen support
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> for gay, lesbian, transgendered, questioning, bisexual and non-labeling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>."-- A contributor to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New Youth Connections</ENAMEX> , a high-school
newspaper. Is it just me, or do the non-labeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> lack the courage of
their convictions?
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Intercranial noises.

         
      
   
