
   
   
      
         
            I Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard J. Daley</ENAMEX> was alive and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, no one gave him a harder time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Mike Royko</ENAMEX> did. Maybe the funniest piece <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rokyo</ENAMEX> ever wrote was an extended
parody of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s frequent solecisms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>, responding to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>,
once uttered the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like a</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX>: 'He who hasn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sinned</ENAMEX>, pick up the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>.' " Royko riffed on this through an entire
column, as in:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>,
leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israelites</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>: "Let's get out of here."

               Ahab,
sighting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great White Whale</ENAMEX>: "Let's all get that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>."

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas MacArthur</ENAMEX>. leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>: "Let's all come back here
some time."

            

            In a less madcap vein, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rokyo</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX> , a
devastating portrait of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Daley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine</ENAMEX> and probably the best book ever
written about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> politics.

            Yet when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> dropped
dead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Royko</ENAMEX> sat down at his typewriter and banged out
a column that was both an interpretation and an appreciation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s abuse of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language didn't offend <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who weren't "that far removed from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> who knew only bits and pieces of the language," Royko
wrote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s abuse of power didn't bother those who had lived through far
worse: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who came here in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> were accustomed to someone
wielding power like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, be it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, or rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> noted. "The niceties of the democratic process weren't part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> experiences. So if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machine</ENAMEX> muscle offended some, it seemed like
old times to many more." It's hard to imagine a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX>--or any
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> for that matter--framing it so simply, or so well.

            Reading these gems in the new posthumous selection, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
More <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time: The Best</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Royko</ENAMEX> , I found myself wondering: Why doesn't
anyone write a newspaper column this good anymore? Royko wasn't quite a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twain</ENAMEX>,
or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mencken</ENAMEX>, but his writing was distinctive and memorable and in its time the
closest thing to lasting literature in a daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> could make you
laugh and make you think, stir outrage at a heartless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX>, or bring a
tear to the eye when he flashed a glimpse of the heart hidden beneath his hard
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shell</ENAMEX>.

            He performed this range
of feats with a regularity and prominence that no city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, or any
national one, can match <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> wrote his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> words <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times a week,
sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> who writes something decent twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> is
a marvel. For the better part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34 years</TIMEX>, everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> read him, first
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> , then in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
News closed, then in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> bought the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX>. (Even after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> said that no self-respecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> would be
wrapped in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> paper, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Alien</ENAMEX>" refused to accept his resignation and
kept reprinting his old columns. This led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> to write: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Alien's Tongue</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'I Quit</ENAMEX>' is 'Vacation.' ") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s fame spread nationally despite the fact that
he seldom left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and refused to do television. By the time he died in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, he was syndicated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s hold came in part from his sense of place. He grew
up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> neighborhood on the northwest side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nelson</ENAMEX>
Algren captured in one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s favorite books, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Neon Wilderness</ENAMEX> ,
and he never left it in spirit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a milkman, and the family
lived over a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tavern</ENAMEX>. Before finding his way into journalism, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> already had
experience "setting bowling pins, working on a landscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, in a greasy
machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, and in a lamp <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX> around a department
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX>," as he noted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. When he said he became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> because it was
easier on the feet, he half meant it. To his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working class</ENAMEX> and
working-class-once-removed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> was, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>, "one of us."

            But where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> often
drew on the worst side of ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>--its tolerance of corruption, its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parochialism</ENAMEX> and racial prejudice--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> spoke to its better instincts. A
neighborhood populist, he celebrated the corner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tavern</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> softball
game. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> also challenged white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s prejudices, skewering bigots
who tried to keep a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> that had adopted a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> out of their
neighborhood or a funeral parlor that didn't want to bury a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>
killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. In the column he wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Washington</ENAMEX>
became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> began with one of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inimitable</ENAMEX> openings, "So I told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Chester</ENAMEX>: Don't worry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> doesn't want to marry your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>."

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Chester</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slats Grobnik and Aunt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>, didn't really exist. I'm sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Sianis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beloved Billy Goat Tavern</ENAMEX>, didn't say many of the things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> attributed to
him. I'm not sure how many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> understood that much of what he
wrote was facetious or fictionalized. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are no
longer allowed the kind of license he took. As journalism has become less of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> and more of a profession, once common vices like embellishment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plagiarism</ENAMEX>, and binge drinking have ceased to be regarded as charming. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnicle</ENAMEX>, a second-rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roykoesque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, was fired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> for blending fiction and fact in a way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> did routinely.

            Nor is it possible for a
newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> now to be as blunt as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> was. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missouri School of Journalism</ENAMEX> released a list of words for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to
avoid, including such terms as gorgeous, lazy, sweetie, and fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fried chicken</ENAMEX>, fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>. I said it and I'm glad. Sue me,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> wrote. His refusal to be sensitive got him in trouble in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the year
before he died. In a column lampooning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
was a useless <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that should be invaded and turned over to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Club Med</ENAMEX>. By
then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s tone had grown increasingly bitter and his irony was easy to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">miss.</ENAMEX> The result was an enormous protest outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that took his comments literally and demanded that he be fired.

            If journalism has changed since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s heyday, so too have
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ethnics</ENAMEX> have ceased to be the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> life. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> moved to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium</ENAMEX> in a lakefront
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">high-rise</ENAMEX>, he cast himself as a bungalow-bred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Mead</ENAMEX>, studying yuppies
by living among them. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>--or at least the suburbanized offspring of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slats Grobnik</ENAMEX>--were increasingly his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> saw himself as more and more of an anachronism. Before he died, he quit
drinking and unhappily moved to the suburbs.

            So why don't we have newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> as good as
him anymore? To summarize: We no longer have his kind of newspaper. We no
longer have his kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. But mainly, we don't have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Royko</ENAMEX>--a
newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> grounded in a place like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, with a gift for explaining
it to the world, and the world to it.

         
      
   
