
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">212</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Bad Chubbies&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fill in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> blanks with the same word in this remark by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>: "There is no __________ ... I know what _______ is. There is no
________ going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>."
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 212</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Chubbies":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     
                        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itsy Bitsy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> told a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bubbly Chubbies</ENAMEX> must be destroyed.
Why?
                     
                  
               

               
"Because they refuse to sign the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peace agreement."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saucier</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rothman</ENAMEX> had a similar answer, but with sufficient
whimsy to distract from the stench of death.)

               "Old
Yeller bit them."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX>
               

               
"They're much too butch."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
monologue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> might live."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
               

               
"Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bubbly Chubbies</ENAMEX> are made by exploited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, while Itsy
Bitsies are made by exploited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Oder</ENAMEX>
               

                

                

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

            

            By rights, this story should have taken place in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, the most cuteness-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on earth and, coincidentally, the most
pornography-laden <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on the planet and hence a popular destination for
vacationing animated space monsters. With perky breasts. And huge, adorable
eyes. Whose crazy adventures are recounted in comic books available in vending
machines on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> of every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. So what are we to make
of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Kitty</ENAMEX>-porn juxtaposition?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Boop</ENAMEX>. That was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> manifestation of a big-eyed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-talking erotic ideal, a sexual
fashion that's come and gone. (It is gone, right? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poppin' Fresh</ENAMEX>--he's a whole
other thing, right?) Perhaps in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> the cute and the concupiscent do not
coincide but coexist as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct phenomena. Like here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
with sex and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>. Still separate, right? Could I have that with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pepperoni</ENAMEX>?

            
               Telechubbies
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bubbly Chubbies</ENAMEX> must be destroyed because they're a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knock-off of Teletubbies</ENAMEX>.

            The suspiciously cuddly and maybe just a little too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">adorable</ENAMEX> dolls, on sale in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,435</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, threaten the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800-million</NUMEX>-a-year business generated by the originals. Even the name was
chosen "deliberately to rhyme with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX>," charged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for the Itsy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bitsy Entertainment Company</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would never
knowingly infringe anyone's copyright," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Maher</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can</ENAMEX> I offer you a drink--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croaka-Cola</ENAMEX>, or maybe something stronger, like a
shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Spaniels</ENAMEX>?" he didn't add.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Stock</ENAMEX>'s
Extra
            

            Other real life trademark cases:

            

               Bozo the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clown</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bozo Steakhouse</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin Cheeseheads</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> Cheesetops

               and now pending in almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Conglomerate</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX> the Small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX> Where
They Make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beer</ENAMEX>

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ikea/Valhalla</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Which of the following is
a well-designed yet inexpensive CD rack sold at the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> furniture
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX>, and which is a figure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norse</ENAMEX> mythology?

            
               God or
Furniture?
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Stiltje

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Adhumbla

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Rätt

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Skallid

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Sleipnir

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Golif

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Ymir

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Moppe

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Solna

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Hela

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>, wicker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$59</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Huge cow in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norse</ENAMEX> creation myth

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rack</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood & metal</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.95</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. CD <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34.95</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odin</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-footed steed

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. CD <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, pine, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14.95</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> formed from condensed fog who lived on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adhumbla</ENAMEX>'s milk

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. CD chest, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plywood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$29</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Neither; it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Goddess</ENAMEX> of the
dead

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay Teletubbies</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
