
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">248</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Re Place&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Kennedy</ENAMEX>, it's a place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "practice newly learned
vulgarities, erupt with anger, tease and embarrass each other, share offensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, flirt, push and shove in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, grab and offend." Where is this
wonderful, magical place?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 247</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does This Look Inflected?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 The author of a new
book charges that a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> not only betrayed him, but also "[h]is
mocking pronunciation of my name ... sounded like a jeering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>." Who is this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insensitive American</ENAMEX>, and how did he mispronounce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s
name?
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selleck</ENAMEX>. And he was complaining about the insinuating way that little English
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> used to call him 'Magnum' on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnum P.I.</ENAMEX> Just between you and me,
this Selleck seems pretty sensitive for a he-man."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
"Aren't we all insensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> when we say 'NetanYAHOO'? Or worse,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'NetanLOSER</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shear Gabel</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H Nelson</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> in question was self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajesh Ajeerinmob</ENAMEX>, who should really be
less sensitive, in my opinion."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Wasik</ENAMEX>
            

            "It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, and he pronounced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s name as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'Liddy</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Craven</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>, I've been rethinking that 'he<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-man</ENAMEX>' stuff I said about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Selleck</ENAMEX>. It
wasn't fair. Some of butchest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> around go all atwitter when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> ask them
about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. Remember that time you and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gary Cooper</ENAMEX> and I were having
fondue at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedda Hopper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and she just wouldn't let up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coop</ENAMEX> about the
hunting? That was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>- or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>-worst time I ever saw him
cry."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dong</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pun</ENAMEX>, and not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pun</ENAMEX>, a Big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ho</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pun</ENAMEX>--such is the provincial, infantile, cross-cultural fun available to anyone
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> phone book and a cold heart. Imagine the torments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Fatty, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Fatone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Bigham</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Bigas</ENAMEX> whose schooldays must
have consisted largely of correcting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> as she called the roll.
There's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brook Sissay</ENAMEX> (that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sissay</ENAMEX> , like a really rich <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">French sissy</NUMEX>)
who we can only hope finds sympathy and comfort in the arms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page-mate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shittko</ENAMEX>.

            What recourse is available to these sufferers?
None. Tolerate those boorish mispronunciations and look like a sap. Or say
something--You're doing that on purpose! Quit it! I'm telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>!--and look
like a bigger sap. Hopeless.

            Of course, no sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would indulge in
this kind of childish mockery. And so I'm going to make a long overdue phone
call of apology right now, to Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helene Lickdyke</ENAMEX>.

            Now we are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.

            
               Treacherous
Back-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stabbing Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deliberately mispronounced it
"Boo-trus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boo-trus</ENAMEX>," just to mock him, charges former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>.

            The pink bellies, the short-sheeting, the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>
deliveries of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> pizzas he didn't even order--had any of these actually
been mentioned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>'s book they too would have been part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to deny him a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign, out of fear for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, who was accusing the
administration of cooperation with international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. Bastards!

            And that liar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> was even worse. In
Unvanquished: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> Saga , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX> asserts that the wily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> sought to unseat him "with determination, letting pass no
opportunity to demolish my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> and tarnish my image all the while showing
a serene face, wearing a friendly smile and repeating expressions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friendships</ENAMEX> and admiration through the poutiest ruby lips I have ever beheld.
Except, of course, for the part about the lips, which look though you may, you
will not find in this book, for I did not write such nonsense. Aiee, this
paradox makes my head ache. And I didn't write that either. Or that last
bit."

            (Note: The actual book
quotation ends with the word "admiration.")

            
               Ads Up
Extra
            

            Which of the following
are from those twee little ads in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , and which are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-bedroom <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WBFP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RivVu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWM</ENAMEX>, and ... no wait, sorry--which are
crude <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">travesties</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adopt Me</ENAMEX>! I'm a smart,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charming</ENAMEX>, rare <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gloucestershire Old Spots Pig</ENAMEX>. Adopt me for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> and help fund
...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Swim at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Swim in other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
homes while they're summering in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>, out for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>, or just sleeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soundly</ENAMEX> ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adopt Me</ENAMEX>! I'm a portly
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Adopt me for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX> and help fund the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX> and
...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. A different kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khaki</ENAMEX> ... price <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Superb Handmade</ENAMEX>
Tie--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Petrol</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisp</ENAMEX>, elegant black & white puppytooth. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$95</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Sock Garters Handmade
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>--"Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ankleton</ENAMEX>" ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$85</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upton Tea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Importers</ENAMEX>--purveyor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World's Finest</ENAMEX> Teas

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabridged AudioBooks</ENAMEX>
Read in plummy English accent ...

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lighthouse Pin a</ENAMEX>
beloved coastal beacon made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Breakell</ENAMEX> in sterling silver <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>. 14k gold
$200

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discrete Unattractive</ENAMEX>
Jewelry ...

            12.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inn</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lap ...</ENAMEX>

            
               Actual
Ads
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 5, 6, 8,</ENAMEX>
10.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Gibbens</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wary Iowans</ENAMEX>
not socked
G-string flashers
Boost disaster.

            
               --Madison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20, 1999</TIMEX>

         
      
   
