
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> 
               continued to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Scorecard:
Significant damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX> and command <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, but not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, which are escalating their assaults on ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> had lost no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. Stress points: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are to blame for
dragging them into a disastrous war, but so far the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are rallying behind
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> are
cautiously supporting the bombing, but not the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> suggested resuming peace talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say the allied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> is holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protesting</ENAMEX> loudly but aren't matching their harsh words with deeds. The naive
anti-bombing spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombs will never get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s peace
plan. The pro-bombing spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will soon attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
directly, crippling their ability to slaughter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>. The sophisticated
anti-bombing spin: That's when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> will start shooting down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. (For the overseas' press reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX> see "" and
".") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> issued a new ruling on the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> is seeking his extradition from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> on charges of
murder, torture, kidnapping, and conspiracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> wants to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>,
where he is immune from prosecution. The court ruled that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> can be
extradited but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) only for crimes that are illegal in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>.
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> didn't sign the global treaty on crimes against humanity until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, this means <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s alleged pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1988</NUMEX> crimes--nearly all the charges
against him--can't be used as a basis for extraditing him. Both sides are
happy: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> now expect him to escape extradition, while human
rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> hail the ruling as a sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> who have committed
more recent crimes can be extradited. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The forewoman
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> said she was willing to indict <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for perjury. The good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: She voted for him, attended
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> gala in his honor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, says, "I absolutely love him" (in part
because he has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>), doubts he committed
obstruction of justice, and doesn't think he should have been removed from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The bad news: She says that he committed perjury (by denying that he
had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>) and that his sexual exploitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was
"awful." She also says <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> was just doing his
job; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) she felt maternal sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> were
suspicious of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> and annoyed by her "self-righteousness."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/26/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> canceled his visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> . En
route to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary</ENAMEX>
Fund, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX> turned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> around and went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
decided to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s vigorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>. The
pessimistic spin: This marks a "significant souring in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>
relationship" and "could poison discussions" on arms control, which are more
important than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. The optimistic spin: As long as we're holding the
purse strings and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> is hard up for cash, he'll be back. The in-between
spin: Canceling the visit offered both sides a graceful way to avoid a
face-to-face fight over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> is botching his murder trial . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>'s case relies on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> video that shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> giving a lethal injection to a
terminally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> after obtaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s consent. Kevorkian, acting as his
own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, is arguing that it was a mercy killing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has tried in
vain to explain to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> that mercy killing is not a valid defense against
a murder charge under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> law. The spins on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX>'s courtroom
performance, in order of ascending irony: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He's nuts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He doesn't
understand the difference between morality and the law. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) He's committing
legal malpractice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) He's killing himself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) He's unfit to make the legal
decisions by which he's killing himself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) He'll escape conviction thanks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> nullification yet again. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> won't run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s spin: He can do
more good by pressuring Wall Street to invest in poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. Other spins:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) He decided he can't win. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) His absence helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> by
clearing the field. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) His absence helps former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, by
freeing up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s left-wing platform. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore talked Jackson</ENAMEX> out of running. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s behalf, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> talked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX>
out of running. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) It doesn't matter much, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has already wrapped up
the nomination. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/24/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
                
               
                  in Love
                shocked
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> by winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Award</ENAMEX> 
               for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Picture</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> , which had been expected to win, instead received
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> lesser awards, including best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> awards, including best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>).
The happy spin: Love beats war. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-cynical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy</ENAMEX> beats tragedy.
The completely cynical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney-Miramax</ENAMEX>'s publicity campaign for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks-Paramount</ENAMEX>'s publicity campaign for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> . The ceremony's political controversy was a lifetime
achievement award for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> revered for his films but
ostracized by much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> for outing fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> era. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX> completed the first round-the-world
balloon trip . Their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-day</TIMEX> odyssey achieved aviation's most elusive goal,
beating more famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Fossett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Branson</ENAMEX>.
Their prize is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the cost of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX>. While applauding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">co-pilot Brian Jones</ENAMEX> for overachieving, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> concluded in retrospect that
the pilot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertrand Piccard</ENAMEX>, had been destined for greatness, since his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandfather</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to reach the stratosphere (in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>)
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had attained the oceans' lowest depth (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35,000 feet</NUMEX>). The spins:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The trip was a triumph of human ingenuity, skill, and endurance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It was a
triumph of meteorological, communications, and auto-piloting technology, which
babysat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It was a triumph of lucky weather. (For more on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> piece "") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan State</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX> reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> basketball
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tournament</ENAMEX>'s final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> is the clear favorite to win it all, having
won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> straight games. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzaga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Missouri State</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>--were wiped out in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rounds, leaving no true
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underdogs</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> are cheering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has earned its
first final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> appearance, having choked in the tournament in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.
Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan State</ENAMEX> is making its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such appearance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>.
The best story belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX>, which was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8-22</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and is the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> ever to reach the final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> without having qualified for the tournament
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
