
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">229</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Don't Think So&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fill in the blank in this quote from cognitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
Bagemihl: "We shouldn't have to look to __________ to see what's normal or
ethical."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 228</ENAMEX>) "Still Not Sure"
            

            

               At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s ceremony honoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teacher</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
recalled that his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> once told him, "If you don't learn the
difference, I'm not sure whether you're going to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> or wind up in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">penitentiary</ENAMEX>." What difference?
            

            "None,
apparently."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Between 'Voulez vous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couchez</ENAMEX> avec moi, ce soir ?' and 'Kiss it.'
"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Oder</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
difference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 18 and 17</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Between 'principal' and 'principle</ENAMEX>.' As we know, the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> is our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'pal</ENAMEX>' and 'principle'--well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is still having trouble with
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Goodman-Malamuth</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Wetherbee</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorry</ENAMEX>,
but I am not going to give aid and comfort to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> by lampooning
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wartime</TIMEX>. At least not until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> gives me the
go-ahead."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teacher</ENAMEX> of the Year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Baumgartner</ENAMEX> is the kind
of educator who has delighted his kindergarten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with a wedding for
Sleeping Beauty, complete with limousine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>, teaching them, I suppose,
that nothing is worthwhile unless it is entertaining. By that standard, I owe
more than I thought to my junior high-school social studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. I'm still
not clear what "social studies" are, exactly, but I'll never forget his stories
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX> that sometimes hovered outside his window, conducting experiments
through a metal cable attached to his neck (he showed us the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">marks</NUMEX>). I'm more
conflicted about my high-school writing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, who announced that his lessons
were so valuable that he deserved <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the profits from our first
books. At the time I agreed, but now he goes around saying he learned more from
us than we did from him, and I still haven't seen a dime from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s
Ashes .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teacher</ENAMEX> of the Year
program is sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholastic Inc.</ENAMEX>, best known among impressionable school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for distributing cool <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> whose exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertiser</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Forces</ENAMEX>.

            
               Indiscreet
Answer
            

            The difference between
"when to talk and when to keep quiet." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letourneau</ENAMEX>.

            
               Long Shot
Extra
            

            In the following quotations from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , the italicized sentences were spoken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> discussing
the search for extraterrestrial life. The nonitalicized sentences were spoken
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and others discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            

               "I'm at the top of my game. I'm going to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. The idea that we're not going to live to see it is not one that's
holding us up in particular."

               "I don't get into it unless I can see my way through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">270</TIMEX>, which are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electoral</ENAMEX> votes needed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> know it's a worthwhile
pursuit, but this makes it known to the wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> we find intelligent life in space in my lifetime? The answer
is, 'Absolutely.' "

               "Now the question is, 'Can you win?' It's a very remote
possibility."

               "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> doesn't provide chairs to little green men
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>. Too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>, too liberal, too intellectual."

               "Now I'm out campaigning for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidency</ENAMEX>, and it's the ultimate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhilaration</ENAMEX>. There is a general belief that while it is a difficult
pursuit, this is so important that it is worth the time."

               "It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and I, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 months</TIMEX>. I've pretty much reached
the conclusion that the occurrence of technological life is an extremely rare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">occurrence</ENAMEX>."

            

            
               Farewell
Extra
            

            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> of deliberation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX> voted
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> in favor of lethal injection. There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
who'll never walk his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> off the leash again. Finishing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my week</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest host</ENAMEX>,
I'd like to thank you all for making me feel welcome. Your inspired
contributions over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few days</TIMEX> are all the gratification I require. There
is no need to e-mail me with praise, nor to cc: jackshafer@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            Now please welcome back
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obi-Wan</ENAMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Anakin</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX>. Believe me, this job isn't as
easy as he makes it look.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The elusive meaning of "is."

         
      
   
