
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 27</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> one of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>'s "riskiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX>." The action sets a dangerous precedent by
attacking a sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for suppressing an ethnic minority with
secessionist aspirations. Its strategy is faulty: Member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are
reluctant, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> is strong militarily, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has forsworn the use of ground
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. And it's unrealistic to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> can halt ethnic cleansing
without destabilizing the region. ... An article says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> waited too long to
prepare the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> for military action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. He procrastinated
because there were reservations within his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and administration about
the wisdom of humanitarian intervention. ... A survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Cardoso</ENAMEX>'s
order to let the real float, which was issued from a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio</ENAMEX>'s
international <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, deepened the recession and worsened inflation. Now that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal</TIMEX> austerity and higher interest rates have been imposed a more prosperous
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> could emerge so long as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilians</ENAMEX> stay committed to reform.

            

               
                  Ms.
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April/May 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The feminist magazine
relaunches with articles on subjects predictable (female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, abortion clinic violence) and less so (adultery, the benefits of
eating soy). ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> narrates her face lift. At first, she feels
like "female goods in a dick-driven market," but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks later</TIMEX> finds her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smoother</ENAMEX>, younger face a source of pleasure and confidence. ... A photo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Praise of Women</ENAMEX>," features shots of impoverished or oppressed women
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, with lushly worded captions. ("Though worlds
apart geographically, we are all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>.")

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover book review
warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is not prepared for the surge in its elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
Policies and social custom encourage early retirement, subsidized by government
programs. As the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> increases, these programs will dominate
the federal budget. Increasing savings and reinventing retirement as a mix of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leisure</ENAMEX> and work could alleviate the looming crisis. ... An article
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> share the same misguided view of gender
relations: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are pervasively victimized by society and need special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society is more flexible than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> and
traditionalists recognize: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> manage to have a "workable balance of job
and home responsibilities."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story by
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must
designate itself as enforcer-at-large of global stability. This role is
mandated by history (it's a natural extension of the melting-pot tradition),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> stands to gain most from globalization), and necessity (no
one else can). ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> asserts that "spermination"--the
increasingly common practice of impregnating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm retrieved</ENAMEX> from
comatose or dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>--should be banned. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> bioethicist "has coined a
term for this new kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>: the sperminator.") Like rape and forced
abortion for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, spermination invades bodily privacy and denies reproductive
choice.

            
               
                  The
Nation
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The special showbiz
issue on "the relation between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>" features stars
ruminating on politics and politically minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> commenting on film.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> says that both making movies and running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> are too
expensive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX> blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment on "the deep, deep shame
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> since [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>] have pretty much been synonymous with."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writers</ENAMEX> name their mostly predictable favorite flicks: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edgar Wideman</ENAMEX> goes
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hoop Dreams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> picks The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>
("I was very moved by it"). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX> chooses Five <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Easy Pieces</ENAMEX> .
... An editorial warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> excited about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s
presidential run to remember "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> rule: A tough broad can
lead a developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and do nothing to improve the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story exposes homophobia on Wall Street. Though some of Wall Street's
leading lights are gay, the industry is still "a testosterone-drenched frat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> complete with ritual hazing." Closeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> lie about
their extracurricular lives; out (and outed) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> suffer insults, wage
discrimination, and demotions. Few gay Wall Streeters are willing to risk their
positions to challenge the status quo. An exception: A top securities executive
who was fired when he requested health benefits for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> is now suing
his old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75 million</NUMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               and

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The newsweeklies offer history lessons. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
profiles "the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and thinkers" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 100 years</TIMEX>, the
latest installment in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearlong</TIMEX> celebration of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>. Among the chosen are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigmund Freud</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Salk</ENAMEX>. In
his assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilbur Wright</ENAMEX>
               
                  ,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> says they
made the airplane "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>" of their era. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> opines that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX> ' theory of government spending "saved
capitalism." The inventors of the television, the computer, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> make
the list, as do more provocative choices: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ludwig Wittgenstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Piaget</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover chronicles "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2000 Years of Jesus</ENAMEX>." Belief in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, "the
dominant figure of Western culture," has redefined the relationships between
living and dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and society, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. In a sidebar , a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX> urges the religious right to
withdraw from partisan politics, comparing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to the
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teetotalers</ENAMEX> who passed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX> in a misguided attempt to regulate
morality. "The vision of worldly power is a distraction," he warns.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is renovating his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s kitchen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> for himself,
enlisting the youngest, most libertarian, and most idealistic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>. "The revenge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX>," an older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> calls it. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">berates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> as "a cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> caught in the
wrong <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>." Her absolutist policy style, formerly lauded, is now deemed
reactive, inconsistent, and ill-timed. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> below for more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> bashing.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America's Best Graduate Schools</ENAMEX> ," suggests which graduate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> should attend, but then asks if they should enroll at all. The
expansive job market makes young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> increasingly hesitant to trade their
robust starting salaries for tuition debt and library toil. There are few
surprises on the lists: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> is top medical school, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> is top law school,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> is top business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
blame their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>' sorry poll numbers on the same strain of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-presidentitis</ENAMEX>" that afflicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> run.
The good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fidelity to Tipper</ENAMEX> has never been questioned. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> wants
his campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to resemble a Web site, where "each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> links to many
different areas." ... The magazine reports on the bawdy race to conceive the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX>. Events for the all-important <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first week of April</TIMEX>: A radio station in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> erected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> "togetherness" session, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Auckland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX> is shelling out for hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> for fecund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> is broadcasting programs on the mating rituals of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> and chimps.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            An unflattering profile
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s influence has waned
under her watch and also suggests that she intentionally withheld information
about her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> heritage. Twice prior to her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> public revelations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>
had contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and documents telling of family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' religion and
deaths at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>. ... A piece calls academia's recent embrace of
pornography a cheap thrill. From college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> articles, the newly
respectable field of porn studies evinces the ivory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>'s desperate need to
seem cutting edge. ... An article describes the bitter war between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superposh Inn</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Washington</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the bucolic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> where it is located. The townspeople find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietors invasive</ENAMEX> and
insufferably haughty; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, in turn, call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals homophobes</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rubes</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
