
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Phony War</ENAMEX>

            This is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> of refusal in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals, exhausted, refuse to revive themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX>, anointed, refuses to campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> arrives.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, terrified of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, refuses to do anything at all.

            Politics, too, abhors a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vacuum</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has concocted a story to fill the void: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>,
whose presidential campaign was written off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just months ago</TIMEX>, is surging, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> presumptive, is in deep trouble. No matter
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 months</TIMEX> away. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ,
many smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsweeklies</ENAMEX> have touted the viability of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign and the messiness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Sunday</TIMEX>, the great sage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was struggling and conferred the mantle of
electability on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s numbers seem to be rising in the polls: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shows Bradley</ENAMEX> favored by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, trailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> by only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> points. (Other polls show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20s</TIMEX>, trailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 25</NUMEX>
points.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is an impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, blessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>,
thoughtfulness, and a good heart, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can be an erratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Surge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Stumble</ENAMEX> have little to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. We
are witnessing one of the first fake battles of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Policy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Marshall</ENAMEX> calls "the phony war" of the campaign. This is the
period when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are indifferent, and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troublemakers</ENAMEX> spin and position and jockey to write
the script for the coming real campaign--in this case, a script that makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a white knight and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> a looming disaster.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> reason for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Surge</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX> is proving himself a better fund-raiser than
anyone expected. He collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.3 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three months</TIMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> raised, but more than enough to make him a
legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> fund-raising reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> an opening to laud him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> surge also owes something to his fame.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> of the left, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who turns baby boomer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> weak in the knees. His "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, sense-of-where-you-are,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhodes Scholar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knick</ENAMEX>" mystique won him a free pass as the thinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>. This was only reinforced by his celebrated reluctance to run for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988 and 1992</TIMEX> and his "politics is broken" retirement speech in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. His reputation as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> too good for politics has been a key
feature of the early adulatory campaign coverage.

            But the most important
reasons for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s supposed surge are independent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
has lucked into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> race. Besides serving as yet another useful
basketball metaphor for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>--"I'm going <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>"--the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-man race gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> instant viability. He's automatically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gaffe away
from the nomination. Political <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is desperate for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> horse
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, but a horse race can only happen if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is perceived to be strong,
and he will only be perceived to be strong if everyone says he is.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> campaign also explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s apparent
rise in the polls. As the only challenger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> collects all the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s numbers have climbed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> dropped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Wellstone</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> from their surveys. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifty-two</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> looks a
lot better for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52 to 13 to 12 to 10</TIMEX>," gripes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s media boomlet
also depends on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> anxiety about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> trails both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> in nationwide polls. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 50 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> poll sample
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> "boring." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has become a kind of voodoo doll for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: When
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is in trouble, his approval ratings remain high, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
numbers sag. A recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pew Research Center</ENAMEX> survey found that the vast majority
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are sick of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> scandals, and they are
taking out their frustration on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want someone who continues
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policies and programs but who is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ought to fit that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Kohut</ENAMEX>. "But somehow there is a link between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> that is hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> feeling panicky over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
numbers are touting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as the remedy: Every piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> emphasizes
that he shares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s moderate, thoughtful, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> politics but isn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handcuffed to Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are doing their best to intensify this
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> anxiety about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. They are trying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quaylize Gore</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have been assaulting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few months</TIMEX>, trying to turn him into a figure of fun. They have ridiculed
his "creating the Internet" comment, his claim that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tipper</ENAMEX> were the
model for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Story</ENAMEX> , and his anecdotes about growing up as a farm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.

            The notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
is rising and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is falling can become true if everyone keeps declaring it
so. But what's more likely is that time and the natural course of campaigns
will take their toll. Campaigns are self-correcting: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> gets close
enough to be a real challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, he will be subject to the same withering
fire that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> faces. It will be pointed out again and again that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is
just as awkward a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, who has belittled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microproposals</ENAMEX> (sprawl, traffic, etc.), will see his own self-proclaimed ""
questioned. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">plucky</ENAMEX> challenger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can campaign both to the left and
right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, picking up support from anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, pro-labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> on one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX> and boosting his pro-business, pro-free-trade agenda to Wall Streeters a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days later</TIMEX>. But if his campaign really prospers and he has to explain what
he believes, he'll have a hard time holding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> together. At the
moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can promote his support for campaign finance reform, but if he
does well, he'll be battered with questions about his own aggressive fund
raising.

            The progression of the campaign will also rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> from
his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vice Presidential Malaise</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fretfulness about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s polls is
premature: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice presidents</ENAMEX> always poll terribly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> before their
presidential campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, you may remember, trailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>
polls, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> even ran a cover story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and "the wimp
factor." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lackey for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than six years</TIMEX>. He's loyal to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and that loyalty makes him look ineffectual. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kills Gore</ENAMEX> in poll questions about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is the manly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> Reinventing Government seminars.)

            The cure for the phony war will be the real one.
Come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, surges and stumbles will really mean something. By then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will be campaigning seriously, distancing himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and
running macho ads; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will have defined his big ideas and endured the
inevitable media backlash to his current rave notices; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will
actually be paying attention.

         
      
   
