
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Hideous
Kinky
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratosphere Entertainment</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Winslet</ENAMEX>'s first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">post- Titanic</ENAMEX> film, the tale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s journey to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marrakech</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1970s</NUMEX> in search of adventure and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX> wisdom, gets high marks on aesthetics
and so-so marks on plot: It's "better at creating a picturesque travelogue than
at building a compelling narrative and full-bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
Wloszczyna, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> goes
gaga for the whole package, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslet</ENAMEX>'s performance as the naive young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who drags her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> to the ends of the earth "perfectly captures
[her] as a well-meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who has no notion that she need be anything but
self absorbed." (This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hideous Kinky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site offers
stills from the film, a chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and information on the novel the film was
based on.)

            

               
                  Life
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> in a "disposable vehicle for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic superstars</ENAMEX>" that has "more
heart and soul than usual" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Hornaday</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> ). The comedy
chronicles the adventures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life. Despite
a nice turn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>, "it's hard to miss the basic unfunniness of the
situation," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maslin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Makeup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Baker</ENAMEX> wins
kudos for transforming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> from young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">1930s hipsters</ENAMEX> into aging
'90s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geezers</ENAMEX>. (Check out this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Lawrence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> page, which has information on
Life as well as fun bits from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> , including video clips of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> as everyone's
favorite weave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheneneh Jenkins</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Goodbye,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lover</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say this murder-filled comedy-noir
strains to be funny and off the wall but fails royally on both counts: It has
an "offbeat eccentricity that feels like the comic equivalent of silicone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">implants</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). The ensemble cast includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen DeGeneres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Johnson</ENAMEX>, and none performs well in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' eyes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX> wonders why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodbye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lover</ENAMEX> didn't go straight to video and asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arquette</ENAMEX>,
the film's sexpot, "exudes all the erotic energy of an inflatable doll with a
taped voice muttering potty-mouthed come-ons." The film receives an upbeat
review from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Seiler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , who gives it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and calls
it a "darkly funny, brashly cynical" thriller that "breaks every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> rule
that deserves to be broken." (Try this
somewhat funny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen DeGeneres</ENAMEX> word lib.)

            
               
                  SLC
Punk
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> like this
"surprisingly genial and affecting comedy about the trials and tribulations of
teenage rebellion during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'80s</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jami Bernard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ).
The title refers to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">punks</ENAMEX> whose tentative attempts at
rebellion are more funny and halfhearted than seriously anarchistic: It's "an
absurdist coming-of-age comedy" that's "better defined by its polish than by
punk trappings" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Some are not impressed with
the film's watered down rebellion: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his energetic but poorly structured,
rather self-congratulatory look at spike-haired rebelliousness in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'80s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
could strike unbiased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> as more grating than gratifying," and the film
"doesn't quite grasp how its slick, flashy package undermines any actual punk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cred</ENAMEX>" it might have (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Harvey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brush</ENAMEX> up on your own punk
cred by seeing how many of these bands you know.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Girl Who Loved</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Gordon</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scribner</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>'s unscheduled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quickie</ENAMEX> novel gets a warm response. The story follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trisha</ENAMEX>, a 9-year-old girl
who gets lost in the woods with only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Walkman</ENAMEX> and common sense to keep her
alive as she wanders for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight nights</TIMEX>. She listens to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> games on the
radio and fantasizes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Gordon</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and crush. As she
struggles for survival, she takes a page from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>'s book and relies on God
to get her through. "For those who have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of adulthood circling
around questions of faith, it may be a little jarring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trisha</ENAMEX>'s hasty
conversion," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Ascher-Walsh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> . Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> describe it as a departure from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s usual style--it's overtly
religious and a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> pages long. It is "almost old-fashioned in how
satisfyingly scary it is" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sherryl Connelly, Daily News</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kipen</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> finds the book tedious: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine days</TIMEX> is "an
awfully long time to spend in the largely unrelieved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of one little girl
lost." (Find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsZone</ENAMEX> .)

            
               
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prayer</ENAMEX> for the
Dying
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart O'Nan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Holt</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> heap praise on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Nan</ENAMEX>'s
latest, the gruesome tale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>
to find his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> engulfed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diphtheria</ENAMEX> epidemic and hemmed in at the
edges by wildfires. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Cryer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> calls it an "urgent,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">economically</ENAMEX> told novel." This "deeply unsettling and sophisticated horror
story" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Megan Harlan, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ) is "more than a brilliant
exercise of darkness," (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ), it is a work
of unusual emotional impact and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eder</ENAMEX> says the prose has "so much that is
implicit and hollowed out, so much emptiness between the sentences, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> is called upon to enter, invent and rearrange," and with "a shivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> of means and a dreadful lavishness of effect, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Nan</ENAMEX> advances the
horror on parallel tracks." (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Nan</ENAMEX>'s 
                  Slate
                "" and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of his last novel A World Away [requires
free registration].)

            Find a
movie playing near you on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Go ;

               
                  Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dreamlife of Angels</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Never Been Kissed</ENAMEX>;
               

               
                  
                     Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metroland</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ground Beneath Her Feet</ENAMEX> , by Salman
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iceman Cometh</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Neill</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX>
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>
               

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Things I Hate About You</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Walk on the Moon</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie- - <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Out-of-Towners</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Financier</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strouse</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Life and My Life With the</ENAMEX>

                  Times , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Frankel</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mod Squad</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EdTV</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dates</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Futurama</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- All Too Human: A Political Education</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief of Unbearable Urges</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englander</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  True Crime ;

               
                  Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> and I ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces of Nature</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renewal</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
