
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TK&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Center</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goethe Institute</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Cultural Center</ENAMEX>; the other group
includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Original Levi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Store</ENAMEX> and You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> . What's the
distinction?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 215</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here's the Pitch":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Fill in the blank. After creating the highest-rated movie ever
made for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Weideman</ENAMEX> is about to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sequels, but the
project was a tough sale. "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>' eyes would glaze over as soon as I
said the words, '____________.' "
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highest-rated</ENAMEX> movie ever made for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Oberg</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmanuelle</ENAMEX>, but with clothes."-- Ananda "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Getcher Cheap Astroturf Here</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gupta</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Baruch ataw adonay ..."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Frick</ENAMEX>
            

            "My two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kittens</ENAMEX> and my new laser pointer."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Reynolds</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            What I hadn't realized
when I posted this question was that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different types of responses were
possible--those that mock the idiocy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Weideman</ENAMEX> for proposing truly
stupid movies, frequently involving an abstruse philosopher, and those that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mock Showtime</ENAMEX> for making truly stupid movies, frequently involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon Tweed</ENAMEX> with her shirt off. These are both worthy goals, and that's what
I admire about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weideman</ENAMEX> mockers and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mockers</ENAMEX> can respect each other and work together to mock various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, and maybe some kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>--that's why the anti-missile system doesn't work, see, because of his
crazy antics, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has him executed, and all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> can sleep peacefully! <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tweed in Fry His Monkey Ass, Governor Hero</ENAMEX> . Oh, like you wouldn't
watch.

            
               First-Class
Answer
            

            "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>' eyes would glaze over as soon as I
said the words 'post office .' "

            The postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> did not directly finance The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspectors</ENAMEX> , starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Gossett Jr.</ENAMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fisted</NUMEX> postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>,
but it did spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> promoting it--printing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> commemorative envelopes,
hanging movie posters in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> post <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gossett</ENAMEX>'s voice on
its phone system so you hear a movie promo when you're on hold.

            The idea for the movie emerged when the postal
service hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weideman</ENAMEX>, an ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was very big in product placement, to
improve its image.

            While ludicrous on the
face of it, there have been less likely government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Widmark</ENAMEX>
played a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fisted health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> tracking down a pneumonic plague carrier
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1950 Panic</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Streets</ENAMEX> , directed by the odious but talented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>; it won an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> for best story. And I believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Hackman</ENAMEX> once
played an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who supported the civil rights movement and battled robot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neptune</ENAMEX>.

            
               Silver Lining
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
tests, an anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> missed its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>. But that's really a good
thing, according to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>, which built the
system.

            

               "It was a very close miss."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Caniff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>
               

               "We came very close to hitting this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> ... and we're very encouraged by
that."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Corcoran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>
               

               "Much of the operation was as it should be."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Corcoran</ENAMEX>
               

               "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> were courteous and neatly dressed."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Corcoran</ENAMEX>,
or perhaps that was me
               

               "And lunch. That went well, especially those spicy shrimp, mmm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mmm</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Corcoran</ENAMEX>, or was that me too?
               

               "Oh, right, so you're so perfect, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perfect</ENAMEX>,
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goddamned Big Nose Perfect Sissy Boy Stupid</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Corcoran</ENAMEX>; oops, me
again
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unlikely Old Bore in Love</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
