
   
   
      
         
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
endorsed sending <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> . The nonbinding resolution
backing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to assign <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to a peacekeeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> passed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">219</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">191</NUMEX>. Forty-four <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, joined <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in support. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> argued that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can't be trusted to bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> home on time. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of playing politics and undermining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> unity in foreign
policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s old spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> shouldn't endanger the peace talks by
debating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s new spin: The "bipartisan" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote
"confirms the strong commitment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-cynical spin:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will fail to fulfill the conditions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> placed on its approval (a
timetable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>' return; that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will explain to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> why
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were sent; that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> will report to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> only).
The completely cynical spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> will kill the peace deal,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will withdraw its support for sending the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for leaking and lying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
Bakaly, says he's innocent but will resign. Background: After the New York
Times reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> thought he could indict a sitting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> launched an internal probe. In that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakaly</ENAMEX> denied to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> that he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> has
found evidence contradicting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bakaly</ENAMEX>'s denial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is referring his findings
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> calls this "an implicit
admission that [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>] suspects serious wrongdoing on his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spins: 1</ENAMEX>) This proves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is a vicious leaker. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) This proves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> won't
tolerate vicious leaking. Best tidbit: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">developments</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> launched her presidential
campaign exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. Pundits slotted her as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> field's
runner-up, trailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> staged her announcement
with ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, in implicit contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign launch days
earlier. Together, their announcements sandwiched the candidacy kickoff of
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX> The positive spins on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She's the first
serious female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) She's a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> but not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) She'll restore "civility" to politics. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) She'll listen to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> rather than dictate her views. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) She's attractive to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">independents</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) She's attractive to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The negative spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She's too
tightly wound to handle the campaign trail's surprises. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) She's too tightly
wound to handle the press. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) She's too tightly wound to handle criticism. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
Her views are vague and mushy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Nothing is more political than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>
who pretends not to be one. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Reports indicate
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> obtained atomic secrets from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> and may have
used them to vastly improve its nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and the media
demand to know why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> security was lax and why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
didn't recognize, admit, or aggressively investigate the problem when the first
signs of trouble appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> says it got wind of the
problem in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> and responded promptly. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> plan to hold a hearing. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spins: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't want to believe there was a problem because he knew it
would disrupt his policy of constructive engagement. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He knew there was a
problem but hid it anyway. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) He hid the problem so it wouldn't stop him from
helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> sell technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> under the guise of constructive
engagement. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) He hid the problem so it wouldn't stop him from being nice to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in exchange for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign contributions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are blaming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in order to hide similarly lax security under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents Reagan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/10/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabisco</ENAMEX> 
               is breaking up . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabisco</ENAMEX> will jettison the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
tobacco interests and will sell its foreign cigarette business to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Tobacco</ENAMEX>
to shore up the severed domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.J. Reynolds Tobacco</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> spun the story in two directions with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>. Story 1 is
about the excesses of the leveraged buyout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>--exemplified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR Nabisco</ENAMEX>
merger--and the comeuppance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kohlberg Kravis Roberts & Co.</ENAMEX>, which saddled
the merged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with unbearable debt. Story 2 is about the rise of tobacco
litigation and regulation and the gradual financial buckling of evil cigarette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The convergence story is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> merged with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabisco</ENAMEX> in the hope of
escaping its "tobacco taint" but found instead that the taint simply spread to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabisco</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/10/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> died of complications from lung
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> surgery. News accounts recited his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumé</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> World
Series championships, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> All-Star games, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Valuable Player</ENAMEX> awards--but focused on his record <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> game hitting steak in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>, which still stands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. While sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> compared his greatness on
the field with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lou Gehrig</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> traced his
celebrity to his courteous, humble, all-American, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>-of-immigrants
personality. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> represented the grace and dignity of the
good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">old days</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty Cobb</ENAMEX> represented the pugnacity and decadence of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">good old days</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> was the exception. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/8/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, announced he is forming a presidential campaign
exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. Though he won't officially declare his candidacy until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, he paraded notable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> such as former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts Jr.</ENAMEX> before the press. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> also listed
scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> who are backing him. Everyone
agrees his strategy is to create an air of inevitability and suffocate his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. The spins against him: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He's inexperienced in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
He's inexperienced in national politics. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) He has no base. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) He lacks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> in early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) He's had it too easy and is due for a fall. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)
His expectations are too high. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s entry into the race will
kill his momentum. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> don't know what he stands for. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) He
doesn't know what he stands for. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/8/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Film director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> died . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obituaries</ENAMEX> recalled his movies' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Awards, focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangelove</ENAMEX> , A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clockwork Orange</ENAMEX> , and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Odyssey</ENAMEX> , also mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lolita and The</ENAMEX>
Shining . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> debated the significance of the bleak fantasies in
which he portrayed human recklessness, madness, brutality, murder, and nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">holocaust</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-cynical spin: He hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and portrayed them as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savages</ENAMEX>. The completely cynical spin: He hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and portrayed them as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savages</ENAMEX> because they deserved it. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/8/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
