
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">208</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Favorite Things&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Urine-absorbing disposable diapers, mistake-eradicating liquid paper,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bullet-stopping Kevlar</ENAMEX>--what's the connection?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 207</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Samaranch Hand":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     
                        
                           
                              As it prepares to convene in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> has invited a
well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> to join its reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>. Who and why? (Question
courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX>.)
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee Clipper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe DiMaggio</ENAMEX>, because of his grace under pressure and his
unimpeachable sense of fair pl--What? He did? Oh, never mind. Can you get me
tickets to The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion King</ENAMEX> for my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rakoff</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eliot Cohen</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>. Anyone who can take a junket on the space shuttle is all right with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Lemke</ENAMEX>
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ubiquitous Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX>. Because he's ubiquitous."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan E.</ENAMEX>
Snow
               

               "Whoopi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>. It's a trap: They're going to push her into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pit</ENAMEX> and cover it with a
steel plate in order to prevent her from hosting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX>. It's far-fetched,
but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can dream."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>, but only if he agrees to bring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Jordans</ENAMEX> for each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, plus some hookers. In return, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> becomes the official shoe
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC Reform Committee</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deathly Afraid of Freeways</ENAMEX>"
Carvell
               

                

                

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

            

            Do dark and brooding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> regard any effort at reform as insincere or just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>'s?
What about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFSCME</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC37</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> union? What about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>'s recent plan--what was it called? oh yeah--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pride</ENAMEX>,
Respect, or I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot</ENAMEX>. No, wait, it was CPR: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courtesy, Professionalism</ENAMEX>,
Respect. How's that working out, by the way? Here's how: According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> survey, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African-Americans</ENAMEX>) believe most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> use excessive force; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX>
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> often engage in brutality against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> think
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou Diallo</ENAMEX> shooting has made matters worse.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> said everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is just wrong: "The poll
numbers seem to be driven by false perceptions." That's a kind of reform plan.
And by "dark and brooding," I, of course, mean appealing and simpatico.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz Time</ENAMEX>
Line
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> slam at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16, 1999</TIMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenesaw Mountain Landis</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16, 1999</TIMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> use of phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> ass" (not alluding
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landis</ENAMEX>)--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16, 1999</TIMEX>

            

            
               Honest to God I'm
Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making Up This Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> , seeking the moral high ground, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Antonio Samaranch</ENAMEX> has invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> to join the reform
panel, for reasons that utterly confound me. The secret war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>? The
overthrow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Allende</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>? The harassment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ellsberg</ENAMEX>?

            Also invited, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni Agnelli</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samaranch</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazzetta dello Sport</ENAMEX> that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>
would include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> each from international sports federations and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, "plus a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> of great prestige and
some global <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> of unquestioned fame." A lovely phrase, that:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unquestioned</ENAMEX> fame. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idi Amin or Cher</ENAMEX>.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Price Is Right</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Match each dollar amount with the item it buys.

            
               Cost
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,099</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.5 million</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.25 million</NUMEX>

            

               Benefit
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chainsaw</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s back pay from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Bonus</ENAMEX> payment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey</ENAMEX>
Bible.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Amount</ENAMEX> left on contract of fired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Nets</ENAMEX>
coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Calipari</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D. Panasonic</ENAMEX>'s high-tech toilet seat.

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-D: The "personal hygiene system" advertised in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> features "intimate washing, heated seat, air dryer."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-C: Off to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-17</NUMEX> start, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calipari</ENAMEX> will likely get
to keep the money. Of his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> he said, "I do believe that they care
about me." None of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> was heard to say the same about their
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-B: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>'s bonus, a reward for his part in the
settlement with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, was approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the compensation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Reed</ENAMEX>. As co-chair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> got a bonus of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. That's called "empathy."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-A: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>, the
dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> says he's owed the money; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> says he's not. Sunbeam,
incidentally, does not make a personal hygiene system, but for enough money,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> will come to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, give you a sponge bath, and fire your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don King</ENAMEX>. (Oh, right--you
kill one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and I suppose that makes you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgmental</ENAMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
