
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spikey's Hypocrisy</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncovering Clinton</ENAMEX> recounts the
events of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> from the perspective of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who in investigating the
story became a key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in it, since news that his article might appear
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> precipitated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s hurried
investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s dalliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. This
being a book by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, we asked another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> to review it. Lucianne
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> is a literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> who served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s main
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> and put many of the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX> in touch with one
another. She was also one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s main
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
               
                  
               
               
To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>, click .
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the many amazing
things about "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spikey</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncovering Clinton</ENAMEX> , is the
dexterity of its execution. It must be difficult to type and cover one's butt
at the same time.

            Throughout this
enthralling tale, one feels a "please don't hit me" cringe coming from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, he plunges relentlessly ahead as he details his deep
involvement in the development of the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monicagate</ENAMEX> and the agonizingly
slow revelation of the squalid behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. On virtually
every page he risks journalistic scrotal torque as he stiff-arms his reluctant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and sucks up to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, who he wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to believe are as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">duplicitous</ENAMEX> and sleazy as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and his sock-puppet mouthpieces.

            He is particularly savage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> love to
hate (a cheap and easy shot in order to provide the book with a villain).
Without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> and her dogged documentation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> goings-on,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> would not have had the story of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> and a book that will send
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to college. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> were performing the same task, exposing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> had a powerful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsmagazine</ENAMEX> and all its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> had a cheap tape recorder, a like-minded and determined friend
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and an iron will. It is not sporting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spikey</ENAMEX> to dump on his
source to provide cover for his own deep activity as a deep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in this
drama. [Click to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s doubts about whether he should have used Tripp
as a source, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">356-57</ENAMEX>.]

            I knew of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>
long before I met him. He was one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, for quitting his job at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> would not publish his reporting on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. When I heard he had gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> I was saddened, for to
me that meant the end of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bimbo Beat" for Isikoff</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> would be no different from his faint-hearted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-loving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . No one, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, wanted to publish what they
all knew--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had a long history of abusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and threatening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to cover it up.

            Then, suddenly, news--or, more correctly, gossip items
concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> gropes--began to appear, and I saw
that the Sex Beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbo</ENAMEX> was on the job again. In those items a name I had all
but forgotten cropped up again: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda R. Tripp</ENAMEX>. She was telling a story I had
heard before in a book proposal she submitted to my literary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">l996</TIMEX>.
Subsequently, she had withdrawn the project and we parted company, a common
occurrence in the publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August of l997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> was back on the
phone. She needed help. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> was "hounding" her about what she knew
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> wanted to talk to him, but not alone. In that
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phone conversation I learned that she now had far more damaging
information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Would I help her get the story out through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ? Long a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> I knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abused</ENAMEX>, most particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>, I jumped at the chance to be
involved.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> makes much in
this enthralling tale of the fact that I "secretly" taped those first calls
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> and how we "conspired" not only to "overthrow" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but also to
arrange a "big-bucks book deal." A book was discussed in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> calls. I
only knew her as a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> I have looked at
everything and everyone that passes through my life as a possible book. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>'s tale quickly developed, talk of doing a book became a moot point that I
can say faded to the vanishing point. Note to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irony Police</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> never
gave me a word on paper regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> and I am at this moment reviewing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s "big-bucks book." Note to anyone who calls me after closing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>: Expect to be taped. It's legal and it saves me pawing around on my night
table for paper and a pen. [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Click for Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s account of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> call from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">190-91</ENAMEX>.]

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks</TIMEX> after that fateful call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>, I met the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crumpled</ENAMEX>, rumpled, and I was soon to learn, occasionally hysterical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. I
liked him. He had no small talk, he barely smiled, his shirt was out, his tie
was down, and he accepted a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. At that meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> produced her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
phone tapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> keening about her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul mate</ENAMEX>" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and she
offered to play them for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. He declined. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncovering</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> he protests a bit much on this point, for he has been criticized by
less biased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> than me. He claims he didn't want to become a part of the
story. Jeepers! I wish I had known that: I wouldn't have spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">countless hours</TIMEX>
on the phone with him after that meeting, keeping him up to speed as we worked
throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> to expose the goings-on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. My theory, at
the time and now, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> had a car downstairs that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to take him
to a TV appearance. I mean, first things first. [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Click for Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s
explanation of his abrupt departure <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">205-06</ENAMEX>.]

            Further, he waits until Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">348</NUMEX>, upon learning that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX> had withdrawn its offer of a job for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, to go all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Fields</ENAMEX> on
us and exclaim, "What do you know? It's true. It's really true."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>?

            
Not once in all the often breathless
conversations I had with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those weeks</TIMEX> did I doubt for a minute that
he believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>'s story and the facts I was relaying to him regarding her
ongoing documentation. But I should have paid closer attention. Right there on
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">302</NUMEX>, he explains. In his frantic manipulating to get hold of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>'s tapes
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, he phoned me in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and remembers it as follows:

            

               You've
got to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>] to let me listen to those tapes, I shouted at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>. You've got to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> to give him the go-ahead. You don't
understand how important this is. Without that, if I can't write that there is
compelling evidence backing up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s allegations, this is going to blow up in
your face--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp's</ENAMEX>. ...

               That, at any rate, was
what I was telling them. It is the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> operate: We threaten, we
cajole, we feign sympathy. But the truth for me was slightly different:
Whatever was on those tapes, listening to them, and quoting them, would make
this a much more compelling and dramatic story for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .

            

            Ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spikey</ENAMEX>, your sudden burst of candor, like a summer
squall, comes without warning. What he meant, of course, was that he could put
his hands back on the keyboard. His butt was covered.

            All along, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in this story, and he has written a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>'s book. That is
what makes it so engrossing. He guarded the story with the ferocity of a mother
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tiger</ENAMEX> hovering over the last shard of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">impala</ENAMEX>'s bloody haunch. Never mind
that a wily Internet jackal, in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>, leapt out of the
jungle of cyberspace and ran off with a juicy chunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spikey</ENAMEX>'s hard-won <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>.
The bulk of it still belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. He worked for it, he earned it, and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncovering Clinton</ENAMEX> he has found a medium where he can't suffer the fate
that gave him his nickname.

            It is a riveting tale written by someone who gave it
texture as it unfolded, and I doubt that any reviewer save this one will take
him to task for his ingratitude to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>. She is an easy target. But it
does seem a tad mingy for someone as talented and resourceful as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> to
take such cheap shots at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff ends Uncovering Clinton</ENAMEX> with a quote
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> made during a phone call at the end of the whole ordeal. He tells me
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thinks we are scum. I reply, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, we are scum. If anyone ever
did to me what we did to him, I would hate them too."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> writes, "When
that happens ... I will plan to be there, watching, listening and taking
notes."

            Spikey, tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> you'll be right down. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> nor I nor the handful of dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who made up the
truth-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tellers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vast Right-Wing Conspiracy</ENAMEX> will ever be elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and proclaim that theirs will be the most ethical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> in
history. None of us will ever take a manipulative young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">intern</ENAMEX> into the Oval
Office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and have her perform sex acts about which we will force an
entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> to lie.

            When, not if, the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> comes to me with an amazing story that I know in my heart and gut
is true, I will simply bypass the agonizing mainstream media, the doubting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomases</ENAMEX> and whiners, and go directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>.

            
               To read the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passages from Uncovering Clinton</ENAMEX> to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> refers, click
.
            

         
      
   
