
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">223</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;You Who</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "I'm on top, I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years old</TIMEX>, I don't want to get hurt anymore, and
I've got nothing left to prove." Who said this about what?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 222</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zanimax":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    
                                       The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farsi</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>") and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> movie
company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Mira</ENAMEX>"?) are in trouble for similar offenses.
What?
                                    
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            
"Running afoul of parent company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Fein</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Requesting public information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>
Gaffen
            

            "I have
no idea what the offense is, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khomeini</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farsi for 'Weinstein</ENAMEX>.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrianne Tolsch</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into lesser roles."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chrysa Kieke</ENAMEX>-Sciglitano
            

            
"Trouble at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zan</ENAMEX> due to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX>. Trouble at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> due to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clerks</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Schoenberg</ENAMEX>
            

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> sound so deliciously trivial, so
delightfully parochial. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zan</ENAMEX> . It's no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX> . That's my delightfully parochial view, an easy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to maintain
because here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> we're No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>--except for education, income, and infant
mortality. Do other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> escape this jingoism? Surely neither <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> nor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belize</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX> can assert this sort of claim. But of course they can; every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> can, as long it avoids hard data and stakes its pride on cultural
superiority.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the big "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gypsy Caravan</ENAMEX>"
concert presented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romany</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. Musafir, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, featured a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> who played unimaginably <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> rhythms on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dholak</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kalyi Jag</ENAMEX>, featured a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> who played the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> can. Can the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarians</ENAMEX> really believe it's all culturally relative?
Surely the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> wakes up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> and admits to
himself that the dholak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is just better.

            Of course these kinds of
questions always confound me because I'm from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> owns the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news and the only compelling rhythm is the beat of my heart when the
camera zooms in on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>. He articulates so clearly when he speaks of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">cherry</ENAMEX>-tree-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beavers</ENAMEX>!

            
               Infidel
Answer
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> are in hot water for
sassing religion, a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> in this, the neo-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Middle Ages</TIMEX>.

            Miramax embarrassed prissy parent company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> by
making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dogma</ENAMEX> , directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clerks , Chasing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> ). Everyone involved apologized meekly. "Why make trouble?" asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contrite Miramax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Weinstein</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> says his movie was "from first
to last always intended as a love letter to both faith and God almighty." The
movie, featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alanis Morissette, Selma Hayek</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Rock</ENAMEX>, will be distributed by some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so that really gullible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> had nothing to do with it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> confiscated copies of Zan
after it printed a cartoon showing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> being asked to kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> rather
than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> because under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> law a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s "blood money" is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> that of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood</ENAMEX> money is compensation that must be paid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of a victim
who is murdered or killed in an accident.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gholamhossein Rahbarpour</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Revolutionary Courts</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zan</ENAMEX> insulted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> because blood money is "one of the main judicial and religious principles
of Islam." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is banned from publishing until after the case goes to
court.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faraj Balafkan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zan</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, is expected to continue her fight for press freedom.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, is expected to continue his fight to make as
much money as possible.

            
               Ultradull
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were invited to invent an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> more soporific than "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Business Leaders for Sensible Priorities</ENAMEX>," a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> that ran a policy ad on the op-ed page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s New York
Times . A few particularly tepid examples:

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana Dentists</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic Responsibility</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Pollack</ENAMEX>
               

               "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Osgood Appreciation Society</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ya-Ya Sisterhood of Concerned Scientists</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens Concerned</ENAMEX> With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Development</ENAMEX>. (An actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Danenberg</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corporate Lawyers Against Unnecessary Integrity</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
Heaney
               

               "Mid-Level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executives</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Cap Companies</ENAMEX> for Increased Median
Compensation."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Connelly</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporatecomedy</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. (An actual Web
site.)"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Anonymous</ENAMEX>
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> antipathy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salman Rushdie; Western</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antipathy</ENAMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
