
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Unlisted&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert White</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 4</NUMEX> on a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,600</NUMEX>.
What's the list and how did he get off it?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 216</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yin and Yang?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Center</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Council</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goethe Institute</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Cultural Center</ENAMEX>; the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Original Levi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Store</ENAMEX> and You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> .
What's the distinction?
                  
               
            

            "Oh,
like we need to know something about a place before we bomb it."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            "The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> got the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb's blood</ENAMEX> 'X' on the door."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Things
that were burnt down and things that should have been burnt down."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Hoover</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Hobson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            "The
latter contain no copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sorrows of Young Werther</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            "Aw,
jeez, have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> sided with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> already?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

             

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> goes to war. And damned uneasily. If we
neglect the war, the quiz is marginalized into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weird</ENAMEX> ; if
we refer to it, we risk trivializing genuine suffering. Catch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> was
funny about war by blasting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s bureaucratic madness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M*A*S*H</ENAMEX> --at
least the TV version--offered a pseudo-anti-war stance while enjoying frat boy
high jinks: I believe their contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> required that in every third
episode the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> would see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loretta Swit</ENAMEX> in the shower and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Alda</ENAMEX>
would wring his hands sensitively. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>) had a
favorite scene in a service comedy: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">in No Time for Sergeants</ENAMEX> , when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith</ENAMEX> made those toilet seats stand at attention. Not strictly speaking a
war picture, but it was very, very funny.

            I suppose it is better
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> to risk being overly dark than to risk being overly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Ambrose, who seems to find war, at least <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, so thoroughly enjoyable
that we should do it again and again. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> died delightfully.

            
               Evil of Banality
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group 1</ENAMEX>: bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> stuff. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group 2</ENAMEX>: good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
stuff.

            While cops stood idly by, mobs trashed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
listed above, but they spared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>'s outlet across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Center</ENAMEX>, and rentals of that marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX> movie remain high,
notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Erlanger</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , so some good has come from
these tragic events.

            The worst part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX>? They're boring and there's nothing on television. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erlanger</ENAMEX> quotes one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serb</ENAMEX>: "There is a deepening sense of boredom--the war is really very boring,
especially with this monotonous war propaganda on the news. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is bored; he
can't go out, except to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX>, where it's boring. My
little one is bored, because all her favorite cartoons like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Rangers</ENAMEX> have
been replaced by those interminable news programs."

            
               Either/Or
Extra
            

            

               "They deny everything. They essentially say to their very best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
that you get what's coming to you for believing us."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gaylord</ENAMEX>
refers either to the ad campaign for The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mod Squad</ENAMEX> that lured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, or to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>, which was just ordered by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$81 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlboro</ENAMEX> smoker
               

                "They are important when they bring in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. If not, they are
not."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ignatius Byamugyisha</ENAMEX> refers either to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX>'s breasts, which could
attract <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Studios</ENAMEX> Tour, or to endangered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Ugandan gorillas</ENAMEX> whose habitat is coveted by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man</ENAMEX>, if I can continue to do that good, who knows? The sky's the
limit."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> is either cheerfully befuddled about his
plummeting approval ratings or gigglingly mean about the support he's reaped
from an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> Web site
               

               "This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in all my visits that they've given me a hopeful
sign."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion Picture Association of America</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Valenti</ENAMEX> refers
either to his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> break-ins at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baldwin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> compound or to his
trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> movies
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The odd misconception that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> would bomb the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Center</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
