
   
   
      
         
             A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> of Linux

            Linux may be impractical
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>, but its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> cachet--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man</ENAMEX> doesn't have me under his
thumb!"--appeals to the motorcyclist in me. Walking out of a bookstore with a
Linux manual under your arm is like swaggering into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> carrying a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcycle</ENAMEX> helmet: You can feel the waves of envy.

            Since my technical education ended with a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>-grade "Computer Literacy" class in which we played "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lemonade Stand</ENAMEX>" on
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IIe</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Linux</ENAMEX> goals for this article
were modest:

            

               Prove that a computer ignoramus can install the operating system on a
computer that was running Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>.

               Install a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Linux</ENAMEX>-compatible Web browser and read 
                     Slate
                   in
it.

               Install a few other Linux applications.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purchasing Linux</ENAMEX> in a book, I must admit, was a second
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resort</ENAMEX>. Originally, I intended to download the free version of the
much-heralded operating system, but then I found out that it would take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and that the download doesn't come with instructions. Chickening out, I
visited the computer section of my local bookstore and grabbed a copy of the
friendly yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Linux for Dummies</ENAMEX> . But the cashier all but refused to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> it to me. "You can't get that book," he said, obviously speaking as one of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Linux</ENAMEX> initiate. On his advice I paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34.63</NUMEX> plus tax for Mastering
Linux , a phone-book-sized tome, which includes a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Hat Software</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.1</NUMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> on CD.

            Cracking Mastering
Linux open, I was struck by its similarity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle manuals</ENAMEX>. "Remove
cylinder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>," says the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle manual</ENAMEX>, without explaining how you
do that. "Create boot disk," commands <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastering Linux</ENAMEX> . What's a boot
disk? I found myself turning to a dictionary
of computer terminology on the Web to decipher every <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> acronym (BIOS?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATAPI</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCSI</ENAMEX>?) and figured out that in this case you create an installation boot
disk by copying files from the CD to a floppy.

            
               Making Room for
Linux
            

            After creating the boot disk, I was supposed to
make a new partition on the hard disk of my computer, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentium</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">133</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
megs of memory. Partitioning a hard disk means corralling off some space, and
that can be done in Windows with a program called "fips," which I copied from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> CD onto a floppy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windows</ENAMEX>. I then restarted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows in DOS</ENAMEX> mode
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the options when you shut down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Windows 98</ENAMEX>) and ran "fips.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exe</ENAMEX>" from the
floppy. Although I had never used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> before, I followed the straightforward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX> and made room for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>.

            The next step was to run
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> installation program from the boot disk. I shut the computer down and
put the boot disk in the drive and turned the computer back on. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>! The
boot disk asked me to check boxes for the language and the keyboard I'd be
using, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> from which I'd be installing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>. I told it to go to my
CD-ROM drive where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> CD resided--and promptly hit a brick wall. The
program refused to recognize my CD-ROM drive, a fairly standard one, and
rejected the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> nonstandard options from the list. I studied Windows' device
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for clues on my CD-ROM drive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mastering Linux</ENAMEX> suggested that if
the installation program fails to detect your drive, provide very specific
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX> for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">IO</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRQ</ENAMEX>." I entered these new settings and still
failed.

            Everyone who talks up Linux mentions how "elegant" it is.
As I tinkered, rebooted, and failed, and tinkered, rebooted, and failed over
and over again to get it to recognize my CD-ROM drive, all I could think was:
yeah, elegant like a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cradle</ENAMEX>. And this was only the installation program.

            So I telephoned the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Helpdesk</ENAMEX>. Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is supposed to demolish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Helpdesk</ENAMEX>, which provides computer assistance to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, was
surprisingly helpful. As I described my trouble, the Help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> replied, "You're
setting up <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Linux?</ENAMEX>" Pause. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, you know we don't really support that?" Yeah, I
know, but can you help me anyway<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "Well, I don't know much about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX>, but
talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence</ENAMEX> (not his real name). He'll help you." In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 or so</NUMEX> calls to the
Helpdesk, I encountered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who sounded annoyed rather than curious
(and even, dare I say, gleeful) at the fact I was firing up Linux.

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Case of Mistaken</ENAMEX>
Identity
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> that came with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastering Linux</ENAMEX> was
never going to communicate with my CD-ROM drive, and I began to lose all
enthusiasm for the project. Just the sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastering Linux</ENAMEX> induced
the stomach-churning sense of dread that my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>-grade math textbook once gave
me: "I don't get this. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get this. Why don't I get this? I think
I'll go watch TV."

            Instead of watching TV,
I made a fresh start by purchasing a newer version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>. The version of
Linux that comes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastering Linux</ENAMEX> offers no technical assistance, but
Red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hat</ENAMEX>'s version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.2</NUMEX>, which costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39.99</NUMEX>, promises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> of free e-mail
support. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CORRECTION</ENAMEX>: After this article was posted, I learned that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macmillan Digital Publishing</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Hat Software</ENAMEX> provided the e-mail
support for this version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>. That new information is now reflected in the
remainder of the piece.)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Hat</ENAMEX> manual offered clearer directions, and the new
version automatically partitioned my hard drive. But it still snubbed my CD-ROM
drive. I e-mailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macmillan</ENAMEX> with my problem and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> e-mailed back a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-line response: "Set your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIOS</ENAMEX> to boot off of the CD." I wrote back: "How do
I do that?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macmillan</ENAMEX>'s e-mail answer was another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>. I clicked
the link, which led to a page of more links to lots of information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIOS</ENAMEX>, but
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX> search yielded no information on booting from the CD-ROM drive. I
e-mailed back asking for a more specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>, and they wrote back, "Look around
there. ... You also may want to check the site of whoever manufactured the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motherboard</ENAMEX>." Thanks a bunch.

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Helpdesk</ENAMEX> assistance I figured out
that my CD-ROM drive was probably connected to my sound card and not to the IDE
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">port</ENAMEX>, and thus was foiling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>. I reluctantly returned to Mastering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> and found an alternative method for installing the operating system
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have CD-ROM drives: install from the hard disk. For this
you create a "supplementary disk" from the CD-ROM and use it after booting from
the installation disk. The supplementary disk loaded an unfamiliar blue
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Welcome to Red Hat Linux</ENAMEX>" page, but after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> of nothing happening, I
figured I had worn out my welcome. I turned off the computer and went home.

            My next move was to
hornswoggle a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, a tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> Web site, into
helping me. I informed him of my CD-ROM/sound card suspicions, and he pried
open my computer's metal box and started gabbing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40</NUMEX>-pin connections. My
troubles were over. Here was someone who knew the acronyms, someone who could
shine <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a light</NUMEX> into the cave I was blindly fumbling in. So with the CD-ROM drive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">securely</ENAMEX> connected to the correct IDE <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in my motherboard, we booted up
again. Again, no dice. It was a new low in my Linux morale.

            
               Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDE Port</ENAMEX> in a
Storm
            

            After some chin scratching my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> suggested we
look into my BIOS setting. There he discovered my IDE <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> was disabled. He
enabled it. We booted up and victory! The CD-ROM drive started purring, and
from there the installation was cake. The hard disk whirred away, occasionally
asking for information. I typed it in, it whirred some more, and within an hour
installation was complete.

            I then logged on as "root"--the master <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loaded X Windows</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>'s graphical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user interface</ENAMEX>. It looked like a pale and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wan</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Windows</ENAMEX>--with tiny, little crude buttons--even though
it predates Windows. But it worked. I loaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> browser and tried to
call up 
                  Slate
               , but 
                  Slate
                did not appear. Instead I
got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> error messages, one telling me to adjust my SOCKS environment, and
another saying there was something wrong with my DNS server.

            So I was on the phone
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helpdesk</ENAMEX> again, learning about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SOCKS</ENAMEX> and my DNS server. My
officemate suggested that maybe all I needed to do was adjust my proxy settings
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netscape</ENAMEX> and not my SOCKS. He was right, and victory was mine.

            
               I Suffer a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Core</ENAMEX>
Dump!
            

            Next I wanted a word
processing program. I downloaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WordPerfect 8</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corel</ENAMEX>'s Web site.
I unzipped and "untarred" (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de-archived</ENAMEX>) the program. I installed it. And it
didn't run. I bribed my tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy friend</ENAMEX> to come and help me again. He went back
to the original download and started over, but he couldn't get it to run
either. So he fiddled around with my PATH and a few other things beyond my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comprehension</ENAMEX>, when a "core dump" occurred. This is some type of serious error,
although I'm still not sure exactly what it is. So we started over and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">downloaded</ENAMEX> again. After reinstalling and receiving increasingly mournful error
messages ("Unable to go on," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Floating</ENAMEX> point exception") and another core dump,
we called it quits. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three and a half hours</TIMEX> of help from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who makes his
living working with computers and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> to show for it.

            Why would a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> like me want to use Linux? The first
reason is price. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is free if you download it off the Web. With a manual
and a CD it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $40</NUMEX>. Compare that with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Windows 98</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$199</NUMEX> for a full setup,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$89</NUMEX> for an upgrade, or bundled for "free" as part of nearly every non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>
computer. I didn't investigate running Windows software under a Linux
Windows-emulator, mostly because I already have Windows on my system to run
Windows software. I also didn't attach my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Linux</ENAMEX> machine to the company
network--because I couldn't find easy instructions in my books, and further
consultations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helpdesk</ENAMEX> would have been cheating. I'm fairly certain
that setting up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX> is easy, but I'm taking the word of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> on
this.

            Either I'm not ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX> isn't
ready for me. Or both. I feel guilty about having used not one but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> manuals
to install <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linux</ENAMEX>, and worse still that I couldn't make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> work. I feel
malignantly guilty about having paid cash money for a free operating system and
for enlisting both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helpdesk</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in my endeavor. Yes, I finished
the marathon, but I did it by putting on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roller skates</ENAMEX> and grabbing the
suspenders of those who knew what they were doing.

         
      
   
