
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardball High School</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> satire rarely
comes more winning than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election</TIMEX> , an exuberantly caustic comedy that
shows the symbiotic relationship between political go-get-'em-ism and moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">backsliding</ENAMEX>. That's hardly a new theme, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Payne</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Ruth</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preston Sturges</ENAMEX>-like gift for going against
the grain of his own cynicism, so that the movie fairly drips with irony
without ever losing its raffish energy or its sense of wonder. It feels
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">miraculously</ENAMEX> fresh.

            
               Election
unfolds in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neb.</ENAMEX>, high school, where its go-getter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Flick</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witherspoon</ENAMEX>), mounts a tireless run for presidency of the student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>.
Flick's name is clearly an hommage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Glick</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> hustler
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budd Schulberg</ENAMEX>'s classic portrait of '30s ambition, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Makes Sammy</ENAMEX>
Run
               ? Glick was viewed through the eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Manheim</ENAMEX>, a jaded
lefty alcoholic who regarded this new species of capitalist human with contempt
but also with awe: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of nature. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Manheim</ENAMEX> of
Election is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McAllister</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Broderick</ENAMEX>), who watches
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>'s hand shoot up in class and can't bring himself to call on her. Her
know-it-all persona makes him sick, and without fully realizing what he's
doing, he sets about trying to sabotage her candidacy.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">achievers</ENAMEX>--call them carpe diem -ists--have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and passion and deserve to rise, but many are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> without payloads.
That's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>. Friendless, encased in a hothouse terrarium of her own ambition,
she has no goals beyond furthering her own career. At the same time, there's
something maddeningly attractive about her: She's a hot little number. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Payne</ENAMEX>
freezes on her face at its most nauseatingly self-congratulatory, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McAllister</ENAMEX> recalls (in voice-over narration) how his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Novotny</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Harelik</ENAMEX>), initiated a wildly destructive affair with
her and got himself booted out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and his marriage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX> grew up
without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Camp</ENAMEX>) whose hobby was writing to
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and asking how they did it. In class, her legs cross primly
under her desk while her hand snaps up like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sieg Heil</ENAMEX> . When she stamps
out "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Flick</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>" buttons on her hand-operated button press, she
sets her big jaw and grits her teeth and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> down as if eliminating her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> with every squeeze. The cogs in her brain turn feverishly. Scanning a
rival's nominating petition, she seizes instantly on an unfamiliar name: "Who's
he? I've never heard of him."

            
               Election will
make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witherspoon</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> came into her own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Freeway</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">B-movie Red Riding Hood</ENAMEX> story that was a little too campily
self-conscious for its own credibility. But its central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX>, in which the
runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX>-park teen climbs into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> driven by a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> (Kiefer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutherland</ENAMEX>), made for a ghoulishly amusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">psychodrama</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witherspoon</ENAMEX>'s
mixture of soulfulness and incorrigibility was enchanting. She's OK playing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX> , but she goes into the comic
stratosphere when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have a mighty will--when she can use that
steel jaw and laser-light delivery. Announcing that "the weak always try to
sabotage the strong," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX> instantly sizes up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broderick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAllister</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
work magically well together. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broderick</ENAMEX> provoked a lot of nasty reviews in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), but it wasn't his fault that his worried wiseguy act
came to embody everything that was lightweight and fatuously noncommittal about
that awful movie. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election</TIMEX> , he has his first fully rounded grown-up
role, and he's perfect: He makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s anguish absurdly funny without
caricaturing the pain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broderick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAllister</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who wakes up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and
realizes he's grown and has nothing to show for it. Stuck in a sexless and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">childless</ENAMEX> marriage (he retreats to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> to watch porn tapes) and
presented with a certainty--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>'s election--he makes the fatal decision to
fight the power. He picks his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, a sweet, injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metzler</ENAMEX> (the delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Klein</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> so unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX> that he can't even
bring himself to check off his own name on the ballot.

            E lection is scaled small. Working from a trim novel
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Perrotta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payne</ENAMEX> and co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Taylor</ENAMEX> don't squander their resources
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> or parades or elaborate spoofs of ceremony, the way most political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">satires</ENAMEX> tend to do. Nor do they feign an understanding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>, in this
case a student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> that seems uninterested in which of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> ends up
getting a job that usually consists of planning the prom. They keep the focus
narrow, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. But each private act has rippling and tumultuous
public consequences. The geometry of the movie becomes dizzying. When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">girlfriend</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie Ingrassia</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>) has a bout of homosexual panic and throws herself at the unwitting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jock</ENAMEX>, the vindictive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tammy</ENAMEX> jumps into the race as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, adopting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nihilist</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Cares?</ENAMEX>" platform that nearly sandbags the whole election. And
through some weird <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">transference</ENAMEX> (displaced lust for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>?), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McAllister</ENAMEX> becomes
fixated on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Novotny</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delaney Driscoll</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of his exiled best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>. His desperate attempts to bed her make him reckless and seal his doom:
Stung by a wasp outside her window, he staggers into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>
with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> as swollen and saggy as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quasimodo's</ENAMEX>--and morally hunchbacked, to
boot.

            It's difficult not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overpraise Election</ENAMEX> : It's perfect. Some will complain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAllister</ENAMEX>'s
slapstick-tragic lust for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> shifts the focus too much from the campaign to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>, but the movie means to be more than a study of electoral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">machinations</ENAMEX>. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>' glib Primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colors</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), which
seized every opportunity to take cheap shots at its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payne</ENAMEX> seizes
every opportunity to give his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> more dimension. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX> comes upon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> at a table, gathering signatures for his nominating petition, she responds
with cold fury, but she also scrawls her name on his sheet--a complex, defiant,
irreducible gesture. And when she glimpses defeat, her pain is truly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heartbreaking</ENAMEX>. She curls herself up in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s lap and weeps with the
agony of the empty. That's what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Election</ENAMEX> so much more insightful
than Primary Colors : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX> isn't fatted and self-satisfied like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>'
version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. She's insatiable because the hunger to succeed is what
formed her. She has no self to deform.

            I'll try not to eviscerate the laughably dour
eXistenZ , a virtual-reality guessing game of a thriller in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Cronenberg, evidently licking his wounds over the calamitous receptions of
Crash (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Butterfly</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naked Lunch</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>),
goes back to the terrain he once profitably mined in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scanners</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Videodrome</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronenberg</ENAMEX>'s early movies were somber but had
horrific metaphors that ate into the mind, and he showed signs in The
Fly (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead Ringers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>) of actually developing a sense of
humor to complement his paranoid-gynecologist's vision. But eXistenZ is
a return to the lugubrious. It's named for a virtual-reality game that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> play with "biopods"--living disk drives that plug into vaginal holes
at the base of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s spines. (The only time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronenberg</ENAMEX> seems to be having
fun in the film is when he's exploring these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squishy</ENAMEX> openings.) As the game's
ingenious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>, hunted by militant "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">realists</ENAMEX>" who want to stamp out virtual
reality, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Jason Leigh</ENAMEX> is just the kind of drudge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronenberg</ENAMEX> doesn't need. Trying to underact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, she still can't walk
across a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> without looking self-conscious, and the rest of the performances
(by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jude Law</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Holm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem Dafoe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Eccleston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don McKellar</ENAMEX>)
are so terrible that it's hard to know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronenberg</ENAMEX> wants to signal that
much of what we're seeing isn't "real" or he has just forgotten how to write
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hemoglobular flesh vessels</ENAMEX>--i.e., human beings.

         
      
   
