
   
   
      
         
            Wake Up, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               and 
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               ,
May <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
cover story on the future of technology forecasts a post-PC
world where household appliances are connected to the Internet and each other.
Your sprinkler will check with the weather service before it waters the lawn,
your refrigerator will order more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> when your carton expires, and your
toilet will test your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> and notify your health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> when
you're out of sorts. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, by contrast, envisions a
PC-plus future , where the PC will remain the primary
computing tool but will be integrated with other smart devices.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover package on troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> includes a poll showing that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> were evacuated from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because of post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>
bomb threats. A piece argues that smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> might be an antidote to the
gargantuan high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> anonymously drift into deep trouble
and despair.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has approved a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> plan to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">destabilize Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> will be
trained to commit acts of sabotage such as cutting telephone wires, ruining gas
reserves, and launching cyberattacks against secret bank accounts where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has stowed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>, presumably pilfered from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says that
evangelical youth gained a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooters</ENAMEX> killed Cassie
Bernall as she affirmed her faith in God. Post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>, campus <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> are
more organized and energized about their evangelizing.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story recounts the story of a black <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> hero
later refused re-enlistment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> because of trumped-up charges of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> activity. He was posthumously awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Medal of Honor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, but his family still awaits an apology. ... A piece describes the fervent campaigning for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
straw poll. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Underdog Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are seizing it as their
chance for a breakthrough. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frontrunner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> faces a dilemma: If
he participates, he risks losing to the social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who dominate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
straw polls; if he skips the poll, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowans</ENAMEX> may spurn him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>'s
all-important caucuses. ... Parents are abandoning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA</ENAMEX> in droves for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that are more local and hard-hitting, says a report . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA</ENAMEX>'s reformist mandate--it pioneered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>,
hot lunches, and kindergartens--has degenerated into mere boosterism.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>
            

            The
magazine gleefully anticipates a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>: "It feels like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidy for wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>."
... In a piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ingmar Bergman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film director</ENAMEX>
attributes both his psychologically probing cinematic style and his tumultuous
love life to his emotionally frigid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. ... An article defends Chai
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ling</ENAMEX>, who led the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> protests and now runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Internet
start-up, from charges of selling out and, more gravely, of guiding the
protests with naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremism</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover package forecasts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s electoral strategy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece says the veep
is likely to take credit for wiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> to the Internet--even
though this wiring is subsidized by a "universal service charge" on everyone's
phone bill. Another article admits that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX> is a political asset but
warns darkly of her agenda. She appears to be an apolitical soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, but
she's actually a liberal do-gooder and her advocacy of mental-health issues
threatens to increase health-care costs for most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. ... The
Standard rejects the line that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-designate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summers</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> clone. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summers</ENAMEX> believes in lots of

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story protests the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s failure to hike
interest rates despite early signs of inflation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s laxity is
encouraging "speculative excesses." Since higher interest rates take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to
restrain economic expansion, postponing a hike is like waiting "to brake a
runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> until it is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few feet</NUMEX> from the cliff's edge." (For a dissent, see
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s .) ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> instructs new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> "to
note what the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> did and do the opposite." <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> priorities:
negotiating deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. ... An editorial berates the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s proposal to
eliminate trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for several crimes including theft and weapons
possession. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> asserted that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> demand jury
trials "for no good reason other than to delay proceedings.")

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s senatorial
run would harm <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> whether she won or lost. She would "divert resources
from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, politicize their races in ways that don't play well
beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX>, and become a rallying point for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> still
itching to exploit anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sentiment," thus thwarting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> efforts
nationwide. ... The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB "</ENAMEX> column tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> not to fret over the rising cost of
health care. The expenditures are worth it because the care they fund is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">state-of-the-art</ENAMEX>, and nothing's more important than health.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23</TIMEX>
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> visits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> of the bloodthirsty, hyper-realistic, and immensely
popular video games blamed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> shootings. They are indifferent to
charges of inciting violence ("Why would I care about that?" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sniffs).
... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> criticizes the editing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s soon-to-be published unfinished novel. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s manuscript was more
convoluted draft than coherent novel. The radical surgery performed by his
literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executor</ENAMEX> may have removed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s vision from the work. ... A
piece alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s services for the mentally ill have
deteriorated under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>. An example of the tragic
consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>'s neglect: A demented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, refused care by several
overcrowded health care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, recently killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> by pushing her
under a subway <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>. 

         
      
   
