
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>

            The
relationship between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pablo Picasso</ENAMEX> is the subject
of a new exhibition at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kimbell Art Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Matisse and Picasso: A Gentle Rivalry</ENAMEX>." The theme of this show, and of the
book that accompanies it by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yve-Alain Bois</ENAMEX>, is that
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of modern painting were playing a kind of chess game all their
lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX>, the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, was constantly trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>'s
attention by showing off, stealing from his work, and rudely parodying him.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>, envious of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s success, tried to ignore him until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> when
he needed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s influence to bring himself out of an artistic funk. After
that they traded paintings, visits, and little notes. But they were too
competitive to really be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bois</ENAMEX> takes
this implication of this creative tension quite far enough. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Matisse-Picasso</ENAMEX>
rivalry is more than just the great artistic competition of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. It's a scheme for dividing all art into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts. Side by side, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> can look amazingly similar. Yet at a deeper level, they
are fundamentally, radically incompatible. Although it's possible to admire
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, something impels you to choose sides. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>,
everyone is either a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Matisse person</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> is a cool, calm, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Picasso</ENAMEX>
is a hot, temperamental <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spaniard</ENAMEX>. Matisse famously said that a painting should
be like a comfortable armchair. His paintings are harmonious, luxurious, and
soothing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX> can virtually copy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> tableau without producing
anything like the same effect. In his rendition, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> on a pedestal
contains an element of dissonance, disturbance, and even violence. Where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> is sensuous, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> is sexual. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matisse</ENAMEX> loves fabric. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picasso</ENAMEX> loves
flesh.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> seems like a
version of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> drawn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedrich Nietzsche</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Birth of Tragedy</ENAMEX>
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollonian</ENAMEX> and Dionysian art. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollonian</ENAMEX> comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> god
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>, the god of light, who was associated with rationality and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subspecialties</ENAMEX> law, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, and philosophy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysian</ENAMEX> comes from
Dionysius, the god of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and fertility, who was worshipped with drunken
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orgies</ENAMEX> in the woods at which nonparticipants were ripped to pieces. The
Apollonian spirit is one of measure, reason, and control; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysian</ENAMEX> is one
of abandon, irrationality, and ecstatic release. The clash between the two
principles was what produced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> tragedy, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nietzsche</ENAMEX>. That
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> is essentially an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Apollonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso a Dionysian</ENAMEX> is evident
even from the backhanded compliments they paid each other. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> called
Picasso "capricious and unpredictable." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>'s paintings
as "beautiful and elegant."

            In dividing all art into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nietzsche</ENAMEX> rendered
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of coming up with one of the great intellectual parlor games of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> love to devise variations for their fields. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Martin</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costume Institute</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, divides the world into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giorgio Armani</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX>, with
his serene, muted tones and clean lines, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>. The late
Versace, with his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> colors, outrageous impracticality, and explicit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexuality</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysian</ENAMEX>. And it's true: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX> ads look like
Greek statues. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Versace</ENAMEX> ads, they look like drugged bacchants. The Apollonian
spirit is about good taste, elegance, and beauty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysian</ENAMEX> mixes bad taste
with good taste, pain with pleasure.

            You can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apply Nietzsche</ENAMEX>'s dichotomy to just about any set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> or creative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, you might start with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX>,
the scientific rationalist and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX>, is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollonian</ENAMEX> (his work is owned
by, among others, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archrationalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, though he
worked principally in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollonian</ENAMEX> medium of marble, expresses a more
animalistic violence and passion (work owned by the pope). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Rothko</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> type. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Pollock</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> type. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, with their
well-crafted melodies, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollonians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stones</ENAMEX>, darker, more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subterranean</ENAMEX>, and with a deeper rhythm section, are more in touch with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysius</ENAMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dionysians</ENAMEX> have sympathy for the devil. You might like both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bands</ENAMEX>, but ultimately you're with one or the other. You're either a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stones person</ENAMEX>, just like you're either a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Matisse person</ENAMEX> or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Picasso person</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> literature, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Rahv</ENAMEX> devised the classic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories in a famous essay titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Paleface and Redskin</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> were either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europeanized</ENAMEX>, literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimps</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX>, or
celebrants of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native animalistic spirits</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Twain</ENAMEX>. The Apollonian
line begins with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Irving</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysian</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fenimore Cooper</ENAMEX>.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> column we find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Dickinson</ENAMEX>. Opposite
her, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dionysius-Picasso-Versace-Stones</ENAMEX> column, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Whitman</ENAMEX>. Nathaniel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawthorne</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Melville</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>. In the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, we come to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>) vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>) vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>, who wrote a biography of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX>.

            You can, in fact, apply the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> to just about
any natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pairing</ENAMEX> and then use that pairing to redivide the world. (Of course
you can. Who's going to arrest you?) I've been soliciting examples from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, and random <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> showoffs. To see
some of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>, . And you can play too: Send suggestions by e-mail to
browser@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> . Check , where we will post <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> pairings
that meet or surpass our (pretty low) standards.

         
      
   
