
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excuses</ENAMEX>, Excuses

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, after finally admitting to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that he had carried on and covered up an inappropriate relationship with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> went on national TV to apologize. He began
by calling his behavior "wrong" and taking "complete responsibility" for it.
But within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tarnished his apology by lapsing into excuses,
self-justifications, and blame-shifting. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, as he tries to explain
thing.

            How
did the bombing happen? According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
"attacked the wrong target because the bombing instructions were based on an
outdated map," which "inaccurately located the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in a different part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>." Henceforth, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> will report to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> whenever foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> move." In other words, people
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> who knew the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> had moved hadn't bothered to tell
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who were deciding which <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. There's nothing for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to say about this except that we perpetrated a moral outrage
through inexcusable stupidity and recklessness. But as usual, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
finding plenty of other things to say.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) I've already apologized. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, when asked to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apologize</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> repeatedly insisted that he had already done so. But saying
you have already apologized is the opposite of apologizing. The latter is a way
of accepting criticism; the former is a way of deflecting it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, in his
initial remarks about the bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> expressed "regret" and "condolences"
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> but never used the word "apologize." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, he declared, "I
have already expressed our apology." When asked about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> responsibility
for the tragedy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
Department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Rubin</ENAMEX> reiterated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had already
"apologized."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) My actions were minimal. In his speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
used weasel words and passive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">verbs</ENAMEX> to minimize his deceit. "While my answers
were legally accurate, I did not volunteer information," he allowed. "My public
comments and my silence about this matter gave a false impression." To minimize
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called it a "mistake," "accident," and
"tragic event" (other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> called it "regrettable" and an "error"
entailing "loss of life"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used the passive voice to obscure his
responsibility ("the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> was inadvertently damaged and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lost
their lives") and offered good intentions as an excuse ("We're doing everything
that we can to avoid innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian casualties</ENAMEX>").

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Everybody does it. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> smothered questions
about his adultery by confessing to "causing pain in my marriage," refusing to
say more, and pointing out that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> were in a similar
position. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX> speech, he offered the same defense. Likewise,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that in war the occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing is to be
expected. "This will happen if you drop this much [ordnance]," he argued
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> echoed that line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> ("In combat, accidents will happen"),
as did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Mistakes happen"</ENAMEX>).

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It's the economy, stupid. Unable to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> that he was truly sorry for offending their values, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> appealed
instead to their material interests, vowing incessantly to "keep working for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, having bombed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
making a similar appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s prudence. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, he reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> of
his "commitment to strengthen our relationship," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> and Lockhart
emphasized that "good relations are manifestly in the interest of both nations"
and that "a broad-based relationship ... serves both our interests."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) It's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>'s fault. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ruined his speech last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> by blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for forcing him to shade the
truth to fend off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation, which had "gone on too long, cost too
much, and hurt too many innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> again buried his
apology under a recitation of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>'s wrongs. He even used the same
word--"proportion"--to deflect scrutiny. "We need some sense of proportion" in
evaluating the bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pleaded. "This was an isolated, tragic event,
while the ethnic cleansing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> ... is a deliberate and systematic crime."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> reasserted that distinction, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bacon</ENAMEX> pointed out that the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> started
the fight: "This was not a fight that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> sought. It was a fight that could
have been avoided, but Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> decided not to avoid it."

            It's
true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' crimes dwarf <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s in scale and malice. It's true that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s financial interests are best served by stifling its anger. It's true
that wars always cause unintended civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>. It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is
trying to avoid such casualties. And it's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has apologized.
These are all perfectly good spins. But the point of an apology is to accept
responsibility for what you did and otherwise to shut up. To apologize, in
short, is to abstain from spin--one of the few feats of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seems
incapable.

            
               Photograph on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX> of
Contents by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sasa Stankovic/AFP</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
