
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Missoula Winter: the Thaw, the Ice Floes</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX><BR>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mountain</ENAMEX> and hill shall be brought low.
In the middle of its long white sleep,
our world begins to thaw. Streets flood.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> around the house
goes to water
which finds its own level
in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement lodging</ENAMEX>. I lug
wet rugs up stairs that lead
to the world of air, up and down
the steps I go, dragging sodden things
to light. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX> on the news they show
ice floes moving like dreamships
up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Fork</ENAMEX>, silent and serene,
knocking out <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, destroying homes
along the verge. A boy
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>, track star goofing
with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> at river's edge, slips he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">falls</ENAMEX> in and she watches him carried away
in silence, arms outstretched like wings, not
a word or sound or sign of struggle:

Neither could I move or scream, the cold
was everything, it owned us, only our eyes
were free once the rapids had him
and we locked gazes then, as if seeing
            

            
               could save us, as if
it were believing.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> our world has turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> again
and the search for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is called off.
Everything hardens. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> underground
I imagine him nearby somewhere, long limbs
caught quickfrozen in a runner's pose,
fingers reaching, hard as marble-- I am
poured out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O Lord</ENAMEX>, poured
out like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> --<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> I dream him
in that posture of longing, held
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">stilled</ENAMEX> beneath the motion
and the industry, the unimaginable
weight of our living world.

         
      
   
