
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Abort
Face
            

            What is especially enjoyable about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party's agony over abortion is that the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> lights are almost
surely pro-choice in their hearts. Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, but
they're not the ones doing the agonizing. The agonizers are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, and their agony isn't moral, goodness knows.
It's political: How to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s hard-line pro-life stance from
driving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> away.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> and the rest all claim to share the
hard-line anti-abortion view, as they must in order to be leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
lights in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. But who believes them? Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX> really think
abortion is equivalent to infanticide? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. mourning</ENAMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>? Not likely. So they must pretend to a deep moral
belief they probably don't have, then pretend to have come up with a reason
this deep moral belief shouldn't really matter. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> might have
trouble executing this double-reverse flip-flop fib off the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. Are
lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> up to it?

            The official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> position on abortion, as expressed
in the past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>, is so extreme that if it were taken seriously,
no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> could be elected to any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> except, perhaps, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>. Fortunately
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are aware of it, fewer still understand it, and those
who do understand it assume correctly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> doesn't really mean
it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> reads: "The
infringed. We support a human life amendment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and we endorse
legislation to make clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment</ENAMEX>'s protections apply to
unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">14 th Amendment</ENAMEX> guarantees all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> "the
equal protection of the laws." If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">14 th Amendment</ENAMEX>, an abortion must be treated exactly like the
premeditated killing of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>--that is, like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree murder. There can
be no exceptions for rape or incest. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who procures an abortion is
guilty of murder just as if she had hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> to kill her born offspring.
In a death penalty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> platform favors the death penalty,
naturally--she must pay with her life.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> platform goes
on to say, "we have only compassion" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who procure abortions and "our
pro-life agenda does not include punitive action" against them. Which only
shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> does not even believe itself, since that stuff about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">14 th Amendment</ENAMEX> can have no other meaning.

            But the current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> position is logically
consistent. If full human life begins at conception, then full human rights do
too, including the right to equal protection of the laws. It is a concept that
does not easily lend itself to compromise, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> are demonstrating. Their search for a way out has led most of them
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rhetorical strategies.

            One is the notion the
late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Atwater</ENAMEX> called "the big tent." There's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for everybody. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>
says about the abortion issue, "I believe we are an inclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and we can
be so without changing our principles." What does this mean? Does it mean that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should feel free to vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> even if they disagree with what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> stands for? A nice offer, though I wouldn't expect many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">takers</ENAMEX>. Or does it mean that because there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to divvy up, the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> needn't stand for anything in particular? Not a big vote-getter
either.

            Asked about abortion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX> also invoked what is apparently the
party-line phrase: "inclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>." He elaborated, "We want to reach out and
grow this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. ...We're recognizing that there are differences. This is a
huge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It's a continent really. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270 million</NUMEX> of us, and there
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. So why wouldn't we have some differences?"

            It's surely true that it
would be suicidal for a party to demand agreement on all issues from either its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> or its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. The tricky question is what are the core values that
really define you and what are the fringe issues on which differences are not
crucial. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would prefer not to be defined by their position on
abortion. But if you take it seriously, the anti-abortion position is
definitive by definition. How can you make the capital gains tax a litmus test
issue but say that the slaughter of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is something
about which you have only a mild preference and don't care much if people
disagree? The truth is that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> don't actually take their
alleged position on abortion seriously. But they can't admit this.

            The other rhetorical way out for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> is
to say that you yourself are as hard-core as ever, but since a majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> apparently disagrees, there's no point in trying to do anything about
it it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> goes further: There's no point in even discussing it.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> she called on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to "set an example" and "refuse to be
drawn into dead-end debates" about something that is "not going to happen."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>, sounding like a very promising cross between his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, explained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> why he opposes pushing for a constitutional
amendment, although he favors one himself: "There are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who
don't view the abortion issue as a matter of life. I do. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why
I'm a pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."

            This is an imaginative
attempt to dress craven pragmatism as high principle, but it makes no sense.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> are littered with proposals that are
"not going to happen." Almost nothing is going to happen if a majority must
already favor it before any political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> will speak out in its favor. If
she actually believed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of human lives were at stake, the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> surely wouldn't try to build a holy crusade around
refusal to discuss the matter. Nor would she blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for an "inordinate
focus" on the issue.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>'s way out is worth noting, though it
doesn't rise to the level of illogic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> says that we should "move
state-by-state to change laws and culture so there will be fewer abortions,"
and therefore "I do not support a constitutional amendment that would overturn
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> ." Well, you see, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> held that state
anti-abortion laws are unconstitutional. That's what it was all about!
Maybe--to give him the extreme benefit of the doubt--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> means that he favors
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overturning Roe</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision rather than by constitutional
amendment. This is an unlikely occurrence and, combined with the state-by-state
business, a rather leisurely approach if you honestly believe that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slaughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX> is going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>.

            Finally, since the subject is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, logic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jurisprudence</ENAMEX>, and advanced metaphysical speculation, you're probably wondering
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> comes down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> agrees with everybody else that a
constitutional amendment is not going to happen. "But that's not
important . The important issue is where you stand on this
important debate. I have always been pro-life." In other words, as long as you
murder, it's not important whether you actually do anything about it.

            This is, of course, a truer statement of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> position on abortion than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s. But it is more than
that. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> may actually have produced a compromise in what seemed to be a war
of moral absolutes. Speaking, if I may, for the pro-choice side of the debate:
Pro-lifers may profess any principles they care to, as long as they agree not
to act on them. They can actually believe what they say, for all I care. Though
I doubt, in the case of most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, that this last
concession will be necessary.

         
      
   
