
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>

            Each of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s big art
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">museums</ENAMEX> has its own, distinct personality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> is a noisy extrovert
that craves attention. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> is deep, mysterious, and aloof--it takes years
to really get to know it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> is a bit vain, justifiably so. The oddball of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>, which suffers from an
institutional version of bipolar disorder. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> it shouts obscenities in
your face. The next it's calm nearly to the point of affectlessness.

            Lately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> has
been taking its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>, in the form of new management. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ross</ENAMEX>, who left to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> created a glittery uptown showcase
for exhibitions of political and conceptual art that often took the form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whirring</ENAMEX> installations and blurry videos. The most notorious of these was "The
Black Male in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Art</ENAMEX>," at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> were handed buttons reading "I
Can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imagine Ever Wanting to be White</ENAMEX>." This was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> that so angered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX> that one of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weeklies</ENAMEX> used to run ads for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney</ENAMEX>-shaped trash can. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>, run by a dapper fuddy-duddy named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell Anderson</ENAMEX>, who came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Art Gallery</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, is just the
opposite in almost every respect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is traditional,
art-history-minded, and eager to ingratiate itself with, rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flabbergast</ENAMEX> and dumbfound, up- and out-of-towners.

            The distillation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>'s new sedateness is "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Century</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> and Culture <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900-1950</TIMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half</TIMEX> of a millennial
survey scheduled to occupy the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next eight months</TIMEX>. Drawing
heavily on works in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s permanent collection, some of which are rarely
displayed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s first attempt at a blockbuster eschews political
correctness, offers no historical revisionism, and even includes work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX> without quotation marks. It is a bland, textbook summary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
culture that eschews any explicit judgments at all for fear someone might
disagree. Broad surveys don't have to be dull. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> series and
book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Visions</ENAMEX> managed to cover a much longer stretch of artistic
waterfront with verve, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>, and erudition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> show, by contrast,
makes no sense out of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art or culture. It merely drowns us in it.

            The phrase "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>" was the coinage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Luce</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> declared the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
"the intellectual, scientific, and artistic capital of the world." The first
question asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> in his introduction to the exhibition catalog is
whether Luce was right when it came to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art. How does the art created
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX> stack up against that created by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>? But having raised this issue, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The American Century"</ENAMEX> never gets
around to proposing an answer. It's as if such a massive assemblage is supposed
to speak for itself. Actually, this exhibition does make a clear statement, but
I don't think it's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> intended. The message is: basta !

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 700</NUMEX> works on display here, including
not only paintings, drawings, sculptures, and photographs but also sheet music,
music playing in the stairwells, clips from movies, movie posters, novels,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">furniture</ENAMEX>, design objects, architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, and stills from dance
programs, plays, operas, and musicals. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> presents this haul
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chronologically</ENAMEX>. After finally getting through the line and into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> get a brief orientation on the ground floor, take the elevator to the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> floor, and work their way back down.

            By the time they reached
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX>, on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> were exhibiting the dead-eyed
stares of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dust Bowl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker Evans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothea Lange</ENAMEX>
photographs on the walls. By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>, it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bataan</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> were collapsing on benches with advanced cases of art
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prostration</ENAMEX>. The last section of the exhibition--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionism</ENAMEX>--was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly</NUMEX> empty, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> having surrendered. To see this show at a brisk
clip--say <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX> per object, and ignoring the banal wall text--would
require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> visits. To curate is to choose, and by failing
to do so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> has abdicated its essential responsibility.

            Nor does "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The American Century</ENAMEX>" divide up this motherlode
in any thoughtful or even coherent way. The top floor, covering the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
decades of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, begins with works that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Eakins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singer Sargent</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus Saint-Gaudens</ENAMEX>,
happened to produce after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>. It ends with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man Ray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel Duchamp</ENAMEX>, never
having given you much sense of how the vast distance from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX> A to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Point B</ENAMEX>
was covered. While <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>) do stand as a plausibly
distinct "era" in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>) and the 1940s
(<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>) don't. The various forms of politically driven realism that
flourished during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> continued to dominate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art through the
end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York School</ENAMEX> of abstraction, which became
predominant after the war, was near its apex, not its end, by the arbitrary
cutoff date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>. If you're going to bundle art into packages, they should
at least be tidy. And what's the sense of imposing a rigid and arbitrary
deadline on the exhibition and then decorating the cover of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> catalog
with one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jasper Johns</ENAMEX>' flag paintings from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>?

            By shoveling so much in,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Haskell</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> who put together the exhibition, seems to
be trying to build a case that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half</TIMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> was up to the standard of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> art. But for me, the
exhibition vindicated the conventional view that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art can't hold a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">candle</ENAMEX> to what was happening overseas until after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. When you look
at the early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> modernists such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsden Hartley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Dove</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stella</ENAMEX>, you see inventive and delightful things. But you
can't compare these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>, such as Pablo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georges Braque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piet Mondrian, Amedeo Modigliani</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustav Klimt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egon Schiele</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wassily Kandinsky</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasimir Malevich</ENAMEX>. Or maybe
you can, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> doesn't try. It is content to examine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modernists</ENAMEX> in relation to their far less interesting domestic contemporaries
and a broad cultural context that seems mostly irrelevant to their work. This
approach may not make you homesick for the tendentiousness of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>.
But it's an only slightly preferable alternative.

            So, what should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> have done for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>?
I'm not sure a modern art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> needs to celebrate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> at all. But one better possibility would have been a real
examination of how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> in art did finally turn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> by way of
various attempts to absorb <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> influences without being smothered by them.
The raw material for that show is all here. Walking through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, you
glimpse a series of moments when an art both new and distinctly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
appears. One was around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Strand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Schamberg</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheeler</ENAMEX> rejected the gauzy pictorialism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Stieglitz</ENAMEX> for a
cubist-inspired photography that also had a documentary purpose. Another,
related, bright spot was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1920s'</NUMEX> movement that has come to be called
Precisionism, which celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> industrialism as a new religion
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheeler</ENAMEX> called one of his paintings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> My
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> ). And, finally, the greatest and most distinctively <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> modern
school was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionism</ENAMEX>, which blossomed after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snipped</ENAMEX> in mid-bloom by the end of the exhibition.

            Another way to do it would have been a look at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> itself. Such a show might have opened with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Henri</ENAMEX>
portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney</ENAMEX> included here and brought many of the
same paintings she collected out of the vault for a fresh look. But such a show
would have meant the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> taking a hard look at its own, often controversial
part in the art world. And I don't get the sense that's something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>,
or its conciliatory new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, is very eager to do.

         
      
   
