
   
   
      
         
            <EM>Glasnost</EM> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> reported "strong irritation" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX> over the
arrangements for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. It quoted a source in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schroeder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> as saying: "We must make it clear to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> is here." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in a front-page report that as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late as Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> still hasn't provided <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX> with a proper
presidential timetable. Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uwe-Karsten Heye</ENAMEX> has frequently
used the word "chaos" to describe the situation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. Die
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welt</ENAMEX> 's main lead was about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s decision to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> to help with humanitarian relief.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a sudden
volte-face by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> on the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> would accept. After being criticized, especially by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, for
only accepting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">330</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> so far (compared with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,800</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,354</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,166</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>), the government
announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from now</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> would be flown
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> called the
decision "overdue"; the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> crisis
has been "slow and niggardly." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> 's front-page lead,
headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Terror of the Twisters</ENAMEX>," was about the tornadoes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>.

            The refugee crisis also dominated the main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
papers, which led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has decided to take in
another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from the overcrowded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>. To prevent
them dispersing throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> peninsula, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> of them would be
sheltered at the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> base of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comiso</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sicily</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX> reported. "Bad has been turned into good," the paper commented on its
front page. "The instruments of death have been replaced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ones</NUMEX> of survival."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> published a brief front-page comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nadine Gordimer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Prize-winning South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>, deploring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> offensive "because it
doesn't bring a solution to the horrors committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>." "But the
terrifying aspect of the problem is that so many of us who believe this don't
have any other solution to propose," she added.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led not on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> but on a
domestic political crisis resulting from the jailing for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> history of a prefect (provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corsica</ENAMEX>. The prefect,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Bonnet</ENAMEX>, who was sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>'s island by the socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lionel Jospin</ENAMEX> to impose law and order on unruly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corsican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>,
is alleged to have ordered his police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to burn down a beach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> as
an example to them. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> wants to know how much, if
anything, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jospin</ENAMEX> knew about this illegal act. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> papers led on a
politically controversial decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to commit ground
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to join an eventual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> 's second
front-page story was about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> killed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> in a safari
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alicante</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had his throat torn out, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decapitated</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led
postpone the declaration of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. It also noted his riducle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s election claim that this was his
government's achievement. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>] has no doubt in his mind that the sole
causes of this outcome were the pressures and threats that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> applied to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> and the crude hints about the possibility of annexing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">territories</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-occupying them," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial. But it pointed out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> had merely postponed the declaration and that, meanwhile, he had won
broad international support for the principle of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> statehood. He has
"surpassed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in status at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>," the editorial said, while
"<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> stands united behind him, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are only waiting for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> to send official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> papers have been telling of
"glasnost " in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> reportedly easing government
restrictions on freedom of expression and political opposition. According to a
piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has
approved a number of "specific political and security" measures to tackle the
"political and social frustrations" caused by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly nine years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
sanctions. These included a new law on "political pluralism," passed recently
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Assembly</ENAMEX>, which would allow certain "active political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>"
to hold meetings and form new political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Another was the decision to
show "various degrees of tolerance" toward public criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
government. The article was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bassam Badareeen</ENAMEX>, who reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqis</ENAMEX> were becoming more openly critical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> without
apparently fearing retribution by the secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> devoted its front-page lead and its
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> editorial to the first decline in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> of the power and influence of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> extreme right. An opinion poll conducted for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> showed
that a recent split between the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruno MÃ</ENAMEX>©gret and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Marie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Pen</ENAMEX> has greatly reduced their popular appeal. Support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Pen</ENAMEX>'s ideas has
fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. The editorial said the bitter
battle between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> has "totally destabilized" their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> who have
been raised in "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>." It has also opened the public's eyes
to "the true nature of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and their methods." Other factors in their
diminishing appeal have been their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and the economic recovery in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. In another front-page story
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> reported that, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>,
Global <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Witness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> forests are being illegally destroyed to feed the
garden furniture industry in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Chaplin</ENAMEX> has written to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto</ENAMEX>
Benigni, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar-</ENAMEX>winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful</ENAMEX> , to
thank him for reminding her of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX>, with "his elegance
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> in every little gesture, his nobility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, and, above all, his
ability to be moved." She said in an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that during the
Oscars she gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benigni</ENAMEX> the original bowler hat that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chaplin</ENAMEX> wore in The
Gold <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rush</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> gave extensive coverage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
to the putting up for sale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">35 million pounds</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $56</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>), making it, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , "the most
expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>." By grand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> standards it is relatively modest,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> reception <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, a small garden, and a
wine "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cellar</ENAMEX>" that is "actually more of a cupboard." But it is very close to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kensington Palace</ENAMEX>, where the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> lived. The sale consists of a
lease of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 99 years</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchaser</ENAMEX> will have to pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an additional 1.2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million pounds</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.9 million</NUMEX>) in taxes and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $328,000</NUMEX> in legal fees,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that raccoons imported from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> have become an ecological and agricultural "nightmare" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
Escaped or abandoned raccoons have been breeding in the wild for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and have damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>, watermelon and melon <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>, and rainbow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout hatcheries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. They have also driven native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> foxes
and gray <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herons</ENAMEX> from their natural habitats. Raccoons, particularly baby ones,
became fashionable as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> because of a popular cartoon
program on television called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Araiguma Rasukaru</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rascal the Raccoon</ENAMEX>).

         
      
   
