
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lethal Weapons</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> high-school
massacre, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposed new gun control legislation and asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to rethink the issue. "We've got to keep working until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start
thinking about this stuff the same way they think about X-rays and metal
detectors at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>," he declared at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> ceremony. "We have to
redefine the national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> so that we have a shared obligation to save
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lives." To the gun control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> in attendance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pleaded,
"You change the culture, we'll change the laws."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech was a textbook illustration of how
to use a national trauma to reframe an issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has opposed gun control
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. By changing the "culture"--i.e., the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> "think about"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firearms</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hopes to swing public opinion in favor of gun restrictions.
In the past, he observed, rural <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in terms of
hunting and the right to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. In the future, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to
think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in new terms: bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. His strategy is threefold.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-opt the "culture"
argument. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of gun control have framed the debate as a choice
between blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who abuse them. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> don't kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," goes the famous slogan. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> tend
to oppose pornography and divorce as well as gun control, they get a twofer by
attributing tragedies such as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> to a degenerating "culture."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> put out the word that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> were going to kick off a "national dialogue
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and culture" to address nongun-related causes of the massacre.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tried to neutralize the importance of
culture by acknowledging it. In her opening remarks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> invoked
prayer and religion and repeatedly charged that the "culture of violence" in
television, movies, music, video games, and the Internet "is having a profound
effect on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>" and "causes more aggression and anti-social behavior."
"We must resolve to do what we can to change that culture," she proposed. Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> claimed that several of their pet causes and projects were
ameliorating anti-social conduct: V-chips, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s television, Internet
filters, and mental health awareness. By suggesting that the cultural causes of
violence were being sufficiently addressed, they sought to shift attention and
pressure to the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. 
               Focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX>
who can't stand the idea of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> telling them what to do are usually
willing and often eager to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> impose identical restrictions on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> aimed their legislation and rhetoric at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words that should never be put
together in the same sentence," argued <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, who managed to squeeze
off countless criticisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in between her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> invocations of "our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> repeatedly drew applause as he announced proposals
to "raise the legal age of handgun possession from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 to 21 years</TIMEX>" and "prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juveniles</ENAMEX> who commit violent crimes from ever buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Equate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> with bombs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> love rights and recreation but hate crime and mayhem. The most
important element of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s strategy, therefore, is to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to
stop associating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> with hunting and self-protection and to start associating
them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> and terrorism instead. "We have a huge hunting and sport
shooting culture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> observed. But "I want to make a plea to
everybody who is waiting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next deer season</TIMEX> in my home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to think
about this in terms of what our reasonable obligations to the larger community
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> are. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX> time you get on an airplane, think about how you'd
feel if the headline in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> right before you got on the airplane
was 'Airport <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Metal Detectors and X-Ray Machines Abolished as Infringement on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Constitutional Right To Travel</ENAMEX>.' ... And right next to it there is
another headline: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Terrorist Groups Expanding Operations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.'
"

            To fortify this unorthodox analogy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>
bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and bombs together in their legislation and in their analysis on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> tragedy. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> preached against juvenile access to
"bomb-making materiel" and decried "the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>, and bombs that
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> were able to bring into their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> earned another ovation by proposing to "require Brady background checks
on anyone who wants to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>."

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> don't recognize soon how the emerging prominence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and explosives
is transforming the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s image of deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may succeed in
reshaping the debate and turning the political tide against <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> of
gun rights say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is "exploiting this tragedy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> to further his
gun control agenda." Of course he is. They're missing the point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX>
don't ban <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> with persuasive arguments ban <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
