
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I have been together for more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and married for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX>. He has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with an
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> has told me that the ex confessed to planning
the "accidental" pregnancy because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was talking of leaving her, and
she hoped it would keep him around. I was quite disturbed by this, and now more
so since a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman friend</ENAMEX> of his ex told me she has done the same thing to
another unsuspecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               I feel that someone
needs to put this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in her place but don't know if it's any of my business.
I think if I don't ... no one will. (She's a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to have mad at you, by
the way.) It just doesn't sit well with me to see another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> used in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, and another good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> being manipulated like this. For some reason I just
can't forget about this. 
               Thanks.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.T.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear J.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> understands why this issue presses your
buttons. It is not, however, your job in life to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in their places.
Another reason for butting out is that you say this latest trapper is a bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to have mad at you. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> can get knocked down, as well as up, you
know. What I mean is that by confronting this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with something that is
really none of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, you run the risk of incurring her enmity and
making yourself a target for social unpleasantness.

            There are times when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dearly</ENAMEX> held principle makes interjecting oneself acceptable: when you can
affect the outcome. In this situation, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is already trapped (and
presumably committed to child support) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is not about to undergo an
integrity makeover. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you go to the gym to work off some of this
(understandable) hostility.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, athletically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Is it proper to make your bed in a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at
the end of your stay? More to the point, is it considered impolite to not make
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bed</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               I was brought up to make the bed before leaving,
but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> say it is just more work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>--who has to strip the
sheets anyway.
            

            
               Your
thoughts?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondering</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Won</ENAMEX>,

            You have slipped a stitch somewhere. Making one's
bed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is like whipping up your own souffle in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been employed for just those purposes.

            You perhaps are confusing staying in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> with
being a guest in someone's home, where it is good manners to make your bed. The
wild card, however, is when your stay is over. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> finds it useful, and
mannerly, to ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> how they wish the bed to be left. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want
it stripped, others left as is for their housekeepers to deal with.

            Prudie applauds your
thoughtfulness, however, and is sure you are one of those considerate people
who, when ending a hotel stay, leaves a tip for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, tidily

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have been in a relationship now for about two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> with a most remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. He and I have been going through many
growth and development phases. We have realized that I am somewhat conventional
and that he is non-. The differences in our values are sometimes trivial,
sometimes important. None of the differences, however, interfere with our trust
or love. The differences have to do with issues such as saving/spending money,
independence, and socially expected behavior.
            

            
               How does one know
when you are giving, expecting, or hoping for too much? Is there an answer to
this? Thank you.
            

            

               --Questioning
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Quest</ENAMEX>,

            A lovely Zen quotation comes to mind: There is no
solution, seek it lovingly.

            Using the word
"remarkable" bodes well for your future together, as does your understanding of
your differences. There are no guarantees, of course, about how differences
will play out, so all you can do is try to look ahead and imagine if you both
will adopt the other's ways, carry on comfortably with distinct approaches, or
wind up killing each other.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, philosophically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               How should young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> address <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>? My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I believe that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">or Mrs.</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> are in order. For very close
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, perhaps "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt" or "Uncle</ENAMEX>." Most of our (yuppie) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> call my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and me by our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names. Not a big deal, but we think this
is a bad example for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. What do you say?
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear E.</ENAMEX>,

            As a rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should address <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in the
manner in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> ask to be addressed or, alternatively, in the way in
which their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> instruct them. The real example for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> ought
to be what is comfortable and polite. With luck, they are the same thing. It
sounds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> as though you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> are a little more formal than
the times. Perhaps you might take a social inventory of who is calling whom
what in your circle and then make a standard ruling for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. If,
however, you are seriously unhappy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> calling their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> by
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names, no one could take affront with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt" or "Mrs.</ENAMEX>" form of
address. It might make your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> stand out, however.

            As you said, not a big
deal.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
conversationally

         
      
   
