
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">221</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;No Carrying On&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fill in the blank on this comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Wiggins</ENAMEX>, jubilant
over the voting on a new proposal: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Missourians</ENAMEX> do not want __________ carried
into football games and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>."
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 220</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sticks and Stones":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 The list includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>, fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX>, and hordes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>.
List of
what?
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "The
'Important Numbers' section in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day Runner</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheft</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cass</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "Things
that 'do it' in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX>'s wisely discarded first draft."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
residents who had premarital sex."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Pascover</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
don't expect you to believe me, but they're all thanked on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX> Chicks
CD."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            "All
the cute, available <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Shuger</ENAMEX>
            

             

             

             

             

             

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            It is instinctive to reject a patriotic list of
Official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enemies</ENAMEX>. The more these authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> are shot at in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone-Schwartzenegger-Willis</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX> movies, the more one wants to be a drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> or terrorist when he grows up. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> does glamorize everything.
(Except maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Fishburne</ENAMEX>--what was he rambling on about in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX> ? I dozed a bit there.)

            It is harder to rebuff a national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> list when
bombs are falling, particularly when those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> are implicated in appalling
deeds. It might, however, be possible to resist the grossest forms of jingoism.
Consider how badly certain <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> songs have aged--"I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Going To Slap</ENAMEX>
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Little Jap</ENAMEX>." And those wartime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> cartoons where Bugs
Bunny battles grotesque caricatures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>--they don't quite hold
up.

            So how to prevent outrage
at human suffering from tilting toward vile stereotyping? One guideline: The
more that anchormen get all huffy, the more you must be on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
Rather reaches for the adjectives, be careful out there.

            
               Demonizing
Answer
            

            This is a list of terms used to refer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, by order of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Ministry</ENAMEX>, reports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Erlanger</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> television,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Hitler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Clinton</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Führer.</ENAMEX>

            
               Augmented
Quotations Extra
            

            Each final sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.

            

               "There is absolutely no evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. We were, however,
able to remove a large house <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> that seemed to be making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cranky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Alim Muhammad</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s
successful surgery.
               

               "I shudder at the idea they will leave this haven. They are trusting. They
don't understand danger. They could end up inside the large intestine of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stefania Caruso</ENAMEX> on the homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Clemente</ENAMEX>, a
small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>.
               

               "There's no scarring mark physically or mentally. Not like when we spank
their delicious bare bottoms with that nasty paddle ... ooooh!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> 
                  in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> story about branding fraternity pledges with a hot wire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hanger</ENAMEX>, as recalled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>.
               

               "I know there are going to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are cynical about this. I've been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> for too long not to realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be cynical
about any good step that's made in the direction of decency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Idiots</ENAMEX> like that
should be shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> times!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> 
                  on imaginary
criticism of his plan to give police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> wallet-sized cards listing tips
on interacting with the public. He seemed upset. It could be some kind of
feline intestinal blockage.
               

            

         
      
   
