
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">196</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;To Go&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has already got rid of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66,000</NUMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year's end</TIMEX> will remove
another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX>. What?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 195</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suggestive Gestures":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  
                     
                        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> received a letter
offering advice on an ongoing investigation. From whom; suggesting
what?
                     
                  
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX>, claiming he knows EVERYTHING."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Graver</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX> had a similar answer, with dandruff and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin</ENAMEX>.)

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> intimating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> knows more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack the Ripper</ENAMEX> than he's saying. (I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hear Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> tried to get him a job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
(similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Spencer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX> )

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayer</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX>: 'Do what we do. Grind it, spice it, case it, pack it, ship
it. Call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy Dogs</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX>,
suggesting that, in light of recent events, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> looking into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death might want to see whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Moss</ENAMEX> was driving around
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> in question."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
               

               "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pope</ENAMEX>, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> not be extradited to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> did,
however, suggest the extradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX>, for 'crimes against God.'
"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>
               

               Click
for more answers.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, "investigation" is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theological</ENAMEX> (angels?), financial (angles?), historical (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engels</ENAMEX>?), or scientific
(something about string theory and tangles?); "investigation" means crime
pursued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX> it meant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinkerton's</ENAMEX>,
which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> agreed to be purchased by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securitas AB</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$384</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1850</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Pinkerton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> ran
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butch Cassidy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sundance Kid</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on behalf of wealthy
railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, and beat the heck out of striking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> on behalf of anyone
with a few bucks. It also thwarted a plot to assassinate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>, and
thank God for that, for the entire course of history might have been different
had the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Emancipator</ENAMEX> been cut down. (Oh, all right; they uncovered an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX>
plot, a whole other thing. But I still blame them for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Raindrops Keep Falling</ENAMEX>
on My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX>.")

            "You need to do more than
post a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> with a doughnut and a nightstick," said financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Schnelle, commenting favorably on the merger. "If you are going to enter the
global market, why not do it with a marquee name?" Like, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>?

            
               Humanitarian
Answer
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX> knew, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Office</ENAMEX> received a
plea from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> to free <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Lamont</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lerwick</ENAMEX>,
the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX> who elicited the written appeal, said, "I suspect that
the representations have been made at the highest level, recognising the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>'s great contribution to protecting freedom during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>."
Speaking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamont</ENAMEX> added: "Having lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, he
understands what a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> is all about. As a great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, he values human life and he understands what happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>. As an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ironist</ENAMEX> ..." Well, OK, I added the final phrase.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>'s
Anniversary Extra
            

            Part of the official celebration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz New</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>. By mayoral order, fireworks and criticism are prohibited.

            What do Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> think
of us here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>? For answers, turn to the Excite search engine,
where, when you enter a phrase, the site automatically suggests "select words
to add to your search." These are words that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who did similar
searches have included. Selected results:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>: irony,
Canada

            
               Our
Targets
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: disgusted, castration

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>: indecent

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>: cowed, mobbed

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>'s ass: crap, missy

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>: revitalizing

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>, richest, wealth, hell

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>: exhilarating, lewd

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>: pogroms, nazis, haman

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>: persecution, persecutions,
persecuted

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientology</ENAMEX>: successes

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>: giants

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>: crackle

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>: curling

            
               Us
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX>: wormwood

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>: lazily

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>: unoccupied

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eve</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>: somatosensory

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>: clarity

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX>: anger

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX>: philistines

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX>: jail

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX>: gobble

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Goodman-Malamuth</ENAMEX>: phonics

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>: blissful

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kitch</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX>]

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelley</ENAMEX>: flake

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joydip Kundu</ENAMEX>: erupting

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">santa</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>: love

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Oder</ENAMEX>: intern

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX>: earthworm

            Alfa-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Olson</ENAMEX>: calliope

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>: moralistic

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophie Pollitt-Cohen</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prolife</ENAMEX> [does <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> know?]

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>: rusty

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rakoff</ENAMEX>: smote

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Rickey</ENAMEX>: thinks

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nell Scovell</ENAMEX>: immersing

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>: savoring

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Silow-Carroll</ENAMEX>: devotion

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Smith</ENAMEX>: liberator

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>: envelope

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb Stavin</ENAMEX>: decay

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>: operas

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>: schnauzer

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX>: bombshell

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will 
               become the property of

               
                  Slate
                
               and will be published at

               
                  Slate
               
               's discretion.

               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its site in
connection with your submission .

         
      
   
