
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> Comes in From the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>

            The visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammad Khatami</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, the first by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to
western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Islamic revolution of 1979</ENAMEX>, was a major international
story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Awsat , Amir Taheri</ENAMEX>, a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shah</ENAMEX>,
now living in exile, urged the West to give cautious support to the reforming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, while pressing for further changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s policies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>, he
wrote, is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to have been "elected through a more or
less acceptable process" and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who has ended <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s acts of terrorism in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and its "active campaign against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process." He has
also established an indirect dialogue with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and invited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt and the Süddeutsche Zeitung of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> both saw the visit as a demonstration of the extraordinary progress that
has been made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> came to power two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. In an op-ed article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>'s objectives in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> were threefold--to win <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> endorsement for his reforming efforts, to
foster international acceptance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> as a regional power with legitimate
security interests, and to entice urgently needed foreign investment. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> claimed that the recent municipal elections backing his reform
program were "the first local elections in over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,500 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>
history." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>'s charm offensive is being impeded by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s apparent
attempts to develop nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, fueling the drive for more sanctions by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX>. "The nuclear issue and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> greatly
complicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s efforts to reform the economy," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX> said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> dwelt on the
coincidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX>'s arrival in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>, to receive an honorary degree from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Turin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX> said that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX>, the object of a fatwa issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayatollah Khomeini</ENAMEX>, still can't be free of the nightmare that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fanatic</ENAMEX> might try to kill him, "it is certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, whatever it does,
cannot get free of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX>."

            The "banana war" between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> was
cited in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> as a reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> not to trust the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. In its main editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> had
particular cause for dismay over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' "punishing tariffs" on
their products, because they have given "unquestioning and unhesitating support
for all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policies and actions--even to the extent of exposing their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and interests to danger, and calling into question their true
commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> are learning that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'special</ENAMEX> relationship' they have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 20 years</TIMEX> nurturing with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> is worthless when economic interests collide. ... This behooves
us to ask: If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> treats her most trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, in such
an ungrateful manner, is she going to treat those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> who think they can
befriend her any better?"

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> devoted a full page
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> war, predicting fiercer trade battles to come on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone-treated beef</ENAMEX> and genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>, and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> A3XX
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX>, which is due to be launched <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next November</TIMEX> in direct competition with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">747</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was isolated on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>
and had managed to unite the whole of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> against it by "maladroitly"
including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> cashmere among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> products it has chosen to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">penalize</ENAMEX>.

            But the main story in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> was the
acquittals of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurent Fabius</ENAMEX> and one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> on charges of criminal negligence and manslaughter in the deaths of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who contracted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> from transfusions of
contaminated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> evening paper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>-Soir reflected
widespread outrage at the verdict with a front-page headline saying the dead
had been "mocked." Referring to the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">François Mitterrand</ENAMEX>'s
establishment of a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to try <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fabius et al.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that "no
ordinary accused have ever been treated with such consideration in the annals
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>." Special justice means that the strong always triumph, it
added, and to this there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> solution: "The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for everyone,
which would be a revolution in our judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu of</ENAMEX>
Madras carried an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> about the rapid growth of crime in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberspace</ENAMEX>. It said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> needed both changes in the law and advanced
technological training for police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> in order to combat the "nefarious
activity of a well-educated and highly accomplished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> which is making its
debut in cyberspace." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, it added, must be kept "in pace with the
galloping pace of high-tech in brilliantly planned and executed operations
which could transform electronic gadgetry into burglar's tools when the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> is in its last gasp."

             

         
      
   
