
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">249</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Cam Com Can Gal&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               The list includes
cameras, laptop computers, canvas bags of tools, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">665 gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. List
of what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 248</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Re Place":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Kennedy</ENAMEX>, it's a place where people
"practice newly learned vulgarities, erupt with anger, tease and embarrass each
other, share offensive notes, flirt, push and shove in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, grab and
offend." Where is this wonderful, magical place?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Routledge Press</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Ricci</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamos Security</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Williams</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camp</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            
"drudgecharterschool.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Novak</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            It's much noted that if
you saw what goes on in a restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>, you'd never eat out again.
Similarly, you're advised to avert your glance from the making of sausages, and
laws, and presumably laws about the manufacture of sausages to be fried up in
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that you won't be visiting. And yet, it really would be nice if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> were televised. Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are televised without
diminishing our respect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX> is on television <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>, without
diminishing our ... OK, bad example. But what is the argument against putting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in a glass-walled, street-level <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, cranking up the theme
music, hiring a second-tier comic to warm up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>, and ... OK, again,
there is no doubt some kind of case to be made against that. But if the court
could be televised discretely, in black and white, surely justice would not be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imperiled</ENAMEX>, and might even be improved. At least we'd get a more vivid idea of
how justice works. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each December</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> do all those
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>-in-review shows, there'd be swell footage of mighty impressive fatuity.
And of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> vomiting up sausage all over the waiter. And the name of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Kennedy</ENAMEX>.

            
               "In the Final
Analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Case Is About Federalism" Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> fondly recalls his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school days</TIMEX>,
what he terms "the real world of school discipline."

            In a dissent that ran longer than the decision, he
argued against the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s tampering with school fun, just as it,
presumably, ought not have messed around with slavery, or what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> would
call "the real world of agricultural labor."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Day O'Connor</ENAMEX>, who wrote the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-4
decision, found that school districts can be liable for damages for failing to
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s dissent, endorsed unsurprisingly by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>, would "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">teach little Johnny</ENAMEX> a perverse
lesson in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Federalism</ENAMEX>," but the majority found a way that "assures little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>
may attend class."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaShonda Davis</ENAMEX>--little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>--was a fifth-grade girl subjected to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> of harassment from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classmate</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> refused to help her, even by changing her seat. Her
harasser was eventually charged and convicted of sexual battery in juvenile
court.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene Hellerman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Infelicitous Metaphor Corner</ENAMEX>
            

            "These
theories have all been tried before and have all been shot down before."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Sanetti, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-president</ENAMEX> and general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sturm, Ruger & Co.</ENAMEX>, the
largest and only publicly traded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
poo-poos legal arguments against his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>'s
Philosophy Corner
            

            Why is it that when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> sends love letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>, she forwards them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX>,
but when I do, she sends them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>?

            
               Rough Translation
Extra
            

            IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ORIGINAL LANGUAGE</ENAMEX>:

            "It is particularly
disturbing in this instance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trooper Burke</ENAMEX> jeopardized the public trust and
his career over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $200</NUMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Zoubek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Acting Attorney General</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey</ENAMEX>

            IN <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ENGLISH</ENAMEX>:

            "This is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>: big
bribes only."

            
               Headline
Haiku
            

            Anticipating family
grief

            Hadassah open meet

            Dressler, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of old

            Orthotics alter
walking

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stuyvesant Town & Village</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>

            Battle for Funds

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upstarts Challenge</ENAMEX>

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Movie</ENAMEX>

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overly Violent</ENAMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20, 1999</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary O'Driscoll</ENAMEX>

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            It's a flirty, pushy, shovey, grabby world after
all.

         
      
   
