
   
   
      
         
            Unhappy Birthday

            The bombed shell of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> was the favorite
front-page picture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> the war got
personal," commented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slobba's Cracking</ENAMEX>," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
tabloid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> made a new peace offer only
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> had "blown his bed to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX>." The main story in both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> was the new hawkishness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>. His statements in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that victory was the
only acceptable "exit strategy" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> are part of a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX> deal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> claimed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
have "forged a new strategic partnership in which Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> is the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>
and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tacitly goes along with deeper involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. ...
While Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> tried to stiffen spines among the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
arriving for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> birthday, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made it clear
that the world's sole superpower was underwriting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-led
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">escalation</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> '
front-page headline was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawk Blair</ENAMEX> stiffens <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> resolve." It compared his
behavior in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>'s spine-stiffening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> visit before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>." The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> highlighted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>'s call for a new "doctrine of international community" and his explicit
statement in a speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> that his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>" thinking offers a
framework for the entire globe. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> led on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s peace offer,
which it said included "a key <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concession</ENAMEX>"--agreement to an
international security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            In an op-ed article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anatole Kaletsky</ENAMEX> attributed the triumph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX> to the global economic
crisis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>. This, he said, is "one of the luckiest breaks
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> ever had, even in their amazingly lucky
careers." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaletsky</ENAMEX> wrote, "Nobody seems to believe any longer that markets work
best if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are simply left to their own devices or that capitalism can
avoid booms and busts without active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> intervention. ... In short, the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> Way faith in 'smart' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> seems to have triumphed completely over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> doctrine that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is the problem and market forces
the solution."

            In an analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s
"new internationalism" on its editorial page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> described
it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> as "a kind of humanitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilsonism</ENAMEX> that wouldn't be limited to the
right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> to self-determination that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodrow Wilson</ENAMEX> wanted to impose on
the defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> empires after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> ; it defends the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, and cultural and religious freedoms." The author
welcomed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s attempt in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to break openly with the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX>
but warned that the new internationalism contains paradoxes that could spell
trouble in the future. One is its willingness to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, rather than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, to enforce the aims of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Charter</ENAMEX>; another was
uncertainty about its geographical extension (should its writ run outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>?); another the tendency of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> "messianism" to mask egotistic,
nationalist policies; and yet another the clash of different national values
and principles around the world.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> led on peace moves under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX> expects much from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-operation</ENAMEX>." While
highlighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> conditions for peace--an
immediate end to the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>; a withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> military, paramilitary,
and police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>; and their replacement by international peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enforcers</ENAMEX>--it said in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> can only leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> as
"victors." The main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers all led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> agreeing to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> led with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> authorizing preparations
for a land invasion. In a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> said
it is now clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are divided into doves and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> being the leading doves and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>.
Corriere della
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> carried a front-page report that the southeast Italian
region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apulia</ENAMEX> has experienced a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> fall in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> tourist bookings
because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict and has appealed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to
declare it an economic crisis zone.

            According to the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , an interview in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secretary-General Javier Solana</ENAMEX> revealing a dusting down of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> invasion
plans was "arranged" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. In an article on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s birthday
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brussels</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> recalled how one week
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s air campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solana</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> not to worry about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
spoiling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. "I'm sure the problem will be solved before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23</TIMEX>," he
said then, with a reassuring smile.

            Among several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> editorials on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s birthday, the
Times ' warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> against trying to woo <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> with "the moral
fervour which comes so naturally to him," since what was most needed to sway
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> opinion was "an informed case based on strategic interest, an argument for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committing US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> that explains why the future contours of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> peace
are being decided in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>." It warned him, too, not to "jump the gun" on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and to "avoid the slightest hint that this is a Bill-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX> show,
with the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> hanging on their coat-tails." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> are vital, because the key is the decisive thwarting of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s campaign, as destabilising as it is criminal, against its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , under the headline "Unhappy
Birthday," said the celebrations were taking place "in the wrong place at the
wrong time" because "the war will need to be over--'won' is hardly apt--before
the profoundest question of this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">anniversary season</TIMEX> can be addressed: whether
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Atlantic Alliance</ENAMEX> can and should continue into the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> st
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , however, extolled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> as "the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organisation</ENAMEX> capable of upholding the international order" and defended its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> offensive as a means of keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> happy. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,
with its Wilsonian moral impulses, could not be held indefinitely in an
alliance that sat back, fat and happy, while atrocities were being committed on
a large scale in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s backyard," it said. "Disgust with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
complacency would have led to fresh calls for withdrawal."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
world, newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> were urging an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> contribution to solving
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Ra</ENAMEX>'i of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Fanek</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> should put together a peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that
would be acceptable to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX>, while Clovis
Maksoud, writing in both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Khaleej</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Arab Emirates</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab al-Hayat</ENAMEX> , said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> should work to take the initiative out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s hands and restore it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, where it belongs. Maksoud, a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> now heading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Global South</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, noted a "frightening and obscene"
convergence between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s ethnic cleansing and the behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, which
has taken international law into its own hands.

             

         
      
   
