
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Belgrade Gets the Baghdad Treatment</ENAMEX>

            The lead story at most
papers is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has decided to begin bombing a wider range of government
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, including some in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> runs the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> to get the 'Baghdad treatment.' " An editorial argues that
airstrikes have been (and will continue to be) more effective at destroying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> military than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think. Nevertheless, the article concludes,
if the strikes don't stop the atrocities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> within a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few days</TIMEX>," ground
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> should be sent in. Another editorial urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> to donate
humanitarian supplies and eventually grant immigration visas to "our share" of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
has posted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> on the border between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to
interview the incoming flood of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. He writes:

            
               The stories are too horrific to tell in
detail. I heard of murder, rape, looting, and persistent abuse--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX>-butt
and boot. I heard of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hiding in a cave that once formed
an old marble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarry</ENAMEX>, being taunted from outside by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> firing machine-pistol
volleys into the air. ...
            

            
               There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX>, almost identical
accounts of the operational technique of ethnic cleansing. First the roar of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> coming down the valleys, then the sound of whistles being blown and the
firing of automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and hamlets that dot southern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> ... are surrounded by regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who order the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
move.
            

            
               Then come the hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, often masked, who
separate the important ones from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> are forced south,
taking only what they can carry, where they must brave further "checkpoints" in
the form of armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbers</ENAMEX>, before they reach the border. The "important ones"
stay behind.
            

            The angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
complains that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Macedonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 miles</NUMEX> away, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> swells are eating
"steak au poivre ... washed down with the fiery <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Macedonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile, no
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has bothered to set up aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> at the border to
distribute hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porridge</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> aid to the dehydrated and hypothermic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>.

            Most papers mention that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> were
been captured by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, though there are few details. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> claims the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> when arrested; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbians</ENAMEX> say they
had crossed the border into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. A picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--one with a badly
bruised face--was displayed on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> TV and reproduced in newspapers around
the world.

            An article in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> Times
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has sent a warship to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> and is prepared to
send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has promised not to intervene militarily
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> situation. Nevertheless, commenting on the ship movements,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> ominously said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Ministry</ENAMEX> is also
considering more decisive actions that will be recommended to the leadership if
the situation changes." Another article says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are feeling increasingly unsafe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> has been
attacked, the windows of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caf√</ENAMEX>© were smashed, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Consulate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> urges <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> not to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> too
loudly on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. The article interviews many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX> who feel
threatened, but none has been physically injured.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> reports "speculation" that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is thinking about creating a
"safe haven" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The area would be secured by ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Amazingly,</ENAMEX>
the article doesn't say who exactly is doing the "speculating." The news peg
for the article is a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> border by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>.

            But the big news in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> is the peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertie Ahern</ENAMEX>. The latest news is that, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> of negotiations, the two
sides failed to agree on when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> must disarm. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Protestant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are refusing to share power with the IRA in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> until the
IRA disarms. IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> want to create the coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> before
disarming. Talks will resume <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>.

            
               Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boring Headline</ENAMEX>
Ever<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "Capital <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Legislator Want More Facts on Daylight Savings Time</ENAMEX>" from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> . A close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Why Farm Sheep at All?</ENAMEX>" from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falkland Islands</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Penguin News</ENAMEX> .

             

             

         
      
   
