
   
   
      
         
            How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Free Is Louise</ENAMEX>?

            The
indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International War Crimes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribunal</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX> was variously interpreted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press.
The hawkish papers of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Street</ENAMEX> raised loud hurrahs, while some of the more
dovish ones on the continent were gloomy about its effects on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war.
There was also widespread suspicion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> had more to do with
the timing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosecutor Louise Arbour</ENAMEX>'s announcement than she, insisting
on the independence of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> role, cared to admit. There was general
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unanimity</ENAMEX>, however, that her decision made a peace settlement much more
difficult to achieve and increased the prospect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> being
eventually deployed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , both conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, were delighted.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said the indictment would put muscle into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> because "though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> might be happy to compromise with a
fugitive from justice, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could not stomach such a peace with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dishonour</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said the West "has to thank the brave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>" for ending any chance that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> would grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> immunity from
arrest and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>--one of his principal peace conditions. Such immunity
would not only be "morally repellent," it was "now illegal," it said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Independent of London</ENAMEX> was no less pleased, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
should have been indicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long ago</TIMEX>. Its main front-page headline said the indictment has split the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, but this was
effectively contradicted in an article by its political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Macintyre</ENAMEX>, claiming that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> were holding much closer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> positions
than was generally imagined and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schr√∂der</ENAMEX>'s
much-reported statement that a ground invasion was "unthinkable" had actually
meant only that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would not participate. Clearly relying on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macintyre</ENAMEX> wrote that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> don't rule out
entering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in "non-permissive" circumstances, but instead he described it
as "hypothetical" (though in an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panorama</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamberto Dini</ENAMEX> warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> would
"dissociate itself" from an invasion).

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, while leading with the headline "War
crimes move dims peace hope," pronounced the indictment "overwhelmingly
positive" and said it augured well "not just for the resolution of this war,
but for the world of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-first century</TIMEX>." Its international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Woollacott</ENAMEX>, wrote that the indictment, combined with the commitment of
more ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, a hardening of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s peace terms, and the intensification
of the air campaign, represents "a new strategy." It marks a moment when "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
ceases to be ready to deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> and declares itself ready, instead,
to deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woollacott</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arbour</ENAMEX>'s words in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX>, while
underscoring the independence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>, "suggested quite directly that
the timing of the indictment had been affected by the disclosure of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> by certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The control by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
of intercepts and other secret information has always meant that the war crimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> could be played at a moment they deemed would best serve their
interests."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> ,
welcoming the indictment as an important new step "in the fight against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impunity</ENAMEX> and barbarism," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arbour</ENAMEX> had acted with full independence and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>, but this view was questioned south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della Sera of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indro Montanelli</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s most
influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, said he hoped it wasn't so, for this would mean that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> had deliberately timed the indictment to sabotage peace
negotiations. While <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers were expressing the hope that it would lead
to the overthrow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montanelli</ENAMEX> predicted the opposite.
So did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, which said in an editorial that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Chirac</ENAMEX>'s call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> for an internal coup against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
was most unlikely to come about. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> also said that to think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> would now desert
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> showed "a deep misunderstanding of the psychology of a people
which considers itself persecuted and besieged." Writing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernardo Valli</ENAMEX> reported that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s unpopularity and lack
of charisma, he now appears to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> behind him.

         
      
   
