
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">252</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;Euphemism?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "We want to be
able to land in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">grandma</TIMEX>'s backyard at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, in thick fog, without hitting the
clothes line," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Allison</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> on the project. What
project?
            

            
               
                  (This question
courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Pope</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 251</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now Even Reformier</ENAMEX>!":
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Gary Bretton</ENAMEX>
Granatoor of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Wise Synagogue</ENAMEX>, at the forefront of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
Reform Judaism, says, "There is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morei Derech</ENAMEX>,
which means role models, and they are lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> taking on responsibilities
that in the past many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregants</ENAMEX> felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> had to do." What
responsibilities?
            

            

               
                  (This question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

            
"Selling reconditioned hyperdrives to stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi knights</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            "I'm a
huge anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Semite</ENAMEX>, so I'd have to say they're celebrating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rogers</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"Molesting young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>? Oh, sorry, wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Chris "Pushing the Limits</ENAMEX>
of Taste" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Closed-captioning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> broadcasts in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>, so everybody laughs
at the same time."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Converting non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> by tapping them on the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and proclaiming,
'Jew!' "--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris Jackson</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Goodman-Malamuth</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            With subtle--Talmudic!--reasoning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Sheldon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimmerman</ENAMEX> sees anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semites</ENAMEX> behind the movement to reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Judaism</ENAMEX>:
They're just not anti-Semitic enough. Bastards! The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion</ENAMEX>, our seminary, suggests that as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX> has declined in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> less frequently
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">reminds Jews</ENAMEX> of their identity, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> embrace ritual to, as he puts it,
"find themselves Jewishly."

            When I worked at
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Night</ENAMEX> (oh, no, not another of his tedious stories about the old
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>!), I asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> to scan the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> mail pile for
correspondence I could use in my planned anthology, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>
Letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> . For a while there was a satisfying flow of vitriol
beginning "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Jew Letterman ...</ENAMEX>" It seemed like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Anti-Semitism Classic</ENAMEX>. But
anyone who envisioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>'s big, friendly, goyish head bent over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>
needed not more tolerance,  but more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>. It wasn't genuine hate mail; it
was nut mail, and there wasn't enough of it to do a book. I felt like an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Apache</ENAMEX>
contemplating the last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> buffalo, sad and scraggly and demented. But
I still had a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham sandwich</ENAMEX> for lunch, he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewishly</ENAMEX>.

            
               Mucho Mitzvah
Answer
            

            Some lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to visit the sick.

            That's just part of the "remarkable transformation"
going on at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Wise</ENAMEX>, including more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> in the service, more singing
and chanting by the congregants, and a greater interest in religious education.
These changes are typical of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Judaism</ENAMEX>.

            Begun in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a century ago</TIMEX>, the
Reform movement emphasized ethics over ritual, abjuring the wearing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tallis</ENAMEX> and yarmulkes at services, for instance, and encouraging the use
of local languages rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Conference of American Rabbis</ENAMEX> adopted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Principles</ENAMEX>, reviving many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX> in what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> call a reclaiming
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Judaism Lite</ENAMEX>, and even
harsher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call a retreat from rationalism.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayn Rand's Panties</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past Sunday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX> presented <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Passion of Ayn Rand</ENAMEX> , with the fierce and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smoldering Helen Mirren</ENAMEX> as the dishy right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">egomaniac</ENAMEX>, leaving many
otherwise sensible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hungry for the forbidden passions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>. Satisfy these cravings at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laissez Faire Books</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The World's Largest Selection of</ENAMEX>
Books on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Liberty</ENAMEX>." Below, some items from its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> catalog.

            
               Those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirty Rotten</ENAMEX>
Taxes , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Adams</ENAMEX>

            "A lively chronicle of courageous, patriotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who hated taxes and did something about it."

            I believe he also wrote
Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dirty Rotten Prices</ENAMEX> , a lively chronicle of courageous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shoplifters</ENAMEX>.

            
               Hide Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assets</ENAMEX> and
Disappear , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Pankau</ENAMEX>

            "A step-by-step guide to vanishing without a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trace</ENAMEX>."

            And yet, so few on the
right actually do.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drink</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James T. Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas J. DiLorenzo</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nannies, Busybodies</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyrants</ENAMEX>."

            A heartfelt plea for the
return of tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>.

            
               That Every <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man Be</ENAMEX>
Armed , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen R. Halbrook</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halbrook</ENAMEX> shows that your right to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> isn't
some crackpot notion."

            I particularly enjoyed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Legal Theory From Those Screaming Voices in My Head</ENAMEX>."

            
               Freedom in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chains</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bovard</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shocking</ENAMEX> story about government gone wild."

            Party down with those
maniacs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> ... if you dare.

            
               Myth of the Robber
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barons</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton W. Folsom Jr.</ENAMEX>

            Turns out, those steel
strikes were staged with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> who were not killed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinkertons</ENAMEX>, but
retired to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX>.

            Hayek poster: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.95</NUMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX> marks the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centenary of Friedrich August von Hayek</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>,
anti-socialist, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, and dreamboat. There's only a cursory
description of the poster, but I smell string bikini.

            Video: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Donahue</ENAMEX>
Interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayn Rand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Friedman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Part I and Part II</ENAMEX>
            

            Oh, like I don't already
own it on laserdisc.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ayn Rand: A Sense of</ENAMEX>
Life , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Paxton</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hundreds</ENAMEX> of revealing, never-before-published
photos."

            The perfect companion
for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Buckley</ENAMEX> vibrator.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloated Indulgence Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are still
invited to find a sentence in an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> that best conveys hideously
conspicuous consumption in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Submissions due by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>.

            
               Headline
Haiku
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making of</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Threat:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX> in Love
And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Ale</ENAMEX>

            
               Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 1999</TIMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
Heaney
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            It's a brisathon.

         
      
   
