
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Race Bait</ENAMEX> and Switch

            More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> after
freeing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> from slavery, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are promising to liberate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> from a newer type of government-sanctioned exploitation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>. As part of their effort to seize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> issue, and in
particular their campaign for privatization, they argue that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security system rips off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> for the benefit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, has also taken up the cry. And so have some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Essence magazine</ENAMEX> invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to visit a
"community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>" Web site about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and become involved "to
ensure that we get our fair share." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale Sun</ENAMEX>-Sentinel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">editorialized</ENAMEX> recently: "The average black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> can expect to work all his life
to help finance a comfortable retirement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> for middle and upper class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, then drop dead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> after he collects his first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s best-known black political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, has called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
"a form of 'reverse reparations.' "

            Their argument is simple
and plausible: Everybody pays into the system during his or her working years
then gets a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> check during retirement. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> have a shorter life
expectancy than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, they are getting a worse deal and, in effect,
subsidizing longer-living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.

            So, why is this wrong? <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is
progressive by design. Everybody pays the same share of income into the system
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 6 percent</NUMEX>, plus another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> from your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>). But the
formula for benefit payouts isn't proportionate to what is paid in: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Low-income</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get more (not in absolute terms, but compared with their contributions),
while affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> get less. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> report by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting</ENAMEX>
Office confirms that this formula outweighs the effect of lower life expectancy
for all low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
benefits don't go just to elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> pays benefits to
younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with disabilities that prevent them from earning a living, and
also to surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX>
benefit disproportionately from these aspects of the system. Although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 12</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is black, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a quarter</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits paid to surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            The main source for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Screws Blacks</ENAMEX>
campaign is a study by (who else?) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>. Its study has been
pretty well demolished by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s actuaries and by a counterstudy by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distortions</ENAMEX>, it assumes that everyone retires at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>, although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> stop paying in and start collecting benefits earlier than that--which
reduces the disadvantage of a shorter life span.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> calculates that
a low-income, single, black male born after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> would face a rate of return on
his investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> of -<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.66 percent</NUMEX>, compared with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.38 percent</NUMEX>
rate of return for a random low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> from the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The
"rate of return" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is calculated by imagining that each of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s payments into the system over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> is deposited in an account,
from which payments from the system are subsequently withdrawn. Then you
figure what interest rate on that account would cause the payments in--plus
interest--to exactly cover the payments out, and that is the rate of return on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> as an investment.

            Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>'s calculations were accurate, its choice
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> would be tendentious. Almost all current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> are getting a
positive rate of return on the very low payments they made for most of their
working lives, even if some are getting a better return than others.
Conversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20s and 30s today</TIMEX> will get a negative rate of
return, though some will be more negative than others. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> chose a year
when, by its calculation, the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was still just barely in
positive territory while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> had moved into negative numbers, in order to
claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>' losses were subsidizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>' profits. That would never be
true of the system as a whole, even if it were true of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> born around
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>.

            The analogy to an investment with a rate of return
is only one way to think about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, and not necessarily the best.
Another is as insurance against poverty in old age or disability at any age.
When you buy auto insurance, you don't hope for a lot of accidents to improve
your rate of return on the premiums. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is also a transfer
program. The reason the rate of return is so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 40</TIMEX> is that
their money is going to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>, rather than being invested for their
own benefit. Proposals to improve the rate of return for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gen X</ENAMEX> and after,
through privatization and what not, invariably omit the money current workers
will have to supply to current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> one way or another from their
calculations.

            In any event, a government-staffed study of the rate
of return on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> based on records of actual workers
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>, puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s rate of return at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.1 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.6 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
