
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">218</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;You Smell Something</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "It stinks in God's nostrils, and I know it stinks in the law's
nostrils, and it stinks to me." Who said this about what?
            

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 217</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unlisted":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        Up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert White</ENAMEX> was No. 4
on a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,600</NUMEX>. What's the list and how did he get off
it?
                     
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary</ENAMEX> plagues, according to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renewal Movement</ENAMEX> haggada. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>,
who won a spot on the list <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tikkun</ENAMEX> contest, was
dropped along with smog, imperialism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who spit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">972</NUMEX>
others in an effort to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Seder 'not</ENAMEX> quite so long, for a change.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rickey Ray Rector</ENAMEX> memorial execution list for tough-on-crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> seeking
to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rector</ENAMEX> (of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> is also brain-damaged, so he
gets the chair."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Oder</ENAMEX>
            

            "List
of 'worst-dressed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX>.' He got off the list by turning in his taffeta chaps
and getting leather ones instead."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Sexiest Murderers Alive</ENAMEX>' list, which he got off of
by getting offed."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">People</ENAMEX>
who've sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, danced with him naked as a frat prank, or
got good and puking drunk with him in a whore <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Or, oh yeah, helped him
move a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. I'd say more, but let's wait until he wraps up the
nomination."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Chris "Contact Your Pastor for a Copy of My Videotape That</ENAMEX>
Proves Everything" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

             

             

             

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX>,
racism, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>--no, not the answers to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> questions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theme Seder</ENAMEX>
I attended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, but what we know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. We also know <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, a
narrow yet passionately held definition of manhood, and a cynical and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ill</ENAMEX>-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> who'll do anything to achieve even higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. But if
you put "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>" in the question, you get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in the answer. On the other
hand: Had he given us the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> but not given us <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> can hats to wear
to the game ... Dayanu !

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Not
Technically Part of the Wrap-Up
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cops are
arraigned on murder charges in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou Diallo</ENAMEX> shooting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, with
characteristic sensitivity, holds a ceremony to rename a city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>. That's the routine part. But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours later</TIMEX>, in a frivolous bit
of mutual assistance that involves declaring it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out-of-Towners Day</ENAMEX>" to promote
the just-remade <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon</ENAMEX> movie--oh, yes, they're remaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon</ENAMEX>
movies--who's at city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall giggling</ENAMEX> and simpering with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>.
You know: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, the ... you think of
the word.

            
               Final
Answer
            

            The list comprises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> awaiting execution,
arranged by time spent on death row; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> was removed from the list by lethal
injection.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert White</ENAMEX> was on death
row from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 26, 1974</TIMEX>, for killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with a stolen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine gun</ENAMEX> and
stabbing a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, a gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and one in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, have been awaiting execution longer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>'s final words were: "Send
me to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, warden."

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Moment</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX>
            

            I agree with your father
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Time for Sergeants saluting</ENAMEX>-toilets scene. I have always
loved it. I loved it when I read the novel; I loved it when I saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
adaptation; I loved it when I saw the movie; I continue to love it. Truth is, I
have always enjoyed toilet humor. It's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> and my triumph.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruelest Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            If you like your tax tips innovative, your
conspiracy theories baroque, and your anti-Semitism classic, you can't beat the
Posse Comitatus
Web site. Their take on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>: "jewish orchestrated MURDER of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Christians</ENAMEX>
using the armed forces of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S</ENAMEX> and others under the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>!" Their
take on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> politics: "THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RACIST JEWISH MAFIA CONTROL AMERICA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>!" And yes,
there is a transcript of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX> hosted "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Centennial</ENAMEX>
Meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learned Elders of Zion</ENAMEX>." Also impressive are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of links
under "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>
Watch: Keeping a Close <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Communities</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> subcategory, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jews on Stage, Screen, Musicians</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers</ENAMEX>, etc.," lists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of names along with capsule comments,
an odd melange of minutiae, misinformation, and admiration so befuddling it's
tough to tell if the list was assembled by -phobe or -<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philo Semites</ENAMEX>. I quote a
few without comment.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakob Dylan</ENAMEX>--lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wallflowers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the great Bob
Dylan

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Lawrence</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, skeptic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of Edie Gorme

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Moon</ENAMEX>--The Who (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Reputedly Jewish</ENAMEX>)

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Parisi</ENAMEX>--of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village People</ENAMEX> (cowboy)

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> maternal grandparent

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel Proust</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actor</ENAMEX>. Describes himself as "half <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Reizen</ENAMEX>--Great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX>, "probably the greatest bass voice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
ever produced"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Rivers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Comedian/writer/jeweler/actress</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX>--A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GUY THAT WRITES SONGS FOR COOL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">JEWS</ENAMEX>!

            

            Surely it's assembled
with a goofy sort of ethnic pride, but once it's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posse Comitatus</ENAMEX> site,
does that matter?

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ambition.

         
      
   
