
   
   
      
         
            High School <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confidential</ENAMEX>

            It's no fun being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">highbrow</ENAMEX> if you don't sometimes swing low. I know an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">century English</ENAMEX> history who devours mystery novels by the shopping bag load, a
prominent intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> shoot'em-ups, and a

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who admits to being hooked on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX> . In
this context, I am prepared to admit an entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> of my own: the teen
flick. This is a genre that flourished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, then fell into
abeyance for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX>, and is now, I am happy to report, experiencing
a modest renaissance.

            The new rash of teen
movies seems heavily skewed toward quasi-remakes of the classics. The genre
revived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clueless</ENAMEX> , which was based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX> is the zillionth adaptation of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Liaisons Dangereuses</ENAMEX> . She's
All That is loosely based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> , which was loosely based
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Fair Lady</ENAMEX> , which was based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pygmalion</ENAMEX> . Arriving at multiplexes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX> will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> , a version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Othello</ENAMEX> set against a backdrop of high-school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Things I Hate About You</ENAMEX> , an adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Taming</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shrew</ENAMEX> .

            But it would be wrong to think of these films as classic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comics for the Clearasil</ENAMEX> set. Most of them are movies that utilize classic
plots as new ways to frame their exploration into what it's like to be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>. At their best, these films immerse you once again in all
the joys and anxieties of adolescence. To me, they are the quintessential good
bad movies, because while seldom subtle or artful, they are capable of
recreating a familiar and utterly compelling world.

            The first teen movies
were made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, but the genre was largely codified by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hughes</ENAMEX>, who drew on his experiences at a large
suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> in a series of movies made in the
1980s. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> directed was the romantic comedy Sixteen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candles</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ringwald</ENAMEX> plays a quirky, intelligent sophomore who
wakes up to discover that everyone in her family has forgotten her birthday.
Insult is piled on injury as she confronts her so-called life. In the clip
available at right, she faces the daily indignity of the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. The plot
winds and unwinds a mismatch of affections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman geek</ENAMEX> with braces,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Michael Hall</ENAMEX>, has crush on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringwald</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringwald</ENAMEX> has a crush on a cute
senior who is dating the feathered blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prom queen</ENAMEX>. The film has all the
commonplaces of the genre--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that utterly trashes someone's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>, the voyeuristic visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> betting about
getting laid, and the happy comic resolution: The geek beds the prom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>,
Ringwald lands the cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior</ENAMEX>.

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S ixteen Candles</ENAMEX> is awful in some ways. A racist
subplot revolves around a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Duk Dong</ENAMEX>. Yet
the movie sets up the basic theme of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' subsequent--and I would maintain
all successful--teen movies, which is to overthrow the stereotypes that
comprise the basis of adolescent identity. The basic insight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>
films is that high school is built around a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caste</ENAMEX>/class system, which is
basically vicious and unfair. Like his subsequent movies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sixteen</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candles</ENAMEX> is essentially a fantasy about throwing out this system: The
excluded are included and the exclusionary are either enlightened or humbled.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX> get to be cool, the cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get humbled, the druggies get smart,
and the smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get stoned.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> handled this
theme in a more self-congratulatory and heavy-handed way in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">The Breakfast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>). This was probably the most famous of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flicks</ENAMEX>,
launching as it did the careers of several of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brat Pack</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>--including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilio Estevez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judd Nelson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally Sheedy</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> different types--a geek, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">richie</ENAMEX>, a screw-up, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX>, and a sullen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arty girl</ENAMEX>--are forced to spend a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> in detention considering who they are. This is my least favorite of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> films, because it's a moral lesson with flashes of humor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>'
best films are romantic comedies informed by good values.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happily</ENAMEX>, he returned to form in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pretty</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink</ENAMEX> , which was stylistically the best of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX>. This time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ringwald</ENAMEX> plays
a sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from the wrong side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> who has to choose between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">richie</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew McCarthy</ENAMEX>, and her loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duckie</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cryer</ENAMEX>. Pretty in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink</ENAMEX> is tragically marred by the wrong ending: Ringwald
walks into the sunset with the preppie rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> must have realized
his mistake, because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> he essentially rewrote it as Some Kind of
Wonderful . The quirky and talented poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Stoltz</ENAMEX>, has a
crush on the prom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>, which breaks the heart of the orphan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> (!) who has
been secretly infatuated with him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Check out the clip available at
right for the scene in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stoltz</ENAMEX> makes the right choice.

            The male <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ringwald</ENAMEX>
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX>, who started his career with a minor role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sixteen</ENAMEX>
Candles. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> coming of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hughes</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Crowe</ENAMEX>, who cast <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cusack in Say Anything ...</ENAMEX>, a funnier and more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">touching John Hughes</ENAMEX> movie than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> ever made. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cusack</ENAMEX> plays the funny kid
from a broken home who crushes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A-student</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">valedictorian</ENAMEX> played by Ione
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skye</ENAMEX>. In the clip available at right, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cusack</ENAMEX> answers her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s question about
what he plans to do with his life after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>.

            At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 1980s</TIMEX>, teen films took a darker turn with
the black comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heathers</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, who all have the
same name, take up <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winona Ryder</ENAMEX>), who can't resist the offer of
inclusion but detests their values (they make her ignore her old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and
play cruel practical jokes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>). Only this time, instead of humiliating
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slater</ENAMEX>, kill them. View the clip available at left to see them off the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather</ENAMEX>. As black as it is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heathers</ENAMEX> has the same theme as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringwald/Cusack</ENAMEX> movies. It's a fantasy about high school as a kind rather than
a cruel place. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> realizes that murder is not the right approach and offers
to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">prom night</TIMEX> with the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> everyone abuses.

            What makes these teen
flicks the ideal good bad movies? The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the familiarity of the world
they portray. Not everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> goes to a big public high school, but
everyone goes to a high school governed by a hierarchy of popularity and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cliques</ENAMEX>. Films set at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> are never as universally recognizable, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s experiences after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> are too different to generalize about.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Universities</ENAMEX>, unlike high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, are not unitary social structures. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> essential quality of these films is that they are all, basically, the
same. The formula allows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to savor minor differences and adaptations.

            For some reason, teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flicks</ENAMEX> died out for a while after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heathers</ENAMEX> --perhaps because it took the conventions of the form as far as
they could go. Then, following the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clueless</ENAMEX> , teen films
started to trickle back. The trickle has suddenly become a torrent. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> are easy enough to understand, lacking major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, these movies are
inexpensive to make and draw the ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> who are capable of
seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> times. She's All That was made for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>
million budget and has already grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $60 million</NUMEX>.

            What's different about
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s'</TIMEX> version? Teen films no longer glorify <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, but other than
that, very little. As the genre has expanded, it has broken into sub-genres.
There's the black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heathers</ENAMEX> category , the most recent exercise being the
reportedly awful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jawbreaker</ENAMEX> . There's the self-referential horror
category as manifest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scream</ENAMEX> movies. There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juniors</ENAMEX> category that started with the delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baz Luhrmann</ENAMEX>
version of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo + Juliet</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Danes</ENAMEX>.

            But the reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> is still the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughesesque</ENAMEX> romance,
the most recent example of which is She's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All That</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> from a broken home whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> cleans swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>. The most perfect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, who dates the most popular bitch, makes a bet with his best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> that he can transform the ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duckling</ENAMEX> into the prom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>. Of course,
the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> ends up ditching his snobby clique and falling in love with
her. Even the racy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruel Intentions</ENAMEX> , set among rich <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper East Side</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, is a spin on the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> formula. The evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-rich girl</ENAMEX> makes a
diabolical bet with her stepbrother that he can't corrupt the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> at
school. The stepbrother falls for the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and the wicked stepsister is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humiliated</ENAMEX> in front of everyone.

            These films have been derided as "teensploitation,"
but I don't think the description is fair. Instead of pandering to the
prejudices of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, they offer a fantasy about a freer and happier
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adolescence</ENAMEX>. Their message is that there's life beyond high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't
bound by what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> want from them, how their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> think of them, or the ways
in which they categorize themselves. All <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> films are exploitative to
some extent. But I'd say a sweet, dumb movie such as She's All That is a
lot less insulting to teen intelligence, and to the average adult <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patch Adams</ENAMEX> or Message in a Bottle .

         
      
   
