
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>

            In ","
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> examines <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s struggle between idealism and
realism. In "," he discusses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s watered-down apologies for the embassy
bombing.  In "," he lambastes the hell no, we won't go <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>; in "," he
asks who's miscalculating the belligerence level. In "," he strafes the bogus
arguments against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> war plans.

            In
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Bedfellow</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> looks at , shows how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> has turned and
doves into <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX>, and discusses why .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mathew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> in "" explains there are good reasons for what we're doing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Credibility isn't one of them.

            Massa
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gessen</ENAMEX> introduces , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> nobody knows, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>."

            ""
says we can prevent genocide.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Chait</ENAMEX> debunks the myth of the underpaid solder in "."

            
"Explainer" tells how frees <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>; describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s ; finds out who is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX> provides a ; and gives the lowdown on which way to "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," depending on
your politics.

            What
solution does history dictate for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>? Good question, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Greenberg</ENAMEX>
in the "."

            In ","
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> dissects the diplomatic doublespeak for negotiating with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. In a "," he asks: "How can we justify invading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> after
promising not to<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" and decides that it sounds like a job for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> are playing a head game over who's punishing whom. In "," Saletan
shows how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is winning the spin war.

            How
did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> win public support for bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>? By rephrasing the question,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saletan</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ask, "Why bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asks, "Why not?"

            says,
that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Milosevic</ENAMEX> to you. he examines the justification for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s outrage at being expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> helps you translate the favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> unwilling to
take a stand on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> bombings.

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">International Papers</ENAMEX>" summarizes what the world press has to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">,</ENAMEX> , and columns.

            ""
tells you what's going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and also what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> say is
going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            And ""
gives you the latest from the armchair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> talk show
circuit.

            Read
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Allen Paulosand Lisa Zeidner</ENAMEX> think about the news coverage of the
conflict in "."

            Masha
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gessen</ENAMEX> supplies "," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eliot A. Cohen and Owen Harries</ENAMEX> debate ""

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Kagan</ENAMEX> discuss ""

            ""
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discusses</ENAMEX> newspaper coverage of the bombings.

            does
his bit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> by concentrating the full power of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anagramgenius</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. Sample: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>" yields "So, so vile, bold,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manic</ENAMEX>!" Also, he that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will lie his way to victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            
Finally, if you're a little rusty on what exactly they're fighting about in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, here are squibs on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) (hint: They're not the same); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the difference
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) why fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> could spark ; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) . Or click for a
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
