
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">234</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;I Can't Kuwait&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               You give the (brief) lead; I give the headline from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
Times : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tips To Reduce 'Burden' of Students</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 233</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courtly":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     "I couldn't do my current job without them," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> as he waved something in the air.
What?
                  
               
            

            "Four
of the world's tiniest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>-educated law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Schoenberg</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "These
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX> videotapes: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birth of a Nation and Mandingo</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
Hotchkiss
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Federalist Society</ENAMEX> lickspittles."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Hitt</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oder</ENAMEX> )

            "The
various remote controls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wilde</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Novak</ENAMEX> )

            "Penal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">implants</ENAMEX> (cc: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX> magazine competition No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1108</TIMEX>, 'Misspellings we'd
like to see')."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Scheft</ENAMEX>
            

             

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Given: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> respond with particular enthusiasm to questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court. Given: The law is a particularly unhappy profession. That is, a
remarkably high percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are discontent with their jobs.
Therefore: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who take out their
frustrations on a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> just because he is a coldhearted,
reactionary bastard with dubious views about race and little understanding of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. I have no legal training, but isn't there some kind of logical
error in this paragraph? Because, aside from the dubious propositions, the
unsupported assumptions, and the illogical conclusion, I can't figure out where
I went wrong--just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX>.

            
               Courtly Love
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX> waved his glasses.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> was hearing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cases that
seek to define disability under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990</ENAMEX>, in
particular, whether the act applies to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who can restore normal
functioning by, for example, taking medication or wearing glasses. And it's as
neat a Catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> as you're ever going to see, even through those disposable
contact lenses. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> declined to hire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>
based on their uncorrected vision--i.e., glasses off--but argued that the women
couldn't sue because with their vision corrected--i.e., glasses on--they are
not disabled.

            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> goes with
the broadest possible definition, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would be considered disabled,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ill-mannered</ENAMEX>, and unattractively dressed, and would rarely be asked out by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from more stylish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> goes with the broadest
definition actually under consideration, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> could indeed be
considered disabled, but their attractiveness wouldn't be relevant. I blame the
system.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
in These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> Extra
            

            This is apropos of
nothing, but I've noticed an Internet ad for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell South</ENAMEX> using the slogan "The
Real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Pages</ENAMEX>." Is it a good idea nowadays for any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> to
go around proclaiming itself as "real white"?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Wonderland Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Driving through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX>'s bison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> out near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Big Sky</ENAMEX> (there's an easement through the property
so you can get to a state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> on the other side), I saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my favorite
warning signs ever. It reads, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately</NUMEX>:

            
               Warning! Bison have sharp horns!
They can run faster than you!
They are not tame! Do not attempt
to pet the bison!
            

            
               Common
Denominators
            

            Scalia as regressive; balls as metaphor; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ventriloquist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummy</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
