
   
   
      
         
             Ground <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War Euphemisms</ENAMEX>

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> went on television to explain the rationale for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> participation in
the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. "I do not intend to put our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to
fight a war," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> assured the public. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> observed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s verbal gymnastics about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
("It depends upon what the meaning of the word 'is' is") had made people
suspicious of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "parsing" his words about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. "When you say
you have 'no intention' to commit ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to accomplish the mission in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rather</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "does that mean we are not going to have ground
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in there--no way, no how, no time?"

            It's possible that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can still avoid a ground war. But the probability that he will have to
reverse that position--and explain his way out of it--is now at least as high
as the probability was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> that he would have to admit to an
"inappropriate" relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and explain away his previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">denials</ENAMEX>. If an about-face on the question of a ground war becomes necessary,
the phrase "no intention" will be only one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s escape clauses. His
promises to avoid a ground war, like his denials of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair, are
laced with convenient loopholes.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "Permissive environment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has pledged not
to send <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> into a "hostile environment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
to use <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to "invade" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> or enter a "combat situation."
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have held out the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> would be sent into a "permissive environment."

            At first, everyone assumed that a "permissive"
environment was one in which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>, his will
broken by the bombing, had agreed to "permit" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unchallenged</ENAMEX>. Lately, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have enlarged the meaning of
"permissive." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> acknowledged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> might never
willingly yield. "There are other ways, however, to create a permissive
environment," she added. "What we are doing is systematically diminishing or
degrading his ability to have that kind of control over the area."

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, in a
cat-and-mouse game with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> over the meaning of "permissive environment,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> alternately defined it as a) "one where there is
a political settlement"; and b) "an environment where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
don't have the ability to impose their will." On this theory, once the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>'
defenses are sufficiently crippled by bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> would enter
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> without significant resistance.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>." In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX> speech,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would join a "peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>" to "implement"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s peace plan if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> accepted it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week later</TIMEX>, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
pointed out that the peace plan was dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> insisted that the Kosovars
must nonetheless be allowed to return home and live safely. "That will require,
clearly, for some period of time, some sort of international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that will be
able to protect their security," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> conceded. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alternately</ENAMEX> described this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> as an "international peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>,"
"international security presence," "implementation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>," and
"post-implementation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>."

            But ever since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
captured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> snooping around the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Macedonian</ENAMEX> border a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week ago</TIMEX>, "peacekeeping" has become a plastic term. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> insisted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> "were carrying out a peaceful mission in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>--protecting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> from the violence in neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>." The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, when reporters
asked what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> had been up to, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockhart</ENAMEX> insisted "they were left there
in a peaceful and peacekeeping fashion, as a peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>." This may be
just the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many armed confrontations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> plans to attribute to "peace."
When asked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s plans to return <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to their homes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> that the "peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>
"were always planned to make sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX> could live in
peace and harmony."

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protectorate</ENAMEX>." From the outset,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stipulated that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> wouldn't fight for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> "independence,"
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> wouldn't impose an "occupying force" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told Rather it would not be "appropriate" to discuss "creating
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> enclave that would keep [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>] there forever." When Rather
pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pledge to guarantee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>' "security"
amounted to the same thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asserted that this wasn't so and argued
that he was only saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> were "entitled" to security. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mirrors Clinton</ENAMEX>'s favorite domestic policy spin: arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
"entitled" to assistance or protection (e.g., a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' bill of rights")
while avoiding discussion of what it will cost. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ruled out an
"enclave," anonymous senior administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> came up with a new phrase
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-guarded territory to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> would return: an
"international protectorate."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Supporting the air campaign." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s original
promise to deliver "air strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> responsible for the
brutality in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>" without putting "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to fight a war" has
proved to be self-contradictory. To hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> who are committing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brutality</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has to bring its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> down to the ground. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in
this transition is the delivery of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX> are more like ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> than like air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>: They will fly
low over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, shoot at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, and risk being shot down in
return. That's why they belong to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>. To protect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is also sending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> surface-to-surface rocket
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">launchers</ENAMEX>--indisputably a ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>.

            To operate, service, and guard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is supplying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, adding to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who
are arriving in the region to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. Everyone knows these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> are
trained for combat and can be quickly converted into an invading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.
Alternatively, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> and communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> they will build can be used
to support an invasion. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> insist that at most these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> might
be dispatched to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovars</ENAMEX> back to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> once "hostilities"
have ended. Presumably, these are alternative euphemisms for a "peacekeeping"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> in a "permissive environment." Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> assert that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are "an expansion of the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>,"
"supporting the air campaign," and "not a ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> hawks have
complained for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> underestimated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s rigidity. By
swearing off ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, they argued, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s hands, giving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> confidence that he could destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> without effective resistance.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, in turn, may have underestimated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s agility. A president
who can talk his way out of a perjury rap can talk his way into a war.

         
      
   
