
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethnicity Slickers</ENAMEX>

            
               But They're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmless Stereotypes</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Merchant of Menace</ENAMEX> ," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX> for using racial stereotyping in the new Star Wars movie. While
it's undeniably true that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar Jar Binks</ENAMEX> is reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stepin Fetchit</ENAMEX>, and
those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> noseless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> of the type not seen
since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> movies, I take issue with the implication that this is
harmful.

            Let's face it--these stereotypes have been out of
circulation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 or 40 years</TIMEX>, kept alive almost exclusively by crackpot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">racists</ENAMEX> and horrified anti-stereotype <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigades</ENAMEX>, mostly the latter. Your typical
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> does not associate those traits with those ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>
stigmatizes no one but computer-generated alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creatures</ENAMEX> with these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">portrayals</ENAMEX>--in fact, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is prominent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi counsel</ENAMEX>. There is a
distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> influence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of the queen of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naboo</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX> points
out, the ultimate villain of the story is an influential, rich, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> has been
appropriating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> from other movies his entire career. It only makes sense
that he would revive these long-unused stereotypes and squeeze them for their
entertainment value. I salute him for finding ways to do it without hurting
real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Krause</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canoga Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
replies:
                
               The response to my recent article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Merchant</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Menace</ENAMEX> " has been overwhelming--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> e-mails and counting. In that
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article I</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> revives long-standing racial
stereotypes about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. Many of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> e-mails told me
that I was wrong to make this claim. A smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> told me that I was right.
Other than what I wrote in the initial article, I have nothing to add to this
debate.
            

            
               But a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Krause, concede that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> did indeed revive racial stereotypes but think this
revival is no big deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krause</ENAMEX> says that in this modern age stereotypes no
longer have the power to do harm. A surprisingly large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>
add that only intentional racial stereotypes are harmful (and, as I say in the
original article, I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> intended to offend anyone).
            

            
               Frankly, I had not anticipated this type of
argument. I'd always assumed that the revival of certain racial stereotypes in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s movie would be universally deplored. But apparently not everyone
feels this way.
            

            
               So, why is it wrong to milk ancient stereotypes
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">modern-day</TIMEX> laughs? Mostly, it is tasteless, since the racial stereotypes at
issue have been used to justify all sorts of historical barbarities.
Admittedly, there is no bright line dividing an ethnic joke that seems funny
from one that is vicious. The ingredients of humor are hard to pin down. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reviving Shylock</ENAMEX>--without a trace of historical awareness--to amuse
uncomprehending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> seems obviously vicious rather than funny. At least to
me. One thing is sure--it certainly is not imaginative.
            

            
               And there is yet
another valid concern: that the widespread transmission of racial stereotypes
might indeed be helpful to hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The influence is sure to be diffuse.
Many claims about the influence of popular culture are exaggerated. But it's
hard to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not affected by the images and stereotypes they
encounter as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. I am not completely confident that racial stereotyping
in movies has a significant effect on racial politics. But neither am I
confident that it doesn't.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naboo Tea</ENAMEX>
Party
            

            I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s in the imaginary
universe of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moneybox</ENAMEX>"). But his attempt to
characterize the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> as
ridiculously hostile to taxation forgets that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are in
good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Have you forgotten <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history? By making a tax dispute the
putative reason for invading a planet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> merely transposed historical
events that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> ought to be familiar with. Beyond substituting spacecraft
for sailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, it wasn't much of a reach. Does "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Tea Party</ENAMEX>" ring any
bells? How about "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX>" or "no taxation without
representation"?

            Moviegoers are told very
little about why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naboo</ENAMEX> was invaded, but the few facts we get are credible,
albeit too sparse to test with the criteria for just wars.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick O'Hannigan San Luis Obispo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Let's Go to the
Tape
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> needs to hit the replay button on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prepare To Win</ENAMEX> tapes (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"). As obvious and as simplistic as he deemed the
content, he still managed to miss the point.

            We want to encourage more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> to
run for office. Frequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> announce before they have given real
consideration to the basics: Why am I running? Where will I get the money? How
do I get started? "Thunderingly obvious" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> on his perch it may be, but
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who rush to announce before thoughtful consideration, the result
is a no win .
            

            He takes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kit Bond</ENAMEX> for advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>
and potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to "be true to yourself." This advice is easier said
than done, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> cautions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> that once you sell your vote, you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> your integrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> finds this advice cynical and shabby. In this case,
the eye of the beholder is less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20-20</NUMEX>.

            Cynical and shabby is
alive and well in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and that is just one of the reasons it is
necessary to caution potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--on the obvious--that selling your
vote or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> is a formula for "prepare to lose."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Harrison Co</ENAMEX>-chair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican National Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden</ENAMEX>
'90s
            

            I suppose it figures that you would pick <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sitcom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> to debate the value of writing for television and movies (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"). What
either of them has to say is irrelevant: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Half-hour</ENAMEX> comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> write jokes,
not shows. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> exception, which they both ridiculed, is, in my opinion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Night</ENAMEX> .

            As far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> go, it is hard to remember
a movie in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> that is as well written as the prime-time dramas
we have seen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 15 years</TIMEX>. I am referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hill Street Blues</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Law , Murder One , Picket Fences</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> Hope
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Law & Order , Homicide: Life on the Street</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn South</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Practice</ENAMEX> , and yes, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> .
Show me any <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX> show that approaches the wit, intelligence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relevance</ENAMEX>, and drama of the shows I mentioned.

            We are experiencing right now a golden age of drama
on television, not in the theater, not in movies, but (mainly) in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock-to-11 o'clock hour</TIMEX> almost every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Look at these scripts then go
back and look at what was called "the golden age of television" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>.
Sadly, most of it doesn't hold up compared to what we see now.

            There are some fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> out here, and they are writing drama, not jokes.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duncan Sherman Oaks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
