
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Valid
License
            

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> who still insists he's a
Chicagoan, it's nice to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Royko remembrance</ENAMEX> (see ""). But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> raises about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slats Grobnik</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX>'s occasional fictionalizing and
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> understood it bothers me. It doesn't give enough credit to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, for one thing, and it neglects the implicit bargain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> strike
with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> to be on the level.

            It seems like everyone I knew who read his
column--and that's nearly everyone I knew growing up, even in the
suburbs--understood that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slats</ENAMEX> and others were inventions. And everyone, I
thought, knew the difference between the columns in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> would create a
situation to make a broad point and the columns in which he was talking about
flesh-and-blood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and life-and-death matters. When he got someone real on
the spit, you could smell it.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the big
differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royko</ENAMEX> on one hand and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Barnicle</ENAMEX> and similar truants on
the other is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royko</ENAMEX> himself didn't confuse his fictions with reality, and
he didn't promote confusion about them. Whatever license he had was earned over
a long, long time by drawing a clear line between his creations and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, and by scrupulously honoring an unarticulated deal with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
that he wouldn't lose track of which was which, so they wouldn't, either.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Brekke</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX>
            

            In his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Assessment" of</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. O. Scott</ENAMEX> says the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> "resulted from the unlikely
collusion between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Groening</ENAMEX> ... and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>." Not really. The real
creative story is the collusion between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L. Brooks</ENAMEX>, former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Tyler Moore</ENAMEX> Show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of flicks such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadcast</ENAMEX>
News and Ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> (and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">protégé</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Simon</ENAMEX>)
brought with him the story discipline that made The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Simpsons</ENAMEX> such great
television. (For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first few years</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> shared the "created by"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX>, but that has since changed.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of talented, bitter ex-Ivy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, led for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conan O'Brien</ENAMEX>, is responsible for the show's
lasting greatness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> and all that, but any moving picture is
a collaboration, especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> comedy TV. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writers</ENAMEX> covering televison and
movies should tell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that the auteur theory isn't really relevant,
especially when a new episode (complete with perfect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-act story
structure!) needs to be cranked out once a week.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Swett</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Lack of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resolution</ENAMEX>
            

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
on-the-mark "" about linguistic dodges served up by "thoughtful" commentators
on the conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, let me contribute <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following</TIMEX>, perhaps the
grandest of them all--the congressional resolution of "support for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>."
I've never been on the receiving end of such support but, at the risk of
appearing ungrateful, I would probably rather know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> also
happened to support the mission I was being asked to risk my life for.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.B. Howard</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore</ENAMEX>

            
               Affirmative
Reply
            

            I read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts Jr.</ENAMEX> attacked
as racist. I'm no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>. I think you are right that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
place him in the forefront because he's black. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is trying to appear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inclusive</ENAMEX> when it really is not. However, to say that is his position is a
result of affirmative action is offensive. Your premise that affirmative action
promotes or gives positions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of color who don't deserve or are
unqualified for these positions is what I find racist.

            It's the promulgation of ideas and derogatory
comments such as yours that debases affirmative action, and misleads and
misinforms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about affirmative action policies. Affirmative action is just
that--affirmative. It gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are qualified and knowledgeable an
opportunity to display their skills. It opens doors that might have otherwise
been left closed because of race. It promotes the inherent value of diversity
in any given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> or business.

            Call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts Jr.</ENAMEX> a
front <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, or say that he's being prostituted, or whatever. But don't say he's
a result of affirmative action.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Archia</ENAMEX>
            

            Carrboro, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
