
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story warns that cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, though a boon to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, could bankrupt the poor and politically unstable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that
produce it. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> diagrams the current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese-American</ENAMEX> diplomatic
impasse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> berates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for human rights abuses and illicit
transfer of defense technology; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inconsistent</ENAMEX> and hypocritical--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has sent mixed messages about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and most favored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> status. ... A piece describes the monuments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> has
erected to himself. One is made from a fallen <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> missile melted down and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remolded</ENAMEX> in the image of agonized Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> groveling at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s
feet.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A profile accuses
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Edley</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s premier policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, operative, and
ghostwriter on race--of being doctrinaire and intolerant of dissent. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">single-handedly</ENAMEX> closed the discussion on class-based affirmative action and
excluded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s race initiative. ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Prostate cancer</ENAMEX> screenings are now <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">de rigueur</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, says a piece, but
they may lead to premature and overaggressive surgery. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> are often
deadlier than the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> itself. ... The cover story calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Tenet</ENAMEX> an energetic, clever, and appealingly iconoclastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> but
questions his--or anyone's--ability to reform the stumbling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. ...
A review savages <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kingsolver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX>: Their writing is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heartfelt</ENAMEX>, but their politics are naive and their use of emotion is cheap.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s special
shelter issue, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Human Habitat</ENAMEX>," self-consciously departs from
glossy, expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior-decorator</ENAMEX> culture. The opening essay rejects
overdesigned sleekness for the "flowing, tangled" realism of everyday mess.
Short pieces feature a family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, repossessed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> suburbs, and the many uses of storage lockers. There's even a special
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making the Most of It"</ENAMEX>) devoted to the poor, portraying
struggling-but-content <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, living in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30-</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> mountain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shack</ENAMEX> and in the slums of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio de Janeiro</ENAMEX>. A photo spread depicts how people
have made various unlikely settings--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile silos</ENAMEX>, water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mausoleums</ENAMEX>--into cozy and functional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                
               and

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's peculiar cover story announces and names the new "femaleist" movement:
biological feminism based on new research showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are
"tougher, stronger, and lustier" than stereotype dictates. According to
femaleism, ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> hunted along with their male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>, the clitoris is
anatomically superior to the penis, and menstruation is an expression of
"primal female power." The story is oddly competitive, keeping score between
the genders on strength, agility, and aggression, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mischievously</ENAMEX> wondering
"which sex should rule." Photographs of scantily dressed, genetically gifted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> illustrate it. A sidebar traces political attitudes toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Sanger</ENAMEX> to ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cybill Shepherd</ENAMEX>. It's a big week for women's health
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , too. Its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health for Life</ENAMEX>" supplement gives practical, soothingly written advice on a
long list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s health concerns, from familiars such as pregnancy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> to perimenopause (pre-menopausal hormonal irregularities) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's regular issue is devoted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> at war. The introductory essay argues that war has been the central
influence and organizing principle of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. The bulk of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is given to firsthand narratives by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> and others. A
sampling: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SEALs</ENAMEX> recalls his near-drowning at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadalcanal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Halberstam</ENAMEX>
describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s spin apparatus in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> reminisces about the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>
summit.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> prints a
quick and dirty guide for rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> who aspire to statehood. From Chechnya
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdistan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>, independence is achieved through television, luck, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">location</ENAMEX>, location, location--no way for far-flung <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, maybe for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Kurdistan</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The grim cover
story explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> is so hard to treat effectively: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insurers</ENAMEX>
won't pay for the trial-and-error process of finding the right <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>, and
the disease is still mistaken, even by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> doldrums. The
cover promises new treatments, but the story inside says very little about
them. ... A piece asks if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is finally losing his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marbles</ENAMEX>--or at least his judgment. Unsettled by sanctions, riots, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s steady bombing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> has been firing military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassinating clerics</ENAMEX>. ... An article describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> personal-injury lawyers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thronged</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> bombing, convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyans</ENAMEX> to sue
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sachs</ENAMEX> argues that the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is a mirror of capitalism itself. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s decision to go public was driven by unbridled individual greed and
represents the demise of the long-term, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>-oriented thinking that spurred
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s original success. One telling detail about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s legendary
emphasis on teamwork: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> have constant access to a database where they
can input evaluations of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>' performance. ... Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, and gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unrepentantly</ENAMEX> describe
how they blew their inheritance at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> blackjack tables. ... A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> finds head-spinning confusion at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Archives</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX>
are straining to keep up with the antiquatedness of old technologies and the
information sprawl caused by new ones. For example, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> court case requires
all federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to archive their computer files and e-mails, but it took
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archives</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> just to copy the records of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
And even those records "are gibberish as they currently stand," sighs one
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archives</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The lead editorial
pleads with the media to pursue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX> story. ... The
cover
story opines that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> should be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, because he's smart, principled, and destined to lose. Whereas
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would have to play hardball to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is a "listless
and uninspiring" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who could be vanquished quietly and nobly.
... An article sings the virtues of "alternative country music," which
is authentic and religious. Big-name country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> have forsaken the
form--not only for filthy lucre, but also because mainstream success helps them
"lose the sense of inferiority they've had since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appomattox</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
