
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpha Zeta</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caper</ENAMEX> movies can often get
by with only one great visual idea; in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entrapment</ENAMEX> , it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX> in a black <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">vinyl cat</ENAMEX> suit doing ballet amid a field of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laser</ENAMEX> beams. She's supposed to be an undercover insurance operative who's out
to catch legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">burglar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> in the act of stealing a priceless
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> mask--or is she actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX> herself planning to bag the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scrumptious Scotsman</ENAMEX> along with the motherlode? A mystery, that. In the
meantime, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connery</ENAMEX> whisks her to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> on an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Inverness</ENAMEX> loch, where he rigs
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s cradle of red string to represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lasers</ENAMEX> that she won't, at the
site, be able to discern. As she practices her moves, blindfolded, the
firelight casts a golden aureole around her sculpted bottom. But she's even
more alluring when she does the deed for real. She begins in the lotus
position, then unfolds and sends a long leg sideways in a neatly executed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fouetté</ENAMEX> . "On point ..." says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connery</ENAMEX>, peering into his laptop screen at
the beams that only he can see. "Now, lift !" The whole sequence has an
archetypal enchantment, made even more savory by its naughty underpinnings: The
aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> directs his prima ballerina in a sacred dance to larceny.

            
               Entrapment
doesn't hit the rest of its marks with comparable élan, but it's bearable. With
its featherweight premise, casually amoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, and exotic locales, it
conjures up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>) when twisty, romantic heist pictures
were routinely ground out as tax shelters--and sometimes cast with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>' model girlfriends, so that expensive vacations could be written off,
too. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entrapment</ENAMEX> is an A-list production, but despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ving Rhames</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connery</ENAMEX>'s enigmatically surly cohort and a bevy of state-of-the-art sensors,
cybergizmos, and digital readouts, it can't manage to brush off its B-movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cobwebs</ENAMEX> or to freshen banter that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhett</ENAMEX> would have been too progressive to lay
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarlett</ENAMEX>. "Has there ever been anyone you couldn't manipulate, beguile, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">seduce?</ENAMEX>" asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connery</ENAMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX> has stretched herself languidly out on
a plush <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-poster. In the climax, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> must walk a fraying tightrope
between the twin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> of the world's tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>) while
millennium fireworks explode around them. But the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s dialogue remains
laughably mired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last millennium</TIMEX>: "They're <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in a trap!"

            E ntrapment is built around the object that is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>, who, as the headstrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mask of</ENAMEX>
Zorro , did a dazzling job of staring down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Banderas</ENAMEX>. She has almond
eyes, a luxuriant black mane made for high-toned hair commercials, and an upper
lip that can flare or pout with silken ease. Supple physically, she is
nevertheless somewhat stolid--probably the upshot of a monotonous, untrained
voice of the sort that brings most goddessy supermodels crashing to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. It
doesn't help that she's opposite an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who can do a fouetté on every
syllable.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connery</ENAMEX> is also the
embodiment of everything unfair in nature--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, but especially to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
being one of the few male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> who actually makes a plausible heartthrob for
a female <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>. "You're the most beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX>
I've ever seen," he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>, toasting her with that voice while eating
her up with those bandit-chieftain eyes--and you can picture sundry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Age</ENAMEX>
Bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> clucking, "I remember when he said that to me , sonny."
Connery mocks <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father Time</ENAMEX> by disguising himself as an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with glasses and
a paunch: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This</ENAMEX>," he seems say, "is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of my age are supposed to look." Of
course, one way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> assist the aging process is by playing roles
that give their features and emotions a workout. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connery</ENAMEX>--superb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> though
he is--hasn't broken a sweat since The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Untouchables</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>--who, coincidentally, wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connery</ENAMEX>'s marvelous
dialogue in that movie--gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> theater a brusque shove out of the
romantic realm of disillusioned lefties such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene O'Neill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> into a brutal capitalist realism, wherein every encounter was reduced to
an attempt by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> party to hoodwink, psych out, or otherwise overpower another.
Who'd have thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mamet</ENAMEX> was secretly in love with the well-carpentered,
'40s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'50s</ENAMEX> drawing-room plays of the terribly <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Terence Rattigan</ENAMEX>, whom
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Angry Young Men</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '50s</TIMEX> loutishly blew off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>--thus paving
the way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX>'s expletive-laced theater games? In choosing to adapt and
direct The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winslow Boy</ENAMEX> , based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rattigan</ENAMEX>'s most tidily crafted
problem pieces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mamet</ENAMEX> points up an aspect of his own work that has increasingly
dwarfed all others: the drama as a procession of archly formal negotiations.
Beat by beat, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX> turns out an immaculately staged, crisply paced, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">elegantly</ENAMEX> acted movie. It's also a tad bloodless, but you can't have
everything.

            Set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, the play (based on an actual incident) tells the story of an
adolescent boy expelled from a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> for the theft of a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-shilling postal money order, and the financially ruinous attempt of his
proper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> (played in the film by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawthorne</ENAMEX>) to clear his son's
name. Relativist that he is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mamet</ENAMEX> clearly loves the fact that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winslow</ENAMEX>'s
guilt or innocence is never satisfactorily resolved. What matters is that the
Winslow cause--at least when viewed from the perspective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s
increasingly frail but determined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--has its own sterling truth. More to
the point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX> can have himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> of a time directing a series of
civilized confrontations that escalate in importance--from the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winslow</ENAMEX> senior for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s hand in marriage (and the precise amount
of her dowry) to a cunning barrister, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Morton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Northam</ENAMEX>), who
uses every rhetorical trick he can think of to wear down a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> weary of
a twopenny schoolboy scandal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawthorne</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslow</ENAMEX> an air of gorgeously ineffable
sadness; he seems to carry on his ever shakier shoulders the knowledge that
this gray way of life, this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, is doomed. If only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rattigan</ENAMEX> had given him
a stronger <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> act! This the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> ceded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>, the coldhearted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Establishment lawyer</ENAMEX> who unexpectedly throws himself into an anti-establishment
cause--and who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northam</ENAMEX> plays (brilliantly) as an alert snake increasingly
unsure of where to strike. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX>, however, the core of the piece is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, a snootily progressive ingénue and a suitable romantic foil
for the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>. She is played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Pidgeon</ENAMEX>,
whom he means us to find weirdly irresistible--I find her weird and resistible
but not unattractive, having spent much of my early manhood pursuing similarly
small, dark-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who looked as if they had some lewd secret that would
only be divulged after a protracted psychodrama. (The secret, of course, was
that there was no secret.) Along these lines, the saucy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pidgeon</ENAMEX>'s chief talent
is for looking as if she knows something that you don't and--even after
ravishing her--never will. Clearly, this is what gets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX> through the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
