
   
   
      
         
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>'s
Awards
            

            Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley for buying into our list at the beginning of his recent "." But his
later point about "gratuitous meritocracy" did not seem up to his usual level
of argument. Of course we evaluate (unscientifically) the merit--the relative
merit--of novels, paintings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> songs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, etc. Could
there be art without such evaluations? (This is a philosophical, not an
economic, question--and a serious one.) Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> lists and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> are simply a
rather formal, inevitably somewhat pedestrian method of evaluation. Our list
certainly has a target or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> on it for everyone (including us list <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>).
Still, I thought the whole thing was worth doing because journalism is rarely
compared across <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>; because such comparisons make for enlightening
discussions (like the one you, all too briefly, embarked upon); because our
memory for good journalism tends to be awfully short; because most of the work
on our list (like that in item No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>) deserves to be honored; and because in
so doing we hope to inspire more gutsy, eye-opening journalism. Could a similar
case be made in support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cable Ace Awards</ENAMEX>? Perhaps. But our list does
have the advantage of including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarbell, Steffens, Murrow</ENAMEX>, and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephens</ENAMEX>
            

            Chair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journalism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               The (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>'
Room
            

            As a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>, I found the in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Music</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in rock fascinating. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Wyman</ENAMEX> asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Phair</ENAMEX> is
trying to maintain an indie sensibility while flirting with mainstream
commercial music. This seems to be a time-honored argument leveled at women
from all walks of life. It seems that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> shows any duality in her
opinions and/or her career endeavors, she is either confused about what she
wants (and therefore weak), or she shouldn't be venturing out into the big, bad
world of rock 'n' roll. Ooh, too scary!

            I find the whole issue of
"Women in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>" a bit off-putting as well. There shouldn't be a delineation
between where one creative process ends and another begins. It is a universal
language, or should be in an ideal world. I am constantly amazed at the number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (yeah, they've been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>) who have told me that my musical career
would be bolstered if I would just be willing to "work the sex angle."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>

            
               Everybody's Got a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungry Heart</ENAMEX>
            

            The argument in "" seems really stretched,
particularly to anyone who's ever done something like lock his refrigerator (I
don't, but I keep it empty for a similar reason). The irrational act isn't
"locking the fridge," it's "snacking at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>"--you gain weight, use up
food, and get less sleep. The momentary pleasure isn't remotely worth the
drawbacks.

            So why do it? Because of
an irrational urge to eat, doubtless a holdover from some ancient time when
eating whenever possible was a survival trait. As long as you're positing an
evolutionary urge with no present-day benefits, why assume the most complicated
explanation is correct? Or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are too stupid to realize what's bad for
them?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>
Mandelbaum
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
Around
            

            I note one glaring
omission from the "" item in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story arrived
in the press after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> had established a pattern of behavior toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and of soon-to-be-inoperative denials. But prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accusation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX> book, no one had ever accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> of
anything remotely approaching the sort of behavior alleged. There was no
pattern to match the behavior and, therefore, the press did not pursue it or
demand a forceful denial. To add further injury to the premise that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> accusations are "remarkably [a]like," the Broaddrick
story was exhaustively researched by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter Lisa Myers</ENAMEX>, whose reputation for honest, nonscandal reporting is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unquestioned</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> accusation was "reported" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX> (whose
reputation for veracity is questionable at best) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.
Not exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX>, is it?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Laing</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               Core
Values
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "" is in many ways a sophisticated
look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>, the best exemplar of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> higher
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>. But it does repeat a few inaccuracies.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> name, under which it
was incorporated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>. That is "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> may
have been misled by a poorly reported story in a local newspaper that confused
discussions about the various shorthand versions of our name.

            The new curriculum does not dilute the general
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">education Weisberg</ENAMEX> lauds. It provides a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> in all the large
knowledge domains of humankind and in analytic thinking skills, a bit more
choice to explore the ideas and fields introduced in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>,
and a series of courses taught by full <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> in a small, focused discussion
style that has long been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s hallmark. The "core" curriculum will now
constitute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> plus a year of foreign language, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> required for
graduation. This is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fewer than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> required since the latest
curriculum revision in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, but it also means <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more
courses in their concentration(s) (or major) or in other areas. Additionally,
the curriculum is under constant scrutiny by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, and is revised
regularly (typically at intervals of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a decade</TIMEX>) in a process that
culminates in a vote of the college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>. Their vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1998</TIMEX>, by a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-to-1</NUMEX> margin, approved the new curriculum.

            Education at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> will continue to be great fun, in the traditional,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> sense in which our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have always found some of life's greatest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satisfactions</ENAMEX> in the enthusiastic, unbridled pursuit of the life of the
mind.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Arbeiter
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>

            
               Brownian
Emotion
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best University in America</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>
writes: "Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, whose undergraduates have a higher average <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> score
than those at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, and which gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as many applications
precisely because it has a reputation for being a blast and lacks any real
requirements."

            Your one sentence
explanation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s attractiveness to prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> is an insult to
Brown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and alumnae, to those who have applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, and to

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who hate seeing arguments built on unsupported
stereotypes instead of facts.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Flynn</ENAMEX> ,
Brown <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
