
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monomoney Mania</ENAMEX> 

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of days ago</TIMEX> my CW
alarm starting buzzing furiously. For something like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> I was talking to had just declared, in the tones of someone
stating a profound insight, that the modern world economy no longer has room
for scores of different national currencies--that the inexorable logic of
globalization will soon force most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to adopt the dollar, the euro, or
the yen as their means of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. This particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX>,
and was clearly influenced by the recent discussion of "dollarization" as a
solution to his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX>'s woes, but I have heard pretty much the same line from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>. No doubt about it: A new conventional wisdom has emerged.
And you know what that means: It's time to start debunking.

            At first sight, it might
seem obvious that the fewer currencies there are, the better. After all, a
proliferation of national moneys means more hassle and expense, because you
keep on having to change money and to pay the associated commissions. It also
means more uncertainty, because you are never quite sure what foreign goods are
going to cost or what foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> will be willing to pay. And as
globalization proceeds--as the volume of international transactions rises, both
absolutely and relative to world output--the cost of having many currencies
also rises. So why not have fewer--maybe only one?

            There's also the matter of speculation. The financial
crises that have shaken much of the world all started, at least in the first
instance, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> betting that the currency of the afflicted nation
would fall in value against harder currencies such as the dollar. Why not spoil
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>' game by giving them nothing to speculate about--by replacing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pesos</ENAMEX> and reis with portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> (or, if you happen to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>, with generic pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> and gates--for more on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
currency design, see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> 
                  Slate
                piece)?

            But not so fast. There
are still some very good arguments for maintaining separate national
currencies. Not only that, while globalization and technological change in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> are pushing the world toward fewer currencies, in other ways they actually
reinforce the advantages of monetary pluralism.

            The classic argument in favor of separate national
currencies, with fluctuating relative values, was made by none other than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Friedman</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> appealing aspect of this particular debate is that it
cuts across the usual ideological lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> like unified
currencies, so does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> like floating
exchange rates, so do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcherites</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> started from a more or less
undeniable observation: Sometimes changing market conditions force broad
changes in the ratios of national price levels. For example, right now the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> economy is booming and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> economy's sputtering. Clearly, prices
and wages in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> need to rise compared with those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. Now, you
could simply rely on supply and demand to do the job, producing inflation in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> and deflation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. But even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-marketeer</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>
realized that this is asking a lot of markets and that it would be much easier
to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> prices stable in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> currency, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> prices stable in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish</ENAMEX>
currency, and let the exchange rate between the two currencies do the
adjusting.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> offered a
brilliant analogy. He likened exchange rate adjustment to the act of setting
clocks forward in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX>. A truly devout free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> should--if he
is consistent--decry this as unwarranted government interference. Why not leave
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> free to choose--to start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the working day earlier</TIMEX> if and only if they
feel like it? But in reality there is a coordination problem. It is hard for
any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> business to shift its work schedule unless everyone else does the same.
As a result, it turns out to be much easier to achieve the desired time shift
by leaving the schedules unchanged but resetting the clocks. In the same way,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> argued, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> whose wages and prices are too high compared with
those abroad will find it much easier to make the necessary adjustment via a
change in the value of its currency than through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of changes in
individual prices.

            So there is a trade-off. You don't want too many
currencies--you wouldn't want to have separate dollars for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>.
But when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are subject to strong "asymmetric shocks"--which is
econospeak for saying that if they shared a common currency one would sometimes
be in a boom while the other was in a slump and vice versa--there is a good
case for their having separate currencies whose relative values are allowed to
fluctuate. The question, then, is whether changes in the nature of the world
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> have altered the terms of trade-off--and if so, in which direction.

            Now the increasing volume
of international trade and investment does, other things being the same, make
it more costly to maintain multiple currencies. But other things are not the
same, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> arguably make the optimal number of currencies in the
world larger rather than smaller.

            Consider, in particular, the effects of modern information
and communication technology--which may also be the driving force behind
globalization. Surely that technology has made it easier, not harder, to deal
with a world of many currencies. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of a single
currency used to delight in pointing out that if you took a grand tour of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, starting with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> deutsche marks and changing your money into
local currency at each stop, at the end you would have only something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX>. This was always a bit of a red <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX>, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissions</ENAMEX> that
businesses pay on foreign exchange transactions are far smaller than the fees
at foreign exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX>. But anyway, who needs to change money nowadays?
When I go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, I pay for most things by credit card and get petty cash
from local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX>, which are happy to accept my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BankBoston</ENAMEX> card.

            Information technology
also makes it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to deal with the risks associated with
fluctuating currencies. It has always been true that such risks could in
principle be "hedged" away through ; the problem was that the necessary markets
were sometimes thin or nonexistent. Thanks to computers, however, investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> now offer a vast array of financial instruments, and hedging has become
much easier.

            I can't resist mentioning a related issue. When you talk to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>, they invariably claim that one of the great benefits of the
new currency will be "price transparency." Once all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> prices are quoted
in euros, it will be obvious to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> when a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is charging
more than its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> or vice versa--whereas it wouldn't be if the
prices were quoted in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">francs</NUMEX> and marks and had to be converted at the going
exchange rate. This claim always puzzles me: Here we are in the information
age, able to process gigabytes of data with a single mouse click--but we
imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't multiply and divide?

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> remaining question is that of currency
speculation--fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>, not the desire for efficiency, is what has
led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentina</ENAMEX> to talk seriously about replacing pesos with dollars and made
dollarization at least a topic of discussion elsewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>. But
while currency speculation may have had disastrous impacts in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>,
in others letting the currency drop seems to have been just what the doctor
ordered. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>'s floating dollar has apparently allowed the island
continent to sail almost unscathed through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis. Even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> it
appears that fears that a drop in the currency would bring back hyperinflation
were unwarranted. And to me, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazil</ENAMEX> both look a lot like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>: resource-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> a long way from anywhere, with no dominant
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Hemisphere</ENAMEX> trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. Economic logic suggests that in the long
run such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, if they can put their inflationary histories behind them,
have no business adopting the currency of a faraway <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which will not take
their interests into account.

            So let's recognize this current enthusiasm for
currency unification as what it is: an intellectual fad, not a deep insight. I
say let <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> currencies bloom. Well, maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 or 30</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
