
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Formula for Disaster</ENAMEX> 

            The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX>
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> pulled no punches in its assessment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 11 days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> campaign,
describing them as a "fiasco" in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. "At this stage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>
confronts the real possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> may end up with de facto control
of an ethnically cleansed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> takes responsibility for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX>
or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> would have lost before the challenge of a minor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>. This cannot be allowed. To lose would be to validate and entrench
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, dangerously strengthening militant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slav</ENAMEX> nationalism in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. It would be a betrayal of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
whose sole crime is their race. The refugee crisis would destabilise <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> would be exposed as a sham, and its military threat no more
than posturing. The security of the West and the central prop of the western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> would be humiliated," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attacking NATO</ENAMEX>'s lack of
commitment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> opined that "[s]o far <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> has prosecuted the
war as if its aim was no more than to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> a salutary smack, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in particular rating the risk of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military life before
the lives of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> whose condition is the explicit reason
for the intervention. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> has to raise its game, with all that implies
both in terms of acting on the ground militarily and of relieving the refugee
crisis." Surmising that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> is reluctant to
pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to step up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> commitment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> concluded
that "if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> wants to be a successful war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>, he must learn to be as ruthless."

            The 
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is "at risk of
being humiliated" and suggested that the only opportunity for success is the
use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. "The only way to ensure victory is for there to be
massive intervention. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> will have to guarantee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s independence,
making it in effect a protectorate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> will undoubtedly challenge this
violation of what they regard as their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX>. It will be a form of peace
and justice, but it will be fragile. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West</ENAMEX> must accept that it is going to
be there for a very long time." While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX>
                editorialized that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Europe Must Mobilize To Help the Refugees</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn Neeson</ENAMEX> articulated a much less charitable position in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
mass-circulation tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Star</ENAMEX> : "It's hard not to be moved by the
pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> streaming out of the war zone, especially the
terrified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. But have you spared a thought as to where they'll end up? Make
no mistake, they're headed here. Soon you won't be able to move for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head-scarfed women</ENAMEX> clutching wide-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and holding out their hands in
your direction. Of course, the majority have been through a hell we can only
imagine, but does that mean we have to swamp our already over-burdened welfare
state?"

            An op-ed piece in the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> recommended a return to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> model" for the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columnist Teddy Preuss</ENAMEX> concluded that a "solution will only be
found if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> will agree to implement the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> that can
prevent a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Balkan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">holocaust</ENAMEX>, the model created by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
which assured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> of peace in the whole of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>: autonomous
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> status for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>." Nevertheless, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preuss</ENAMEX> was pessimistic that
such an outcome would occur since "[c]ommon sense and the ability to see all
sides are qualities as plentiful in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, unfortunately, as they are in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> " In an exclusive interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> and
Mail
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX>, who is due to arrive in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, said, in regard to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict, that while
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> respects human rights, "we do not think that we can possibly disregard
the sovereignty of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world. And if military interventionism is
to be allowed in all the internal matters like a question of human rights of
any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, that will open a very bad precedent in the world." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu</ENAMEX> stressed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> expects the same theory of nonintervention to apply to the situation
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> views as a breakaway <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> that must ultimately be
returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s control.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> welcomed a new territory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> as
Nunavut was carved from the eastern part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northwest Territories</ENAMEX>. In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> said,
"At a time when the international scene offers us too many horrific images of
the intolerance and bullying that can govern relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> and
ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> is proving once again that intelligence and innovation,
when applied with good will, can almost always permit the accommodation of
difference." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Inuit</ENAMEX>, and in
the view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> , "This alone marks an important step
forward in relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guaranteeing</ENAMEX>, for instance, that when federal, provincial and territorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> meet, there will always be someone speaking for an aboriginal majority
somewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." Writing in the conservative 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post</ENAMEX>
                of
Cananda, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frum</ENAMEX> was less optimistic. He theorized that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s reliance on federal money from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ottawa</ENAMEX> will lead to misgovernment. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nunavut</ENAMEX> will be misgoverned not because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in charge are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Inuit</ENAMEX>, but because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> has adopted the same
system of governance as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss Tweed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> [or] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> ... Revenue from outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> minus an effective opposition plus a
co-opted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is a formula for disaster, regardless of whether the
government is controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Inuit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Sea Islanders</ENAMEX>."

             

             

         
      
   
