
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream Comes True</ENAMEX>

            Peace
hopes run highest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> both led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with upbeat
reports on the new flurry of diplomatic activity over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX>
quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joschka Fischer</ENAMEX> as saying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few days</TIMEX> will
be "decisive." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reported strong speculation that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf Scharping</ENAMEX> will be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>,
succeeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spaniard Javier Solana</ENAMEX>, who is expected to be appointed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> as
the first foreign policy supremo of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> title will
be "high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>" for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> foreign and security policy, but
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, he is already colloquially known as "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pesc</ENAMEX>" after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> acronym for the job.

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solana</ENAMEX> as an excellent choice for
a position that requires "both a sure-footed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-salesman</ENAMEX>." It
said, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solana</ENAMEX> will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> on the end of the telephone to take
calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> whose absence was always bemoaned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>." A front-page report
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune of Paris</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are confident that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solana</ENAMEX> "would
help guarantee that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> military cooperation fits with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and does not
challenge the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s primacy in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> security."

            Having
apparently forgotten that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only last week</TIMEX> they ruled out <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> as a negotiating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> because of his indictment for war
crimes, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> talks very
seriously. "Crunch talks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>" was the main headline in the liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> ,
which said the discussions will decide whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> halts the bombing or
launches a ground war. "Vital <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peace" said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> noted
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martti Ahtisaari</ENAMEX>, is
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> since the start of the bombing
campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX> and that "hopes were higher than at any time." But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Independent</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> lead
was the killing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s deputy air force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ljubisa</ENAMEX>
Velickovic, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> air raid. It called this a "success" to be weighed
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s continuing "blunders."

            
Another military blunder made the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. This was the death of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> shelling of a school
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s efforts to evict <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> from
the disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">territory</ENAMEX> entered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh day</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> led on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> repelling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cross-border raids that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> denied had taken
place. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX> led on a much-criticized statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Fernandes</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> would consider granting the
guerrillas safe passage back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernandes</ENAMEX> insisted that "all
those who have been pushed into our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, including their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, have to go back, dead or alive." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> press has generally advised
against any escalation of the war, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> ran an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> discounting a much-reported remark by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX> that "we will not hesitate to use any weapon in
our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> to defend our territorial integrity." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> was "crying nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. The nuclear gap between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> has widened in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s favor: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> may not mind sacrificing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few hundred</NUMEX> of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mercenaries</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> air strikes, but they are not
going to expose their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to needless risk."

            Back
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>: The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post of Canada</ENAMEX> ran a tough editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> saying that acceptance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s
position on the implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> peace plan would be "little better
than a surrender in stages. ... Rather than attempting to dictate the niggling
terms of peacekeeping, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> should be obliged to negotiate on the
broader subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s future as an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--which has not yet
been discussed at all," it said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> was equally tough.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s "purported acceptance" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> "general principles" is
"meaningless in itself, notable only as a hint of desperation," it said in an
editorial. The only reason for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> was "to
spell out exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> has to do to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s own clear demands in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX>." But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "still needs more clearly to be told, the truth is best
conveyed by bombs and by the speedy reinforcement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> on the
ground."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the other main stories were to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Soir</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> led with
the resignation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> scare over the
sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> containing high levels of cancer-causing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dioxins</ENAMEX>. The
story was given wide coverage throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> reporting on its front page that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> were planning
the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">416 Belgian</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and possibly also
from some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> that used contaminated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry feed pellets</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, a long-running controversy over genetically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">modified</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crops</ENAMEX> took on aspects of a constitutional battle after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> defied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> by publishing an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX> criticizing the regulations governing their production.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> has repeatedly insisted that genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> are safe, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the throne attacked the lack of independent scientific research and
said the regulations were not tough enough. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> is "infuriated" by government efforts to portray anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>
campaigners as hysterics. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soil Association</ENAMEX>, which campaigns
for organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> is also said to be upset by an article written by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s chief scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soil Association</ENAMEX> was run
by "ayatollahs" as a "theological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s Wenhui
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sang Lan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gymnast</ENAMEX> paralyzed at last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill Games</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, has accused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> of failing to help her. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sang</ENAMEX>
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Sports</ENAMEX>, assured her they would cover all costs
after a highly publicized vaulting accident <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21</TIMEX> left her with severe spinal
cord damage. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, they didn't produce <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX>," she told the paper.

         
      
   
