
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I don't know if that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> hrumphing about in-laws who won't visit, but let's say it wasn't. Still,
let me tell you my story: I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> who gets along nicely--I
thought--with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, but who refuses to enter their
apartment because they have hung a lewd picture of themselves, er, copulating
in the living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. They call it art, I am sure, but it is almost medical in
its detail.
            

            
               I like them, I like
their values, but I just cannot stand to see that picture. They must know how
it can bother a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> to see such a graphic representation; even if the
behavior is encouraged-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>, bring them on!--I don't have to see it.
And if they don't know it, they should. I thought I was avoiding a
confrontation but evidently not. I guess I will tell them ... even if that
wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> hrumphing. Thank you.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Garman</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Greg</ENAMEX>,

            Whether or not and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> certainly march to a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> ... perhaps one who
owns an adult bookstore.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is in your corner, and she is blushing. Art
it may be, but in such poor taste that one wonders what this young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> is
thinking and where is their judgment. Since you like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but do not
wish to see the image you describe, by all means articulate your discomfort and
suggest they throw a blanket over the "art" when you come to call, or
temporarily substitute a nice still life.

            By the way, this drama makes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Prudie</ENAMEX> feel
clairvoyant, because she answered the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who wrote that his in-laws
would not step foot in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>: "There is some little missing piece here." The
piece is that picture.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> outgrow their need to shock and that you can enjoy visits in each
other's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> soon.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, properly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have a question about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I recently started
dating. I am an attractive single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and he has spent a fair amount of time
getting to know me and taking me to nice dinners, dancing, etc. We laugh and
have great fun together and share many of the same interests. He has kissed me
and I feel that he is physically attracted to me. My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is that he seems
to have nearly all the characteristics of most gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that I know.
            

            
               This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was born in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, is wealthy, educated, well-traveled ... so I don't know if he is
exhibiting the lifestyles of the rich and famous--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> style--or is gay.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, he has more clothes than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> I know and loves to shop. He
doesn't like to watch sports. He doesn't like violent movies, just the sweet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> ones. He stays tanned and gets his hair colored. HE DRIES <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">FLOWERS</ENAMEX>! He
drops names of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that he likes, and a lot of them are
frequented by the gay community. (I know this because my late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was gay.)
I know he is open-minded and has gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, so surely, if he were gay or
bisexual, why would he hide it? I don't want to come right out and ask him
about his sexuality because if he hasn't "come out," then my asking him will
not be answered honestly by him anyway. I really like this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but my inner
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> is telling me he must be gay.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masculine Mystique</ENAMEX>? From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Cities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Masc</ENAMEX>,

            Your gentleman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> could be straight or gay, but
he is definitely effeminate. He could be highly repressed, he could want to use
you as cover, he could be in denial about being one of nature's bachelors, he
could see you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul mate</ENAMEX>, or he could genuinely want to build a
relationship with you.

            Since you do not want to
ask him outright (which you may want to reconsider) there is a piece of
furniture that could go a long way toward answering your question. It is called
a bed. If he shows no interest in going there with you, that's a pretty strong
indicator of where things are. That you felt he was physically attracted to you
from his kiss is something to consider. Your task now is to decide if you wish
to have him in your life as any of the following: a bisexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, a
platonic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, or a straight though swishy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, empirically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am often greeted with the salutation: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi</ENAMEX>,
how are you?" when I meet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in a crowded psychotherapy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> waiting
room used by many of us. I learned quickly not to reply with: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fine</ENAMEX>, how are
you?" Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would launch into their troubled lives no sooner than the
last word escaped my mouth.
            

            
               At any rate, now I
have trained myself to answer with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fine</ENAMEX>," or "OK." Would you advise on a more
appropriate reply please?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busted</ENAMEX> Confidence
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Bust</ENAMEX>,

            Your noncommittal
response "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fine</ENAMEX>" or "OK" is just right, in that it does not invite an answer. In
other words, your one word reply is the perfect verbal package ...
shrink-wrapped, as it were.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, psychologically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I'd appreciate your views on when it's time to
settle down and when it's time to settle. I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>, no looker, but reasonably
attractive, in good physical condition, well educated, and employed in a
challenging position that pays well. I regularly attend cultural events,
contribute to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> (both monetarily and through volunteering), and read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voraciously</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Not surprisingly, I would like to meet someone
with similar characteristics. When I actually do meet such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, I am not
afraid to express my interest. Unfortunately, I find my interest is almost
invariably unreciprocated. Equally unfortunately, I find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expressing
interest in me do not possess the qualities I seek in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               I am quite
comfortable as a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, but I would prefer to develop a personal
relationship with someone who can share my interests and characteristics. My
question to you is, at what point (if ever) does it make sense for someone to
abandon, wholly or partially, his or her search for an ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and settle
for someone with a less than complete set of assets?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Settlement-Minded in Our Nation's Capital</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Set</ENAMEX>,

            What a thoughtful problem to bring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>. You
sound extremely desirable, if not perfect, but obviously something is wrong. It
might be useful to ask a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, of either gender, from whence your
difficulty springs. Explain that it would be an act of helpful friendship to be
totally honest.

            The idea of settling is an interesting one. This
probably depends on how badly you wish to be part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instinct</ENAMEX> is to tell you to wait for someone who does seem just right. Prudie
also understands your wish to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">life à deux</ENAMEX> (which is why she has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rice</ENAMEX> marks, herself, from her various tries).

            It was comforting to read
that you are comfortable as a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Until someone wonderful comes
along, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes that, to quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauriac</ENAMEX>, you will "revel in the pleasure of
the unshared bed."

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, uncompromisingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Surely I am not
alone in my complaint: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">weeknights</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>, if there is any kind of game on
television, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is watching it. We have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, so I can't stick it
to him that he's ignoring the little ones, but I feel he is ignoring me--and
might better spend his time reading or socializing or going to different
events. What would you do?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annoyed</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pound Ridge</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ann</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would make popcorn. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMS</ENAMEX>,
why can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>? Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> sounds as though he's not particularly
interested in doing other things, so your best bet is to suggest something
you'd like to go do and ask if he's inclined to go with. If not, make your own
fun ... go out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, start a project, read a book.

            If it's a no-hoper and
the darling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> continues to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> himself in front of the tube, get into the
spirit of things. Don't cook. Order out. In fact, you could lay this blessing
on him: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino Vobiscum</ENAMEX> (The pizza <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s here).

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, poppingly

         
      
   
