
   
   
      
         
            <I>The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX></I> Strikes Back!

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). A
trickle of praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> after the first wave of
negative reviews. The film "offers a happy surprise: it's up to snuff," writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he Star Wars franchise
was funnier and scrappier when it was new. But it simply wasn't capable of
this." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> awards the film <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Travers</ENAMEX>' generally negative review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> concedes that
the movie is "loaded with cool stuff" and that "in terms of visual
sophistication ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> ranks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>." The majority continues to
slam the film. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gripes: 1</ENAMEX>) wooden acting, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) bad dialogue, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) confusing plot, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
weak storytelling. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a synopsis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s negative reviews and to
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review of the film in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notting Hill</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). Adoring early
reviews for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant</ENAMEX> romantic comedy that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Weddings</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Funeral , Part 2</ENAMEX>. Both films were written by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Curtis</ENAMEX> and both cover the same turf--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> falling for a ravishing but
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">distant American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--in this case <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>, who stretches to play ... a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">skittish Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">megastar</ENAMEX>. Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX> Schwarzbaum
calls the film "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">blithe</ENAMEX> and exhilarating," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>
calls it "utterly charming--and very smart." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roberts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site, here for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site, or here for information on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> neighborhood where the film is set.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse &</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Street</ENAMEX> Kidz
               ,by Jesse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camp</ENAMEX> (PGD/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are surprisingly kind to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">VJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Camp</ENAMEX>'s
foray into the world of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>. The sound is equal parts glam, punk, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX>,
and features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheap Trick guitarist Rick Nielsen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> gives it
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and says "believe it or not, his album is a genuinely rocking
detention-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blowout</ENAMEX>, a spew of motormouthed microwaved teen rebellion
upholding the noble legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Twisted Sister"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Sheffield</ENAMEX>). Many, though,
find the album as irritating as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camp</ENAMEX>'s goofy on-screen presence and call it
"ersatz rock--all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and poses" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Browne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ).
(Find out more about Jesse here.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woman: An Intimate Geography</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Angier</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>). Reviews--published and killed--of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angier</ENAMEX>'s feminist exploration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s biology stir up a
journalistic controversy about conflict of interest. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
published a review by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Yalom</ENAMEX> in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> review slot calling the book
"dazzling," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angier</ENAMEX> had positively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reviewed Yalom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A History of the Breast</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. Also, the
Times ' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> book review section killed a second review of the book, a
negative one by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helena Cronin</ENAMEX>. Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review Editor Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX> defended delivering the spike to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronin</ENAMEX>'s piece: "I didn't like the
tone of the review--I thought it was too snarky. ... And I thought the review
failed to address the whole range of the book." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronin</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angier</ENAMEX>'s book was "totally idiotic. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]he was so wrong-headed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> where I knew the science that, even if there were areas where she might
have been correct, I could no longer trust her." After killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronin</ENAMEX>'s review,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> ran a gushing review of the book ("it is a tour de
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>, a wonderful, entertaining and informative book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"--Abraham Verghese</ENAMEX>). But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also apologized for violating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' conflict-of-interest
policy by assigning the book review to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yalom</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Back to the
book: Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> give it a warm response--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Jacobs Brumberg</ENAMEX> writes
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angier</ENAMEX> "eviscerates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ... old saws: that
hard science must be boring and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> have no sense of humor." Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are put off by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angier</ENAMEX>'s ecstatic, florid prose. (Read the first
chapter here [requires free registration].)

            

               
                  Music for Torching
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.M. Homes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Weisbach</ENAMEX>
Books). Mainly positive reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homes</ENAMEX>' latest novel, which, like her other
work, is designed to outrage: A corporation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> gets genital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tattoos</ENAMEX>, a bored
suburban couple burn down their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on a whim, etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> find the
novel's transgressive bent a touch stale, but the pack praises it. The
Westchester, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, setting makes the story read like "Cheever <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on crack"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norah Vincent</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> will be talking about this
one" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkus Reviews</ENAMEX> ). (Read an excerpt of the novel here.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guide to Hunting and Fishing</ENAMEX>
               , by Melissa
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> love this collection of interconnected stories of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who navigates the worlds of love and dating from the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> to the age
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>. "[F]ast and funny with real moments of poignancy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahlin Chang</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ) and "one of those rare occasions when a highly touted book
fulfills the excitement" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> detect shades
of the single-gal dippiness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Jones</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary</ENAMEX> , but most say that
this is much more witty and sophisticated. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Coppola</ENAMEX> has hired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> to
write a screenplay of the book.) An overtly negative review in the New York
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Review</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Weaver</ENAMEX>, calls the tone "self-consciously
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humorous</ENAMEX>"; says the wit at times "disintegrates into cutesy one-liners"; and
complains that the stories are plagued by a "certain generic weariness."
(Read one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>'s stories, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Worst Thing</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Suburban Girl Could Imagine</ENAMEX>.")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Movie
            

            
               
                  Love
Letter
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Capshaw</ENAMEX> (a k a Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> in a so-so romantic comedy about an older divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose life is
changed by the discovery of a love letter. It's plagued by "bland dialogue and
dull sitcom acting," writes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
