
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equality Equation</ENAMEX>

            After all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> I am
still amazed at the persistence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in believing things that are unproved
or that are more complicated than they realize. My most recent example is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equity Day</ENAMEX>, called to protest the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s pay is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 74 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s. Pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equity Day</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 8</TIMEX>. Perhaps you missed it.

            Why make pay equity the
subject of a protest? Surely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pay Equity Day</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> don't think that
everyone should get the same pay. I'd guess that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX>'s pay is less
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74 percent</NUMEX> of the pay of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>. Why don't they protest that fact?
Presumably they would explain that they are more productive than my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX>. But the only evidence they have of their superior productivity is
the fact that someone is willing to pay them more than anyone is willing to pay
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX>.

            One might think that would be the end of the matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>
get paid more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> because someone is willing to pay them more, just as
Pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equity Day</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> are paid more than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX> because someone
is willing to do it.

            But, of course, that
isn't the end of the matter. If we accept productivity as a proper measure of
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should earn, we have to consider the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>'
willingness to pay is a wrong measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' productivity. It could be
wrong in either of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> senses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX> may have an incorrect estimate of the
relative productivities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Or, having a correct estimate of the
relative productivities, they may want to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> less than their
productivity merits because they have some prejudice against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the
workplace.

            In a perfect world we could compare the relative earnings
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with their relative productivity. But there is no good way to
measure relative productivity--at least, no better way than looking at relative
earnings, which only leads us back to where we started. So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of the
subject approach it indirectly, comparing the earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are
similar in the respects that contribute to productivity: They compare the
incomes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of the same age, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same years</TIMEX> of work experience,
the same years of education, and in jobs of the same stress, riskiness, and
difficulty. When they do, they generally find that the gender gap in earnings
remains but is smaller than the gap for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in total. But the results
are difficult to interpret. The number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> devoted to education and the
number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of experience, for example, do not make the same contribution
to productivity. And it is never possible to be sure that you have taken
account of all the factors that determine productivity.

            Suppose you compared the earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and women
who are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, all childless, and all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Review</ENAMEX> graduates
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School</ENAMEX>, and found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s earnings are higher than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s. (I'm making this up.) Would this mean that there is discrimination
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>? We would also find that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in this category do not
earn the same salary. There is something, some <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X Factor</ENAMEX>, other than the
conditions I have listed and other than gender, which explains the difference
in salaries among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. But if this <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X Factor</ENAMEX> is unequally shared by men
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, there will be a difference in the average earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and women
that does not reflect discrimination.

            Maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X Factor</ENAMEX> is
height. A taller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> can reach the books on the top shelf without a ladder.
If all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were paid the same as all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of the same height, the average pay
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would be higher than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> because the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is taller.
But there would be no discrimination.

            Much of what we know about the economic status of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is
summarized in an excellent monograph by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Furchtgott-Roth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine</ENAMEX>
Stolba, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's</ENAMEX> Figures: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Progress of Women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> . One
striking fact presented there is that childless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 30</TIMEX> earn <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX>
as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> at the same age, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> earn <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 75 percent</NUMEX> as much as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. This suggests that the relatively low earnings of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are related
to their relatively low productivity because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-bearing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-rearing
interferes with their productivity in the marketplace. But another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> may be
at work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> who can command earnings that are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> as high as those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> may decide not to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rather than forgo those earnings. We don't
know how the earnings of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> compare with their productivity. If their
productivity is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> higher than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the fact that they are paid
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5 percent</NUMEX> less would not show that there is little discrimination.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gaps</ENAMEX> involved in this
discussion:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The gap between the earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The gap between the earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and their
productivity.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The gap between the
productivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and the productivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            There is plenty of evidence that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> gap has been
declining--fairly rapidly by historical standards. There is no good way to
measure the gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s earnings and their productivity, but it is
reasonable to say that their earnings have risen pretty much in line with their
productivity. At least, it seems clear that the earnings of the total labor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> have risen pretty much in line with productivity (output per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hour</NUMEX> of
work) when measured correctly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> are so large a part of the labor force
that it is hard to believe that this could be true of the total if it were not
also true of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. If the gap between the earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> is
declining, and if the earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are rising in line with their
productivity, it follows that the productivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> has been rising
relative to the productivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. That would be consistent with what we know
about changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s education and their distribution
among occupations.

            Whether this combination of facts and speculation
is grounds for demonstrations of protest is a matter of taste.

            I think there is a problem lurking here, but it is
not the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> have been protesting. In an earlier age, when
incomes in the market were lower than they are now, the cost to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> of
forgoing market employment in order to stay home and care for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was also
lower than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. And when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wage gap was lower, the clear choice
was for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to stay home and look after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. But given higher
market incomes, having and rearing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is more expensive in terms of
forgone income. And with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wage gap narrowed it has become less
clear how the staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> should be divided between the mother
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. This problem of family life is not a result of incomes being
too low or the wage gap being too big. It is rather the reverse.

         
      
   
