
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">232</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Summoning DiMaggio's Ghost</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               The list includes whistling, making certain hand gestures, and carrying
bottles, baseball bats, or flashlights. List of what?
            

             

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 231</ENAMEX>)-- "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ultracolossal":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               An announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> roiled the world of the superjumbo. Who plans to
do what?
            

            "In a
concession to economy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long Dong Silver</ENAMEX> is downsizing, but he promises to
continue his fine work under the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medium Dong Silver</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Steinkohl</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> plans to reclassify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 9</TIMEX> as carry-on luggage. They must be
stowed in overhead storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compartments</ENAMEX> or slipped neatly under the
seat."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Marcus</ENAMEX>
            

            
"7-Eleven plans to recall <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> cups designed to hold its newest
extra-extra-large <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'The Big-Ass Gulp</ENAMEX>,' after it was discovered that a
printing error had placed the hyphen between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'Ass' and 'Gulp'</ENAMEX> "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> announced that in the new incarnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> , fat is no longer a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feminist</ENAMEX> issue. 'No wonder we couldn't sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinem</ENAMEX> said. 'This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> around, it's all about thin thighs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> butts.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            
"Superjumbo? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superjumbo</ENAMEX>? Well, I'm sure as hell not buying Jumbo
anymore!!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Shuger</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fat</ENAMEX>
Wrap-Up
            

            Posing this question meant risking fat jokes, but
mercifully most of you steered clear. The fat joke assumes that the body is a
physical manifestation of the mind, an outward sign of inward gracelessness. It
assumes that weight is volitional, that the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> chooses to be fat--i.e.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lazy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy</ENAMEX>, undisciplined, self-indulgent--and thus ought to be mocked. Not
so, of course. Like most things about the human body, genetics play all too
indomitable a part. Unless the human is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Anderson</ENAMEX>. She's still classified
as human, right? After the surgery and all?

            Much is made of the
modern focus on weight, but it's an old form of unkindness. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Orwell</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> novel Coming up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> , the protagonist muses on how years of such
mockery transform a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>:

            
               I've been both fat and thin in my life, and
I know the difference fatness makes to our outlook. It kind of prevents you
from taking things too hard. I doubt whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's never been anything
but fat, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's been called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatty</ENAMEX> ever since he could walk, even knows of
the existence of any really deep emotions. How could he? He's got no experience
of such things. He can't ever be present at a tragic scene, because a scene
where there's a fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> present isn't tragic, it's comic. Just imagine a fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamlet, for instance</ENAMEX>! Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Hardy</ENAMEX> acting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo</ENAMEX>.
            

            This was, of course, not
meant to be good news. But what is?

            
               Massive Capacity
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everything Except Pleasure Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> may develop an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-passenger</ENAMEX> airplane.

            Fending off rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus Industrie</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will invest <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> either to build a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX>-seat version of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">747</NUMEX> or
to start from scratch on something even bigger and more uncomfortable. Current
versions of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">747</NUMEX> seat between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272 and 386</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, depending on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">configuration</ENAMEX> and how much the pilot is distracted by pathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">whimpering</ENAMEX> akin
to that of caged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.

            In a countermove, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> announced plans to
build <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A318</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">107</NUMEX>-seat passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> that will pose a challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">737</NUMEX>, a still-popular commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> derived from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>'s technology.

            And in a countermove to superjumbo fat jokes, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> has approved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman-LaRoche</ENAMEX>'s orlistat, the first
in a new class of anti-obesity <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s absorption of
dietary fat.

            
               Errata
            

            Due to an editing error,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Afternoon Delivery</ENAMEX> ran the wrong quiz question. Sorry. Those
interested can write in for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s name and a detailed map to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Positioning Thingy</ENAMEX>--it's a marvel!

            
               Roiled Riled
Retort
            

            What? It's a perfectly
fine word! What's the problem?

            
               Common
Denominators
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) fast-food portion control, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
penis size, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) breast size.

         
      
   
