
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' reactions cover the spectrum.
The story, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer Hickam Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">memoir Rocket Boys</ENAMEX> , follows a few
backwoods <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> who use amateur rocketry as a steppingstone to
college scholarships and an escape from the coal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> where their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
work. Those who praise the film say it's "one of the most unfashionable movies
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>, and one of the most appealing. Made with a gee-whiz
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earnestness</ENAMEX> and simplicity that's so out of style it's refreshing" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
Turan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Others are more wary of the movie's
syrupy core: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> says the film is "borderline corny, but I was held by
it; I was even moved by it" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
                "agreeably guileless for such a manipulative genre." The
most critical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> call it predictable: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he visuals, the dialogue, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sentiments</ENAMEX>, all seem lifted right out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boy Scout Handbook</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visit Hickam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>'s Web page to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>
reaction to the film.)

            

               
                  Jawbreaker
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TriStar Pictures</ENAMEX>). "Feeble" and
"inadequate even by lazy-pastiche standards" is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Lim</ENAMEX> of the
Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> describes this mean teen movie about a posse of cruel
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who accidentally kill one of their own and try to cover it up.
Although it pitches itself as an hommage to films such as
Heathers , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clueless</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darren Stein</ENAMEX> "can't decide whether he's satirizing his demon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heroines</ENAMEX>' homicidal indifference or celebrating it" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The film has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> things worth looking at:
the eye-popping costumes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose McGowan</ENAMEX>, who has the part of the
bitch-goddess down pat. (Read this article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGowan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>, in
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>. )

            
               
                  Office
Space
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). Good reviews for the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beavis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butt</ENAMEX>-head and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> . "Bristling with shrewd
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX>, inspired humor and all-around smarts," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . The subject is the soul-crushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monotony</ENAMEX> of life in
a corporate cubicle, and how a few drones manage to shake things up. The only
negative reviews come from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who write for big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> --which
makes you wonder if they've got so successful they've forgotten the torture a
jammed copy machine can inflict on the lowly. (The official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> has a variety of
screensavers you can download to brighten up your own cubicle.)

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot</ENAMEX>
Rock
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleater-Kinney</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kill Rock Stars</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> album from
the hard-rocking female punk rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, gets great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his cerebral album ... is a striking countermelody to the junk that now
passes as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Top-40</ENAMEX> rock" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher John Farley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). After years on
the indie scene, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> is now receiving praise everywhere from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone to Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> , whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Hermes</ENAMEX> asks, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX>
Sleater-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinney</ENAMEX> the greatest rock & roll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>?" and gives the
album an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> The only sour note comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Cromelin, who finds some of the songs cold, tight, and remote. (Listen to samples from their latest album courtesy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> .)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  Traveling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercies</ENAMEX>: Some Thoughts on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Lamott</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon Books</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Lynn Grossman</ENAMEX> sums up the responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamott's</ENAMEX> collection of essays on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>: "Either you recognize your own personal truths in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lamott</ENAMEX>'s highly
personal epiphanies ... [o]r she makes you spit, sputter, and slam things. You
don't find it remotely enlightening to share relentless intimacy with someone
so angry, self-righteous and strange--and so proud of being candid" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call the collection "funny, warm and sagacious"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regina Marler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ), but there are a few who condemn
it as self-absorbed. (Read an excerpt here.)

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elegant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Universe: Superstrings, Hidden Dimensions, and the Quest for the Ultimate</ENAMEX>
Theory
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian R. Greene</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.W. Norton & Co.</ENAMEX>). Excellent
reviews for math and physics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Greene</ENAMEX>'s explanation of the basics
of string theory, currently the most popular "theory of everything," cited as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of reconciling the otherwise incompatible theories of general relativity
and quantum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> compare him to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hawking</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Feynman</ENAMEX> for his ability to make complicated problems of physics
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensible</ENAMEX> to the lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX>. "He has a rare ability to explain even
the most evanescent ideas in a way that gives at least the illusion of
understanding, enough of a mental toehold to get on with the climb" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, courtesy of the New York
Times --free registration required.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Blast From the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Past</TIMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Message in a Bottle ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Favorite Martian</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testament</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haruki</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  Death <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of a Salesman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene O'Neill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

            :

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Payback</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simply Irresistible</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Rushmore ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry Cleaning</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werewolves</ENAMEX> in Their Youth , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chabon</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- You're a Good Man</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  She's All That ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">24 Hour Woman</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Still <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- My Name Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Mothers Didn't Tell Us: Why Happiness</ENAMEX>
Eludes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Woman</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Crittenden</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabelle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Strout</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heavy Water</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie
                  --
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --
                  Playing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another Day</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Face-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Tarloff</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Miss Nobody , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomek Tryzna</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
