
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> newly behind us, a question
begs for resolution. It's common knowledge that many big box office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> often
borrow glittery gems for special occasions from the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Winston</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX> At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globe Awards</ENAMEX>, in pixel-perfect color viewed from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barcaloungers</ENAMEX> around the world, we all gasped in horror when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Redgrave</ENAMEX> (the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> now embroiled in an almost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kentuckian</ENAMEX> divorce drama) lost an earring.
There, in front of the breathless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>, it fell from her ear while she, being
the consummate professional, continued without even seeming to notice. One
might have assumed that as soon as the camera panned elsewhere, she scooped up
the errant earring. However, for the rest of the event she was photographed
with only one earring.
            

            
               My question is this: Did she find the earring?
Was it borrowed or her own? Ah, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the good old days</TIMEX> when there was no doubt
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX> were her own.
            

            
               Teleficially
yours,
            

            

               --S.D.
            

            

               P.S.: Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is free once again, do I have to return my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groovy</ENAMEX> umbrella?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear S.</ENAMEX>,

            What an amusing
"problem" to offer Prudie ... who of course has no idea whether Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX>'s
errant earring was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) retrieved or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) borrowed. Just to free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
herself, loves jewelry and is known to intimates as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sparkle Plenty</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jewelers</ENAMEX> have ever offered to lend her any baubles.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, sparklingly

            P.S.:
Consider the groovy umbrella a keepsake from the Messrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               To return to the ""
discussion, my favorite response is "I'm told I'm great!" Gets a laugh every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">f.f.f.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear f.</ENAMEX>,

            Tres charmante, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">risqué</ENAMEX>, aussi.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, responsively

            
               
                  Dear
Prue,
               
            

            
               I have an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> whom I dearly love who was
my roomie in college. We talk on the phone often and try to get together
regularly--shopping, dinner, etc.
            

            
               The only problem is
when she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> invite me over to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. It's filthy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgusting</ENAMEX>! Cats crawl all over you, and the noxious fumes of the litter box
are enough to make you lose your appetite--or worse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> sink is filled
with dishes that have been there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> on end. From having lived with her
before, I always knew she was a clutter-bug but not unsanitary. I invite them
over to my place as often as possible, but I can only refuse going to theirs so
much before their feelings get hurt. How can I handle this?
            

            

               --Nauseously Yours
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Nause</ENAMEX>,

            No one should be burdened by having to hold his
nose when paying a social call. Prudie offers you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways to proceed. If you
are feeling faint of heart about leveling with your chum, simply refuse to
convene at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> have taken over. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would hope, however,
that you would take a more direct approach, which might actually be doing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kindness</ENAMEX>. Since you and this longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> have a history of warmth and
friendship, why not tell her the conditions in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> are way beyond the
"clutter-bug" stage, and you are worried about her health.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has always felt there is something a little
nutty about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are able to ignore an extreme mess and the sensibilities
of others. In the spirit of constructive advice, a word from you might focus
her attention and remedy the situation. If not, simply state that you can no
longer be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> to her home.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, hopefully

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am about to launch
a campaign for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. I would appreciate advice on how best to share
details of my life with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. I grew up poor. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (from another
country) had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighth</NUMEX>-grade education and raised <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on her own. As
a result of poverty we were homeless a few times, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> spent some time
in foster care. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> we are all doing well. I have been able to achieve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX>--a great postgraduate education, a good job, civic achievement,
and a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. I think this is an inspiring story of what is right
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. My problem is that I want to avoid seeming as though I want
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to feel sorry for me because of the deprivations of my youth. At the
same time, I do want some credit for being able to overcome some serious
challenges. How do you think I should handle this information?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> With a Dilemma
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dem</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks you should relay this information in
your campaign speeches and literature just as you have in your letter. Your
remark about your personal history illustrating what is right with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is
the perfect approach. You would only elicit sympathy if the deck stacked
against you had caused you to fold your hand.

            Everybody loves a success
story, and triumph over adversity is always uplifting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> wishes you
victory and, with luck, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> who prepped at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Paul's</ENAMEX> before going on
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, strategically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am constantly fighting the battle of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bulge</ENAMEX>. Everyone in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX>. I, however, am determined to lose
weight and keep it off. The keeping it off is the problem. When I eat at home I
can control what's going on. When in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, I can somewhat control
things. When at dinner parties, however, I am totally at the mercy of the
menu.
            

            
               Do you have any
ideas for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in my situation? I know we must be legion.
            

            

               --Fighting Being a Butterball
            

            Dear Fight,

            Short of bringing your own dinner in a paper bag
(only acceptable for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Channing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with severe food restrictions),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you incorporate the following <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ploys: Do not finish
everything you are served, and push the unconsumed portion around on your
plate.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is becoming aware
of more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having a bite or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of desert, for example, and then
eating no more. And she is sympathetic to your plight. For some reason, even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostesses</ENAMEX> who themselves try to eat nutritiously feel that dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> fare
requires a feast, where everything on the plate is essentially a butter
sculpture.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, sparingly

         
      
   
