
   
   
      
         
            Tame at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX>

            Why do big<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-studio</ENAMEX> movies that celebrate wildness
and primal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and equate civilization with corruption tend to play as if their
plots have been hammered out by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> on car phones? And why do
those pictures always feel as if they've been honed with the help of focus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in suburban shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> to ensure that no aspect will be jarring to
the middlest of middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instinct</ENAMEX> is the newest specimen of
commercially overprocessed primitivism. The film, which purports to explore the
circumstances under which a celebrated anthropologist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Powell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX>), disappeared among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> and emerged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mute</ENAMEX> and wild-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> of park <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rangers</ENAMEX>, is loaded with radical credos--ideas
evocative of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX>, deep ecology, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dian Fossey</ENAMEX> at her most gorillaphilic.
But every one of those conceits is rendered toothless by a form of storytelling
that's the opposite of instinctual. The more subversive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instinct</ENAMEX> gets in
proclaiming free will an illusion fostered by a rigidly repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>, the
more captive it seems to a rigidly repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instinct</ENAMEX> is
"inspired" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Quinn</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> cult novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ishmael</ENAMEX> , which is largely a
Socratic, telepathic dialogue between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX>, the latter of whom
hectors the former about the destructive path of modern society and restates
the history of the world as a struggle between "leavers" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, wise nomadic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tribes</ENAMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>" (mostly white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>). Someone must have spent a fortune to
option <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX>'s book before concluding that an interspecies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socratic</ENAMEX>, telepathic
dialogue with huge chunks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> First! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manifesto</ENAMEX> wouldn't burn up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">box</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald DiPego</ENAMEX> was brought in to fashion a story
around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX>'s core principles. (The movie would have been more fun, though, if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiPego</ENAMEX> had left in a token telepathic ape. Maybe just for a prologue: "Gimme
that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> and I'll tell you the story of my old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Powell</ENAMEX>. What a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> ...")

            Anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instinct</ENAMEX> is built around that theater
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">standby</ENAMEX>, the series of charged encounters between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> and a shackled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, during which it dawns on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuba</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gooding Jr.</ENAMEX>) that he and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> are the ones who are actually in need of curing. (Come to think of it,
the first <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> play I ever saw, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equus</ENAMEX> , featured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> in the role
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shrink</ENAMEX> who concludes that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who blinded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> horses with a metal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spike</ENAMEX> has a passion sadly lacking in his sterile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX>.) The ambitious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gooding</ENAMEX>'s first challenge is to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX>, sedated and under heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harmony Bay Correctional Facility</ENAMEX>, to speak. It seems to me that his
next challenge is to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> to shut up, since with relatively little
prodding the ex-mute wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> launches into a stream of resonant orations about
life among the silverbacks: "Did they think of me? I thought of them. ... It
was terrifying and wonderful ... I was coming back to something I had lost a
long time ago and was only now remembering." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Elfman</ENAMEX> puts a swelling choir
on the soundtrack to help us remember those same things--i.e., awestruck
countercultural jungle movies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Emerald Forest</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>) and

            
               Instinct recycles a lot of countercultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">touchstones</ENAMEX>--the lovable psychotics out of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Flew Over the Cuckoo's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nest</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>), the fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cool Hand Luke</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>). "He
lives with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, takes on their behavior, becomes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them," says
Gooding, seemingly on the verge of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctor Dolittle</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>).
"He can give me a look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at his primitive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--ungoverned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">giggle</ENAMEX>, but the idea of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> learning the secrets of the
Dark Continent from a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60-plus</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Welsh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> has its daft charm: "He's
leading me into the jungle," concludes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gooding</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maura Tierney</ENAMEX>, playing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX>'
estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, listens to Gooding talk and struggles to keep her emotions
in check, smoking intensely while her eyes water and her chin quivers. Will she
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gooding</ENAMEX> do the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild Thing</ENAMEX>? No; perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> focus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> turned thumbs
down on interracial romance. Back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gooding</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headlock</ENAMEX> and gives him an intellectual noogie: What has he lost, now that he
has been immobilized by a senior citizen? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>? No: No one has control.
Freedom? No: No one is free. The answer is supposed to be his "illusions"--but
more likely it's whatever remains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gooding</ENAMEX>'s credibility as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>.

            If nothing else, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Turteltaub</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phenomenon</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> from
drifting into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. A raw-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Aylward</ENAMEX> does a good job of
making the warden--a malignly neglectful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX>--recognizably human, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashton</ENAMEX> plays the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villain</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dacks</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose
cruelty arises out of an obsession with control: What makes him scary is his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">watchfulness</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turteltaub</ENAMEX>'s technique is otherwise too slick for his
supposedly primal subject. The larger problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instinct</ENAMEX> doesn't
have the courage to leave its natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> untamed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> are
pussycats, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> isn't a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> after all. He killed a couple of
Rwandan park <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rangers</ENAMEX> in defense of his adorable ape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--which makes the
movie a de facto vigilante picture and thus as mainstream a product as any that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> churns out. "You taught me to live outside the game," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gooding</ENAMEX>,
his eyes misting up. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instinct</ENAMEX> is the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>.

            For true instinct, you must turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Figgis</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leaving Las Vegas</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Night Stand</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>) who's
defiantly not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and whose pixilated, semi-autobiographical,
semi-allegorical The Loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexual Innocence</ENAMEX> would not have got past
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that evidently embraced Instinct . It nearly didn't
get past the screening that I caught at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s indie-friendly Angelika
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film Center</ENAMEX>, which was marked by uneasy throat clearing and lots of walkouts.
What the hell is this thing?

            In the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX> and
Eve show up at intervals looking like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX> models: He (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Femi Ogumbanjo</ENAMEX>)
is black and muscular, she (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanne Klintoe</ENAMEX>) is waiflike and flaxen-haired with
an expensive-looking coif. They emerge naked from golden <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> into a
yellowish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> landscape, explore each other's orifices, and recline beside
a white stallion and in range of a (disappointingly ordinary) snake. At the
end, they eat squishy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>, vomit, and are set upon by paparazzi .

            Before that, seminal episodes of disillusionment, jealousy,
and betrayal are recalled by the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Julian Sands</ENAMEX>). As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lad</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, he peers through a window at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> practicing her
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in lingerie for a drowsing old white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervert</ENAMEX>. Cut to an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
landscape from which all color has been drained, and where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nic</ENAMEX> is a skinny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-ager</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rhys-Meyers</ENAMEX>) whose pubescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> drunkenly cheats on
him during her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s wake. Sex and death are forever entwined: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nic</ENAMEX> sees
photos of a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> stabbed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> bloated after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
in a river. As a grown-up, he drives through the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> countryside
beside a frostily pissed-off blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, whom he subsequently takes from behind
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> cottage while his young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, clutching a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animal</ENAMEX>, wanders their way. Figgis shoots all this through windows to
make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s alienation palpable.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> dreams of coming upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nic</ENAMEX> in a jazz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">combo</ENAMEX>, then dancing half-naked for old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nic</ENAMEX> dreams of being dogged at a
train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> by a gangly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cretin</ENAMEX> who then stabs him. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> rises up
to meet his falling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, he sees himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> walk into their country
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cottage</ENAMEX> and close the door. Cut to a shot of newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>, who are then
separated and grow up to be the lush <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saffron Burrows</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> nearly meet each other in an airport, but fate keeps them from
connecting. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> twin drives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nic</ENAMEX>--who turns out to be a documentary film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>--to the desert of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tunisia</ENAMEX>, where there is further betrayal, loss of
sexual innocence, exploitation of Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>, and a tragic
retaliation. The soundtrack is melancholy classical piano.

            That The Loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexual Innocence</ENAMEX> doesn't gel
is a point too obvious to belabor. Much of it is risible, yet I loved watching
it--not because I thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> was wearing new clothes but because
I thought he looked fine--beautiful, actually--naked. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figgis</ENAMEX>' camera is probing
and alive, so that even when his meanings are laughable, his images remain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allusive</ENAMEX> and mysterious. What can I say? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> gives good movie.

         
      
   
