
   
   
      
         
             Cody Shearer

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Matthews</ENAMEX> interviewed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardball</ENAMEX> , the cable program that aspires to be
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals what <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> was to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> crisis
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert MacNeil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> show was to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. Casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> may have thought
they were watching some kind of "best of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monicagate</ENAMEX>" retrospective--isn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> awfully <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>? But to conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Flytrap</ENAMEX> trivia
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffs</ENAMEX>, and media <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> for whom the end of the scandal is likely to mean
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extinction</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s re-emergence yielded a small, ambiguous, but nonetheless
tantalizing tidbit.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8 last year</TIMEX>, shortly before she was to
testify in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> reportedly had a frightening encounter
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jogger</ENAMEX> near her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>--a complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> who
nonetheless seemed to know quite a bit about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and
her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> declined to identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hardball</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, she said, had asked her not to--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> seemed to have a
pretty good idea who he was. "Is it someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>?" He pressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>. "Is it somebody related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX>? Is it a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shearer?</ENAMEX>"

            What's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shearer</ENAMEX>, you
ask? A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a semi-prominent journalistic/political family
connected to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> in a number of ways. To hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-haters,
these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> are evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s true political colors--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX>-democratic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Left</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McGovernite</ENAMEX>, anti-free-enterprise, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>-hating
tendencies he has so brilliantly camouflaged.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearers</ENAMEX> are also the kind of people <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
mugwumps despise most viscerally: privileged, socially and professionally
ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX> whose liberal-left politics don't prevent them from
enjoying the prerogatives of membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Shearer</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>, was for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, which, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> era, interspersed its celebrity profiles and
sensible recipes with anxious warnings about the dangers of the nuclear arms
race. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occidental College</ENAMEX>, served in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> and then as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX> also
co-authored a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Democracy</ENAMEX> , which served as something
of a manifesto for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hayden</ENAMEX> when the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDSer</ENAMEX> abandoned radicalism for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>. Worse yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yannatta Goldway</ENAMEX>, was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> on a
pro-rent-control ticket. To a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern California Republican</ENAMEX>, this is like
saying she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX> worked on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and is married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, long suspected by
the right of being soft on communism. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> did not suggest that any of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shearers</ENAMEX> were stalking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> in a quiet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> subdivision on
a damp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> in question, he declared, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX>'s twin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cody</ENAMEX>.

            This is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Shearer</ENAMEX>'s name has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">floated</ENAMEX> to the top of the murky <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX> of supposition, innuendo, and sleaze that
passes for political discourse in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Conason</ENAMEX>, who debunks
rumors about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his circle with the same dogged zeal with which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> advances them, defended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> in a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> column.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> could not have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>'s stalker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conason</ENAMEX> declared, because he was
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three days later</TIMEX>, flying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, Shearer
happened to bump into his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Christopher</ENAMEX>. And as a result of being smeared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conason</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> had been subject to death threats and
other forms of terror. (The most disturbing instance was the appearance, a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>' interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> aired, of an armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on Cody
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawn</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who later surrendered, turned out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brother Hank</ENAMEX>. Go figure.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> has since apologized for mentioning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s name on the air.

            For his part, Conason
declined to explain why the bare possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the
harassment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> was so gleefully seized upon by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s own designated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harassers</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Shearer</ENAMEX> did not exist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mellon Scaife</ENAMEX> would have
given someone a grant to invent him. Or maybe, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Harvey Oswald in Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeLillo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libra , Shearer</ENAMEX> is both real and invented--a creature of
multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coincidences</ENAMEX> who seems at the same time to be operating in the service
of a grand, impenetrable design. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the vast right-wing conspiracy
talk about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> in the vast left-wing conspiracy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cody Shearer</ENAMEX>'s
name is bound to come up sooner or later.

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> unfairly sucked into the
vortex of public scandal? If so, the vortex is awfully good at finding him. In
published reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> is most often described as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> or a
free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. His byline has been rather scarce during most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>. Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> he co-wrote, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell Glen</ENAMEX>, a syndicated column on
politics and culture, which addressed such motley topics as trucking
deregulation and the ill effects of skin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> on the male libido. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>,
the column dug up several embarrassing incidents of drunkenness in the past of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tower</ENAMEX>, whose nomination to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense was derailed by
questions about his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> and sexual irresponsibility.

            A conspiracy theorist
might infer that in helping to sink <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> was already acting as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat</ENAMEX>'s paw of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> dirty tricks operation--or, at least, that the Tower
affair whetted his appetite for political dirt-digging and skullduggery. In any
world--through the unlikely medium of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doonesbury</ENAMEX> --to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Kimberlin</ENAMEX>.
Kimberlin, you may recall, was the convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX>, habitual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">all-around</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociopath</ENAMEX> who claimed to have sold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>. Was Shearer
acting on behalf of the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "opposition research" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, which
had floated damaging rumors during the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'92</NUMEX> primaries about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX>' health
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use? Or was he just an enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-lancer</ENAMEX>?

            A similar question arose during <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>'s long,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>, and inconclusive hearings into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
campaign fund-raising shenanigans. There, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s name popped up in the
course of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX>' angry questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Lenzner</ENAMEX>, the private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> who would later, in the thick of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>/Willey/Who
Knows Who Else matter, be accused (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, among others) of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coordinating</ENAMEX> efforts to smear and intimidate those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX> had
apparently acted as a liaison between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenzner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investigative Group</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheyenne-Arapaho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> had donated more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>, hoping, according to testimony, that the
administration would intervene on its behalf in a dispute over drilling rights
on tribal land. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenzner</ENAMEX> had been retained to uncover compromising links between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickles</ENAMEX>--who opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>'s claims--and local oil interests. Lenzner,
while he admitted that he had accepted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>'s retainer, has denied that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Shearer</ENAMEX> had ever worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGI</ENAMEX>--though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> did once employ his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s efforts as a free-lance political fixer
have not been limited to domestic affairs. Much to the embarrassment of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> and the consternation of others in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>, details
have recently emerged about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s efforts, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996 and 1997</TIMEX>, to arrange for
Bosnian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX> to surrender to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crimes Tribunal</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX>. According to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> took less than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> from an associate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karadzic's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1997</TIMEX>. Accounts
vary as to what happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX>, but it appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> was either duped by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> or double-crossed by them. Karadzic, as the saying goes, is still at
large.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Shearer</ENAMEX> is a man
with many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>, able to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheyennes</ENAMEX> and,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unintentionally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-haters that he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who
makes things happen. But he may just be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who things happen to happen
to, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with a penchant for pretending to be what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> want to believe that
he is. Every time he turns up on the scene--and even when (as in the case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>) he doesn't--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ask: What's he doing here? He probably asks
himself the same question.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note:
Several errors in this piece as originally posted have been corrected. Click to
read a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> criticizing the original version.
               
            

         
      
   
