
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehall</ENAMEX> No Longer?

            The top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> story is a
massive strengthening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s anti-racism laws. As a result of a
report on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Lawrence</ENAMEX>, a young black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose murder was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poorly</ENAMEX> responded to and inadequately investigated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, Home Secretary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Straw</ENAMEX> declared all-out war on racist government action. Calling the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> case "a catalyst" and "a watershed," he announced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> will now be personally and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminally</ENAMEX> liable for any
expressions of the "institutional racism" common in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> life. Nevertheless,
the reforms are less aggressive than those sought by the independent commission
that investigated the case. The 
                  Times
                reports that those recommendations would
make "racist language or behaviour" criminal and would allow racial attacks to
be defined by the victim not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> (if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> says they're racist,
they are).

            Despite calls by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> for his resignation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Metropolitan Police</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Condon</ENAMEX> is staying in office. He conveyed his "sense of
shame" and vowed to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> into "an anti-racist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>." The

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
                stresses the drama and context of the changes:
It's the first major anti-racist legislation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> and will cover "any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long-established</ENAMEX>, white-dominated organisation which is liable to have
procedures, practices and a culture which tend to exclude or to disadvantage
non-white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening Standard</ENAMEX>
                relays an embarrassing postscript to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straw</ENAMEX>'s announcement:
He had to withdraw a thick chunk of the already published report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
because it contained the names and addresses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">informants</ENAMEX> who
assisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> calls the information "the most sensitive
that could be imagined to be involved in any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> investigation" and surmises
that those mentioned could already be in danger. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> also
reports that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> after the report was published, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memorial</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> was defaced with paint. The vandals were not caught
because a security camera trained on the memorial was not loaded with
videotape.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers keep a
troubled eye on yet more avalanches in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX> and the rescue attempts they
are delaying. Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX> were digging out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s avalanche
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, another hit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, decimating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The death toll is
still climbing, but all agree that this is the worst avalanche season in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> paper 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neue Zürcher Zeitung</ENAMEX>
                nervously watches smaller, and so
far nonlethal, avalanches in the Swiss neck of the mountains. Most of the
accounts are morose, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> opines that the
Alps are exacting revenge on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy tourists</ENAMEX> for exploiting their natural
beauty.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> news, fresh ripples and rumors about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>'s future plans: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>'s 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX>
               
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> appears to have dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faisal</ENAMEX>
Husseini, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> affairs and, until
now, a name high on his list of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Husseini</ENAMEX> denies that he's
been ousted, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> has already cut off his funding and handed his
portfolio to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. The paper mentions "disputes" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> and
Husseini but gives no specific reason for his dismissal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quotes Arafat</ENAMEX> as saying that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> will be chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in an election.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Ahram</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> is giving new consideration to
the prospect of an official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX>. Given the
recent transfer of power in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> elections, and his
self-imposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX> deadline for declaring a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, the link with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> could help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> consolidate ever-slippery support among his various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">constituencies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
