
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invasion</ENAMEX>

            Quoting "a senior official
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>
claimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in its main front-page story that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> is pushing for a
ground attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> to overthrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>. "Key
figures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> are proposing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> consider a
full-scale armored invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> would capture <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">topple Milosevic</ENAMEX> and haul the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> before a war crimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tribunal</ENAMEX>," wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>. The invasion would be
launched from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, he said. The report, like most others that have promoted
the ground war option, contained the now familiar dampener that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> still
expects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to fall before a land invasion becomes necessary. More
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dampeningly</ENAMEX> still, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, currently the most hawkish of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
failed to sway his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in favor of deploying ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> of each allied
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> had a different take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on both the war and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
summit. The main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Strategic Concept</ENAMEX>,
which includes "out of area" military deployment if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> interests are
threatened. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post of Canada</ENAMEX> welcomed this extension of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
role but warned in an editorial that it should not be "a euphemism for global
humanitarian interventions more properly handled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s both led on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s pledges of military and economic help to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> in
return for their support against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> led on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> playing "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> card," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> splashed the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is ready to block even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tankers</ENAMEX> to
enforce its oil embargo against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> led on the cost of
the war, warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is coming under pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
pay a larger share of it.

            An editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> said the
oil embargo and the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Apache</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> might
yet obviate the need for a ground war, but a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> implied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> might never put the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX> into the air. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reporter Tim Butcher</ENAMEX> wrote that "the final elements
of the deployment are still not in place" and that there is no indication from
any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> of a willingness, yet, "to employ the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Apache</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>
where its low-flying tactics will expose it to ground fire." He said that "the
level of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apaches</ENAMEX>, which are being protected by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, suggests that they are intended to break <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> morale without actually
engaging in battle. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> press has had a field day, reporting that
they are armed with nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>," he added.

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>, the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazeta Shqiptare</ENAMEX> claimed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have started using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> and
biological weapons against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>. It said that a shell
containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">radioactive materials</ENAMEX> and neurotoxins had been fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> near
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> border and paralyzed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>. Traces of "altropine,"
an antidote to chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, had been found by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of
dead <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, it added.)

            In a commentary in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Keegan</ENAMEX> accused media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> of becoming dangerously obsessed with what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> are saying about the progress of the war instead of focusing
on what is actually happening in the field. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s euphoric discussion of
the significance of the deployment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">24 Apache</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> shows how
unrealistic media assessments of the evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>'s war effort is," he
wrote. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, out of a
helicopter force many times larger than that. It also did not win the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
war." In another example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Apache</ENAMEX> skepticism, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> pointed out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> had promised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 4</TIMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apaches</ENAMEX> would be getting "up close and personal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> armor
units in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>" within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks later</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force Hawk</ENAMEX> is "still
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> away from performing any sort of combat mission."

            Writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX>" section, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford historian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niall Ferguson</ENAMEX> said that the slaughters in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High School</ENAMEX>
and the nail bomb attack <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s black neighborhood of Brixton
are all linked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX>. "From beyond his unknown grave,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> has a hand in all these apparently unrelated events," he wrote.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Criticizing Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s overuse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Reich</ENAMEX> analogies in their
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> rhetoric, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> said it would not do for them to say that the
current airstrikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> are based on the lessons of the past.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, it was not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> but rather his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appeasers</ENAMEX> who, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
exaggerated the effectiveness of air power. "Does anyone out there want to
argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> could have been defeated by a policy of air strikes to
'degrade the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine</ENAMEX>' without the deployment of ground forces
other than in a 'permissive' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">environment?</ENAMEX>" he asked. "Invoking the memory of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> have picked a fight with one little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>]," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> concluded. "They should not now be surprised if,
even in the obscurity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brixton</ENAMEX>, they have to fight some even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">littler Hitlers</ENAMEX>, too."

            In a front-page story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> revealed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> has regularly consulted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict. In
a number of telephone calls, all initiated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> and some lasting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">as long as</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>, she urged him to "stiffen the spine" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, as she had
done when she chided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for going "wobbly" during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>.

            In an editorial on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> massacre, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> warned against dismissing it as a problem unique to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-crazy
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The problem, it said, is a wider one "to do with the increasing
solipsism of the world in which our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> live." Not only do they "retreat
into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> which seem as self-contained as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX>'s capsule, each with
its own TV, stereo-system and wired-up computer," but into an "increasingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-referential</ENAMEX> and self-validating" worldview. The things that once linked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> to the value systems of the rest of society have gone, as have "the
frameworks of reality which placed social restraints on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>'s
freedom to think, say, do, or buy whatever is desired."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>'s bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> TV station was much
criticized in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> 's editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> said the action might be
"terribly counterproductive" because it won't change the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> who
believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s propaganda, but it will appear pointlessly destructive of
human lives to those who don't. It could also have "devastating" effects on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> opinion by giving the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is only bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> because it is incapable of taking on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> appears "to have all the time he needs to empty
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, mine frontiers, bury his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> and armored <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, and install
artillery batteries opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> bases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with what is said was "the biggest protest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX> pro-democracy movement began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago this month</TIMEX>." The
story also made the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX>, which
said that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a mystic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fa Lun Gong</ENAMEX> caused
acute embarrassment to security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> by virtually surrounding the compound
where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> work. It said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> "claims <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and
sees human corruption in everything from homosexuality to rock and roll and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
