
   
   
      
         
            Aum My God!

            The pledge by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX>, to hold elections within
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times puts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> on the front but leads with the dispute between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> over how much to pay
former welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> for the state-supplied community service jobs they
are offered when they cannot find work on their own. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feds</ENAMEX> say pay minimum
wage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> says that's not necessary, since welfare-to-work is an
assistance program not an employment program.

            The election pledge is one of several reforms announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> prominent political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
were released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> jailed for inciting a riot,
and the other a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> jailed for insulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>. (The WP
puts this in a separate piece deep inside.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice minister</ENAMEX> said
that the release of other political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> will follow soon. Also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> implies), plans are underway for a trial
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> suspected in the killings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> during
the riots that toppled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>. And, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> also
announced it will review its business dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> owned by former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes this move in stronger terms: the beginning of
"severing" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s close links with those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The LAT
says that already under the new policy some small public works contracts have
been canceled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX>'s pronouncements
came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one day</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> is due to begin
negotiating terms for release of the latest installment of a stalled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43</NUMEX>
billion bailout package.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is strongly supporting reform. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> does not enjoy military support and that these
moves appear to ensure that he will be an "interim <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page story reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aum Shinrikyo</ENAMEX>,
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have been implicated in the twelve-fatality nerve gassing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, had previously conducted numerous biological warfare attacks in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. Using rooftops and truck <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convoys</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> conducted, concludes the
Times , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least nine</NUMEX> germ attacks on such targets as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Imperial Palace</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> naval <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yokosuka</ENAMEX>.
Hearteningly, the attacks failed because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> couldn't obtain or
produce germs of sufficient virulence. Dishearteningly, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> nor
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>--including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>--detected any of
them.

            On the WP front, ace political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> checks in from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to report that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 226</ENAMEX>, which would require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> to get annual
permission from individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to make any political use of dues, is,
despite a commanding early lead in the polls, now sinking fast. The main
reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> reports, seems to be the huge amount of money--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $20</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> have poured into anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">226</NUMEX> ads. Doesn't this kind of turnaround
power of union spending pretty much drive home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">226</TIMEX>'s point?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>'s latest employment-outlook survey, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> businesses
intend to increase staffing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third quarter</TIMEX>. The paper quotes the gloss
provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>: "There has never been a job market even close
to this."

            OK, OK, so you already know it's just about impossible to get any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>.
But that's in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. What about, wonders an LAT front-pager, the
rest of the world? The paper turns up a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42</NUMEX> bottle of the stuff in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
City market, but it's counterfeit. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, the real thing goes for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> bucks
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> on the black market. And in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, the under-the-table price is up to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800</NUMEX> a bottle. But, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> is legal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marino</ENAMEX>--however, the place has been overrun by would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stallions</ENAMEX>, so
good luck finding any. In a world of lurid myopia, it's refreshing to see that
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is still willing to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> on an overseas story.

         
      
   
