
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank Shots</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s big merger announcements, and everybody has
lots of front-page and inside banking stories. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
which led with the mergers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, goes with the looming high costs of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midterm</ENAMEX> elections. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with the mysterious breakdown experienced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s "frame relay" data network, which is used by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to handle such tasks as central database access and
e-mail. The main effects the paper mentions are a reservations slowdown at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX> and travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' difficulties getting credit card
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authorizations</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> emerging from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BankAmerica/NationsBank</ENAMEX> combine will command <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> of all bank deposits
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, close to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent limit currently mandated by federal law.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes however, that unlike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp/Travelers</ENAMEX> move,
which challenges <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX> laws barring different types of financial
services from being offered by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, this bank merger is within the
boundaries of current law, because in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> allowed coast-to-coast
banking. But, mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX> is contemplating
legislation that would raise the hurdles to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> approval of big bank
mergers.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that many bank stocks soared on the merger news, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> identified more with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>,
going high in its story with concerns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BankAmerica/NationsBank</ENAMEX> deal
would lead to higher fees and could eliminate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> jobs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
doesn't get to that latter bit of unpleasantness until the fifteenth paragraph
of its bank story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> breaks out a separate story about what the deal means to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, dominated by wiggle-claims
quoted from others like "bigger is not necessarily better when it comes to the
accounts of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>" and "bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> do tend to charge higher
fees." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's news section cover story on bank mergers says it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flat-out</ENAMEX>: "surveys show that big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> charge higher fees," and backs that
assertion up with several data bullets.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed makes the point that in light of these big bank
mergers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should reconsider the consequences if one of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monsters</ENAMEX> fails. Current law allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to completely protect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depositors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> considered too big to let fail. This policy
ignores the lesson of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and L crisis in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imbroglio</ENAMEX>: the promise of complete protection contributes to bank failures by
encouraging risky bank <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX>. So, the piece argues, big account holders
should have to personally bear some of the loss that comes from a failure. That
would encourage them to monitor their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> more closely.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that the upcoming midterm elections are apt
to break spending records because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are buying television time far
earlier than ever before. The trend is being attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
decision to mount an early and intense television campaign. Another influence
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> cites is that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, who became a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in early
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primaries by spending tons of his own money on TV ads. It's become
obvious that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> fear not having the campaign money far more than they
fear any scandal caused by raising it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Checchi</ENAMEX>, a
buying television ads just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thanksgiving</TIMEX> for the primary vote this
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Checchi</ENAMEX>'s standard, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , promises to lead to the
most expensive state election in history.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column notes a simple position taken by the
to take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> more seriously: use high-school transcripts more in
hiring.

            The WP business section reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that until now has
sold its language-understanding software to the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spy-detection</ENAMEX> is poised to sell a similar product designed to help the
government and brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> monitor the offers and promises made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brokers</ENAMEX>
in communications with (potential) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. The idea is that the program that
once could pick out the needle of a phrase like "covert operative" in a
haystack of e-mails has now been trained, says the paper, to do the same for
"opportunity of a lifetime" and "so safe even my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has it." Forgive
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" for wondering--but how will this software catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> if it
couldn't catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
