
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang Turn</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the arrival in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> of
just-exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang Dan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the conclusion of the economic summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>, where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> decided to go forward with plans to create a
free-trade zone throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. The leads with word that an
all-time record <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million-plus</NUMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident immigrants</ENAMEX> are still waiting to
become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
top fronts feature powerful pictures from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> anniversary memorial service. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes with a "scathing" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> report concluding that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">undergraduates</ENAMEX> at research institutions
graduate "without knowing how to think logically, write clearly or speak
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coherently</ENAMEX>."

            Dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> pro-democracy demonstrations in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> crushed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, landed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>
after his release from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that previously
released dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX> was also flown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, but doesn't explain
the destination. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> does: it's the terminus of the only direct
flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> to the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> was promptly admitted to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> for tests. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in the course of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> stories,
notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> remain imprisoned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for the crime of
"counterrevolution." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX>'s release was part of a "reported
deal" between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that clears the way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is more definite, saying the
release was "one of the last steps in an extensive package deal secretly
negotiated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>" during a "clandestine mission to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend of March 7-8</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a front-page piece on the information turned up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> grand jury he has had looking into <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> financial dealings. The piece, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gerth</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Labaton</ENAMEX> is mostly a useful summary of old news, but there is new ground
broken: the grand jury evidence includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a document found <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">briefcase in Vince Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX> that impugns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s account of how
she came to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James McDougal's Madison Savings and Loan</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony that after the initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> articles on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> he
sent an associate to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDougal</ENAMEX>: "And I might have asked him to, you know,
talk to him and see if we could have no further damaging articles, but I don't
remember exactly what I said."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Outlook"</ENAMEX> column zeroes in on the
closest thing to a storm cloud in the current economic forecast: the stunning
erosion of lending standards. The column reports that last year <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> raised
outstanding credit by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 8 percent</NUMEX>, the fastest rate of increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. And that more financial outfits loosened lending rules than raised them.
What's more, outstanding home and auto loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> with lousy credit
histories surpassed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. That's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> higher than just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>. Not to mention, adds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>-percent-of-home-equity loans and mortgage loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> already in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreclosure</ENAMEX>. Actually, there's another storm warning in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> : In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, mostly because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic collapse, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade deficit
reached <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 billion</NUMEX>, up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.2 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. Worse, says the paper, is
predicted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months ahead</TIMEX>.

            A rave review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reminds "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
of something wrong with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> 's attempts to account for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Scaife</ENAMEX> money it disbursed
in pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> dirt on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: it didn't mention that this Scaife
funding effort was first reported on by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Observer</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> .

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Shenon</ENAMEX> piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>"
makes an incredibly important point: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> wasn't the last big war criminal
walking around free. There's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idi Amin</ENAMEX>, estimated to have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> of his
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandans</ENAMEX>, enjoying life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. There's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX> Radovan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karadzic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ratko Mladic</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shenon</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> the latter had a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nice</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> that took him from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adriatic</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Danube</ENAMEX> and that he often
travels along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads supposedly</ENAMEX> patrolled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. And how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmanuel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constant</ENAMEX>, accused of complicity in the murder and torture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haitians</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>? Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Guillermo Garcia</ENAMEX>, accused of
covering up the rape and murder of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> churchwomen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Salvador</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>? They're both living in...the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>

            A column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Downey</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> brought word of an
invention that could single-handedly reverse the tide of tabloidism: a
miniature device worn on a cap or as jewelry that, whenever a photographer
tries to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wearer</ENAMEX>'s picture, emits a picture-ruining flash.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also featured an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, who
had this to say in defense of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>: "She's a very smart, intelligent,
beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who's going to go places, and unfortunately she's taking her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">licks</ENAMEX>...." "Thanks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>!"
            

         
      
   
