
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Tech</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s passage of a huge transportation-funding
plan, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38 percent</NUMEX> larger than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> currently in effect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cancer rates have
declined in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>, reversing the trend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous twenty</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the revelation that last
fall, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after gaining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s pledge to halt assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
nuclear programs (elicited in return for allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to sell
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reactors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> discovered and protested
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s secret negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> regarding shipping it material used to
make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">weapons-grade uranium</ENAMEX>.

            The coverage of the transportation bill, which includes an LAT
front-pager and a piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , generally stresses that its rich
provisions could be a budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buster</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page piece emphasizes a "little-noticed
provision" (noticed, however, also by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ) that would let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65</NUMEX> a month in tax-free mass-transit benefits (in the form,
for instance, of subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tokens</ENAMEX> and bus passes). This could, says the
Times , sharply cut the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> and subway travel in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
and elsewhere.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> attribute the decline in new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases
to changes in behavior, most notably a drop in smoking, and the decline in
deaths to increased screening and better therapies, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also observes
that these positive trends are not equally benefiting all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minorities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , "remain particularly at risk."
While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">WP front-page cancer</ENAMEX> pieces mention this, the
LAT cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> doesn't mention it before the "jump" to the inside.
Also, according to the graphic accompanying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story, the biggest
increase seen in the most recent data is for melanoma of the skin, yet this
type of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> isn't mentioned at all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story proper.

            A piece on the WP front reports on an organized protest campaign of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of angry phone
calls, letters and e-mails directed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merriam-Webster</ENAMEX> because of its current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>'s definition of "nigger" as "a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--usually taken to be
offensive." The campaign was started by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and has now been
joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kweisi Mfume</ENAMEX>, who warns that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> doesn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bend</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> will urge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> not to buy its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dictionaries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , historically very skittish in its treatment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, doesn't complicate the story with the inconvenient but true observation
that since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> know better than to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-word epithet, and since it
has become a common phrase of salutation and even endearment among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, a
high proportion of its current usage is in fact as a synonym for "black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."

            There's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s quote brilliance unquote suspiciously on display
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports on its front that he literally dreamt of the idea
of making a live video image of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> as seen from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> continuously
available on the Internet, and that after conducting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> of
Internet research, he quickly assembled a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to make his dream a
reality. What's involved is launching a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> that can be stationed 1
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> suggests calling it
Triana, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodrigo de Triana</ENAMEX>, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> apparently knows to be, without
benefit of flashcards, the lookout on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> who first sighted the New
World. Meanwhile, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is depicted wowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
top computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> with his fluent references to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immanuel Kant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuhn</ENAMEX>. What controlling mental authority!

         
      
   
