
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Admitting Mistakes</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>'s disclosure that as a result of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proposition 209</ENAMEX>'s mandate to abandon affirmative action in admissions, the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman classes</ENAMEX> at its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most selective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>, will
have far fewer minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> than in the recent past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s decision
allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to ban the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> use of polygraph results. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with news that might be heartening for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of the now withdrawn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diet concoction Redux</ENAMEX>: a new study suggests that short-term use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is
not associated with an increase in heart valve problems. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes on
to note that the study was sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redux</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> and does not in
any case address the consequences of long-term use.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> admissions situation is relayed most
frantically at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , which states that "the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African Americans</ENAMEX>
accepted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC Berkeley</ENAMEX> has plunged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> and the number admitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> dropped
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43%</NUMEX>," without stating most of the raw numbers behind the percentages. (A common
journalistic mistake/trick.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> does use the raw numbers when
reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, but unaccountably goes back to emphasizing percentages
when discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also shies away from the actual numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> involved, but at least emphasizes the before-and-after-209 minority
percentages of the total admitted pool, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">illuminating datum</ENAMEX>. Both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the minority drop occurred despite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX>'s decision to give extra consideration to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>, thus
proving that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> at least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> isn't race.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> is quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> as seeing in the shift
the message that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> must improve, while the paper
has Prop. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX> saying it means some of the burden for
admissions must be put back on black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
themselves. A more striking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connerly</ENAMEX> quote somehow doesn't make the cut at
either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , but is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and USAT : "These numbers
will finally and conclusively put to rest the lie that we've heard for so long
from these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX> that race is only one factor in how they choose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>..It's the decisive factor." (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> should have, by the way,
changed the present tense in that last sentence to the past, which was clearly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connerly</ENAMEX>'s meaning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> gets this right.)

            Some questions: Why does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline only mention the drop in
black admissions and relegate the drop for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> to the subhead? Why don't
any of the stories mention the graduation rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>
at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> under the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> spills a lot of ink on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, with
pieces about trial lawyers' pursuit of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> cases, the attempt by the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asbestos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> to tap into any settlement deal, and the political spin on
the pending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bill. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capitol Journal"</ENAMEX> column paints a picture of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> in "deep peril," and of a sharply divided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> besieged by an "enraged"
tobacco industry. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, says the paper, it may fall to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to bring
order out of this chaos--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> go front-page with the news that an
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Rosa</ENAMEX>, did research for a science fair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> as a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> that is being published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX>. Her project was a refreshingly simple experiment
that showed "therapeutic touch" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> don't have a special ability to
detect an energy field around human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> question: why does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say she showed that the healers detected a human
hand they couldn't see at a rate "no better than chance" would have predicted,
when her results show they scored <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 44 percent</NUMEX>, which is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>
worse?

         
      
   
