
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Tracking</ENAMEX>

            Life after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> leads all around. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
Times all emphasize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s determination to press on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
stresses instead <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to pack it in, noting that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> were being guided in this by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> polling
indicating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly two-thirds</NUMEX> of those asked thought the Jones dismissal was
good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> responded to the Jones result by holding his first extensive meeting
with the press since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> (which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> characterizes as "defiant,
sometimes rambling"), in the driveway of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report his case for pressing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">sans Paula:</ENAMEX> "If you lie under oath,
if you intimidate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, if you seek otherwise to obstruct the process of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>, it doesn't matter who wins and loses in the civil case."

            Later on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX> brought
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> for questioning. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> were "furious" about this because they feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowles</ENAMEX> has made a
particular effort to wall himself off from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was asked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and he is
widely quoted as saying it "speaks for itself." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was described as more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ebullient</ENAMEX>, and was quoted by everyone as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Both Bill</ENAMEX> and I have felt
throughout this whole thing that it would turn out fine." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> confidante <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX> saying that the ruling means it's
"open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> here in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>
saw something special about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> getting the news while in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>:
"It's a convergence that could only be planned by God."

            There is much coverage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s emotional visit to Goree
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>, a slavery marshaling point off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> paid
tribute there to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> descended from slaves brought from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. Everybody
has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s shock at seeing the size of the iron ball used to immobilize
manacled slaves. But there is something consistently missing in all the Goree
coverage. While the island was owned at various times by each of the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> colonial powers active in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Africa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is wrong to describe it as the place "where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> ended their lives as free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captives</ENAMEX> of white men
sending them across the ocean to an unknown future." What's left out is that
during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four centuries</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade, most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX>
victimized were first captured by other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> and then sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>.
They ended their lives as free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> before they fell into white hands.

            The LAT front reports that teen smoking is on the rise, jumping by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a third</NUMEX> in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>. Especially alarming is the news of a big increase among black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teenagers</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> once believed to be curiously resistant to the teen smoking
trend. This story also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and is inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            More on the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that he will
publish his memoirs in the presidential run-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year of 1999</TIMEX>, and that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
who bid on the book says the excerpt he saw brought tears to his eyes.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" appreciates the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of responses to the
request for a better term for the procedure often described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> as a
"partial birth abortion." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, there was no political agenda behind
the request--it was made purely out of an interest in increased linguistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precision</ENAMEX>.) An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOTP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> cup goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James S. Thompson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newburyport</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, for the simple but effective "partial delivery abortion." TP
will essay to use the phrase and commends it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>.

            And thanks to the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who rushed forward with considerable
expertise to answer this column's somewhat inept question about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's story concerning that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX>'s "therapeutic touch"
experiment. The upshot is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> was mistaken in suggesting that a random
result would have to be a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> score. That would only be true with an
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">infinite</ENAMEX> number of trials. But in an actual experiment, which involves a finite
number of trials, one calculates a range of values above and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">below 50%</NUMEX> that
define what would still count as random results. This is the margin of error
produced by the sample size. So since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s result of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> was within
that range for the number of trials she undertook, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 
               was
correct to say that her result was no better than chance. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> would add
this: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story, like all statistical stories, should have
mentioned the margin of error.

            Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> for a moment: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> had tossed just a few more
centi-Ks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>'s way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> might have made this trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> before
"Amistad" opened.

         
      
   
