
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>: Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like a Daimler</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> hinted at in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with bipartisan congressional criticism of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s attempt to impose terms on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in its
negotiations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, will buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $35</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, making, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the all-stock purchase
the largest industrial merger in history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> adds that it is also
the largest-ever foreign acquisition of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Given current revenues,
the deal will create the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, to be known as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Chrysler</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gives a feel for the breadth of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> by noting that the top of
the line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S600</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> goes for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130,000</NUMEX> while the entry-level <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge Neon</ENAMEX>
goes for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neon</ENAMEX> starts at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,000</NUMEX> and the top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CL600</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">coupe</ENAMEX>, which sells for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$135,000</NUMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the
deal's motivations include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> getting to expand its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> sales, which
lag far behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> getting the chance to offer
down-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> without tarnishing its snobby brand-name.

            The papers see the deal as the beginning of a wave of consolidation in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, brought on by excess manufacturing capacity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>
gives the lay of that land: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> ready to go shopping include, besides
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Chrysler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>. Likely acquisition targets
include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyundai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renault</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peugeot</ENAMEX>, and even perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's story foresees layoffs, driven by the elimination
of duplicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. But, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>, the merger shouldn't cause
major layoffs because the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car lines</ENAMEX> are so different. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sticks
to this even as it blithely notes that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> has gotten rid
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.

            There's much talk in the merger stories of the challenges presented by the
different corporate cultures of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. A perhaps more interesting
difference is not covered but could be teased out by an industrious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>--a
discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX>'s activities under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>, including any involvement
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> labor.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> go top-front with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>'s apology to fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for the
uproar caused by his selective release of Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> tapes. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
manner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s assumption of responsibility meant that someone else had to
get fired--in this case it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff investigator</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that in a closed-door <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a "circus."
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmaker</ENAMEX> who was there tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> also told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, "I want you to forget the word 'scandals' and start using the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'crimes</ENAMEX>.'"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead reports that at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s presidential press
conference, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> questioner asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> to distinguish between his
case and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s use of executive privilege. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said, "The facts
are quite different in this case," but didn't respond to any follow-ups. The
paper efficiently sums up his position with its headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: I am not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
