
   
   
      
         
            Big Tools

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
national edition leads with the battle for the control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> over tobacco policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s ruling that even a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> can challenge
a grand jury indictment on the grounds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection discriminated
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s rejection of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> proposal that would have provided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> for refurbishing
crumbling school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> will hold its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and decisive vote on whether to ratify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s nomination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sergei Kiriyenko</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has vowed
to dissolve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> and hold national elections if the nomination is again
rejected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>, reports the paper, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s richest and most
ruthless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backer</ENAMEX>, has emerged as one
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiriyenko</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiriyenko</ENAMEX> is also opposed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>). On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berezovsky</ENAMEX> used a newspaper he owns to openly tell
Yeltsin what he has to do to avoid a big fight over the nomination: abandon
market reform.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead is about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s comment at a fund-raiser
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that what's happening with teen smoking has "nothing to do with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX>." More important, he said, are smoke-glamorizing movies like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> responded, saying,
"Teen smoking has everything to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX>, with unscrupulous marketing
campaigns that prey on the insecurities and dreams of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." The
context for all this jockeying is the fate of the tobacco bill, with its
restrictions on teen marketing, now awaiting consideration by the full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> have in the past lamented
the tendency of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> policy battles to become too personal, and this
story is itself a perfect example of the problem. Although the remark by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> quoted above is the only one of his in the piece that's a direct
response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, the headline reads, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Calls Gingrich</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tool of Big</ENAMEX>
Tobacco."

            There's real calumny in another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story inside, which reports that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, who has been heading up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> investigation into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> finances, told the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
Star , "If I could prove <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of what I believe happened, he'd
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>] be gone. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s a scumbag. That's why I'm after him." The story
goes on to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> is planning to release tapes made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s phone calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. He is suggesting that the tapes
reveal incriminating conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Federal law
would prohibit such tape disclosures--except that it doesn't apply to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            
               Damn, why didn't we think of that? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Avon</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX> and other direct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> are building "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ideologically</ENAMEX> charged
sales <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>" headed up by "charismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>," has issued an immediate ban
on door-to-door sales.

            The WP front features a story raising an interesting issue relating
to the new male potency <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>. The pill is designed to correct impotence, but
there are already indications that huge numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who are not impotent,
but who simply want the sex drive of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX>, are eager to take it.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> don't know yet if it would have this effect.) If such a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>
Niagara materializes, insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are likely to require, in order to
contain costs, medical proof of impotence for reimbursal. "Maybe some people
would rather have this than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX>," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>. "But they should do it
with their own money."

         
      
   
