
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> to Judgment

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s dismissal of his entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s
decision to sidestep a "partial-birth abortion" case. (An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOTP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> cup for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> who submits, the best alternative phrase, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s judgment, for the
procedure in question. How can someone be partially born? And doesn't
"Partial-birth abortion" seems about as logical as "partial-life execution?")
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the main economic reaction to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s big
story about oil production cutbacks: a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> rise in oil prices, the
biggest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> percentage gain since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> explained his move by saying his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> needed a fresh and powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> in place to pull it out of its social and economic crises. The biggest
name casualty was long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>, widely viewed
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> apparent. In firing him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> advised him to concentrate
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next presidential</TIMEX> elections, to be held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Odd or insincere
advice, given that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says few give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> much of a chance
to win that election without the power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s
support.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says theories about why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> fired everybody "swirled
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> like a cyclone." But give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> credit for
putting forward its own clear suggestion: With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s health problems much
in evidence of late, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> were increasingly viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s imminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, and "nothing infuriates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> more than the
suggestion that he has lost any of his political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
which runs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> on its front, also settles on this as the most likely
explanation.

            Although all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agree on the basic facts of the shake-up, their
takes on the emotions involved vary. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> made his
stunning announcement in a "surprisingly folksy and conciliatory speech," while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the speech was made by a "stiff-looking" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says he was "grim."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has some excellent detail on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of the firings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, says the paper, met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> in person and gave him a
farewell award for "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatherland</ENAMEX>," while the other big names got
it in the neck on the phone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> account makes it clear that there
are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> too, by reporting that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s moves "had been planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."

            The WP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> brings word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, confronted with its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chance to take up the issue of a particular vexed type of late-term
abortion, decided to punt, prompting an angry dissent from conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, abortion rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> were cheered by the inaction. The non-move is also the USAT
off-lead, but doesn't make the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> or LAT . Both of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> find another judicial story more pressing: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court's decision that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> can ban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts carry the news that the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has indeed, as it first hinted over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX>, decided to
try to block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed-Northrop</ENAMEX> merger.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ghana</ENAMEX> is front-page news at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> opened his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-day</TIMEX> tour of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , by pledging more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interest and aid while
calling for a deeper <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> commitment to democracy and free markets. The
Times describes how the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ever spoke to--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some half</NUMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million Ghanians</ENAMEX>--surged against the barricades, threatening to "overwhelm the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "his face contorted in anger, raged at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> to get back." The picture on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts captures
the moment: It's the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Primary Colors</ENAMEX>" opening handshake gone mad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX> also makes the LAT front.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is
attempting to use its recently announced claim of executive privilege to cover
discussions involving not just presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, but also those involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. The paper points out that this indicates
how actively involved she has been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> response to the scandal.
Meanwhile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial calls the attempt to use executive privilege
in the controversy "an alarming attempt to extend presidential power."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reports that
"<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Eighty-eight percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> surveyed anonymously report that they see a
connection between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s age and productivity. In a poll of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">773</NUMEX> chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson Wyatt Worldwide</ENAMEX> found that most
think productivity peaks around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 43</TIMEX>." "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" is sorry that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> wasn't curious enough to find out the average age of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
