
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodbye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> moves to shore up public
support for its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> stance, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air assault now include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the brewing dispute between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> and senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> he is questioning over whether or not they are relieved from
answering by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the arrest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, one of them a neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>, for possession of
suspected anthrax for use as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. Allegedly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were plotting to
deploy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway system</ENAMEX>--yeah right, like anthrax
could survive that. The anthrax story also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and LAT
fronts, but is pushed inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> not to mistake the
skeptical questions raised at the raucous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> forum as a sign that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> lack resolve for military action. This comment came, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , as a new poll shows <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> support bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
if it doesn't stop interfering with weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>. The poll's fine points
are a little more confusing, however. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> say the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should try to force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> from power, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> also say they oppose
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> invasion with ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. This sort of free-lunch result is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> polling staple--it's just like all those polls that show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> want a
balanced budget, but not higher taxes or reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
benefits.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's coverage of the hearts and mind stage of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> run-up suggests more of an uphill battle than does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's: "A day
after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was passionately picked apart at a town hall
meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tried to reassemble the pieces.."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports this comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> protests made by Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Mikulski</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as he appeared with her at an event on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>: "You and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> weren't exactly angelic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. I don't think you've done too bad being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protester</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead states that presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>
declined to answer some questions during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand jury
appearance, which, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, set the stage for a "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>-style battle"
over the use of executive privilege.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial weighs in on this dispute, taking the
position that as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s questions "stick to the pertinent issues," and
stay out of say, "military options in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>," they should be answered. Of
course, what counts as pertinent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> has already been loosened
considerably, and could get looser. If, for instance, there was prima facie
evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had discussed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> moves with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, then by
the same logic that got us here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> would be entitled to question her
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that too.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> met <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, but
never mentions that this was first reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.K.</ENAMEX>, maybe not all our promises." The LAT front and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside feature stories stating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> is so
strapped financially that it will soon stop paying its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">345</NUMEX> salaried
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece has a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tidy</ENAMEX> break-out of lessons learned by both sides in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , it's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">US: Minimize casualties</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> and military;
stealth technology works; precision-guided munitions work; you need to be able
to deploy quickly; and air power is more effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> than in the past. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Survival</ENAMEX> is victory; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't like casualties on either side;
bring in foreign TV, but not foreign print <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>; portray yourself as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, and don't slug it out, but "shoot and scoot." The paper
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> suspect the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> may be keeping the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of executed political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> in cold storage, to be blown up and
distributed wherever <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> bombs drop.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> has these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> tidbits: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> isn't part of the
joint defense agreement entered into by many other grand-jury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> ties. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> is making plans to hire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
"new" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for a possible impeachment inquiry. For the sake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" hopes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> means "additional."

         
      
   
