
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Drifts and Coasts</ENAMEX>

            The near-global stock market plunge, with an especially deep crisis in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and the New York
Times . A behind-the-scenes look at the just-unsealed ruling against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s use of executive privilege in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> investigation
leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (and is the top national story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ).

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, market indexes dropped in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> (although by the end of trading, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> had recovered
most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s losses). Nothing compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s troubles though,
where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> dip in the stock market meant a cumulative
shrinkage of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the proximate cause was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody's</ENAMEX> downgrading the rating of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and deploring the entire
banking system of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cites that as well as indications
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> is set to announce its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> GDP slip in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. All of this fits
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's general explanation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are increasingly shunning
markets in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            Sometimes the narrative in economic flash stories is a little brisk. What
can the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> get from such sentences as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "In a bid to
restore confidence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> central bank tripled key interest rates to a
staggering <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150%</NUMEX>."? Staggering interest rates just don't sound confidence
building. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads, which focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, meet this challenge with the sprinkling of additional Econ 101
information required: jacked-up rates of return encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to hold on
to their rubles rather than selling them for dollars. Still, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> can't
help but be confused by the widely quoted pronouncement by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>:
"Contrary to what markets and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> are imagining, this is not a
crisis."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> report that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Johnson</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege for both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX>, as well
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-client privilege for certain presidential discussions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, are
legitimate notions. But, they add, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> made a private presentation
to her of secret grand jury evidence, she decided the privileges are trumped by
the particulars of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the legal papers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> submitted make it
clear that early on, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, despite public assertions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
to the contrary, was seriously affecting his ability to focus on his job. The
papers also show that the specter of impeachment was very real for him--so
real, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> claimed, that he needed candid and private advice from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
about how to combat it. Snippets from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s brief suggest nothing short of
Absolute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> : "If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> were to murder a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, he
would argue that the resulting uproar could impair his legislative program,
distract him from his duties, affect his dealings with foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
and potentially give rise to impeachment proceedings--the very arguments raised
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> here..."

            Ready for another high-profile digital anti-trust case that will no doubt
also drag on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>? Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are recommending civil antitrust charges
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel Corp.</ENAMEX>, alleging that the chip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> used its dominant market
position unfairly against smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries the story
inside.)

            Everybody reports another computer development, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
business section calls "a glimpse of the future the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is seeking" in
its case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>: namely, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gateway</ENAMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> negotiated
permission from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX> and Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> equally
convenient choices from Gateway start-up screens.

            In a gimlet editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says it may be too early to call
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> "do-nothing," but not too early to call it "done-nothing." Sure,
notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , there was the (budget-busting, drunk-driving-ignoring)
highway bill, but what about tobacco legislation, campaign finance reform, a
student loan bill, health care, food stamps for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy immigrants</ENAMEX>, child care
subsidies, reforming the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Endangered Species</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act and Superfund</ENAMEX>, or paying up our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> bill?

            But, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> area, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has taken
charge. In hearings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> heard from various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Platters</ENAMEX>,
Drifters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coasters</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogues</ENAMEX> all requesting that federal law be amended to
protect oldies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> using the their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>-names. They can say what they want about our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, our health care,
and our campaign financing, but this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> takes a backseat to no one when it
comes to fighting against doowop knockoffs .

         
      
   
