
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fashioning Paula</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>' settlement of its product-liability lawsuit
against the leading tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The top nonlocal story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is the latest development in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
economic crisis--a rare and boosterish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Suharto</ENAMEX> press conference in contrast to
a further plunging stock market and food riots in outlying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a comprehensive poll about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> concerning
abortion.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> case, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendant companies</ENAMEX> have agreed
to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $15 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> to reimburse the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for expenses it
incurred in the treatment of smoking-related illnesses. That makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> state to settle such a case, joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>. There are,
says the paper, a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> such suits on file, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s turn coming
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' lawyers
hired by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to try the case will receive as part of the deal <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $2.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in fees.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> abortion survey, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, was
based on telephone interviews of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and detects "a notable shift from
general acceptance" of having the procedure: from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent to 32 percent</NUMEX>. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> also detected an increasingly acute sensitivity to abortion
timing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixty</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percent of those polled thought abortions should be permitted
during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trimester, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 15 percent</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
percent in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. (The piece notes that this last stat helps explain why a
focus on partial-birth abortions has proven politically advantageous for
abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>.) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Nearly 45 percent</NUMEX> of those asked to state the present law on
abortion could not give the correct answer.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> notes that the just-concluded football/TV deal will probably
mean even steeper cable bills in the near future. Some local cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, expect the fees they'll pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> to go up more than
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. And they're in the habit of passing expenses along to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Remote</ENAMEX>.
Even nonsports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> will be affected, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> is
usually part of basic cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. (Which raises the question: Hasn't
technology progressed to a point that would allow cafeteria-style programming
choices by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>?)

            A scan of the headlines found cheek-by-jowl on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's Page A6
provides an interesting snapshot of the life of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ex-HUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cisneros</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ex-Mistress Pleads Guilty</ENAMEX>," "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Denies Allegations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Influence-Selling Scheme</ENAMEX>," and "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyson Foods</ENAMEX>
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Indicted Over Gifts</ENAMEX> to [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ex-Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Espy</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that, according to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are twice
as likely to back a tax increase going toward the search for extraterrestrials
than one for gene-cloning research.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> will
describe an experiment in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s biological clocks were reset three
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> by shining a bright light on the back of their knees. The finding, if it
holds up, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , may lead to a simple way for airline travelers
to fight jet lag.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ran a story under the headline "Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones Works</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Court Appearance</ENAMEX>," which, illustrated by pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>,
was all about the various looks she's had since stepping on the public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>.
The piece concluded that she's finally graduated to an image that's
"sophisticated yet soft." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section (that's the
opposite of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>, remember) picks up that ball and runs with it, with a
lengthy discourse on the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PJ</ENAMEX>. "It is," hyperventilates
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , one of the most jaw-dropping public make-overs ever." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX>
apparently has "smoothed the frizzy mane of curls that once reached to such
dazzling heights. Her makeup is now subtle and based on natural, not neon,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hues</ENAMEX>. Her clothing is inspired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">boardroom</ENAMEX> instead of the secretarial
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX>. She has embraced the markers of dignity, refinement and power." In true
newspaper overkill fashion, the piece backs this up by consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynde Watson</ENAMEX>,
national makeup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bobbi Brown Essentials</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Zdatny</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">University</ENAMEX> specializing in the aesthetics and
politics of hair.

            The placement of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pieces is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> triumph, but one carrying the
seeds of its own destruction: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know all this work is going into making
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> seem a certain someone, doesn't that just make it obvious that
she's really somebody else?

         
      
   
