
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> at the Barbarians

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand jury appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the first-time-ever
congressional testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-approved oil-for-food
exceptions to the trade sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> have primarily benefited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> and his inner circle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the strong showing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
parliamentary elections. Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads make
anybody else's front page. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, get lots of
attention everywhere.

            It's widely reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> testified for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than five hours</TIMEX>, and
that he answered every question--mostly about the nature of the career planning
assistance he extended to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX> as a favor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. USAT
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s appearance marks a "pivotal stage" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> investigation.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stress that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>-steps affirmation
of his friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was mighty reassuring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> note the fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> security
arrangements--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls them "almost royal treatment." He ate his
lunch ("hearty vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>"--thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) surrounded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> federal
bodyguards, just a few tables over from the unguarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> who had been
grilling him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> was "assailed" at the hearings, for
suppressing competition, by some of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> he appeared with, as
well as by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' response that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> intervention, not his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, is the big threat to technological innovation, is widely quoted. But
hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> opined afterwards that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is a
monopoly. An idea, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates "</ENAMEX>scoffs" at.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> doesn't even allow laptop
computers in its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>, but that nonetheless some of the questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> had a "laser-like precision." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> as
the richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says he's the richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the
world.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> appearance certainly brings out criticism of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
diary entries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source"</ENAMEX> column says, "A scintillating
read, they are not," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> says they make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' life "sound as
boring as ours."

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report," as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> had issued <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> more money in income-tax refunds than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> says that's because more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are filing electronically.

            There's considerable coverage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> given to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> word addition <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Leahy</ENAMEX> inserted in a bill about federal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Lake</ENAMEX> research money
that had the effect of making his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> eligible for the funds for the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. The sentence declares <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Champlain</ENAMEX> to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Lake</ENAMEX>. The bill will,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , probably be signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> makes fun of the move in his column and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial points out that other lakes, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s
Great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>, are far better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX>. The editorial runs under the header,
"Maybe It's An <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX>."

            It's a shame federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monies</ENAMEX> are used up this way when they could be better
used for things like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s program to provide close captioning for
television shows. But then we learn in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that the program
funds captioning for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baywatch</ENAMEX>." ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers" didn't even realize those shows have soundtracks.)

         
      
   
