
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Depression</ENAMEX>

            Sure,thePope'sinCubaIraqistill jerkingtheU.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.</ENAMEX>around44Copscaughtin
OhiostingPMSisn'tmental andthemicrowavedrierisdead. But get serious. There's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. And it has legs. And pants. And a zipper.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has finally found a way to make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> real estate sexy. In
what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> calls a "rapidly escalating inquiry" into allegations that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had an affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> intern, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and
told her to lie about it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> subpoenaed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
documents, including, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , logs on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s comings and goings.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> all report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> emphatically denies the allegations. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes further, saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is "infuriated" by
them.

            The story was first broken by late editions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" was
castigated by numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> for having poor news judgment, or worse, a
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> desire to suppress news. The truth is much simpler: the story was
held out of the early editions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> this column is written from.)
Today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> slops the most at the trough, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missives</ENAMEX>.

            What gives the tale what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls a "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>-like intensity"
is the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> purportedly has <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least 20 hours</TIMEX> of tape recordings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> telling a fellow federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, about her alleged affair
and about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>'s cover-up instructions. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> signed
an affidavit on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 7</TIMEX> in which she denied any sexual relationship with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> made most of the secretly recorded tapes on her own. But the
last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the collection was made with the assistance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, which set
up a monitored rendezvous between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX> at<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> used these tapes to
get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> and the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who manage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s activities to broaden
his net to its current gaping dimensions. (And further investigation is
required: As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> points out, any of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s statements on tape about
what was said to her are hearsay and probably inadmissible.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> denied a sex relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in his Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case deposition <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says he did testify
that he'd given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> personal gifts. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also oh-by-the-ways that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> acknowledged under oath for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that he did indeed have an
affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> relies heavily in its reporting on a source it says has heard
the tapes. It quotes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> as saying the recordings include "graphic
descriptions of sexual encounters." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that the tapes also
contain "tearful passages." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> also told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about telephone answering machine messages containing a voice sounding
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> elaborates: the messages were played by Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>, who surreptitiously taped them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also
reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp's</ENAMEX>, has possession of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the tapes, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> describes as "shocking beyond belief."

            Not surprisingly, given its historical squeamishness and the fact that it
was scooped, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> holds back a bit. But surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>
writes that he can't believe the charges, and hopes we can get past them
quickly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s real business: making peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kicking Saddam</ENAMEX>'s ass and...pillorying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> in connection with all the
other scandals. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re Saddam</ENAMEX>: note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is now
confronted with a serious "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX>" problem: any strong action taken
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> may be construed in the media as a manufactured diversion.)

            This scandal makes blatant the degree to which the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> holds a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge Grudge</ENAMEX>. None of the stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> today credit him for anything,
even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> Report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s name and that
her allegations were on tapes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s possession. In light of that alone,
it's absurd that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> won't even address questions that mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>.
After all, he still takes questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> --you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who
explained how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Jewell</ENAMEX> bombed the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>.

            Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s expansion of his inquiry is legally hunky-dory. But think
about it: why should you have to tell the truth about anything a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> can think to ask you about? Suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> decides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
video rental records might be relevant--should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> have to say
whether he's watched X-rated videos in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>? Should the video
delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> have to go to jail if he doesn't want to answer that one? It's a
little odd to realize that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this 25th anniversary year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe v. Wade the</ENAMEX>
only sex organ that has the constitutional right to privacy is the uterus.

         
      
   
