
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,001</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabian</ENAMEX> Naughts

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>'s hesitance about involvement in any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline stresses the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> balk, while the headlines at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> acceptance of it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , like the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>, passes along the statement made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> to the effect that while his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> supports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> inspection effort, it does not favor an
attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. But unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the
Times , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't illuminate this comment by describing the cold,
hard military consequences. Those papers point out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> decision not
to press the issue has meant that it has amassed much striking power elsewhere.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> gives this order of battle: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117 stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> and A-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter jets</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jabir Air Base</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-15</ENAMEX> fighter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jets</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahrain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheik Isa Airfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-14</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-18</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter jets</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> on a number of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-52</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Diego Garcia</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonder</ENAMEX> if this means anything to the average
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>. Wonder if it means anything to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-10</ENAMEX> isn't a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fighter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-18</ENAMEX> is a fighter<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-bomber</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> further explains
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> stance is also a diplomatic blow, denying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> a potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> of allied unity.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> stance has to do with its aversion to
involvement with any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack that doesn't have the objective of eliminating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>. But the paper delays explaining the logic until the story's 15th
paragraph: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> are afraid that a mere air campaign will leave behind a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> vengeful towards <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> that supported it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> will probably grant fly-over
privileges to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> taking off from elsewhere.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> states that likely <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> strike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guard</ENAMEX> bases, military command <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and suspected weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and
stockpiles. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports an apparent shift in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy about
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> self-defense against any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> attacks. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, it notes, Secretary
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to refrain from retaliating, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
he was quoted as granting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> the right of self-defense.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports the next phase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation: talking to
current and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> interns as a check on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s story. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says it's very unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will bring criminal charges against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> while he's in office, but that he will probably dump the
matter into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' lap as a potential impeachment case, thus plunging the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into a "wrenching political dilemma" given the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s surging
popularity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> goes on to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> in on record with a
rather loose interpretation of what counts as an impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>, reporting
that he once argued before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> that poisoning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> might be impeachable.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> is set to end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of leniency
regarding cigars. Apparently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is moving towards requiring stogie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to report their ad and promotion budgets. And is considering further
steps such as: requiring cigar ads to carry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General</ENAMEX>'s health
warning.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reports that according to a recently
released <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> have been the site of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>, perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>,
of executions of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> and common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in the latter part of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Faye Tucker</ENAMEX> execution, ran in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" a brutally reported and mug-shot illustrated piece by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Howe Verhovek</ENAMEX> on some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> waiting on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Rows</ENAMEX>.
The piece convinces the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>'s pickax is not an anomaly: "Among
the ways condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have killed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are shooting with an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AK-47</ENAMEX>, slicing with a box cutter, injecting with battery <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, and beating with
a baseball bat. One drowned her paralyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> by pushing him off a canoe on a
family outing, leaving him and his <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 pounds</NUMEX> of metal leg braces to sink to the
bottom."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has had an interesting prior run-in
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. Seems that in law school, she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in a course on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">admiralty</ENAMEX> law that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> taught. And he lost a bunch of exams including hers.
Kind of amazing those exams didn't eventually turn up in the private quarters
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
