
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm Warnings</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the New York
Times lead with a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s ruling that the line-item veto is
unconstitutional. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>'s
face-to-face rebuke of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The top national
story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is the unhappiness among many
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s decision to handle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
scandal by saying nothing critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead, in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Igor Sergeyev</ENAMEX>
forcefully lectured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> right in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
was being too tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and warned that future <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> relations may
be affected. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> kept his cool. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sergeyev</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s allegations in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> agreement by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> equipment that could be
used to develop biological weapons. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> issued a carefully worded
denial.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> portrays the recent diplomacy undertaken by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in
connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> flare-up as providing it with a chance to take on a
global role it hasn't had since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> collapse. And indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> left the
meeting with the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> proposal for softening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspections
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> tensions over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> also get front-page space at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> describes the line-item veto veto as "a major blow" (random
choice of words?) to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>.
The decision sets the stage, says the paper, for a ruling on the matter by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIV</ENAMEX> is often defended as a tool
for fiscal restraint, even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> attributes to it only $1M
in direct deficit reduction.

            The USAT front section "cover story" does a very able job of
covering the geopolitical and especially military nuances facing any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> move
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The paper points out that, of course, this time there isn't
nearly the amount of international support for military action. And it's
suggested that the current goal of thwarting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s ability to wage chemical
and biological warfare is far more nebulous than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>'s objective of throwing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>.

            But on the other hand, says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> smart bombs have gotten
smarter--they're now less likely to be distracted by smoke or bad weather-- and
there will be a lot more of them now. And now almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> in the
gathering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> can launch them.

            This story has a surprising, even disconcerting amount of order of battle
information ("The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117 Stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> stationed nearby in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>.").
Also, the piece makes the point that still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX>,
there is no ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> in the inventory that can reliably destroy bio-chemical
weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> while keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poisons</ENAMEX> from getting into the atmosphere, which
means that true precision will be needed to avoid large numbers of civilian
casualties. Another obstacle noted is that it is impossible to destroy all the
computer disks holding "cookbooks" for making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> and biological
weapons.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of questions about the story however: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that the B-2
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> is a "stealth design like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117" stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, just much
bigger. But actually, the former employs smooth curves to bend radar waves
while the latter uses flat, jagged edges to scatter them. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says
that the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> capable of dropping a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,000 lb</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bunker</ENAMEX>-busting bomb" is
missing from the roster being formed over there. But doesn't explain why. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page piece, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-Marine Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Trainor</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military plan, says that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> pounders will be used.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> advisor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> had a phone conversation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> with.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>. His
purpose: to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s allegations of sexual
harassment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" appreciates all its sharp-eyed grammarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and will
press on irregardless of its occasional missteps.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> features a sprawling op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Know the Answers Before</ENAMEX>
Going to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>." In it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clancy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that we don't seem to have the answers to
very many of the questions relevant to attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s chemical and biological
warfare capabilities. This is interesting, because in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clancy</ENAMEX>'s novels the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
invariably has all the answers, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> perform as required. So maybe
the questions he proliferates here (here, unlike in his books, he questions the
notion of a "surgical" strike, and here he wonders, "Who has told us that it is
OK to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?") are signs of a long-deferred maturity. But
more likely is that this is anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> blather from a conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. After all, in this piece the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>-home-and-fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> turned
global <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> as if it were a model of Clausewitzian
clarity concerning ultimate goals and acceptable means, forgetting in the
process that at the end of that war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell/Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX> axis
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">internally</ENAMEX> disagreed about war issues that had never been articulated for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: Should the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> military, invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">topple Hussein</ENAMEX> even after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was repulsed from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>? Because of that
history, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have now given such matters much more thought.

         
      
   
