
   
   
      
         
            Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with mounting criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, mincing no words
in referring to "his probe into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' disability
insurance claims. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
desire to drop the annual process of certifying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and other nations
are cooperating in the drug war in favor of setting up an international
anti-drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> that such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> would join. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead states that the "consumer" health-care laws (the scare-quotes are supplied
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ) being discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state capitals</ENAMEX> tend to focus more on
protecting "the incomes, jobs and turf of the health-care system's biggest and
richest vested interests," namely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist physicians</ENAMEX> and managed-care
plans.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> used to be among the most dependable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , they've been leaving their jobs to collect disability benefits in such high numbers that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> now view them as in the same claim risk echelon as grocery cashiers
and bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tellers</ENAMEX>, and even riskier than shipping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> and traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX>.
Not to mention far below <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>. The most likely
explanation: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> and unhappiness brought on by the widespread advent of
managed care. As a result, disability premiums for docs are up big-time: one
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX> is charging <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 25 percent</NUMEX> more than just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead states that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> began making
the case for military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> audience <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.." That
"began" is a little unfair, isn't it? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes on to point out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, which began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>'s recess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, left without passing a resolution
authorizing force. Isn't this a rather telling demonstration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'
priorities? Hmmm...what should I do: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Decide</ENAMEX> on whether or not to go to war
or...take a vacation?
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front discusses some of the events that could affect the
timing of any military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Chief among them: moon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phases</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> are easier to eyeball under a full moon), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parents</ENAMEX>'
Weekend at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> are scheduled to go, and
that's not the best place to conduct a war from), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> (there's an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX> convention that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> refrain from war during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX>).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that, as part of his pitch on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX>" shot,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> showed a photo of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> killed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Yet a front-page piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT Middle East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Wright</ENAMEX> states that in the eyes of some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> knew the intelligence it supplied to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 80s</TIMEX> (during its war
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>) would be used to develop chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> plans.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> also brings word of anti-paparazzi legislation about to be introduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feinstein</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Privacy Protection Act"</ENAMEX> (it sounded better than the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alec Baldwin Should Be Able To Punch Out Photographers</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>) would, says the
paper, preserve the right to photograph <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> in public, but would crack
down on actions that could jeopardize safety. This is a fine example of what
Slate deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX> has called a therapeutic law: it
accomplishes nothing, except perhaps to make us feel good via the illusion of
accomplishing something. Really, how many examples are there of paparazzi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endangering</ENAMEX> (as opposed to merely inconveniencing) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s death turned out not to be one--it was drunk driving. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead
mentions a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> waiting for a glimpse,
but again, where's the safety issue there? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Shriver</ENAMEX> being cut off in traffic by videographers, but
that just gets at the redundancy of the law: reckless driving is already
against the law, as is trespassing on somebody's doorstep. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>"
suspects that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feinstein</ENAMEX> gets all this, but can also do the math: a bill
protecting the rights of Arnold and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec</ENAMEX> means serious donations.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s complaint that has led to the current impasse is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
weapons inspectors are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX>. And yet on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's front, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Jeffrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> makes the point that if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> do attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, they will
be drawing in part on data about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> capabilities and targets collected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill-Gates</ENAMEX>-pie-in-the-face incident as a
springboard for a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" thumbsucker about the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> as a
weapon. It wasn't enough to have the de rigeur mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cagney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grapefruiting Mae Clark</ENAMEX>. There were also references to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Peloponnesian war</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Rebellion, Bismarck</ENAMEX>, and the siege of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leningrad</ENAMEX>. But most special,
however, was this passage: "A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> in the face, it's Soupy Sales stuff," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Smith</ENAMEX>, who teaches culinary history at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New School for Social</ENAMEX>
Research."

         
      
   
