
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewatershed</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James McDougal</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the upcoming return grand jury
appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> seeking a tough stance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with drawing the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> battle lines regarding the upcoming
surplus budget. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says a rift has opened between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who continue to aggressively opt for tax cuts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who are more apt to go along with the basic thrust of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> plan.

            The death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> where he
was serving his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> sentence, is widely viewed as trouble for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says it means the end for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> of a steady stream of information
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' business and political activities. The LAT front-page
McDougal piece says his death could be a "setback." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> calls McDougal
a "dashing eccentric." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls him a "wily <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> banking
rogue."

            Everybody quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement of condolence: "I have good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> we worked together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, and I extend my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condolences</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (in its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> profile) mention that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> statement notably lacked any
expression of sympathy from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says there is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDougal</ENAMEX> book on the way titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Arkansas Mischief</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead set out the meaning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
deposition scoop from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX>: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
Currie, had become the central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in his accounts of all his dealings
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. It apparently took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> for that to sink in at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s lead makes essentially the same point. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
quotes this gender- and religion-confused defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> offered by Jesse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> isn't a lone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> shooting from the hips....She is a
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>....It isn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> to be making
independent decisions of her own volition."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead states that on the eve of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> conference in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> is pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> to act decisively to end the recent
outbreak of violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> may balk at punitive measures directed against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's
veteran war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hedges</ENAMEX> provides detailed reporting on the ground from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prekaz</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedges</ENAMEX> says there were clear indications the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> saw heavy combat, indicating
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> side was not unarmed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedges</ENAMEX>' dispatch includes the harrowing
tale of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prekaz</ENAMEX> with her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> after her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was killed.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has a brief front-page blurb and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a more
detailed piece based on the report in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> are investigating the theft, during the height of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
crisis, by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a brown tweed jacket, of top secret documents from a secure
State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> just down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s. So far, the papers
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> suspect an inside job.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that based on recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> performances, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> legal team
clearly is calling the shots in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> flap, and its strategy is simple:
the less said, the better." In the piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee Dee Myers</ENAMEX> joins fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alum George S.</ENAMEX> in dumping on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>: "Throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presidency</ENAMEX>, even times when I was there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has created the
appearance of wrongdoing by being slow to come forward with the facts."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> have been uniformly weak-willed in their inability to resist the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> saga. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> demonstrates an inability to resist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Today, his
column is quite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. Seems ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> had a chance hook-up with her in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">posh Cosmos Club</ENAMEX>: "The dark-eyed young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> looked attractive in a simple
short black dress and black stockings....She was too carefully coiffured, but
had a sort of natural, youthful, exuberant smile that anybody, even a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, would enjoy seeing around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
