
   
   
      
         
            Petroleum Jelling

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the decision by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of some of the world's top oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exporters</ENAMEX>
to cut back production in an attempt to reverse a sharp price slide. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
which runs the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> as its off-lead, leads with the revelation that last
fall, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> shut down some of its worldwide computer systems
because of a suspected penetration by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>. The systems contain unclassified
but sensitive information such as the travel schedules of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> joint appearance of
convention.

            The oil news is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, which together
supply <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a fifth</NUMEX> of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, issued a joint statement saying that
they and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> plan a cutback amounting to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 2.7 percent</NUMEX> of
world production. The move, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls "unusual solidarity," is
expected to send oil prices up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the initial
reaction in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> markets on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was nearly a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> up-tick.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explains that having non-OPEC <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is important because in the past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> production cuts have often been met
with non-OPEC production surges. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also notes that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> had
been predicting the economic pain of low oil revenues would force the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>
to rein in production. Clear enough, but then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes on to "illustrate"
that idea with the following passage from the joint statement, which is
anything but: ".[A] drop in oil prices could lead to a reduction in the
investments needed to secure international supplies, which would destabilize
the world economy in the medium term."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSCAR</ENAMEX> NOTE I: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Full Monty</ENAMEX>," made for a paltry
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.5 million</NUMEX>, could ultimately turn a profit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $100 million</NUMEX>. The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says the movie has already raked
in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $200 million</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OSCAR NOTE II</ENAMEX>: This past <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reported that acting is on
the rise as an occupational choice for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s USAT
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snapshot</ENAMEX>" reports that in a recent poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> surveyed would
prefer their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> grew up to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 32 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> preferred this.)

            Curiously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead puts in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph the information
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Checchi</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Harman</ENAMEX> for appealing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harman</ENAMEX> sniped at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Checchi</ENAMEX> for having a lot of position papers,
and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> attacked them both as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> trying to buy
the election, but delays until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> paragraph the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Checchi</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harman</ENAMEX> said that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> they would seek to repeal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 209</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ballot measure outlawing racial and gender preferences in state
hiring and college admissions, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> would not do this. Plus, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> has to wait to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> paragraph to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> also wouldn't
commit to signing a bill sanctioning gay marriage, while both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Checchi</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harman</ENAMEX> would do that.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a piece inside reporting that according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> have, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several years</TIMEX>, quietly
recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and teach their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> how to
build <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> to carry deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">payloads</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far as 1,200 miles</NUMEX>. The piece goes
on to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> intend to stop this practice. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>,
remarks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , wonder if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can in fact stop the
flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> brings evidence that not every conservative blindly supports
the many turns of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX> of
Law" piece, by a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>, argues
that "it is time for a sober reassessment of the power we have concentrated in
the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and the alarming absence of effective checks and
balances to prevent the widespread abuse of that power."

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> who still think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
sober "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of record," are directed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s front section, page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>.
There, instead of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of straightforward shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX> no
doubt available, the paper opts for a shot of him with a crazed smile and hands
not quite in front his face, making him look like a spastic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> don.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gridiron Dinner</ENAMEX>, that annual
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> masque in which bigfoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> entertain the
government's heaviest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>versa. The centerpiece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s monologue, which featured the following joke he said had
been approved by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knock-knock"</ENAMEX> "Don't answer that."

         
      
   
