
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Leaves</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building</ENAMEX>

            Finally, after a solid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, some of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> lead with monographs
that aren't Monicagraphs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimate Charlie Trie</ENAMEX> and another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in
connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>'s investigation into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
campaign. (This story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , but the New York
Times runs it deep inside.) And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s pronouncement that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> can't be convinced, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is ready
to launch military strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> on its own. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> added that the
diplomatic string is running out and reiterated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> position: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> must have unconditional access to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elsewhere</ENAMEX>,
this story doesn't get that much play either: at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> it only gets a
reefer on the front page, below the fold.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a new poll indicating the strength of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
post<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-</ENAMEX>scandal popular support, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with new details about
the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> meeting between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says its new poll (of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">684</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, done in concert with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>) shows that after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> enjoys his
highest approval rating ever--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 percent</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reports that former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Panetta</ENAMEX> was questioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. (This news is also flagged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box and on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> picked up
evidence from a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s, who says he had an affair
with her.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also offers a glimpse into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s vie en scandale: long days
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequestered</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, watching TV and talking on the
phone in code. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is quoted saying that she watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s SOTU
address. "She thought he did a good job with it," he says. "She thinks he's
done a good job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. She still considers him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>."

            Pursuing a thread <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> pulled by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> delve into that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> 28th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> meeting
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and his ex-intern, prompted by her concerns over a
subpoena in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> claims that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told her at the time that she could testify her visits to him at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> were to see his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, and that he suggested that she could
avoid testifying altogether by being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes on to
point out that besides the issue of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> actually said at this meeting,
it would be "ethically questionable" for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> in a civil lawsuit merely
to discuss the case with a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> already subpoenaed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says this meeting was confirmed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> declined to comment about it and has
refused to release the relevant entry logs.

            The LAT front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside report an
increase in the number of applications to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> (up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.9 percent</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latinos</ENAMEX> (up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX>). This confounds
much-publicized concerns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s decision to end affirmative action
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> would have a chilling effect on minority applications.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>' verbal incontinence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s sex
lives seems to have had immediate results. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>
tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that, although in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would occasionally
talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>, "I doubt that will ever happen again."

            A big color shot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> greeting an exuberant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sits athwart the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> meeting and
astride its story about his trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>. From just one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glance</ENAMEX>, it's hard to say which story the picture goes with. In a way, it goes
with both. It was in fact taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s appearance at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX>. But it captures the very same hands-on political body
chemistry apparent in those shots we've all seen by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>.
Indeed, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the photograph looking up at and/or reaching
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of them are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. They are all smiling at him.

         
      
   
