
   
   
      
         
            Headline

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead with the heating-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> national
edition goes with the maneuvering between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eve</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the likely stance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will take in separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> meetings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>--gentle persuasion, not tough talk.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead states that leaks indicate that in his deposition last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was asked detailed questions about his sexual history with at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> escorted by a state trooper to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rendezvous</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just days</TIMEX> before he became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> denied
sexually harassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> or anyone else.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead has the same thrust, only a little more detailed. For
instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also has the story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> meeting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just days</TIMEX> before his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural</ENAMEX>, but adds the detail that she says
all the encounters were innocent. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> emphasizes that how much
of the collateral sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> gets into the actual trial is up to the trial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> clearly has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones Jones</ENAMEX>, also reporting that she emerged
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s deposition "clearly elated," dining out, drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laughing</ENAMEX>, and putting a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Paula</ENAMEX> piece on the front, about how the public
is taking the whole thing. By contrast, neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> nor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> get to it until the inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead observes that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s talk portraying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> in the struggle against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> imperialism, there's still plenty
of religious repression in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Rohter</ENAMEX> gives an
eyewitness account of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> cops ordering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church group</ENAMEX> to stop
putting up posters advertising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pontiff</ENAMEX>'s visit.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> front-page civil
rights-related stories. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a big picture on the front of a
black church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>, but puts its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX> story, about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> handles his
memory, inside.) One is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> will announce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> DOJ budget increase that if approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would
mean a stepped-up anti-discrimination emphasis in such areas as fair-housing
laws and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> misconduct investigations. The other is the bizarre news that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> murdered in that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> church bombing discovered that her grave is empty.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has largely slipped off the front page, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-lead describes
how both sides are talking tougher now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, reports the paper,
called on TV over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> for "sustained air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>" if the crisis
isn't resolved, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi VP</ENAMEX> urged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> to join a new
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to stage a holy war against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions. (Suggested
slogan: "We do more surrendering before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 o'clock</TIMEX> than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> do all
day.")

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 trillion</NUMEX> worth of
mergers involving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, which was itself a
record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. The paper likens these mega-mergers to the industrial upheavals at
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the twentieth century</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auto companies</ENAMEX>
became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of steel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were forged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX>
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Steel</ENAMEX>.

            Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> has, in a new book excerpted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> , charged
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX>, is such an "ardent IRA
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apologist</ENAMEX>" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> began withholding sensitive security information
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s main <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> announced
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 billion</NUMEX> in export sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>," less-than-full-disclosure flavor of the story comes with the detail
that the these sales are supposed to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> civilian goods such as
airplane fuselages, televisions and hairnets, but there isn't one current
example cited from that other <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>.

            The WP business section runs an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX>,
which reveals that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> now handles <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 million</NUMEX> e-mails a day, and that
up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, Case wasn't able to get his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to understand
what he did for a living. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead with the heating-up Paula Jones
case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> national edition goes with the maneuvering between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> on the eve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the
likely stance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will take in separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> meetings this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>--gentle persuasion, not tough talk.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead states that leaks indicate that in his deposition last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was asked detailed questions about his sexual history with at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> escorted by a state trooper to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rendezvous</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just days</TIMEX> before he became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> denied
sexually harassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> or anyone else.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead has the same thrust, only a little more detailed. For
instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also has the story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> meeting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just days</TIMEX> before his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural</ENAMEX>, but adds the detail that she says
all the encounters were innocent. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> emphasizes that how much
of the collateral sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> gets into the actual trial is up to the trial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> clearly has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones Jones</ENAMEX>, also reporting that she emerged
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s deposition "clearly elated," dining out, drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laughing</ENAMEX>, and putting a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Paula</ENAMEX> piece on the front, about how the public
is taking the whole thing. By contrast, neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> nor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> get to it until the inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead observes that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s talk portraying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> in the struggle against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> imperialism, there's still plenty
of religious repression in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Rohter</ENAMEX> gives an
eyewitness account of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> cops orderi

         
      
   
