
   
   
      
         
            Organ-ized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-brokered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> deal is the consensus top story.
The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> gave his tentative OK to it, but also
that he will keep the built-up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> region to make
sure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> keeps up its end. It's also noted all around that in his remarks
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reserved the right to respond in the "manner of our own
choosing" to any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> breach of the new accord.

            The actual details of the deal are still somewhat unclear, but it has
emerged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> will be accompanied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>--as
yet unidentified-- in their tours of the disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said that the proposed arrangement implicitly supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
critique of the original inspection set-up. But perhaps more telling, the paper
also reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> expressed relief at the
last-minute veer away from an air war. And that includes military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>, one
of whom is quoted, "We had a tough time seeing where this was going to take
us."

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
front-page "news analysis" piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX> states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't have
much choice about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> deal because he was unwilling from the start to
contemplate a campaign that would drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> from power, but only one that
would make him submit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> authority.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has the most reporting on the domestic political reaction
to the deal, stating that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has abdicated
the making of foreign policy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, and that the general mood in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
was caution and skepticism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> is quoted as being concerned that the
administration had "subcontracted its foreign policy to [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>." Surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> said he didn't have those qualms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> articulates the central worry: "How do we avoid
this ratcheting up on an annual basis?"

            The WP front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has subpoenaed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> to appear before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> to answer questions
about any role he might have had in disseminating negative information about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the subpoena is "particularly broad"
and signals "an escalation in the battle between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> was incensed and also that
he accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> of leaking his subpoena to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
prompted by a tip from celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Wu</ENAMEX>, has
produced the arrest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for trying to sell organs from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of
executed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>. Allegedly, it was eye corneas at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> a pair, and
kidney transplants for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> plus. Also in the offing apparently were
pancreases, livers, lungs and skin. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs its organs-for-sale
story inside, pointing out that one of the arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> said that he could
guarantee skin from young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> and lungs from ones who didn't smoke.
Provided that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>" in question are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> tried and executed,
neither piece, it seems, really makes it clear exactly why this practice is
inherently deplorable. After all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> suffers from
an acute shortage of organs for transplant.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reports that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> has found that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> assumptions to the contrary, childless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> do not work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer hours</TIMEX> than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, believe in good old-fashioned conservative
family values? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX> has left her newly
fatherless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year-old</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine-year-old</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> while
she came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to raise money for her campaign to win her late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s congressional seat. Does the prospect of even lengthier absences,
should she win, daunt her? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is in recess often enough
where I could be [with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Springs</ENAMEX>] for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> at a time."

         
      
   
