
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marines Should Have Landed</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with an unprecedented court decision reinstalling in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s office the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> defeated at the polls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the finding by military
accident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> jet was at fault in the deaths
of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Dealers</ENAMEX> are discussing a stock exchange merger. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Wilson</ENAMEX>'s executive abolition of
affirmative action in the awarding of state contracts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s announcement
came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just days</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> said such a move would be legal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that accident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> jet was flying too
low--<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 300 to 400 feet</NUMEX> when it was supposed to be at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>-- and too
fast--<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 100 miles per hour</NUMEX> over the prescribed limit for the
route--when it struck that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> cable car wire. (By the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
is wrong to say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was going "<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 knots per hour</NUMEX>" too fast--a "knot" is
a (nautical) <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">mile per hour</NUMEX>.) As a result, says the paper, they recommend that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> face "some sort of punishment." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> are, in their front-page pieces on the finding, all clearer about
what kind: court-martial and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. In addition, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aviators</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> are also likely to be subject to further
administrative action. Everybody notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> hope the tough stance
will ease <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> demands to try the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aviators</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>.

            None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are very clear on why not only the pilot but also the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> could plausibly be held accountable. None
mentions that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the EA6B</TIMEX> only has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of flight controls and that therefore
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> electronic warfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> cannot control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s
speed, altitude or course. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> barely brushes this topic,
speculating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> may have concluded the tragedy resulted from
a decision by the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. But for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say, the finding makes as
much sense as holding a stewardess responsible for a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>'s flight
violations.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead quickly becomes a primer on the history of the
relevant stock markets and the differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> and culture among them.
But inexcusably, the piece delays until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> paragraph any hint of why the
possible merger could be of interest to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>: it could mean
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. The merger story is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , but doesn't make anybody else's
front.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> inside piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> reveals that she never labeled the
tapes she made of her phone conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, but did keep
her TV on during the calls, knowing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> broadcasts and sitcom
episodes audible in the background would enable the particular calls to be
dated.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the purchase of the average-priced new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> took almost
exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s worth of median family income. That sounds high, so the
real surprise is that, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , this is the lowest
level since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports the results of a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press-Center for</ENAMEX>
Responsive Politics survey on lobbying, which show that interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are
spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> to pressure the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> on pet issues.
The number one noodge is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX>, which, in the first
half of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the most recent available reporting period, spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a big illustrated front-page piece on the recent
discovery that an asteroid, called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"1997 XF 11</ENAMEX>," is likely to pass within
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30,000 miles</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> (that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> times closer than the moon) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 26</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2028</TIMEX>. What's more, there's a possibility it will hit <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> then. (The asteroid
story also makes the USAT front and is inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .) The
astronomer making the announcement is quoted saying there is "no immediate
cause for alarm." (That's right--the cause for alarm is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years from now</TIMEX>.)
We have, he says, plenty of time "to improve our knowledge of this thing and
take steps, if necessary." Steps, like, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , blowing up a
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> near the asteroid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also mentions that two movies
coming out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX> deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX> of threatened interstellar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collisions</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of those movies must just be sooo upset about
this news.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> thinks the big question isn't whether <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">XF 11</ENAMEX> will hit us in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2028</TIMEX>--it's how will it affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation.

         
      
   
