
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Affairs</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation into allegations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> suborned
perjury by a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> intern. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-judge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, reported both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , has authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to explore charges
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> persuaded the intern, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, to deny that she had had a year-and-a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-long affair with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> after she had detailed the relationship in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> conversations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>. Tripp, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> later worked,
recorded the conversations surreptitiously and reportedly turned the tapes over
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> denied the affair in sworn depositions in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX> called the story
"ridiculous" and told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> he "smelled a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>." Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> nor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> would comment on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had discussed her
testimony with her.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> talks lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> goes with the finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Kacszynski</ENAMEX> is legally competent
to stand trial, which is also the top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who will meet with Yassir
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, is getting into an unusual amount of detail in the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> talks.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that before the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> broached substantive
matters, they made an attempt to clear the air about their own troubled
relationship. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> complained about being snubbed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on a prior
visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> chided him for meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX> the
other day, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> has distributed videos suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
may have been complicit in a murder. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its lead, says that
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were "furious" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> rendezvous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> presented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with a stack of gross images of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> met again last night but also
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the long talks have thus far failed to restart the deadlocked
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process.

            Besides the court-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>'s finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kacszynski</ENAMEX> can stand
trial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also pass along indications that she found him to be mentally
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ill. USAT</ENAMEX> quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story saying that in her eyes he's a paranoid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">schizophrenic</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that she concluded he "actually does
resort to violence against those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that he believes
are hurting him." Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> hint at the possibility of renewed plea
bargaining now, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> stating flatly that this is underway. Prompted
by the recent murder of a NYC plainclothes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> during a drug bust, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has an informative take-out on undercover work, which points out
that about twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> a NYC undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> is shot during a buy, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times a month, one is forced at gunpoint by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> to use <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>. The story adds that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 70 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s undercover cops are
black or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report in front-page
stories that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> is reaping a financial windfall from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>'s visit. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> estimates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX> will pump <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an extra $25</NUMEX>
million into the local economy. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that hotel prices
have recently doubled and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has come up with such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> as a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> licensing fee for each satellite phone brought in by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>.
Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> state television is charging each visiting TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> fee for the live video feed of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>'s activities.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> is suing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and one of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, alleging that the car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> concealed ignition switch defects that
led to car fires and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> in insurance claims. (This story is also on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front.)

            The on-off-on again decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX> to invite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> for a look-see while he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> generates an uncommon amount of
opinion at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . Sure, invite him, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hoagland</ENAMEX>.
Absolutely not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s editorial
on the matter says it all, though: "Very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tour [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>] and come
away unmoved and unchanged. Perhaps Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> would be one of those rare
exceptions. But what would be lost by taking that chance?"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial page is likewise on the mark in its discussion of
whether in light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> rapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> college excursions
should be curtailed, pointing out that such enriching experiences are probably
not as rape-risky as fraternity parties.

         
      
   
