
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain Mutiny</ENAMEX>

            
lead with the failure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feingold-McCain</ENAMEX> campaign reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>, which would have barred the national political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> from trafficking
in "soft money." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the federal indictment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> corrections <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> suspected of conspiracy and cover-up in
connection with various improprieties concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>, including a
suspicious death.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feingold-McCain</ENAMEX> defeat came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at the hands of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-led
filibuster. This was, in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , "nearly a replay" of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>'s fate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>. The repetitive outcome, showed, says the paper, that a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of publicity about the excesses of political fund-raising had "failed to
change a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s mind."

            The bills' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX>, argue
that new fund-raising limitations amount to an infringement on free speech. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConnell</ENAMEX> gives away the game in telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that
provide what he calls "valuable grass-roots support" (=soft money) had strongly
opposed the reform bill. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Right to Life Committee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
goes on to point out that while for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had put
the spotlight on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s more unseemly fund-raising efforts, they
have fiercely resisted any legislative fix that would cancel their fund-raising
advantage, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> spells out: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40.2 million</NUMEX> in soft money, compared
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33.3 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> both report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> intend to run on the issue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> congressional elections.
Everybody quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s reason for believing that eventually,
public pressure for change will increase: "There will be more scandals, more
indictments and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going to jail."

            There's another LAT front-page story about jail abuses: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A. City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> is investigating the possibility that beatings of accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child molesters</ENAMEX> were allegedly encouraged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> working in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s
central jail and resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> homicide.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
formally took over the prosecution of police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> implicated in the brutal
attack <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Haitian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abner Louima</ENAMEX>. Conviction on the federal
civil rights charges could mean sentences of up to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> charged pleaded not guilty and remain free on bond.

            The same picture of a jubilant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX> celebrating a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s
finding of no liability in her mad cow trial runs on the fronts of each of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> that use photos. The caption and headline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> join the fun:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jurors</ENAMEX>: no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah"</ENAMEX> ( USAT ), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Savoring Victory"</ENAMEX> ( LAT ) and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next On Oprah: Freedom Of Speech"</ENAMEX> ( WP ).

            The lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is now
"enthralled by the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> methods can remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> from
power," and points out that a tonic for that idea is found in the recently
released internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> report about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Pigs failure</ENAMEX>. Both cases, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , represent overly optimistic expectations that entrenched
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> can be toppled by small acts of insurrection.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>, owned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, was to have published the memoirs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Patten</ENAMEX>, last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have parted company. The paper quotes people
passages critical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> points out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> has a track record of using his media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> to advance his interests
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. For instance, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> dropped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> from the
collection of channels it beams into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> didn't like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> program on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source"</ENAMEX> column says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, reporters
covering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> received an official e-mail from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that was.a long list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex jokes. (We're assuming
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>, not by.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is "looking into it."

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snapshot</ENAMEX>," fully <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>--which the paper notes, includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--would not ever consider doing what either of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> do for a
living.

         
      
   
