
   
   
      
         
            Gone Fission

Times all lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s surprise nuclear tests, which are also the
subject of a lengthy WSJ front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
puts this development just above the fold, but leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s ruling upholding the admissibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> evidence, provided
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> show that correct procedures were used.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atal Bihari</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vajpayee</ENAMEX>, who announced the tests <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, came to power <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX> as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that has advocated the embrace of nuclear
weaponry as a vehicle for achieving great-power status. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
reports that basically, within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> the tests met with neither political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissent</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhian</ENAMEX> pacifism.

            Most everywhere else was different. The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
was "deeply distressed" (but, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , he will still make his planned
trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>
condemned the tests, report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s largest foreign aid
source--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> are considering suspending aid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Although
the amount of direct <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid is minuscule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
explain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is considering invoking a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> federal
law that would, besides cutting off aid, also bar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> bank
loans and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> aid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> adds <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain and Germany</ENAMEX> to
the ranks of those not amused.

            And there was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayub Khan</ENAMEX> responded, reports
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , by hinting that his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would consider conducting its own
nuclear tests. The papers all note the widespread fear that the tests could
signify heightened tensions between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and even a nuclear arms
race between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note, has signed
the treaties that constrain nuclear tests. Most of the papers observe that many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> feel the tests were really designed to send a message to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
especially, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> report,
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just last week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>,
is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s "potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> number one."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> nicely captures the bizarre scene of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
announcement, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vajpayee</ENAMEX> ignored the likely geo-political shockwaves and
spoke instead of measured yields and expected values and offered his warm
congratulations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> responsible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
Post observe that one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tests was of a thermonuclear device.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> that is a hydrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> say that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> satellites, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> tests seemed to have
caught the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and the other established <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX> by
surprise.

            Everybody's off-lead is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision to seek the appointment of an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate allegations that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Herman</ENAMEX> peddled influence and was
involved in an illegal campaign contribution scheme. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has asked for an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial page wishes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s sensitivity to conflicts of interest and campaign fund-raising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">improprieties</ENAMEX> extended to "the broader and more important matter of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
presidential fund-raising scandals." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coverups</ENAMEX>," makes the
same point.

            The LAT front says there's a limit to how big these mega-mergers can
get: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 billion</NUMEX>. That's how much, the paper figures, it would cost for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, the second
largest.

            Buried fairly deep inside the metro edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is a very
brief item reporting that a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> was sentenced in a procurement
case. What did he do? He sold defective parts for the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> used to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">catch U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> as they land on aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. When these cables
fail, aircrews plunge to watery graves and flight deck personnel quite
literally get cut in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. What was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>'s sentence? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three months</TIMEX> in
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club Fed</ENAMEX>, no doubt) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> of house arrest. Do you
think that punishment fits that crime? Another question: It's bad enough that
the law tends to downplay these cases, but why don't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> make more of
being willing to kill service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to make a profit? Maybe it's because
they're too into profit and not enough into service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.

            Incidentally that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> editorial "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coverups</ENAMEX>" makes the
slyest reference yet to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> problem. The piece is ostensibly about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> and the Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> tapes and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> counteroffensive
vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>. But it includes this: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX>, we don't doubt that it's
possible to wave all this away as partisan tit for tat. Problem is, serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> know that this scandal is about a lot more than tat."

         
      
   
