
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon Crazy</ENAMEX>

            A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen-year-old</TIMEX>'s shooting spree at his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> high school leads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . A
record deal--the planned purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PolyGram</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Co.</ENAMEX>--leads at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
national edition lead is the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first day</TIMEX> in office.
Under a banner headline, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>'s
decision not to run for re-election, but its top national story is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>.

            The details of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> shootings are, in the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disturbingly</ENAMEX> familiar": a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> well-known for trouble acts out prior threats
via his access to tremendous firepower. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kipland Kinkel</ENAMEX>, shot up the school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistols</ENAMEX>,
killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and wounding <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>. The carnage was stopped when a
critically wounded student tackled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinkel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, believed to be that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinkel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>,
were later found in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>,
who said that he "murdered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>."

            Afterwards, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> charged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had ample warning that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinkel</ENAMEX> posed a danger to others. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, he had been
suspended from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and arrested for bringing a gun to school, and he was
released to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. And he had, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say, frequently written and
talked about killing in school assignments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that he had
been voted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> "most likely to start <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX>.''

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quote an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>'s observation that the recent
trend of school shootings has accelerated from single specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> to
indiscriminate multiple homicides.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> putting merger over murder <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Its account of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram/Polygram</ENAMEX> seems a bit breathless. The deal, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraph</ENAMEX>, involves the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LL Cool J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Morrison</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pavarotti</ENAMEX>. And it would "radically alter the nature of the architecture of the
business by shrinking the number of global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> from"--can you stand
it?--"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six to five</TIMEX>."

            Deep inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is a report that casts an interesting light on the
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> inspection wrangle with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Boustany</ENAMEX> states that
contrary to the general media coverage, back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> were
barred from one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, they weren't looking
for actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware</ENAMEX>--they were looking for documents
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> such things. Which would explain how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> were able to render the
sites pristine in the relatively short time before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> finally
gained access.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> achieves a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> rarity: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX> of face-time with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> tells the paper he "absolutely" will travel as
planned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy has been unduly
influenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> campaign contributions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> describes his
administration's decision to allow high technology to be exported to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as
"routine." He also tells USAT that during his trip, he will raise the
issue of illegal campaign contributions with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. (That's what
we're afraid of.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that some
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> who voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to restrict <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> had
previously urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to export satellites there.

            Ever wonder if congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> help their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> write their
newspaper submissions? Consider the following from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . "It is vital
that as the global economy goes into high gear, there is a globally consistent
standard for intellectual property. [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copyright</ENAMEX>] Term extension represents one
aspect of the harmonization of the intellectual property regimes." Signed, Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
