
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Mellows</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>. But to the New York
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> there's something much sexier than the
presidential love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> have more of their fortunes invested in the stock market
than at any time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 50 years</TIMEX>, and maybe ever.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Lewis</ENAMEX> (nee <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>) is due back in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> room <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> after being compelled to answer questions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that
according to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> was "aware of a relationship
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." Also, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> was aware her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
was "infatuated" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is scheduled to appear before the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand jury</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this week</TIMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> all quote her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s comment that
she will testify if his attempts to quash the grand jury subpoena are
unsuccessful. "She has," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, "no intention of falling on her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sword</ENAMEX>." Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>: ixnay on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword metaphors</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> was privy to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s taped account of her
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and that her reaction to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s attempt to
conceal it from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> was, "What's the big deal? So she lied and convinced
someone else to lie." The paper effortlessly ticks off several of the scandal's
other new poontangents: a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s denial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s request for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speed-up of the Paula</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case, another federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to get his hands on a sealed deposition made by the allegedly
lipstick-smeared and disheveled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>, and the
turn-over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> of boxes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case materials about yet other women
thought linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes a bit overboard with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120-plus</NUMEX> words on an alleged
conversation between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> that
reveal nothing about the conversation except that it lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> and was not confrontational. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> does a little better,
saying the discussion was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>'s inquiry into why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> was transferred out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> blind-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> this episode, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> credits it by name to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' fianc,.

            None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' accounts addresses a natural question: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> can't
be compelled to testify against each other, how come a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (especially one
who's apparently her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s "closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidante</ENAMEX>") can be compelled to testify
against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>? Why, in the law, is water thicker than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> recently caught a lot of hell for its
ultimately retracted story that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">steward</ENAMEX> had told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had been alone with Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Well, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s WP
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX>, a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is saying the same thing.

            The possible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> attack takes a number and waits. Yes, it gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and a spot on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front. However, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>'s various burnoose conferences slip to page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>. But
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Titanic"'s 14 Oscar</ENAMEX> nominations are front page at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that, thus far, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter Olympic</ENAMEX> ratings are about
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> below what was promised to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, raising the prospect of
expensive givebacks to them.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOTP</ENAMEX> sends along this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch from that ex-midshipwomen's murder
trial: "On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> in the trial appeared bored or puzzled by the defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>'s tactic of presenting a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>." Hmmm.what were they
expecting?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> scrupulously corrects a prior misstatement of the words
making up the acronym of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nemesis organization</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPECTRE</ENAMEX>." Which
is particularly odd given the frequency with which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are
left seriously confused about many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s more significant alleged
redemptions and original sins. Here's a tip, though: "failure to attribute
phrasing" means "plagiarism."

         
      
   
