
   
   
      
         
            These <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guns Not For Hire</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to impose a ban on the import of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>
types of assault-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. This is also the top national story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's top national story is a federally funded
study indicating that a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> previously used to prevent a recurrence of breast
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> could dramatically prevent its onset as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX>'s decision to crack down on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> that use unfair methods to snuff out low-fare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>.

            The news about the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> drug, tamoxifen, comes, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , from the largest clinical experiment ever for testing a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> prevention. However, tamoxifen is also known, says the paper,
to treble the risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX>, and to increase one's chance of
developing blood clots. (The headline over the story at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , which runs
it as its top-of-the-front-page "talker," emphasizes the "big risk.") It's
likely therefore, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> will only be recommended for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at high risk
for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s gun move, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , could keep
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">high-powered guns</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of this
sort have been banned previously, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>) and by an
earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ban (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), but foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> responded by slightly
modifying their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. But now, explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATF</ENAMEX> has ruled that
these modifications are superficial and hence that the ban sticks. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that the timing of the announcement was driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
desire to dramatize government action in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> schoolyard
shootings, even though none of the types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> used there are affected by
the decision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> assailed the ban, and promised to seek relief in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> cites as one reason
for the move the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s series <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were
modifying their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to make them legal but not less lethal. The WP
carries the story inside.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rule of Law</ENAMEX>" feature detailing
the recent trend of the solidification of the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, even vicious
ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> in several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, for instance, have invalidated breed-specific
bans because they "deny <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pit bull</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> equal protection and due process."
Plus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is considering "boneheaded" legislation that would force cities
to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pit bulls</ENAMEX> in public housing.

            A piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section reports that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are
concerned about the proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on the Internet posing as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has issued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> alerts about such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ventures</ENAMEX>, which could appear to be just like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,600</NUMEX> legit,
chartered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> with web sites.

            Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> there's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story stating that according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s latest figures, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is a factor in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 40</NUMEX>
percent of all violent crimes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spousal</ENAMEX> abuse report that fully
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">three-fourths</ENAMEX> of their attacks were alcohol-related.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> pointed out that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> was pressed
recently to justify the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX> he's spent so far javerting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> replied that hey, he always flies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> on his investigatory jaunts to
Little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>. In the adjacent op-ed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert C. Reich</ENAMEX> reported that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>- and
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> seats now account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 22 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>' domestic
passenger revenue, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 9.5 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. And according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , a dozen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> routinely use government
funds for upgrades to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class or for first-class tickets. The LAT
dilutes the effect of this story by not mentioning any of the dirty dozen by
name until after the jump inside to page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> has to wait until the
tenth paragraph to learn that former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Dellums</ENAMEX> routinely booked first
class seats for his trips, at a cost to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times the basic
government rate.

            A related story "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" would love to see: How do the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> handle this issue? Does, for instance, renowned high-liver <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fly <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class when he's on a story and, if so, does
he pay the extra cost or does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Lady</ENAMEX> go to the hip?

         
      
   
