
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zero Effect</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and worldwide stock rally. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the balanced budget proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s attempt to line up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> support for any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> jump in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s stock market on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> fueled the Dow's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">201</NUMEX> point jump. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also cites as a factor the
spreading belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will survive his sex scandal. The rally
also drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> above <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead emphasizes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> balanced budget proposal bars
substantial new spending until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is fixed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that
in contrast to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most past years</TIMEX>, this proposed budget is not arriving on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> dead on arrival. The coverage also features various negative
reactions from the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, who is
quoted, "This is a budget only a liberal could love." The biggest criticism is
the budget's use of a proposed tobacco settlement to partially offset new
domestic social spending provisions. But, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , according to
polls, these priorities generally conform to what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> want.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> budget off-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> covers much the same ground but is a bit more
sensitive to the political angle, saying the budget presents the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with
"another opportunity to portray himself as absorbed in governing, and to
deflect accusations that he had an affair.." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also highlights
political considerations, saying that the budget was "designed to give
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> an upper hand in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>'s congressional elections and provide Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> with an edge as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential election
approaches."

            The main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece says that
despite opening <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> potshots, there is likely to be agreement about the
provisions dealing with child care, transportation, and tobacco taxes. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> sees the big conflicts coming over the expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to
those younger than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>, a minimum wage increase, and national teacher
testing.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> came away from her talks
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> with a statement of support for military action if diplomacy
fails. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, she wants more: access to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> air bases like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> had in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> might agree to
let their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> be used for support <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, but not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>. While seeking
support, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> has, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , made it clear the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is
prepared to go it alone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> discloses that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> did win aircraft
staging permission from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> and is likely also to get green-lighted by
Bahrain, which she visits next.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also passes along word that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> are trying
to cobble a deal that would allow an ad hoc weapons inspection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heretofore-off-limits</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace sites</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is not
enthusiastic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> mission on the front.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that there's been a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than forty percent</NUMEX> drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cases, both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and
nationally. The trend also makes the LAT front, and is inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The likeliest explanation: the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> therapies.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Whitefluid</ENAMEX> development: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX> visited the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times as has been variously reported, but "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three dozen</NUMEX> times" after leaving her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> job. She
was, says the paper, usually cleared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>. The
paper's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who have either seen or been briefed about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitation</ENAMEX> logs. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> say her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> trips
weren't for them. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> wouldn't confirm the number of visits
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> there said the number
"sounds about right."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TP</ENAMEX>" had to read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s WP twice before noticing that key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are apparently suffering the
cerebral ill effects of too much exposure to brightly colored polyester.
Witness this lead on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s front: "The issue of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> golfer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey Martin</ENAMEX> should be allowed to use a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">golf cart</ENAMEX> in tournament play has
captured the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s imagination for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>."

            The LAT front reports that, in an attempt to highlight <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s virtues as a technology marketplace, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> a nickname will be
chosen for the region that will figure in an aggressive marketing campaign. The
paper says it will probably be "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech Coast</ENAMEX>." "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" is still partial
to "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicone Valley</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
