
   
   
      
         
            Case: Dissed Miss

            The surprising dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' lawsuit leads all around, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> going with full banner headlines. Federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Webber Wright</ENAMEX> ruled that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conduct may have
been "boorish and offensive," it was brief, and isolated and didn't result in
physical harm. Therefore, it wasn't, she concluded, under even the most
charitable reading of the record, a sexual assault or workplace harassment. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> gave no credit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' claim of suffering "sexual aversion"
as a result of her run-in with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The papers all note that the judge
dismissed as irrelevant in a few sentences all the Jones allegations of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pattern of extramarital sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> intend to appeal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>
responded to the news by promising to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> on. The ruling, he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
"has no effect on our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes the point that this is not obvious, observing that any
perjury or obstruction of justice charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would be based on his
conduct in a now-dead case.

            The reaction of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> is widely reported: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asked if
the unexpected good news was an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Fools' joke. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> got the news on her
car phone and pulled over and cried. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> maintained a "consciously subdued
tone," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports staff cheers and laughter, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
finds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> walking around his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dakar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX> hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> with a
cigar in his mouth and a drum in his hands (to be replaced <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> later with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guitar</ENAMEX>.)

            The political impact is also generally viewed as pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , may now be wary of moving aggressively
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says it even stronger: "It is now politically inconceivable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will consider
impeachment."

            But, adds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , despite the trial outcome, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the
presidency appear to have been diminished in important and lasting ways." A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page WP</ENAMEX> piece says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit "has had an indelible impact
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political system and on other institutions in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life."
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead editorial sees the development as a "bittersweet
victory for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." Perhaps, the editorial continues, "it is possible
to envision a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> reform and other urgent issues might
capture the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and be at the top of the congressional
agenda. When the debate over health care returns to the spotlight. When the
details of the tobacco settlement become a matter of wide public discussion.
But...the world's suspicions about his truthfulness in many things will dog his
place in history." The scandal, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has made the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> seem
"coated in slime."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature reports that
the rich have, somewhat surprisingly, not been able to shelter their income
from the higher taxes ushered in by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>).
Indeed, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , upper income tax revenues are a big reason the
federal deficit has vanished. Nowadays the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
in earnings are paying <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 32 percent</NUMEX> of their income in taxes, compared to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 26.7 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>.

            A piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (about an article coming out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the
scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> ) reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX>, has applied for a patent for a way of mixing human embryo cells
with those from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>, ape or other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>. His goal: to set off a
debate about the morality of patenting life forms, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX> is opposed to.
Currently, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , patents are not allowed on human beings
(based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX>'s proscription of slavery), but the issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX> is unsettled, because patent law has not addressed "how human" an
animal would have to be before it fell under the ban.

         
      
   
