
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soft Machine</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> passage of an education bill that
would create a new tax break for parental school expenses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> between major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> has an investigation into the latest
leads with the biggest increase in the cost to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> of health care
insurance since the rise of managed care.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> education bill, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , is almost certain to draw
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> veto for such provisions as an IRA-style tax break for private and
parochial school tuition, blocking national testing and allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to
spend federal education funds virtually any way they choose. The story also
makes the front at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and is inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> will announce a domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on the heels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airways</ENAMEX> to do the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> announced a similar
link <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, which, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> in its front-page story,
sparks these actions by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. These new links, explains
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , while falling short of a merger, will mean accepting the frequent
flier mileage earned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> and letting them into
its airport <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>. More importantly, they could mean the consolidation of
flight schedules, resulting in fewer and more expensive choices for consumers
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer</NUMEX> jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The mileage and club arrangements do not require
government approval, says the paper, but the schedule changes do.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> investigation reveals a campaign finance
strategy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX> under which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> from labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> in "soft money" that
cannot be used directly for congressional or presidential campaigns and handed
it over to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a dozen</NUMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, which then sent back to
the DNC unrestricted "hard money" funds that can be spent on individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX>.
The state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , have been charging a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 to 15</NUMEX>
percent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> for their part in these swaps. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says campaign
reform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> conclude that the scheme, "while legal, renders meaningless"
the distinction between general-use-only soft money and unrestricted hard
money.

            The death of convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX> gets
front-page coverage at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and is
inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The coverage notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>
review of the case, based on information recently submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King's family</ENAMEX>,
which had come to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s drive for a new trial, will continue.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a front-page report on disturbing new research by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX> and
Prevention indicating that the recent decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cases is not due to
a notable drop in new infections, but rather to improved medical treatment of
the disease. The rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>, says the study, has
in fact remained quite stable. Despite considerable public education efforts
targeting them, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intravenous drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> continue to contract
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> at high rates.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity Barringer</ENAMEX> piece that details an
important aspect of the recent proliferation of federal investigations:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> are pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> more and more for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX> and other source materials and to a surprising degree, getting them. And
unlike past press-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> conflicts, these latest episodes aren't drawing
much media coverage. According to the piece (which credits earlier
little-noticed reports of such matters in the media-related <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>), in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, the feds have had their subpoena for the complete tape of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PrimeTime Live</ENAMEX>" interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX> upheld and got the
interview tapes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James B. Stewart</ENAMEX> made with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> piece he wrote. And under a subpoena served on him by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> in the
lobby of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Birnbaum</ENAMEX> gave the
government transcripts of his on-the-record conversations with a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. It is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barringer</ENAMEX> writes, "a new season in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> law."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that its latest poll
(undertaken with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX>) indicates <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> approve of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">job Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is doing. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 4 percent</NUMEX> of those surveyed think he will have
to resign.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source"</ENAMEX> column makes a gimlet observation on Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' determination to appear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Correspondents</ENAMEX>' Dinner. In the deposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> made
for her lawsuit, notes the column, she testified, "Every time I look at this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on TV--I don't even look. I just turn it off because it brings back that
terrible day..."

         
      
   
