
   
   
      
         
            Never Say Never?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s new forceful denial about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX> leads everywhere. At
what might be called the tail-end of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> event highlighting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and child-care proposals, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> at his side, the president
stated, "I did not have sexual relations with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. I
never told anybody to lie. Not a single time. Never."

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> feature a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> alongside their stories
about his denial. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's has him looking the angriest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> clenched his jaw and glared as
he made his denial. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement
itself and follow-up remarks by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> seem to make it utterly unambiguous,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> responded by suggesting that still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> may say
that she and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> engaged in an act other than intercourse. "What's
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s definition of sex?" he asked.

            Another development that engrosses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> is the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> has given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> a formal statement about the testimony she could
give in the matter in return for immunity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> suggests the proffer
includes an admission of sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, which, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, an earlier
draft did not.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> quotes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s response to the widely circulated story that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> received
a dress as a gift from him: "There is no dress." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX> cites <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> met privately with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last month</TIMEX>. The visit is alleged to have come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was served with a subpoena in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> signed an affidavit swearing that she had not had a sexual
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            A sign of the scandal's impact: The news at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> that a major point
of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pitch to apply
prospective budget surpluses to shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> couldn't make it above
the fold. By the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> will
visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> to applaud.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s poll numbers are still pretty good, but
also says some of his longstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> were not reassured by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
statement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead says it did buoy his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>.
Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front-page piece reports that the "crisis cabinet" assembled
to respond to the scandal includes the doubly qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, both an experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> and a sex scandalee in his own
right.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> has purchased
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Equipment</ENAMEX>. The story points out how in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just ten years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> has come
from nowhere and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX> has pretty much gone in the opposite direction.
The deal, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> in position to compete directly
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>. This story is also on the front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX>, tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> cat-and-mouse
games he's had to endure, such as being stalled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> replaced hard drives containing records of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s entire
weapons program with ones running only computer games. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> confirms earlier
reports that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> had evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has loaded biological weapons
onto missile warheads.

            Right now, no one is paying the least little attention to military
procurement--which is the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> likes it. So there won't be much
newsplay for the piece inside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> has
managed to keep its hot new airplane program rolling along despite a continuing
serious aerodynamic problem.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> speaks for many when he writes of the
particular betrayal he feels right now. "We overlooked Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s past
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscretions</ENAMEX>--he was hardly the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> with testosterone
overload--on the condition that he pursue his agenda and postpone his next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dalliance</ENAMEX> until after he left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. But he broke the bargain. I knew
he was a charming rogue with an appealing agenda, but I didn't think he was a
reckless idiot with an appealing agenda."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that the scandal has been good media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, with
USAT distributing an extra <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> copies of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> edition, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WP</ENAMEX> printing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 15,000</NUMEX> copies of its daily run, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> adding
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> copies to its usual newsstand run of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s viewership up about
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX>" experiencing pronounced
ratings increases. But, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> nor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> is seeing much of a bump. (But when those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
topless shots show up, don't look for them in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarterly</TIMEX> .)

         
      
   
