
   
   
      
         
            More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satellite Dish</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the adverse affect on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> high technology
export <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> posed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China/Loral</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> flap. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> describes
the emergence of a trans-party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of anti-proliferationists ranging from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Markey</ENAMEX> to the religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>
(apparently, prolife does not entail proliferation). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s proclamation of
innocence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s increased dependence on reserve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead is a near twin to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday NYT</ENAMEX> front-page piece
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Schwartz</ENAMEX>. The broad outlines--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> has, since
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> and that during that same time-frame, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> has enjoyed solid
administration support for its efforts to sell communications technology to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--are the same. And so are many of the details. There is one discrepancy.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> suggests the oddity that despite all his donations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> had
been denied that supreme political plum, an overnighter in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explains that he's been invited twice but his schedule has
prevented him from accepting.

            The focus of both pieces is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>'s denial that his largess was in any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> linked to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s increased access to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Of course, when lobbying is
done skillfully, linking is unnecessary--the money speaks for itself. The
Times --but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> --makes the point, but not until after the
"jump," in the seventeenth paragraph.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports a striking fact: more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reservists</ENAMEX> have been
called up for active duty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> than were called up during all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>,
and the episode marks the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly thirty years</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Guard</ENAMEX> combat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> has been shipped overseas. Unfortunately, the piece focuses
on the grousing of called-up reservists, instead of on the most important
question it raises--whether our part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are trained well enough to
be depended on this way.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" brings out another overlooked consequence of
military downsizing. Seems that budget cuts have forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> to stop
supplying honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> to most military funerals, and this role is now often
filled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly veterans</ENAMEX>.

            An excellently reported piece detailing how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> missed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nuclear
preparations appears on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. (Can't imagine why it's
not Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>. Surely it's more pressing than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign doings.)
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the failure was a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> effort," requiring flubs
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. The piece notes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> explosions, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> recorded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bulldozers</ENAMEX> appearing near the test site, but that this
didn't set off any alarm bells. But the piece doesn't say why. Surely this is
some sort of human breakdown, because the current generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> satellites
download their take in real time. Furthermore, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , early on
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> of the test explosions, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely analyst</ENAMEX>" saw a photo of fences
being removed, but it took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five hours</TIMEX> before more experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
arrived to review the evidence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> doesn't say why they weren't
already there. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" can handle that one--because the more
experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> have rank, and insist that rank has its privileges, like
working during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the daytime</TIMEX>. Isn't that dumb? And isn't it lucky it was only a
test ?

            The LAT op-ed page runs a piece by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> that promises "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How to Stop Mass Public Shootings</ENAMEX>." The prof's
suggestion? Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> (without criminal records) carry concealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.
Now, do you think if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> (and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, for that matter) at
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had also been armed, that would have made the cafeteria
situation safer? After all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> pulled a knife on the cops in the police
station after he was arrested, and presumably he knew they were armed.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> adduces some statistics for his side purporting to show that the
availability of concealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> lessens the occurrence of what he calls
"multiple-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim public</ENAMEX> shootings." Unfortunately, he defines the notion into
irrelevance: it doesn't include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> shootings or shootings that are the
byproducts of another crime. (which means he couldn't even include the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> shootings, because carrying a gun in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is another crime). In other
words, he excludes just about every shooting. The tip-off is that he notes (in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> paragraph) that there are "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> such shootings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>"--not too
statistically significant, given that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> deaths per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Thank God for tenure, or this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> might be running a police department
somewhere.

            Headline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> were mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> barbecuing
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. How else to explain the headline on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of the national
edition: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sukarno & Company: Out</ENAMEX>, Yes, but Still <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hugely Rich"</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>,
it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
