
   
   
      
         
            Nuclear Pakistandoff

            Everybody leads with the expected, but still earthshaking, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>
nuclear blasts. A measure of the event's significance is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times each go with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> front-page bomb stories. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> feature big above-the-fold pictures of jubilant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistanis</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front features instead a shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX> walking alongside his army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> grim-faced.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistanis</ENAMEX> claim to have set off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> explosions, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> confirmed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says "as
few as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.") But, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are concerned that there will soon be at least one
more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> atomic blast. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> announced, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , that it is already fitting nuclear warheads on its long-range
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> saying that this missile claim may be
more a statement of intent than fact. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is likewise consoling
elsewhere in its reporting, quoting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to the effect that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> may not henceforth feel the need to match each other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> for
weapon.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eleventh-hour</TIMEX> attempt to head all this off with a
phone call to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sharif</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late Wednesday</TIMEX>. (And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, the source of most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistanis</ENAMEX>' atomic know-how, also tried
getting them to stop the tests.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>'s announcement of the
explosions--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>, we have settled the score with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>"--shows what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
was up against. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistanis</ENAMEX> there was "intense,
nearly unanimous" support for testing an atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> just prior to conducting the
tests, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> summoned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> and accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> of planning
a pre-emptive military strike on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s atomic testing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.

            In response to the A-blasts, under the same automatic provision of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law
that kicked in on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> moved to cancel all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> (only
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX>) and more significantly, to oppose all international loans. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, made an economic move of its own: to
keep money from fleeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it froze all foreign currency accounts.
But the sanctions will hurt--after all, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes, the globe's
newest open nuclear power is also one of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> sees the sudden <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> nuke-out
(along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> satellite flap) as eclipsing the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>-driven
foreign policy approach of the nineties, and returning security and moral
considerations to the diplomatic fore.

            Everybody's front has the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> move: his attempt to bypass the federal appeals process and go right to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> for a definitive ruling on executive privilege as it applies to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes the least of the story, merely putting
a "reefer" to it on the bottom right front.) The rare tactic, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ,
caught the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> by surprise. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note, it was used
successfully by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Jaworksi</ENAMEX> to pry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s Oval
Office tapes from of his hands.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that a special government report to be released next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> will criticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s failure to anticipate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s atomic tests.
According to the report, the oops wasn't primarily technical--it was human.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> brings word that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEC</ENAMEX> will shortly become the first PC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX> to take advantage of a recent legal settlement between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> by offering Windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95</TIMEX> but no desktop icon for Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX> will both merely be supplied on a CD-ROM.

            Well, if smoking can reduce breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, it's only fair that, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front, catalytic converters have been found by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to be a
significant cause of global warming. Add this to such eco-perversions (noted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Easterbrook</ENAMEX>) as: logging, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> and the hole in the ozone layer all
appear to reduce global warming.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> calling for a vote against <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 226</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ballot measure requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>'s permission before
political expenditures can be drawn from his or her dues. What's wrong, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , is that such a restriction does not likewise constrain
corporate political contributions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> comes out against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">226</NUMEX> too, and for the same reason. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is open to a bilateral version in which labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> must get
permission for political spending from individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> must
do so from individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. Such an "evenhanded approach," says the
Times , "could reduce the amount of special-interest money sluicing into
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and help diminish the corroding influence of big
contributions."

         
      
   
