
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Butts In

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the new tobacco settlement bill
taking shape in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the endorsement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of new tax breaks to
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who must buy their own health insurance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the general split inside <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX> over whether
or not tax cuts should be part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s budget. The story notes that the
current proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> budget includes tax cuts totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 billion</NUMEX>, compared
to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350 billion</NUMEX> worth of cuts called for in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contract</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that the proposed tobacco bill would raise the price of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> of cigarettes by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.10</NUMEX> and would cost cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> more than half
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion dollars</NUMEX>--a considerable increase over the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$365 billion</NUMEX> agreed to in
the proposed settlement reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. Like that settlement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> aims to reduce underage <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">smoking</ENAMEX>, regulate nicotine as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and alter the
tone and reach of tobacco advertising. It also includes a payout to tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> as compensation for lost income.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, "Both the tobacco industry and public health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>
assailed the bill from opposite directions: The industry called its price-tag
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'unrealistic</ENAMEX> and onerous' while public health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> said it was too weak on
the key issue of cutting underage smoking." Yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says, "tobacco
industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> declined public comment." Also, it's very odd to talk about
the reaction of the "industry" and "public health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>" so broadly.
Neither are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monoliths</ENAMEX>. So, why no for-attribution quotes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
account here?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> does explain one nuance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> overlooks: whether that
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.10</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> surcharge specified in the bill will actually raise cigarette
prices enough to significantly reduce cigarette purchases. By the way, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> states the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> plan to pay for their health insurance
initiative with revenue raised from higher cigarette taxes, with or without the
passage of a comprehensive tobacco settlement.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> presents the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Award for Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lunacy</ENAMEX>" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> who sent a letter to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> threatening him with "enforcement action" for "unauthorized" and
"hazardous" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX>-building on his property. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX> responded by pointing
out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX> were built by...beavers.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece notes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> consequence of the absorption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
sex scandals: the further empowerment of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. Especially true,
says the paper, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Raines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a front-page piece noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> is very worried about the fallout from the point-shaving
indictment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. The
amount of money bet legally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s basketball tournament,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , exceeds the amount bet there on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to $2.5 billion</NUMEX> is bet on it illegally. Gee, maybe, the
situation would improve if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> didn't print point-spreads.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front is concerned with another, er, sport. The
Times takes note of the latest developments in professional wrestling:
more sexual content, coarser language, and no more Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX>. This apparently
produced an existential crisis on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">43rd St.</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX>, there is no obvious moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>: everything is basically bad and worse." Thank God, there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maguire</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of sociology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Illinois University</ENAMEX> specializing
in wrestling, for these troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> to quote.

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Titanic</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">King of the World</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> began
exercising the perks of his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> by writing a piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> in
which he tried to fire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s lead film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, author of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> scathing
reviews of the iceberg epic. "Forget about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> wrote, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX>
do we impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>?"

         
      
   
