
   
   
      
         
            High Wiring Act

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the recommendation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s air safety <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX> currently in service be rewired as a precaution against the sort
of fuel tank explosion that destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with an exclusive about the status and
contents of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s impending report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s determination, expressed at a forum on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, to fix the system. This is also the top national story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> .

            The rewiring recommendation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Transportation Safety</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX>, accompanied by the further suggestion that surge suppressors be put on
wires going into fuel tanks, shows, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , how far investigators
have come in their understanding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> crash. But, explains the paper, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has an advisory role only, and implementation must be carried out by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>, which often rebuffs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX>. The dramatic extent of the development is
pointed out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> alone has produced
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX> currently in service, and that the recommendation
applies to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX>, as well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> mention in their accounts that an
immediate motive for the advisory was not just the wiring set-up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 800</ENAMEX>,
but also the unsafe ones observed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> retired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">747s</TIMEX>.

            
               Post <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Schmidt</ENAMEX> obviously had help from someone in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in putting together what amounts to a leaked status report on the fruits of his investigation.
She writes that much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report earmarked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> (on the grounds that it describes potentially impeachable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">offenses</ENAMEX>) has already been written, and that it pertains not only to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s actions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter but also may include material about
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was truthful in his sworn testimony for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> bank fraud
trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also asserts that when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case broke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was on the verge of bringing new charges against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> crony <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> for receiving Whitewater hush money.

            Incidentally, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , although in his present role <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has
fought hard against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s contention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege
shields some key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> appeals court
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "seldom rebuffed an assertion of privilege." Indeed, he wrote or
joined several opinions sending support to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s position.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made a no-new-payroll-taxes comment at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
scheduled regional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>-hall style meetings on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>.
However, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> later said he might support raising more
revenue for the program by increasing the limit on wages subject to the payroll
tax. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would be "reluctant" to do that.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that one of the few concrete positions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took at the
meeting was ruling out a conversion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> to a private pension
system. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is willing to consider private
individual accounts provided the overall plan they're a part of continues to
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> with a guaranteed retirement benefit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , in its
front-page piece, agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sees the possibility of some
privatization.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton advisor Paul Begala</ENAMEX>'s reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>'s comment that if he were facing the same sexual misconduct
charges as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he would resign: "If goofy ideas ever go up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> a
barrel, I'd like to have the drilling rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
