
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Buries</ENAMEX> Lead!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with indications that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may drop his appeal of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s court decision holding that his top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> may be questioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> would support new
international financial aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> if its debt situation worsens. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s big increase in killer tornadoes--nearly double the
twister death toll for all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">365 percent</NUMEX> increase over the total
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the likelihood that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
will approve the most sweeping changes in bankruptcy law in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>--which will
make it significantly harder for those with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> family incomes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $50,000</NUMEX>
to wipe out their debts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead is on the USAT front but no
others. Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> leads are on anybody else's
front.

            Besides executive privilege, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other
legal decisions incident to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case must also be made soon: whether
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> will challenge a court decision ordering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to
testify, and whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself will testify before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> statement concerning debt assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>
was timed to spread calm among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial markets before they opened
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. A senior administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that direct <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
aid is not being contemplated, but rather <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> monies, which
means <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">non-U.S.</ENAMEX> funds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> offers a helpful explanation
of the hoped-for result: once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> realize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and the international
funds are determined to support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, they will stop dumping the ruble, which
may mean that actually making the loans becomes unnecessary. This is, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , "a form of deterrence theory." The story runs inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a front-page story about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockbrokers</ENAMEX> hustle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> . The techniques described
include pretending also to be on the phone with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> who just placed
a big order with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> or who just made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a million dollars</NUMEX> with him.
The big flaw with the story: it never says whether or not such ruses are
illegal.

            The LAT front points out a rather sticky dilemma now arising for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> in the wake of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> race. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> nuclear
weapons are, the paper observes, probably, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> programs of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 50s and 60s</TIMEX>, quite unsafe--vulnerable to both physical mishaps and command
and control mistakes. So the question is, should the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> help both countries
make their bombs safer? Although to do so would violate the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions
imposed on both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and could provoke international complaints that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is spreading nuclear know-how, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that "outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>" think such a course of action is probably under consideration.

            A topic of immeasurable social and intellectual importance is very unwisely
buried deep inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> business section: How could a story about
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" be so badly underplayed?

            A piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has issued
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> letters authorizing the installation of airbag cut-off switches in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1,000</NUMEX> of
these have been accepted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. The reason? These
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> are worried about legal liability, but this doesn't add up, since
the story goes on to explain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX> have agreed to indemnify those
doing the cut-off work.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has obtained a draft of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government report on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> gold taken from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>--primarily as jewelry and teeth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fillings</ENAMEX>--during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, and writes it up on the top-front. Principal
findings: There was twice as much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> seized in this fashion as previously
estimated; it was used to pay--mostly in transactions handled by the Swiss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bank</ENAMEX>--for a huge share of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war needs purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dresdner Bank</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank</ENAMEX>, neither previously implicated and both now doing considerable
business in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, had major roles in the transactions.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" reports on the steady rise in volume
levels at the movies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> showing of
"Bulworth" dwelt mostly in the vacuum cleaner range, except for when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> was rapping, taking things up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">somewhere between</NUMEX> jackhammer and car
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">horn</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" has been employing an effective countermeasure for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>: earplugs. These not only offer excellent protection from
hearing loss, but also from noisy theatergoers and inane movie dates.

         
      
   
