
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goldwater: A View From A Broad</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to
accept a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s ruling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege does not protect his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> from being questioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will
however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, still pursue an effort in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to invoke
attorney-client privilege to block <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s effort to question another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deputy White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>. (This story is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s call for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>--including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>--to drop its sanctions
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> drug
cartels are, via a new far more potent strain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>, gaining a growing
share of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> drug trade.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legal shift has the benefit of allowing
him to fight on, but on much less controversial grounds, and yet still perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delaying Lindsey</ENAMEX>'s re-appearance before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial still sees plenty of controversy,
calling the tack a "dodge" and describing as "stonewalling" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s refusal
to straight-off cooperate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s "reasonable requests for information in
a legitimate criminal inquiry." What's more, argues the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> the claim
of attorney-client privilege as applied to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> is "really little more
than another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege claim in disguise," given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>
is foremost a political and policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>.

            Both the WP front and a piece inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hinting at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> support for additional
international financial loans to shore up the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy utterly failed to
have the anticipated soothing effect: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> stocks fell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another ten</NUMEX> percent
and the ruble worsened slightly.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's political reporting continues to be
disarmingly candid. On the heels of a recent piece that laid bare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s
fund-raising, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s Journal surveys the many competing campaign reform bills on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> docket
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one dozen</NUMEX> bills; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> amendments) and concludes that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> will assume
the role of full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in overhaul legislation--in an effort to kill it." In
the end though, observes the paper, it may be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dingell</ENAMEX>--who seals campaign reform's fate. He has been collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
votes for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> that would study and recommend further changes in the
system. (A big clue to how lightly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> takes the issue. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>
was attacked, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> didn't appoint a commission to study and recommend further
changes in our defense posture.)

            The LAT front brings word of a legal ruling that may spell trouble for "reality" TV shows like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cops</ENAMEX>" and the use of hidden cameras and microphones by the likes of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PrimeTime Live</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled that
accurate, newsworthy news reports are protected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> from
lawsuits merely alleging illegal disclosure of private facts, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
also ruled that story <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> may sue if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> use
offensive or intrusive methods to get the story. The case prompting the
decision involved a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> car accident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> ministered to by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> wearing
a tiny microphone for a TV show featuring real rescues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> survived but
the show broadcast her pleas to be allowed to die.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX> has found another
struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to give aid to: poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Today, says the paper, with
government legal aid programs on the wane, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX> will launch a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multimillion</ENAMEX>-dollar initiative to fund <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 two-year</TIMEX> public interest fellowships
for young law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grads</ENAMEX>, supporting their legal efforts on behalf of such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> as battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the homeless, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> and migrant farm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            Tributes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX> as the last of a breed of terminally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">straight-talking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> continue pouring in, but so far, only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX>'s encomium mentions that the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> once showed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> the near-nude and suggestively inscribed photo of herself a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman fan</ENAMEX> had sent him.

            A bottom front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story reports that yesterday <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> announced an
initiative to have the federal government write its
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of forms, directive and letters in "plain language." An example he
cited is translating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways</ENAMEX> of exit access and the doors to exits to
which they lead shall be so designed and arranged as to be clearly recognizable
as such" as "An exit door must be free of signs or decorations that obscure its
visibility." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> waggishly provides another example, effectively
Goring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice-President</ENAMEX>: "There is no controlling legal authority that says
this was in violation of the law" should be recast as "There's no law against
it."

         
      
   
