
   
   
      
         
            Missilany

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times 's top national story is that despite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of contrary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurances</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> build a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's top national story is an account
of how, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars</ENAMEX>" speech,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> still doesn't have an anti-ballistic-missile defense system. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s decision to oppose
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ballot referendum measure calling for an end to publicly funded
bilingual education, a measure thought to be favored by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>'s
warning to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that failure to approve an emergency spending bill and a
new round of base closings will mean big layoffs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and
fewer high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> that
its help on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> missile project was limited, and didn't
involve the missile design. In return, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> cleared the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> cooperation in space. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence
reports have continued to suggest a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> role. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s technical assistance raises fears of a stepped-up arms
race between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, against whom <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> has fought three wars, and
which has just tested a nuclear<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-</ENAMEX>capable missile of its own.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that out of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> intercept tests in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>,
only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> struck their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. Since the
last success in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, there have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> straight failures. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration has not committed to deploying a national anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shield</ENAMEX>,
under pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> (national missile defense was a tenet of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX>"), it has promised to accelerate testing. But, the paper
reports, only one actual flight trial of the entire system is planned before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> must decide whether or not to place it in operation.

            According to a big USAT investigative piece, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ValuJet</TIMEX> crash, airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> are still being endangered by improperly
labeled or packaged hazardous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> on their flights. For the story,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USAT</ENAMEX> shipped unmarked boxes with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX> services and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them did not do what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> rules require: ask for a photo ID and a
declaration that the boxes were free of hazardous goods. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> seems
to be catching more violators, the paper quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> saying, "We wouldn't know whether hazardous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> are inside if a
package doesn't leak or break open."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece says
that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> views as smart the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic strategy of getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> to come
in with rescue packages that don't directly cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> that much. And hence
if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> defeats the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s proposal to pony up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18</NUMEX>
billion for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> will be at least confused and
possibly hostile.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports the latest sign of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>'s decline: according to federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>'s equivalent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX>,
where deals between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>" were made and disputes ironed
out, hasn't met in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two years</TIMEX>. Why? Convictions and indictments of top
mobsters have created chronic uncertainty about who can speak for the various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> as well as increased concerns about exposure at meetings to informers
and undercover police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front had a home run piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Abramson</ENAMEX> detailing
the current investigation fad in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, along the way coining a good
phrase for it. There are currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abramson</ENAMEX> reported, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> separate official
inquiries into reported wrongdoing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his
administration or figures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. Not to mention all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PIs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> this entails. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has become," she writes,
"the center of a scandal-industrial complex." The piece also carried this quote
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James E. Kennedy</ENAMEX> in response to congressional complaints
about the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> working to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: "It's like
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arsonist</ENAMEX> complaining about the size of the fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, is termed "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> scandal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>."

            Never let it be said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> doesn't kick you when you're down.
In its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section debrief of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s star-studded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Correspondents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dinner</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cavett</ENAMEX> was there, trying to
remember which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> he was the dinner's featured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainer</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
