
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripped Up</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a bit of a bombshell about the grand jury testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> gave
an affidavit about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Wiley</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
The top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is the emerging pressure on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to not just strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, but remove
him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> goes with the severe storms that are forecasted to punish both
coasts starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s quest to find out who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
knew and when did he know her may have gotten a big boost from the grand jury
appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>, who testified that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
were sometimes alone together in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. Additionally, says the paper,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after giving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case deposition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> that he had
never been alone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and that he had resisted her sexual
advances.

            Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> turned over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> several
gifts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>--a dress, a brooch, and a hatpin.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s account to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> issued a
subpoena demanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> surrender any gifts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> gave her, she
discussed this with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and he told her if she didn't have the gifts, she
wouldn't have to turn them over. And soon after that conversation, says the
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> collected the items from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also quotes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s deposition as saying that when asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> if he had given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> any gifts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> replied that perhaps,
but only ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> souvenirs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead nails down the scandal's earliest known
details. In her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 21, 1998</TIMEX> affidavit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> (still under seal but
somehow obtained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> told her of an affair
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> commencing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 15, 1995</TIMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had played at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tapes for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tripp</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s voice and showed her gifts
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> also says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had told her she planned to lie
under oath if questioned about the relationship by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.

            Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s sworn statement in its entirety. In it, Tripp
describes herself as having once served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as an
"apolitical careerist."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that during his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shuttle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> may ask some smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to take up
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter-bombers</ENAMEX> now based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , feels it can live with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> policy of not allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
bombers to base there, but still allowing other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> combat support <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to
do so.

            The WP front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside run stories about the clash
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> over what happened when that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> sliced a ski-lift suspension wire killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
general says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was following a standard training route, and thus far
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> have refused to speak with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> are
charging that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was too low and was hot-dogging. They are even
alleging that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was equipped with a flight data recorder but that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are withholding it. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Killer pilots</ENAMEX>" is a phrase that has appeared in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> press.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of the best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S</ENAMEX>,
Astra, has agreed to pay a record <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $10 million</NUMEX> to female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who
claimed that they were pressured for sex by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and urged to wear
bikinis at a beach function.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> top front piece discusses how newly released documents from the
tobacco industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> make it clearer than ever just how hard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
tried to market cigarettes--especially mentholated ones--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX> document quoted speaks of the possibility that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kool</ENAMEX> will
cover the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> markets in terms of absolute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX>." The revelations have
led to calls from minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> and health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> that some proceeds
from any global tobacco settlement be earmarked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>.

            What with all the headlines about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> fundraising, you might
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX> take in more dough than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. You might be wrong--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> piece inside stating that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> more--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$114 million to $77 million</NUMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ran a story on the current political turmoil in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX> under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Winter of Discontent</ENAMEX>." But that's wrong. After
all, with a latitude of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">19 degrees</NUMEX> below the equator, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>'s now in the
middle of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> .

         
      
   
