
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexual Positioning</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s defense of her motives in
coming forward. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the apparent intention of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>, to submit
material to the trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> covering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' past sex life to rebut her
claim in her previous filings that her alleged encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> left her
with an alleged "sexual aversion injury." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that not too
long ago, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> said one of the things he would not do in this trial would be
go into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' sexual history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the reform pledges made by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the purchase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Dodgers</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, she is "overwhelmed"
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> attempts to discredit her. Regarding the release of admiring
letters she had written to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> after their disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> meeting, he
is quoted saying, "We don't pretend we can compete with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin
machine." Reports about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front also
follow up on the story broken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> that
prior to her "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>" appearance, she had been in discussions with a
tabloid.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX> gave a
press conference in which he laid down ambitious goals for sweeping social
change in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, including pledges to redesign the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and cut its
staff in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, do away with subsidized housing, and make state-owned industries
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solvent</ENAMEX>, all within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three years</TIMEX>. But he also flatly ruled out, reports
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , any reappraisal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s crackdown on democracy in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. The press conference was strikingly Western-style, says the
paper, complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu</ENAMEX>'s deflection of a serious question about eventual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> elections with a quip about pictures of him in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About a third</NUMEX> of the LAT front is given over to coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dodger</ENAMEX> sale. In an unexpectedly one-sided vote,
major league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> approved the sale of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> by the O'Malley
family to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Group</ENAMEX>, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $311 million</NUMEX>, the most ever
paid for a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>. The move makes the team part of a world-wide media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">empire</ENAMEX> valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $27 billion</NUMEX>. Among those assets, points out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , are broadcast and cable rights to games played by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league teams</ENAMEX>. And this is the aspect of the deal that is really
different. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> LAT front-page piece states that the purchase price,
almost double the going rate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, is "so far out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX> that
it's highly unlikely the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> will make money," but, the paper explains,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> sees sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> as another form of content for his sprawling
television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>...."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dodger</ENAMEX> deal is also on the front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , but doesn't make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front, which opts instead for a story about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>
has discussed the possibility of selling a piece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Muncie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> shouldn't be held liable in
the lung cancer death of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">non-smoking nurse</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jurors</ENAMEX> said that cigarettes
weren't a defective product and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> weren't negligent for
failing to tell people that second-hand smoke was dangerous.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts carry word of a new study from the
the suicide rate among black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>. The study's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> suggest that the
surge reflects the strain black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> feel in transitioning to the middle
class. One odd detail: black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> are much more likely than white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> to kill themselves in the presence of somebody else.

            The general degree of personality-, sports- and money-euphoria surrounding
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Murdoch Dodger</ENAMEX> buy is well illustrated by the LAT front-page
effusions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Riordan</ENAMEX> who is quoted saying, "I've never met
anybody whose focus is better....He pays the same attention to the waiter as he
does to the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>." Isn't that the opposite of
focus?

         
      
   
