
   
   
      
         
            Tangled Web

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with promising new cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> soon to be tested on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>--a story that got prominent play in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' harsh
criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> for his release of the Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> prison tapes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s anti-affirmative action ballot initiative. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s rejection of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> proposal for
a transfer of more <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> work, explains <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , by cutting off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> supply to tumors, making it impossible for them to grow. Used together,
they have eradicated tumors in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Which is why they are scheduled for human
trials. But, says the paper, the leap from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is a huge <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead details how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> was accused on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> by congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> of doctoring
transcripts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> phone conversations. The material <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>
released appears to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s decision to continue to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> out of fears that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would lose her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> job, but,
notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , does not include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s statement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had "no idea" of billing irregularities at their law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, or his
assertion that he was not being paid hush money.

            Another dispute centers on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> saying on the tape, "There is
some chance that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX> they will make a move that moots
everything. And I don't want to discourage it." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> says this was a reference to a presidential pardon, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s lawyer
says it was an immunity deal--eventually granted--with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> hits the pardon issue much higher in its front page <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> tape
story, not surprising since it went front page on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> with a story saying
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> took the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>" comment to signify pardon
hopes.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead points out that referenda rather than
legislation may increasingly become the main tool of the anti-affirmative
action movement, because while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 209</ENAMEX> won decisively, the bills
introduced in its wake in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were all defeated. The story also scores
how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> heavyweights line up on the ballot initiative:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX> are against, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is expected to stay
neutral.

            The LAT front story on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s current economic woes runs under: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX>
Cut May Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spur Yen</ENAMEX> to Spend in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>." Do we really need to see this "clever"
use of "yen" in a headline ever, ever again?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is warning Wall
Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> that federal and state legal anti-trust suits against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s introduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 98</ENAMEX> could have "broad, negative consequences"
for the entire personal computer industry if they cause that new software to be
delayed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Outlook</ENAMEX>" piece takes note of recent claims that
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problem will generate a recession of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>-shock caliber and says
that's not likely: After all, the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-day-long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shut-down in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> didn't do that, nor did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to close more
military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> supports the cause with some simple observations: While the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> is down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 46 percent</NUMEX>, its berthing space is down only
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 percent</NUMEX>, and while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> troop strength is down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX>, training
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 7 percent</NUMEX>. Since, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will probably
keep total military spending flat, the paper notes that not closing bases is
equivalent to passing cuts on readiness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> procurement and research.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of some computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> are expected to stage a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> rally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. All together now:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey, Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>, how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">browsers</ENAMEX> did you de-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?"

         
      
   
