
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genocide Chat</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remark that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
should have done something quickly about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> killings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> and having failed to do so, must share in the blame for them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> goes with the developing story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> schoolyard
shootings, which also gets a lot of coverage on the other fronts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s acknowledgement came during an emotionally charged stop at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kigali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> during which he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> listened to the wrenching
recollections of massacre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>. Given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the prior day</TIMEX>'s discussion of the
wrongs of slavery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX> genocide indicate, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , that his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> sojourn is becoming a "contrition tour." But, points out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s statement was different--with it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is referring to an
episode that occurred during his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. The paper points out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> obstacle to taking action at the time was
a lack of credible information about what was actually going on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also
notes that some human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> responded that there was ample reliable
information, just not ample <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that in his mea culpa du jour, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also cited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> as another example on his watch where the reaction to
ethnic killing was too slow. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> does a good job of supplying
specifics on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> inaction in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration blocked a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> on-the-ground effort that "might have saved
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of lives."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">USAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-on-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> pieces note a
political factor that at the time inhibited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> action, but which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
didn't mention: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX> support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> involvement in peacekeeping missions
evaporated just prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> situation when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> were killed
in an ambush in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>.

            The headline over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwanda</ENAMEX> coverage is not a good model.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rwandans Told World Shares Guilt for Genocide</ENAMEX>" doesn't mention by whom, a
particularly oversight when the whom is the prez.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead states that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 13</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>--will be tried as juveniles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says their extreme youth means
conviction might result in sentences of just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>. The LAT front
carries a piece about a new category of criminal suggested by such cases--the
"fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">psychopath</ENAMEX>."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed says the incident implicates the too-ready access
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. (They were apparently stolen from one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>'
grandfathers, but, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> it is perfectly legal
for an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX>.) And a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial
reports, "The overall firearm-related death rate among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> aged less
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> was nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> times higher than among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, who is accompanying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> trip in his role as special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>,
may have found his niche. Some in the foreign policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , which on the whole was wary of his appointment, already feel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> is proving useful. For instance, on the current trip <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> followed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s advice and had a lengthy phone conversation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX> to make sure he didn't feel snubbed because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wasn't visiting his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            Back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansas</ENAMEX> shootings for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sec</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, having learned the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>' names from school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, opt to use them rather than invoking the
usual juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> practice of anonymity. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" would be
interested in finding out the general policy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> on such matters: Do
they print the names of juveniles whenever they learn them? Or only when the
crimes they're charged with are very serious?

         
      
   
