
   
   
      
         
            Mergers and Inquisitions

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new major financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company mergers</ENAMEX>, with the bigger of the two
deals also flagged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> in its front-page news box. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the confusing picture
painted by the welfare statistics collected by the various states. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s poll results indicating that nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of those queried support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s ballot referendum item calling
for an end to bilingual education in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with concerns that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> could derail last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s historic peace deal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BankAmerica Corp.</ENAMEX> has agreed to merge with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NationsBank Corp.</ENAMEX> in a transaction valued at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $60 billion</NUMEX>, creating, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s first
coast-to-coast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, and the largest in terms of total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> and deposits.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> deal, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banc One Corp.</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago NBD Corp.</ENAMEX>, would create the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, which would
dominate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mergers will, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , further raise
the standard for how big financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> feel they need to be.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead asserts that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> after federal
welfare reform, "it is becoming clear that the mass of data the government
requires <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to collect is in such disarray that it is impossible to
determine whether the law is working." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the feds can't tell
whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are meeting the reform law's targets for gainfully
employing former welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> respond that they are
finding the federal data requirements overwhelming. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-part series on
welfare reform the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> also finds the data less than
crystal-clear (no thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, who, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, gradually
stopped cooperating with its requests for information). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s series
kick-off says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> found "scant evidence" that the reforms had moved a
"significant number" of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> from welfare to full-time work. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s installment finds more certainty about outcomes, noting
that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workfare recipients</ENAMEX> have become part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>,
picking up the slack created when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> reduced the city payroll ten
percent.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> poll finds that the end-bilingual-education measure was not
opposed by any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> bloc--whether designated by age, income, gender,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">geography</ENAMEX>, or ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Even among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, there was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>
support. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> didn't mention that a front-page article reporting on an
earlier poll had found the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Latino</ENAMEX> support then to be much higher.) The
paper's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> found that those surveyed were not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antecedently</ENAMEX> familiar
with the issue, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> attributes to the low-level, thus far, of
television advertising about it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front, in a piece by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who broke <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gerth</ENAMEX>, reveals
that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> report, secret until now, concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
from the aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral Space and Communications</ENAMEX> had turned
over expertise to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> that significantly improved the reliability of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. The piece is a thorough and fascinating history of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' development of their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> markets in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. That
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , prompted a criminal investigation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, which was undermined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> approved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>'s export
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> of information about guidance systems. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, the paper
notes with a straight face, was the largest personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> editorial page revisits an argument for privatizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> accounts the
paper has hit before--that doing so would give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and married working women
a much better return on their contributions than these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> now enjoy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX>
are disadvantaged because of their comparatively short life expectancies,
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women workers</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> payouts are presently based
solely on a household's higher earner's contributions. The latter point is also
made in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed.

            A top-of-the-page op-ed piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> responds to the
recent decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> not to prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Fuhrman</ENAMEX> for
any crimes he committed while with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX> by calling for the public
disclosure of all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuhrman</ENAMEX>'s police records. "The documents in his file,"
explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, "may spur a debate relating to how an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> can have a
file containing numerous complaints of misconduct against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and still
be promoted through the ranks." The proposal comes from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a proven
penchant for spurring debates--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" says, fair
enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>, provided you disclose the private information from your
files that you have thus far suppressed. You know, like your lie
detector test results.

         
      
   
