
   
   
      
         
            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> Interns

            The initial phase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> counter-thrust, which hit the beach on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> chat shows, leads everywhere. The main theme is not defend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> so
much as attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. The TV appearances of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX> are
noted all around, as is the return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX>
Kantor, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Thomasson</ENAMEX> (filming "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Place Called Hopeless?</ENAMEX>"). Everybody
also reports that negotiations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX>'s lawyer
continue.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> reports that the strategy includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> issuing a fresh denial
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> AM (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> at an event focusing on his child care proposals.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says this move was still up for
debate as it went to press.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> state that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> were seen "in an intimate encounter" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The front-page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> has this too, but with no mention
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has directed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> to find
out how much the scandal has affected his standing with the public. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says an internal poll has already shown a drop of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> percentage points.
Independent polls mentioned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> also indicate slippage. The
Post paints a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> picture in which anxious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> fear that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is not widely believed. And, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, several administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> privately say they are worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
may not be telling the truth. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff members</ENAMEX> tell
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to omit all mention of the controversy from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech is "totally surreal."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead is accompanied by a large picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
coming out of church <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> sharing a big ole laugh with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. (They must have really enjoyed the sermon, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Eight Commandments</ENAMEX>.")
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that in their public remarks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the pro-Clintonites
were careful not to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. "We don't want to push her into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
arms," is the explanation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> loyalists are
"greatly distressed," and mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> recently looked unusually
depressed and shaken. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying in a private meeting that if
the accusations are true, "it's all over."

            Another case of staff distress is reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , which recounts
how, at a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Jennings</ENAMEX>
broke down in tears in the middle of a speech.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonfire of the Presidency</ENAMEX>" counters the suggestion coming
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some quarters</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX> has an overactive imagination with the
question, "Did a delusional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> make up the point about perjury not
often being prosecuted in civil cases?" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> finds all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychopathology</ENAMEX> in the case elsewhere: ".[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he roots of this crisis lie
somewhere in the psyche shaped by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, troubled childhood and
life experiences."

            The story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>'s departure from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-day</TIMEX> stay makes everybody's
front. A big part of the stories is his condemnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> embargo of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>. But the pontiff also criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">atheism</ENAMEX> and called for the
protection of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX>' rights.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that a new study from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> shows a continuing, and in some ways,
growing disparity between the health of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. Some examples: The
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> cases rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the increase
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. Ditto for infectious diseases. And from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987 to 1995</TIMEX>, the death
rate for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in childbirth jumped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX>, compared with an
overall rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.6 percent</NUMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> still have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times the infant
mortality rare of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.

            In light of the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> to run for his congressional
seat, the LAT front page reports that among first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> candidates
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1916 to 1993</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> won, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 14 percent</NUMEX> of the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> did.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janna</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malamud Smith</ENAMEX> that states "If we're going to make simplistic rules about
truth-telling, mine would start here: Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> should have told Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
why she invited her to lunch.. " Elsewhere on the page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> makes a point in passing that's been overlooked thus far: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> to wear a wire and then used its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> to get permission
to widen his investigation. Shouldn't the permission to widen have
preceded the wire, which was in fact the widening?

         
      
   
