
   
   
      
         
            Courting and Mating

            The surprise congressional resurgence of campaign reform leads at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s warning about creatine, a
muscle-building supplement widely used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> explain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> agreed to allow campaign finance
legislation to come to floor votes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> because reform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> were
close to getting enough signatures on a special petition to force a vote
anyway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is quoted saying the development was "great news,"
but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX> is quoted saying, "This was a retreat
not a conversion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> still opposes reform that reduces
the role of money in politics." And indeed the coverage points out that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has already defeated a ban on "soft money" once this session.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> fronts cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s oral arguments
in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> and final sexual harassment case the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> is
hearing this term. The issue in this one is whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>'s single
threat saying a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate</ENAMEX>'s sexual compliance will ease her working
conditions constitutes harassment when her non-compliance meets with no adverse
consequences. The issue is an ingredient in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case and hence the
Court's decision here might affect her appeal. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> seemed genuinely perplexed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s arguments.

            Meanwhile, the WP front observes firm differences about gender on display in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6-3</ENAMEX>
decision to uphold the law that automatically grants <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> to an
out-of-wedlock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, but not if only the father
is. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul Stevens</ENAMEX>, joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>,
presumed that there is a closer connection between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> than
between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and his. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Ginsburg</ENAMEX> dissented, taking a pure
approach to sexual equality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Biskupic</ENAMEX>, notes that
generational differences seem to be at play in this decision, with the older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> siding with the maternalistic bias.

            No wonder the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX>'s announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that needle
exchange programs do work but won't be getting federal funds seemed so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>:
according to a front-page story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX> before
the press conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Shalala</ENAMEX> was all set to announce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> funding. That was when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX> told
her that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had decided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> position was too
politically risky.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> report stating that the first national survey of
physician-assisted suicide found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> of the front-line <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
responding have hastened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' deaths with lethal injections or
prescriptions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story goes on to say that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of the
surveyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> would write prescriptions for deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">dosages</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> would do so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in the headline over
its survey story, says the finding is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>-assisted suicide is
"rare." Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports on its front that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCartney</ENAMEX> did
not die in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX> as the family first reported. The family admits now
that this was a diversion which, says the paper, has in turn spurred some talk
that perhaps her death was an assisted suicide.

            The WP front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> planning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> to capture
Bosnian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and wanted war criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX> was compromised
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> met secretly with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karadzic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs
the story inside, crediting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> estimates that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> who itemized
gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84.3 billion</NUMEX> to charity, up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.4%</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concomitantly</ENAMEX>, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> are having banner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor Healthcare System Foundation</ENAMEX> has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23 million</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>,
surpassing the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 million</NUMEX> it raised in all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports on a new web page for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> set up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">odci</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/cia/ciakids</ENAMEX>). The site is laced with trivia quizzes on world
geography and history. And it explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s purpose: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> is
information needed by our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, also known as policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>, to
keep our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> safe. Policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, do not have time to
read all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. There are just too many of them."
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" has never felt more patriotic.

         
      
   
