
   
   
      
         
            B-2 Or Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX>?

            Everybody leads with that case-against-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> gave at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Speaking to an auditorium full of military and civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, and from a platform he shared with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> justified possible airstrikes
with an implicit reference to the failures of appeasement in the period just
before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Force</ENAMEX> can never be the first answer," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. "But
sometimes, it's the only answer."

            In its piece on the speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> mentions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>, is going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> to try for a peaceful resolution. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> makes it clear that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> fails to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> compliance, an air bombardment is a "virtual
certainty." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s old line was, says the paper, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> not
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>," but its new one is "days not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has defined down his military objective--now we are after,
not totally ridding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> of mass destruction <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, but seriously diminishing
their threat. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did not, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , explain at what
point he would consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> threat seriously diminished.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bennet</ENAMEX> obviously got to somebody present at the
military briefing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> attended just before speaking. His report reveals
that the briefing ran <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 minutes</TIMEX> and centered on the details of a military
strike. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> mostly listened and made no new decisions. But he did ask about
the potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> in a strike, both among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
weapons in a confrontation.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s dismissal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s desire to exempt certain "presidential" sites from weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX>. One such site, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> explained, is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40,000 acres</NUMEX>, whereas the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> grounds take up but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> includes this quote of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s: "We're not talking about a few rooms
here with delicate personal matters involved." In the age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, you
don't have to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> to find that an interesting choice of words for what
goes on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> wisely puts at the top of its lead the simplest, most
forceful argument <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made, one that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> omitted
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> postponed until the last paragraphs of its story: His
"guarantee" that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> isn't stopped now, he will someday use his
biochemical weapons.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts all report <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case to dismiss her suit
for lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs the text of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legal motion in the matter, which includes an
argument that strikes the lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as bizarrely permissive: Even on the
assumption that then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> undertook the actions towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excelsior Hotel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> alleges, that would not constitute "hostile
environment sexual harassment" because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room</ENAMEX> voluntarily, the
episode only lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at most 20 minutes</TIMEX>, there was no violence or explicit
threats and she was able to leave when she decided to.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front marshals the factors behind that ski lift disaster in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>: on his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> flight in the area, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> pilot
did not have maps showing the ski lift, was violating orders to fly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> above
the ground and was off-course. All this beneath a headline that is simply
extraordinary in this age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> restraining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors restraining reporters</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HOW WAYWARD US PILOT KILLED 20 ON SKI LIFT</ENAMEX>."

            "I know it's not the most traditional way to balance the budget, but it just
might work." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>
recently received notices from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> informing them that they each owed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">agency $300,000,000</ENAMEX>.

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, real-world combat requirements come first--except when they
don't. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-page piece reveals that even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B2 stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> is the most expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> ever built
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> a copy), and could drop large numbers of "bunker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buster</ENAMEX>" bombs on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> without ever setting foot on skittish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runways</ENAMEX>, it's not likely to see
action over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> corridor explanation teased out by the WP
is that if it were to fail it would be a colossal embarrassment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>, while if it were to succeed it might siphon money away from newer hot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> programs.

         
      
   
