
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Kuwaiting Game</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> decision to move <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> as part of its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> build-up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> report's criticism
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s apparent fund-raising appearance at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> during the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX> campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s upcoming compelled appearance before a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> mistakes that may
have led to improper naturalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than six thousand</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the purpose of the fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> is to increase pressure on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, but also collaterally raises the question of how exactly that's
supposed to work, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also states there is no intention to use
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> or those already in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> for "offensive action" against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.
That will be done, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , from the air. (Just a hunch, but look for
an opening move that's more commandoey than what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s reading about in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>. Very possibly one that will achieve the same results as an
assassination without itself being banned by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy because the operation
wasn't designed to be one--wink, wink, nudge, nudge.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's lead
includes a quote from a fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> that nicely distills <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX> geopolitics:
"We're all a little itchy. We'd kind of like to do something.''

            The troop move is in the front-page news box at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and LAT
fronts, and inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead, concerning the report by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s participation at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> fund-raiser, is in the same
mold as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead--a summary of facts already unearthed
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> hearings, with nothing really new. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's
adjacent piece suggests that the report's finding concerning alleged
connections between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> intelligence officials
is in the same limbo. A similar bit of warmed-over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>--about an audience
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apparently granted in exchange for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$325,000</NUMEX> campaign
contribution--graces the LAT front.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s negotiations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> seem to have stalled out, she has been summoned to appear before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> grand jury on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The
paper calls the move "a significant escalation."

            In discussing how when word leaked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, it put an end to any
undercover usefulness she might have had, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> writes, "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>,
word of her alleged affair with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> began seeping out on an Internet
gossip site.." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , in other words, still can't bear to breathe
the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>" as a source of news. This is as absurd and snobbish as
if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX> were to report on a story that originally was broken by a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> on 43rd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Bradsher</ENAMEX> has pretty much owned the topic of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dangers</ENAMEX> presented to normal-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> by sports utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, and today
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradsher</ENAMEX> continues, writing about an auto insurance industry report that urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redesign SUVs</ENAMEX> because they "increase the risk of death for other road users
while providing little if any additional protection for their own occupants."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> sees things pretty much the same way, going high
with the report's claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> hit broadside by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> times
more likely to die as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> occupants. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX> piece says the report is more nuanced,
suggesting that the problem lies not just with the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> but also
with the lack of protective features in small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>.

            On the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> national edition is a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> on the ground in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> that is interesting because it's
the rare shot of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> doing something the rest of us do all
the time: wear sunglasses. The picture helps drive home the basis for the
taboo: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behind those Foster Grants Cohen</ENAMEX> looks every bit the kind of oleaginous
pol the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> has to eventually help out of some little unpleasantness in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a story on its front about the recent discovery that a
much-ticketed truck<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> "whose license was revoked after a crash in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
killed a teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorist</ENAMEX>...." was caught driving again. And atop the story
sits the headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Driver of Truck That Killed Teen is Cited with New</ENAMEX>
Violation." Besides having previously received thirty-two traffic citations,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> precipitated the fatality by running a red light. So, it may seem a
little thing, but imbued with the Orwellian desire to combat imprecise language
that makes lies sound truthful and murder respectable, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" would
urge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> to rewrite such stories thus: "...whose license was revoked
after he crashed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, killing a teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorist</ENAMEX>...." And to put it
under a headline like: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Driver of Truck Who Killed Teen is Cited With New</ENAMEX>
Violation."

         
      
   
