
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> But True

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a story nobody else is paying much attention to right now--the
continued <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> failure to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> with adequate
information. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' decisions
to press on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a story that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> got out in
front on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with news that must strike terror deep within the hearts of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>, mistakenly
leased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of unlisted phone numbers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telemarketers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead is spurred by the latest report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
chief arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is no closer now to
meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> requirements for the lifting of sanctions than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> went to the brink to prevent further arms inspections. The
paper sees a further ominous sign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s new outburst of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
defiance--a call by the highest levels of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the
immediate lifting of all embargoes.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has some choice tidbits from that as-yet unpublished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> (and from others as well). Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> found some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> on their list to have been stripped of all equipment and even
furniture. Indeed, none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> visited outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> had either
documents or computers. And some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> were stunned by the opulence of the
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> in them must have, according to some on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> to furnish.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> died quietly on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flowered mattress</ENAMEX>. The story goes
on to describe televised footage of the death scene: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX>'s body stretched out
on a bed, plastic sandals at his bedside. Or you could turn to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
top front, which has a large color shot of just this scene. The WP
quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nate Thayer</ENAMEX>, who recently did the first interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>, saying he had no doubt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mattress</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> and
dead.

            The emotional scars left by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>'s terror reign are crystallized in a
remark made by a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Killing Fields</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX>, quoted by both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> : "If he's dead, hand over his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>....I want to see
him handcuffed and pushed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>, like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadres</ENAMEX> did to me 20 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is taking the
position that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>'s death should not end efforts to bring to justice other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> implicated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> slaughter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead
editorial states that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> members of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX>'s extermination <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> are
still at large, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial says that the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX>, is also a henchmen.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>'s reaction to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s disclosure of his tax return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> was to label him "Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scrooge</ENAMEX>" for donating <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $353</NUMEX> to charity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> out of his income
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$197,729</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> leading up
to recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> hearings on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> was given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> worth of free software by competitor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> picks up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on a story first reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Morning Post</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX>, in bringing to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Think</ENAMEX>
Different" ads featuring pictures of famous independent movers and shakers, has
decided to drop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s portrait from the campaign. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at first tried to claim that this was because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s face
is not well-known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>--until confronted with the information that
polls show <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are familiar with him. Now the
line is, "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, he may not get across the message that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> is trying to
send." True, since apparently the message is money-grubbing phony
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">individualism</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts report that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanderbilt University</ENAMEX>
study, to be published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> , indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are far less likely than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> to make use of the
Internet. The racial divide is particularly pronounced on the lower end of
the economic scale. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $40,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>
were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times as likely as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to have used the Web. By the way, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story cannot just refer to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>"--oh no, it has to
explain that this is "a popular Internet graphical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, encompassing some
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, that is revolutionizing business and education." Now
think about this--if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> doesn't know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is, would he know what
the Internet is, or what a graphical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is?

         
      
   
