
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> to Learn

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with plunging gasoline prices. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the latest line of inquiry
undertaken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s new take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s inquiry--its slowness is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s fault. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the surprise objection
raised by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed/Northrop</ENAMEX> merger.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> cites warmer-than-usual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and a
drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> demand because of that region's economic crisis as explanatory
factors for the price drop. In its front pager, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s
increased production. The result, is, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> is now selling
at the equivalent of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">27 cents</NUMEX> a gallon in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> dollars. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says it's
less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 cents</NUMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say prices will rise when the summer travel
season gets underway.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is investigating whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
Willey, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> alleged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> to have once received
an unsolicited sexual advance from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>, was
ever asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> ties to alter her testimony about such an
incident. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> may investigate is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> who may have called and met with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>. In the piece,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> mentions that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> was contacted about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> by
"a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>." Why can't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> bear to identify that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who broke the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica L. story</ENAMEX>? Is the
silence a form of shunning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, a former long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who
left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> under strained circumstances?

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> had said it was time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to "show his
cards." But on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> was, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's words, "recalibrating" his
views by now blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s meager results on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. He called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to come forward and tell the whole truth
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> added that he believes the scandal is
beginning to have an impact on the presidency.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> provides a sneak peak at a letter of apology former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX> has written to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> . The upshot: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> now admits
he dug up the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopergate</ENAMEX> for
ideological reasons and he's sorry. Incidentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> writes that he didn't
think "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paula</ENAMEX>" (he didn't use her last name) could ever have been identified. He
says now it was "an oversight" to have left that name in.

            After an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-month</TIMEX> review, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> revealed serious
objections to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $12 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed/Northrop</ENAMEX> merger, and may file
suit to block it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the news surprised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and shocked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, who punished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>'s stock. According to the paper, the
government wants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> to divest all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>'s defense electronics
programs, which may be a deal-breaker, since acquiring them was one of the
merger's prime motivations.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> accounts stress that the
government is concerned that consolidation among military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> may have
gone too far to maintain competition. (Although, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> is for the merger, because it would resuscitate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grumman</ENAMEX>'s carrier
aviation lines.) For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that the merged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would be virtually the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> of certain radar
and electronic warfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>, and would leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> of warplanes. The papers all point out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
reaction is of a piece with its recent tougher antitrust policy with respect to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>: "I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> is taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boehner</ENAMEX> sued <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McDermott</ENAMEX> yesterday
charging that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDermott</ENAMEX> violated his privacy illegally leaking the tape of a
telephone conversation involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehner</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> discussing the ethics investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. It is believed this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has sued another in his
personal capacity.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snapshot</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, the top state for PC
use, expects to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of its home phone traffic be PC rather than voice by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Kim</ENAMEX>, who pleaded guilty to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knowingly</ENAMEX> accepting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$230,000</NUMEX> in illegal foreign and corporate campaign
contributions, was sentenced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to a year of probation, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> fine
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> of home confinement, to be implemented by an electronic
monitoring device. Since, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> point out, the federal program allows
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monitorees</ENAMEX> to go to and from work, look for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> to be inundated with arduous
meetings from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning till late at night</TIMEX>. Many of them in fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>. Many of them with...<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
