
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakti Waves</ENAMEX>

            Nuclear proliferation is the story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s possible imminent
test of a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>, and is also the subject of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> piece tipped high in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s front-page
news box. The confirmation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> that last week <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> detonated a hydrogen
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group of Eight</ENAMEX>'s struggle to devise a nuclear strategy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that despite appeals from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and other world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has decided to conduct a
nuclear test, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> . And this
is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and WSJ headlines say. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also
report that others in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> say the decision has not been made yet.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WP</ENAMEX> quotes Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX>, who had just left
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, as saying that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> left believing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistanis</ENAMEX> were
still undecided. The LAT sums up the situation with its off-lead
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pakistan Sends Mixed Signals</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is quoted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> saying that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> test is "a nutty way to go." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> summit
refused to follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lead and impose sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, reports
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , instead issuing a resolution condemning its nuclear testing. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls this a "toothless statement."

            Meanwhile, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> ratcheted the
situation with its announcement that its nuclear missile program is all but
ready. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explains this means the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> now has a nuke that can
be delivered from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, or launched from the ground or the sea. According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the hydrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> (code-named <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shakti-1</ENAMEX>,
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hindi</ENAMEX> word for "power") they set off is considerably smaller than the
largest hydrogen bombs tested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the other established
nuclear powers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> say they kept their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> "small" to avoid damage to
nearby populated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says
of larger bombs, "If there is a demand, we will do it." An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>
tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> claims about having exploded a hydrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> and
being able to explode bigger ones is quite believable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have known that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> could build an atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, but aren't
sure about a hydrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>.

            As with its reporting on the original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> announcement of the tests last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> captures the national pride they have inspired, a
feeling the paper likens to the way we felt about our original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX>.
Cheers were heard, for instance, on the videotape of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Monday</TIMEX>'s blasts.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front ran a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gerth/David Sanger</ENAMEX> piece reporting at
length on what was suggested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX> piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>/DNC
connection: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">monies</ENAMEX> paved the way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
approval of the export of satellite technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is quoted, "All the
foreign policy decisions we made were based on what we believed...were in the
best interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." In his column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>
calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proliferation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>," arguing that his willingness to
export the technology strengthened <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s satellite and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> technology,
which scared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> into joining the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, which scared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> can now aid with advanced missile weaponry.

            In a WP op-ed, budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Hodge</ENAMEX> takes a look at the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>
billion highway bill, which, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> claim, is full of gold-plated projects.
Actually, argues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodge</ENAMEX>, it's worse than that: it would be far cheaper--less
than half the cost--if the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interstate Highway System</ENAMEX> was just
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gold-plated</ENAMEX>.

            According to information in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>," there's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> respect in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> has no peer in the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Almost half a</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> don't have toilets.

         
      
   
