
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky Outsky</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit to
exclude all evidence relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the apparently floundering negotiations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s lawyers
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All four</NUMEX> fronts are adorned with a fresh picture of Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, appearing far more sophisticated than in the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> shot or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> reel. No doubt about it, sitting chiaroscuro in the back of a limo next
to a criminal defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> is a good look.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case ruling came, explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s even
broader request to halt all of the case's fact-finding in deference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> acknowledged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-related evidence
might be relevant, but says it's not essential. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> were
disappointed, being left in the position, observes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , of not being
able to use evidence their case helped flush out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s suits
liked the decision. "That's huge," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . "That
means we try the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case. That's
huge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has the same quote, but loses the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pace</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that this legal conflict
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> shows that there's not a united anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
front.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead cites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who argue that the decision has a big
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> upshot: if the sworn statements <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> recently gave
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are not admissible, then they cannot be used as the basis for
perjury or obstruction of justice charges. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> doesn't agree.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> negotiations has
plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX>. Such as: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> saying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that she was present
late <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and that she had seen "numerous
gifts" the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exchanged. The story also states that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> removed several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dresses</ENAMEX> and pant suits from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
laboratory has tested them to see if they could be linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The paper
does not know the tests' outcome.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> go front-page with the bombing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> abortion clinic that killed an off-duty police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
working there as a security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>. Operation Rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reps</ENAMEX> joined pro-choice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> in condemning the action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> are looking to see if the
crime has any connection to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unsolved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> bombings.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reminds us that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> can dish it out but they can't take it, with its report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, who is suing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> for slander, has, via his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, blasted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> for having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet The Press</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX> is
unexpectedly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in his support of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> threats against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
stance is also Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . Meanwhile, fully half of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page is given over to calls for action against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kagan</ENAMEX> say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> and his regime
from power. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX> goes that one better: "Eventually he will have to be
killed for the safety of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Deli</ENAMEX> added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> to its
menu <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>: The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>" and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>." And on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> at
least, the former outsold the latter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> are identical concoctions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>, baloney, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX>. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> difference: The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>" uh, comes with
a tomato.

         
      
   
