
   
   
      
         
            Emerging Measures

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers Group</ENAMEX> deal--the largest corporate merger ever--is
everybody's lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX> business and policy and personality stories take
up much of the rest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s news hole.

            The resulting insurance, banking and securities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will be called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX> (narrowly edging out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelerscorp, Groupcorp, Corpgroup</ENAMEX>,
Corptravelers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groupciti</ENAMEX>, we hear) and will become the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>' accounts of the size of the deal vary
somewhat: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 billion</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$82 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> say it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$83 billion</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
figure apparently doesn't take into account the increase in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>'
shares during the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall St.</ENAMEX> explosion--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> closed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX> for the first
time ever--the deal touched off.

            The papers report that the new financial services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will offer
"one-stop shopping" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> are somewhat breathless about the possibility, but the LAT
says it's not at all clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> want this, noting that previous
efforts to offer it have "generally failed." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">elaborates</TIMEX>, pointing out that previous
high-profile attempts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> to cross-pollinate with
Wall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St. partners</ENAMEX> failed. In addition, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , creating a
huge full-service financial edifice <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX> in the face of the trend toward
discount brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and cheap on-line trading.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> emphasize that the most striking part of the deal is that
current laws, in force since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>, prevent financial cross-selling on
this scale. The deal boldly challenges all this, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , putting
pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to change the status quo, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before the deal goes into full effect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calls this feature
remarkable "brashness," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says it is its "most remarkable
aspect." Another pressure factor is that it's widely believed this merger will
inspire other similar ones.

            Another unusual aspect of the deal drawing lots of comment is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Travelers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanford Weill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Reed</ENAMEX> have decided to rule their
new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> as co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>. A piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" front page says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> are dubious about the arrangement. The WSJ wonders if the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> can "merge their egos." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> business section piece on the
relationship runs under the header, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Odd Couple</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> are quoted as saying the merger will not produce large-scale
layoffs. But, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , layoffs of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> followed
each of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weill</ENAMEX>'s previous big deals.

            As has become common in merger reporting, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> attempt to
cloak the event in intrigue and drama. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
try to summon atmosphere with their descriptions of early meetings where the
top <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> sniffed each other. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says "the excitement was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palpable</ENAMEX>" during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s news conference at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldorf</ENAMEX> announcing the merger,
with the arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> reminding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of nothing so much as
"the arrival of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>." But the excitement is not
infectious: after all, what you have here basically is suits writing checks to
themselves.

            Indeed, the only real corrective to all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s money euphoria comes in
the WP front-page piece, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boom Is Fine</ENAMEX>--If You Own
Stock," which notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> still do not
own any shares of anything.

            The LAT front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme Court</ENAMEX> handed a
defeat to unwed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> with its ruling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who fathers a child
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who is married to someone else may be denied all legal parental
rights. As the paper points out, this is significant in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are born to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> who are not married to each other.

            If you missed the two top stories in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> --the
government's first post-deregulation attempt to preserve competitiveness among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> and the emergence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that can prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>--they are
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's front <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a piece inside reporting that during a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> service
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John O'Connor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from the pulpit for taking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> communion while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> who invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to do so is quoted in the
paper as saying that once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stood up, he was thinking about "how much
embarrassment it would have caused him by my saying, please sit down."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novelist Lucian Truscott IV</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">generals</ENAMEX>, writes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed in support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
latest assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> ban. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truscott</ENAMEX> compares the intensive training you get in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> with one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> long before you're ever allowed to fire it,
and then only under the supervision of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> marksman, with the situation
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, where "it's legal for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> to own a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">semiautomatic</ENAMEX> assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> without a moment of safety instruction, training
in how to shoot it or adult supervision."

         
      
   
