
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Road</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stating that finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has really been
cooperating with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons monitoring efforts. The top national story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s debate about widening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with the decision
by federal corruption <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Hoffa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James P. Hoffa</ENAMEX>,
run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> presidency. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>'s
launch of an investigation into the tactics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>.

            The American admission was made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>, about inspections of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s nuclear program and previously
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">off-limits</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. But he went on to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> continues
to oppose any relaxation of economic sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s weapons
inspection program, citing, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s continuing
insufficient cooperation in the areas of long-range <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and chemical and
biological weapons. This story also makes the fronts at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , but the latter emphasizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to
extend sanctions despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s conciliatory remarks.

            The nuances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s thinking about sanctions are on display
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page piece that depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelical leaders</ENAMEX>, unaware that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reporter
was there too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to withdraw its support for legislation
aiming to reduce religious persecution overseas by imposing sanctions because
he said such bills put enormous pressure on whoever is in the executive branch
to fudge an evaluation of the facts of what is going on." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> needs
flexibility, he said, including the ability to impose sanctions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> line on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion discussion is that this is a quite
important issue that wasn't receiving its due in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,
when "after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> of dueling monologues, however, something novel
happened: Debate broke out." But judging by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> examples, it
wasn't exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln-Douglas</ENAMEX>. There was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Biden</ENAMEX> saying, "The worst
time to enlarge an alliance is at a moment of threat. This is the time and the
moment, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> after the wall has come down, to end once and for all the
artificial boundaries," with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Smith</ENAMEX> responding, "They picked winners
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yalta</ENAMEX>. We are picking winners and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> here." (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">helpfully</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX> is for expansion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> against.) And there's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>' contribution: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> could not fight its way out
of a wet paper bag."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead editorial sees the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in a "reckless rush" to
approve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion, stating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> have pressed their case with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slogans</ENAMEX>, not arguments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Cohen</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>'s is actively campaigning against expansion. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX>'s
column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> explains why: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expanding NATO</ENAMEX> would be like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>'s still
wanting to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haagen-Dazs</ENAMEX> out of business even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-D</ENAMEX> had switched to making
hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. The problem here is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> hasn't gotten rid of its, er.ice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cream</ENAMEX> machines.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> who makes it down to the fifteenth paragraph of the WP
lead gets schooled on what it means to be a clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Teamster</ENAMEX>. That's where it
says that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffa</ENAMEX> the green light fined him and
several of his running <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> in the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> election <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $40,000</NUMEX> for
receiving improper campaign contributions, and held that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffa</ENAMEX> "did not testify
accurately" about his personal involvement in the preparation of campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> reports. By contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>
story, broaches this point in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph, and observes in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
paragraph that as a result of the negative findings about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffa</ENAMEX>, neither side
in the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> election can run as an untainted reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column notes that the machinists <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> has licensed a
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>'s item for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 110th anniversary</TIMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winchester Model 94</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rifle</ENAMEX>. Wait till the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> union hears about this.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece that caught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> speaking off the cuff about
sanctions also includes his confession that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX> he often gets a call
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> asking him about some item from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>'s paper that she's
read on the Internet, but that he knows nothing about. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, may
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" humbly suggest."<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>"?

         
      
   
