
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House of Blues</ENAMEX>

            
all lead with the latest developments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> sex scandal. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes another way, leading with the latest developments in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> money scandal (remember?).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter moved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on several fronts, which get covered to
varying degrees. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead reports that while denying any
obstruction of justice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> said that he kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> informed about
his efforts to land <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a private-sector job. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also has
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> traumatic distress syndrome of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, as well as word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> squared off before a
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, but in both regards it leaves important details out. You have to
read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> not only viewed the WP
deposition leak as "reckless, reprehensible and unethical" but also that he
said, "We are going to seek relief in court on this...." (Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
didn't elaborate and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> wasn't about to--after all, it's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is talking about going after.) And to learn that the
point of the closed hearing was so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> could try to convince a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> abide by a preliminary agreement to extend immunity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in
return for her testimony.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> describe the wild scene outside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courthouse</ENAMEX>, mobbed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and topped off with anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> protestors
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chanting</ENAMEX>, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>! Married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't date!"

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also detail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hot reaction to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scoop</ENAMEX>: "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has made it absolutely clear it is illegal to leak and
discuss" his deposition. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the
controversy--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>--deny leaking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">depo</ENAMEX>. Also, the LAT front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "sternly refused" to
explain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> why in his deposition, he said he warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX> that she
was likely to be called in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead plays catch-up on the depo story by pointing out that
the deposition's heavier than anticipated focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> makes sense of the
prior Times scoop about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>'s testimony that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> went over with her the facts about his relationship with the intern.
The piece emphasizes how in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deposition account <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> is the
central figure, even to the point where it was her idea to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> a gift
when he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX> on vacation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> adds this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tidbit</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said in his depo that previous accusations about drug dealing
and even murder had left him "paranoid."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead is the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX>,
who once compared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to a subway, where you need coins to open the
doors, will plead guilty to tax evasion, bank fraud and election law violations
in an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> under which he will cooperation with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reports that another
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> suspected of funneling foreign money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yogesh Gandhi</ENAMEX>, was arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on unrelated fraud charges as he prepared
to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung</ENAMEX> story on their
front pages.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> of
possible airstrikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> have become less confident of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ability
to bomb biological weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> after a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> test in which
a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> that was expected to incinerate a stockpile of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anthrax</ENAMEX>-like
germs instead spread them.

            While all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> were going front-page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> with the news
that hands-on basketballer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX> was being given his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> back,
there was virtually no newsplay of his most recent escapade. It seems that on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sprewell</ENAMEX> was involved in a car accident that sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sprewell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> was
traveling at "high speed" when it struck sand barrel obstacles, hit a wall and
then collided with another car. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Witnesses</ENAMEX> said they'd seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprewell</ENAMEX> speeding.
Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> fears another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arbitrator</ENAMEX> in the wings. It didn't
give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprewell</ENAMEX> a ticket. All this information comes from the only press coverage
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" is aware of--a brief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> item on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s LAT
sports section. You know, where everyone put the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OJ</ENAMEX> had pleaded no
contest to beating his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
