
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butt Heads Butt Heads</ENAMEX>

            The en masse defection of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'
efforts at a settlement leads everywhere. The industry promises to immediately
launch a public relations offensive against a "coercive, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX>-type
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the campaign kicks off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with
newspaper ads reading, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Agreed To Change The Way We Do Business</ENAMEX> . . . Not To
Go <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out Of Business</ENAMEX>." Everybody quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s determined reaction:
"They can be part of it or they can fight it," although oddly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leaves out the most important part of his quote: "We're going to get this
done."

            The tobacco stance became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> with a speech against the tough and
expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bill by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Goldstone</ENAMEX>, described by the papers
as "aggressive" and "defiant." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldstone</ENAMEX> is widely quoted as saying,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has rushed to collect more tobacco revenues while playing the
politics of punishment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes him describing the process as
"broken beyond repair." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldstone</ENAMEX> raised the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specter</ENAMEX> of a thriving black market in cigarettes if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bill were to
become law.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> point out that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can proceed unilaterally in many
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of the proposed legislation, this is problematic with the provisions that
touch on the curtailment of free speech, such as advertising restrictions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldstone</ENAMEX> is quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> saying that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> imposes these
anyway, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> "will fight in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>." Feelings are running just as high
on the other side. The paper quotes the reaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent Conrad</ENAMEX>: "Poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>." Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad</ENAMEX> expressed the idea
that all this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> stridency is a stratagem designed to get the
current deal accepted without the addition of any harsher conditions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is admirably clear about the context producing such
skepticism: "The tobacco industry has dissembled so often in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>--about
whether cigarettes cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, about whether nicotine is addictive, about
whether they market their product to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are never sure what
to make of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' pronouncements." Now, if only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> had
said "lied" instead of "dissembled"...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> seems a little less surprised by all
this, claiming that "the reality is that tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> have been
closed out of the legislative process." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also sends along
word that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summer</ENAMEX>'s original tobacco deal, says he understands the industry position and
calls on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to convene new negotiations.

            And lest we forget what this is all about, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that
suggests that non-smokers not only live longer, but have less sickness and
dependence on others in their last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> each run stories describing a new study
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purporting</ENAMEX> to show that the differences between black and white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
considerable. Among those with incomes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above $50,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 57 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> had money in the stock market, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. And
while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 13 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> believed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> will provide at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> their retirement income, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> thought this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments of Defense</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> to devise plans for the arrest and trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> responsible for the death of perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodians</ENAMEX> in the
1970s. According to the paper, the opportunity presents itself because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>, which has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> under house arrest, is in complete disarray.
Hmmm...wonder if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> subscribes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ...

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX> assesses the career thus far of the
military's "don't ask, don't tell" policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> notes that under the
policy, discharges of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> have increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> if you
figure in downsizing). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> observes, has now fired more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            The front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> national edition brings word that, buoyed
by the soaring approval ratings of the sex-scandalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, the
sex-scandalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Packwood</ENAMEX> wants to get back in the game. He's thinking about
running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" has just the
campaign slogan for him: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Still Packing Wood</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
