
   
   
      
         
            Thanks--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision placing new restrictions
on credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> membership. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">animadversions</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s call for the rejection
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>-brokered accord with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> pieces (as well as a piece on the front
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> national edition) explain that the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> decision
decides a simmering conflict between those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> in favor of
the latter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> had been claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX>, which enjoy tax-exempt
status based on their origins as volunteer-run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cooperatives</ENAMEX>, have, by wildly
expanding their memberships beyond simple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or vocational affiliation (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, more than double the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> total), been able to unfairly
compete for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> vote, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> agreed, even though
consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> complain that this portends bad news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, who've
benefited from the downward fee pressures <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX> provide.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> effort attributes a quotation to "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bankers Assn</ENAMEX>. and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>." Not to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, but to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> themselves. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" guesses this is a
telltale sign of writing the reaction part of the story from a press release.
It would be far better to interview an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> instead, if only because
you can't ask a press release follow-up questions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> lashed out at the
"avalanche of lies" spread about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and defended his decision to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subpoena Clinton</ENAMEX> loyalists to determine if they have been spreading derogatory
information about his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , his grand jury
investigation focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s federal job history, with a
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrangle</ENAMEX> over the possible invoking of executive privilege by certain
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> still on hold. The paper points out that the privilege
issue presents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobson</ENAMEX>'s choice: fight the notion and divert
significant resources to a long court battle, or don't fight it and forgo some
key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead runs a new charge made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s lawyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> may have "manipulated tape-recorded
conversations" she had with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> meant Tripp tricked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ML</ENAMEX> into misstatements or physically edited the tape
to be misleading. It should have.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> does report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> seed money for
a legal defense fund by a benefactor whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> promotes the view that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> need to "use their sexuality" in the workplace to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , it looks as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> was able to take
enough of a break from sabotaging campaign reform to try sabotaging the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to reject
it, accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of abdicating its foreign policy to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> pointedly observes that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> did not say in his speech
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> what he would have done if he were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s position.."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front carries a chilling "special report" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>' hunt for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s germ warfare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>. The piece flatly
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has run an elaborate germ weapons program and that it "had
made enough deadly microbes to kill all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on earth several times
over." There's also the revelation of a crash military program intended to
create the ability for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to wipe out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> with anthrax
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microbes</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts describe how, within the past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> have broken into unclassified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> to
examine and possibly alter payroll and personnel data.

            Sure, the school bus is crawling with safety violations and doesn't contain
seat belts and will be taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who never
actually had to take the subjects they're teaching, but at least according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "Business Bulletin," in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> there will be
satellite-based technology available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that will let them know to the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> exactly when the bus is arriving.

         
      
   
