
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Depo Charge</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s unanimous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court decision that the law barring sexual discrimination in the workplace
applies equally to harassment between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> of the same sex. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> story near
the top, goes instead with the most detailed account yet of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
deposition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" couldn't help but notice
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't comment on the important step the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
took to keep the workplace safe from sexual harassment.

            It's just common sense that same sex doesn't automatically mean no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harassment</ENAMEX>, but the reporting on the decision makes it clear that the
legalities have been murky. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the law of sexual harassment is basically a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court creation, and broadening its application has met with hostility in lower
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX>'s opinion for the
Court--issued in the case of a male oil-rig <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> complaining about his
treatment by male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>--says the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> test for harassment is not the sex
or motivation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, but whether there is sex-based discrimination in
the workplace "so objectively offensive as to alter the conditions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s employment."

            Scalia, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , went on to claim that the decision does not
abrogate all "genuine but innocuous differences in the ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and women
routinely interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the same sex and of the opposite sex," and
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give his example: a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> slapping a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>'s rear on
the way to the field would be lawful, while the same gesture directed at the
coach's (female or male) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> might not be. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> note that the
decision drew praise from civil rights and gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>.

            It's interesting to compare the harassment headlines. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Court Widens Workplace Claims of Sex Harassment</ENAMEX>." This is much less clear
than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Same-sex Harassment Illegal</ENAMEX>." (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has virtually
this same to-the-point headline.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> lead clear across the top. And once again, photo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> in effect put an opinion on the front page. The accompanying picture of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has to be the least attractive one of him ever published: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes hooded</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">JFK</ENAMEX>-style, talking out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of his mouth.

            This story, about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 17th</TIMEX> deposition, represents the most
elaborate press account yet of his description of his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> testified, says the paper, that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exchanged gifts and
that she visited him in his office perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times, and that they may have
been alone together. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> denied having sexual relations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, which for the purposes of the deposition was defined as fondling and
oral sex, but not kissing on the mouth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said it was his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Currie</ENAMEX> who initiated career help for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            In the deposition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> denied that he propositioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> and also
denied having sex with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> he was asked about. He did, however,
say that he'd had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>--just once, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that often during the proceeding's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had to be asked to speak up. And, says the paper, at a couple of
points, he reacted to something that was said in a "frustrated outburst." It's
odd that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> was able to find this out without finding out what
prompted it.

            The story gives a good picture of the personal degradation involved for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in giving the deposition: there were seventeen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in attendance.
Obviously, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of them was the source for this story. Place your money
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> and/or one of her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> (!) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> all go front page with the
news that choke-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX> was given his gazillion
dollar contract back by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arbitrator</ENAMEX>. Everybody has this quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Stern</ENAMEX>: "You cannot strike your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> and still hold your
job--unless you play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>...."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that, voting along racial lines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> rejected a proposal to compensate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of those killed in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in hate crimes during the civil rights era. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard White</ENAMEX> is
quoted as saying, "I don't think we need to....start scratching these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sores</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> column about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> has one of the more striking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> disclaimers you'll ever see:
"....(full disclosure: I worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> and
didn't like him.)"

         
      
   
