
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papal Bull</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> response to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s official repentance regarding the mass
killings of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the news that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>
campuses to generate admissions statistics since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> abandoned
affirmative action have seen their black and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> acceptance rates
plummet.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> was primarily <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold: a strong
denial from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and the release of a raft of friendly letters
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> after the date she alleges she was groped by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. In one letter, widely quoted, she calls herself <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "number one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>." In another, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> asks to be appointed to an ambassadorship. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says some of the letters were "effusive." And a piece inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says they "do not suggest a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who felt betrayed." (There was
also the effort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>, noted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , to portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> as mercenary for trying to land a
book deal.)

            None of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> letters pays the slightest heed to
the well-known phenomenon of even physically abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> having trouble
expressing their animosity towards their abusers or physically separating from
them. It's as if nobody in the entire press corps remembers that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole Brown</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> moved back in with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> after those pictures were taken of her pummeled
face.

            Despite the six-cylinder spin cycle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that "there was no
ignoring the dark mood that settled over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Willey</ENAMEX>'s wake. The
paper noted a rare moment of anger by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>, who lashed out at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who asked him whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had ever received psychological
treatment or counseling for risky and reckless behavior.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead makes that point that when originally
confronted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> charges, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> released a statement saying that he
had "no specific recollection" of meeting with her, but that his current denial
is based on "a very clear memory" of the meeting.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Lewis</ENAMEX>, who spearheaded the anti-Willey
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counteroffensive</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with an appearance on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>" show, was a
leading supporter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead puts a finer point on
the matter, noting, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> among them--had accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> when they noted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>
confirmation hearings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> had continued to stay in close
touch with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> even after he allegedly harassed her with lewd sexual
remarks."

            Such apparently effortless shifting by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is called to task
pointedly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece via
a quotation from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, who says, "What gets to the heart of
it is that feminism is no longer a principle, it's a political tool."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead concerning the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican</ENAMEX> points out that while the
document issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> is described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> as "an act of repentance" for
the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Catholics</ENAMEX> to deter the mass killings in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, it skirts the issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s institutional shortcomings
during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>, primarily its official silence about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. The document,
says the paper, took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX> to prepare, and was greeted coolly by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Everybody carries the repentance story on the front page.

            Everybody's front page also carries word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> trial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> didn't
send the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant major</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> to jail, but did bust him down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rank</ENAMEX>, a move that will cost him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in pension money. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX>
sued his initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX> for libel, asking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX>. Meanwhile, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>
rejected an advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s recommendation that male and female recruits
be housed separately during training.

about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattanites</ENAMEX>' reliance on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>storage referred incorrectly to doves and
a rabbit used in the act of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnie Kolodner</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magician</ENAMEX>. While he keeps costumes
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>storage, the rabbit and doves live in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. A correction in this
space on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> omitted mention of the rabbit."

         
      
   
