
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journalism</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pellet</ENAMEX> Surprise

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic news:
surging growth but the slowest rate of inflation increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX>. The top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hard-nosed
self-defense at his first press conference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
metro edition goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s overwhelming approval of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the earlier</TIMEX>, national edition goes with the tax evasion indictment of
already-once-convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Felon of Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> coverage of the presidential press
conference--accompanied by a picture of a pugnacious double-fisted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--reports that he dismissed allegations about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> as the work
of organized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> "unable to counter his ideas or record," but acknowledged
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> of their attacks have diminished his personal standing with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. This used to distress him greatly, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but not
anymore. The paper observes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> of the questions posed by the
press concerned his still-unexplained relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, but
that despite his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> promise to illuminate it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't answer
them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> wash-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> vote explains that all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> must approve the change in order for it to take
effect. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> story says that such total approval is
expected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50th</NUMEX> anniversary summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> piece also includes a workmanlike exposition of the politics
of the vote, including the observation that expansion was supported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
defense industry, which stands to "reap huge profits" from increased weapons
sales to new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.

            The WP front features new federal statistics about teen birth rates (the story
runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) indicating that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time they are down
among every racial and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Oddly, neither story includes any data on
teen out-of-wedlock birth rates. Highlights: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> teen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">birthrate</ENAMEX> is down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>--its lowest level ever. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>,
while still the most prolific, have experienced a rate drop for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> are still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost three</NUMEX> times less likely to become
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> than either <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> took a front-page look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s
troubled and expensive history with anti-missile defense systems. Today, a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> in the arena gets covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , but is relegated to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> section. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curious</ENAMEX>, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s award to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> of a contract
to develop a missile shield could be worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $5.1 billion</NUMEX>. The LAT
whispers the story the same way. Which, is, of course, the way the defense
contractors like it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front features an excellent story
uncovering a little-known problem: racial discrimination in farm loans. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> describes
the attempts by some struggling black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> to get restitution from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>.
Thus far, despite a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-hour</TIMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and an admission
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Glickman</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> had swept the problem under
the rug, as well as numerous specific findings of illegal denials of loans, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> are still waiting to be made whole. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scandalous</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front covers a sensational, disturbing story likely to be much discussed in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days ahead</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, during <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hour</TIMEX>, near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s busiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intersections</ENAMEX>, a distraught <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> killed himself with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> blast to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>--while many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Angelenos</ENAMEX> watched on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or another of the local TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>'
live broadcasts. Afterwards, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> expressed regret for the
coverage and some offered counseling to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>.

            The episode could have a number of important consequences: Before taking his
life, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had unfurled a banner reading: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are in it for the money!!
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live Free</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Safe or Die</ENAMEX>." So perhaps the suicide will further crystallize
the discussion of the impersonality of managed care. (Why, by the way, didn't
the LAT mention the sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>-- probably <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>--angle?) And perhaps
it will break the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> trend of automatically going with
(invariably highly rated) live broadcasts of potentially violent freeway
incidents.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hubbell</ENAMEX> indictment gets lots of ink and produces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s strangest
quote. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> could indict my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. They can indict
my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>. But I'm not going to lie about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. I'm not going to lie
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> or anyone else." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who was indicted along
with him, must have been thrilled with this disclosure of the true family
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pecking</ENAMEX> order.

         
      
   
