
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> Them Later

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with yet another congressional defeat of campaign
reform legislation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the latest on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> anti-smoking bill. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> finding that most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> field inspectors
feel their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> ignore their safety recommendations. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the filing of court papers by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> that charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> with being a
"stalking horse" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> and with trying to sabotage the case proceedings
by raising unproven salacious charges, such as, in its most recent filings, an
unsubstantiated third-party version of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rape rumor.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that prospects for enacting comprehensive campaign reform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> are
pretty much dashed because on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> adopted rules requiring any such measure to pass, not by the
simple majority that seemed in the offing, but by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>
"super-majority." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s commitment to
the issue dates from a much-publicized handshake deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> made with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. The paper quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> as saying,
"The process has been rigged. . . . What's happening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is a real sham." The
collapse of reform also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts.

            This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX> that campaign reform legislation has
fizzled. The headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP Leadership Defeats</ENAMEX> Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reform Bill</ENAMEX>," is
getting to be right up there with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Extremist Group Claims Credit for Bombing</ENAMEX>"
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union Officials Indicted</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>."

            Picking up where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads left off, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead explains that when, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> officially
unveiled the comprehensive tobacco bill he'd been putting together, it was seen
to place no restrictions on private lawsuits against the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
although it does contain an annual damage ceiling of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.5 billion</NUMEX> (awards in
excess of that amount would be owed in full, but could be carried forward to
subsequent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>). In order to qualify though, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> would have to
meet targets for reducing underage <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">smoking</ENAMEX> and cut back on outdoor and cartoon
advertising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says the absence of a restriction on lawsuits
was a surprise to all sides. A tobacco industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is quoted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> saying that the measure would lead to "a massive contraband market,"
and would "almost certainly drive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> into bankruptcy." In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , tobacco deal strategist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> says industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> "think their stock prices are going to plummet." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that despite such opposition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has won substantial
backing on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" can't help but notice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
name is all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>--besides his smoking bill, he is also
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of banning "soft money." All in all,
excellent issues to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column is given over to a topic near and
dear to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s heart: working at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The latest figures from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Statistics</ENAMEX> indicate there are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> on "graveyard"
full-time. And yes, it's quiet and you can go to the cheap movies when you're
off, but according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are more susceptible to
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX>, stomach troubles and depression. And <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> more likely to
get a divorce.

            An editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that a full <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> after
the passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fair Housing Act</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> are still far more likely to own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>, even controlling for wealth and income. The piece goes on to note that
in a recent study made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> pairs of black and white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX> who were matched in income contacted local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX>, they encountered
evidence of racial discrimination <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX> of the time. Significantly, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "the bias did not take the form of a simple 'no' that would show
up as clearly discriminatory in records. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> didn't return phone
calls, didn't keep appointments, offered more expensive or inferior products or
made greater demands for credit information." The editorial endorses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s budget request for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $22 million</NUMEX> to combat housing
discrimination. A large chunk of that money will, says the paper, go towards
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX>.

            An obvious but politically incorrect fact underlying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brouhaha</ENAMEX> is that the main reason she got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place was probably that she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has to meet with
someone to accomplish a given task he'd just as soon that the someone have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breasts</ENAMEX> and smell nice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> know this and take full advantage. (And why
shouldn't they?) Witness the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andie MacDowell</ENAMEX> is meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reps.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dingell</ENAMEX> to lobby for more stringent oil pipeline regulations for western
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>, where she happens to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX>, you try getting that
meeting.

         
      
   
