
   
   
      
         
            Willey, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adversary</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times covers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> questioning in its lead too, but goes higher in
the story with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may be headed for a grand jury
appearance himself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>
announced that none of a new batch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> is being assigned to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>--because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> feels that illegal immigration there has "reached
a level of control." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Californians</ENAMEX>, including
some area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, dispute this, noting that while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>'s illegal
entries seem to have dropped, nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of inland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> have seen their
illegal immigration arrests skyrocket.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> was coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>,
but nobody predicted this soon. The papers seize on various indications that in
Willey, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> seems to have at last found a cooperative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, noting that
she did not appear to have her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> with her ( USAT ), that she
arrived in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr van</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ), and was accompanied inside the
courthouse by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> projected an air of
unconcern, quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX>'s comment: "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tell the
truth, they tell the truth. It doesn't matter who drove you there." But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was mum about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>, a
clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer</ENAMEX>, managed to wangle the private appointment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to discuss her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s financial troubles and her sudden need
for a job, during which, she charges in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case deposition, he groped
her.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s appearance indicates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is
widening his investigation beyond the allegations involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to
determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has testified truthfully in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
deposition about other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as well. Everybody reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is also
interested in determining if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> was--as she stated in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case
affidavit--approached by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Landow</ENAMEX> in an effort to
influence her to back off her grope charge.

            It has been widely reported that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX> now says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>
asked her to falsely claim that she was told by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> about the incident not
long after it happened. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that it has found another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> friend
who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> told her of the incident shortly after it allegedly took place.
On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also notes that in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> testimony in
connection with a lawsuit over her late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s estate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> says she never
had a conversation with anyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reversals</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Iraqis</ENAMEX> who worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> in plots against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> have now
been declared threats to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national security and hence subject to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deportation</ENAMEX>, in a ruling so secret that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> aren't allowed to read
it.

            Another Times front-page piece describes how fear of litigation has
made high school guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> much more hesitant to pass
along information about applicants to college admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. "They'll
write that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> took these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and was a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>," remarks one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in the field, "but they won't tell you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> burned down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gym</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" says that the number of
tax cases referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> have simply
refused to recognize the basic legality of the income tax has doubled over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX>.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's piece about the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> libel suit quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholar Floyd Abrams</ENAMEX> as saying, "If one were rewriting libel law <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, one
would try to write it to assure that the false statements of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> were
treated as libel." And what exactly would that rewrite say? You know, that
wouldn't allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> to say what he says, but would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Abrams</ENAMEX> to
say what he says.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that according to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5</NUMEX>
million worth of food stamps were issued to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 25,000</NUMEX> dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that when asked to identify himself
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> is located,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> said he was "the sausage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>." The
Times is stumped by this, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> gets it: he's quoting a
line <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Broderick</ENAMEX> used in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ferris Bueller's Day Off</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
