
   
   
      
         
            Bank Shot

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
national edition leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-driven delay of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
in response to its recent A-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> tests. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the reduction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
military presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s unanimous ruling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are
generally shielded from liability for deaths or injuries caused by their
high-speed pursuits. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> carry this story inside.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the disparate treatments various tobacco products
receive under the bill now pending in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. For instance, it restricts
the advertising and marketing of cigarettes, but not that of cigars or pipe
tobacco. As a result, some health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are concerned, says the paper, that
the bill won't discourage overall <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> use, but would only redirect it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>'s action to stop loans for an electrical power grid not
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> hits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> frequently affected by power failures and
shortages--hard, but also serves as a signal to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> about what sorts of
sanctions it can expect if it responds to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> with a nuclear test of its own.
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
could detonate an underground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nuke</ENAMEX> at any time.) The threat of more sanctions
has already sent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s currency plunging to an all-time low against the
dollar. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , also sought the loan action.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> region had begun drawing down to pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>-crisis levels because of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>'s assurances of cooperation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> and to help
improve military readiness and morale. Another factor: domestic political
pressures inside such host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahrain</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> decision even protects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> who act
recklessly in conducting pursuits. Because, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX>, the decision to
pursue is often necessarily a split<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-second one</TIMEX>, and violates no one's
constitutional rights. The story observes that about the same number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>--are killed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> in police chases as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">police</ENAMEX> shootings,
which of course makes "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" wonder why the law should treat reckless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> driving differently than reckless police shooting. After all, the
decision to shoot is usually just as split<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-second</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's front reports that as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s effort to
methodically reconstruct the details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s life that she
communicated to her erstwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has been asked to
provide fingerprints and a handwriting sample to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Is there an end in sight for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation? Well, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says he is looking to expand his office space.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that in a phone campaign
undertaken against <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">California Prop. 226</ENAMEX>, the union dues "paycheck protection"
measure, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> telemarketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> claimed that the initiative would imperil
cops by leading to the disclosure of their home addresses, with the result that
they would become targets for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang members</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> observes that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">226</NUMEX> only requires a name, signature, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s identification for the
approval of union dues for political purposes, not an address.

            The USAT front brings word that based on phone surveillance, police
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> detained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> militants suspected of
planning to disrupt the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> soccer matches, scheduled to start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. The story is carried inside elsewhere.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside run stories reporting that a government
panel has hesitantly approved a vaccine against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lyme disease</ENAMEX>. The main sources
of reluctance are that nobody knows how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX> are needed nor if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> is safe for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">undiagnosed Lyme disease</ENAMEX>. The
stories are lacking in context. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that the tick-spread
flu-mimicking <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> is "a serious threat" in parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> national edition mentions in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> paragraph that the latest
government statistics show <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. (The version of the story
appearing in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, metro edition of the paper omits this.) And the
Times says severe cases can result in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, and nervous system and
heart damage. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say how many cases turn out like this. And
neither story states the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyme</ENAMEX> deaths, if any. We are merely told by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that the disease is "a cause of great concern <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each summer</TIMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and those who spend a lot of time outdoors." In short, nothing in the
stories alleviates a creeping suspicion that this disease, while of great
concern to newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> places in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camp Heapumwampum</ENAMEX>, is hardly on a par with say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat bites</ENAMEX>, lead-paint
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poisoning</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malnutrition</ENAMEX> suffered by inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
