
   
   
      
         
            Peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>?

            The ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-brokered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> deal leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>. The national edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote that keeps
alive a campaign fund-raising reform bill (the metro edition of the
Times goes with a state court decision that gives <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> the
right to kick topless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> and sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead
is <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">El Nino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rainstorms</ENAMEX> that have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
off-lead is the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> will prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> if
he believes they have spread false information about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. The stance,
says the paper, amounts to an escalation of the confrontation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration to "frenetic proportions."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> delayed voting on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> agreement after pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> on several points.
The big unresolved issues, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>: the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> who would
now accompany weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> on their rounds, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command</ENAMEX> now, and whether or not the agreement's nod to respecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
sovereignty could interfere with inspections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> fears
the new inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> will be more susceptible than its predecessor
to outside political pressures. In response, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telephoned</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, reassuring him that inspections will
remain controlled by technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> resolution to
automatically declare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in breach of the agreement if it resumes its
obstructive ways. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs the text of the deal signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>, and the language is surprisingly clear. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" has had
apartment leases that were harder to follow--and longer.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front runs a nice piece of access journalism detailing how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and his top national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>, contributed to the ultimate details of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annan/Hussein</ENAMEX> deal. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
point, apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> consider
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">designating Saddam</ENAMEX> a war criminal. According to the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> was far
more actively involved in planning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s approach than has been previously
acknowledged.

            But the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has decided to
have his closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> cite executive privilege to keep from testifying to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand jury about internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> discussions on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX>
matter. The notion could be put to a test before a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> as early as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> has decided to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
efforts to obtain testimony from presidential bodyguards. The decision was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forged</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, in arguing
that efficient protection requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> proximity and hence agent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confidentiality</ENAMEX>, made a presentation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> that included a slow-motion
videotape of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> taking a bullet intended for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>.

            Some editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> weigh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on the escalating battle between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead editorial says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "absurdly"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subpoenaed White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, and assesses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
strategy of "looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and trying to discredit
straightforward reporting of embarrassing facts" as "sleazy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
lead editorial views <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s move on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> as "bone stupid" tactically and
an "attack on press freedom and the unrestricted flow of information."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that "robust investment returns coupled with strong
donations to higher education have created a financial boom for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> of which now have endowments of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> or
more." The piece goes on to quote various breathless university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> about
how the money is rolling in, but nowhere is the question raised as to why if
financial times are so good, tuition has risen at a ferocious rate, often
outpacing even health care costs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front includes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gina Kolata</ENAMEX> piece describing the rapidly
escalating cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">donor eggs</ENAMEX> for various infertility procedures. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> has just doubled payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> for a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that sperm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> typically get less
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, but also describes in some detail how much less fun <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>
have.

         
      
   
