
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Indonesian: Him Out</ENAMEX>

            Everybody's lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> resignation. Immediately after Suharto
announced he was stepping down, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jusuf Habibie</ENAMEX>, was
sworn in as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> pledged the loyalty of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

            Yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> has not been a favorite of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
military. But only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explains why: He has never served in the armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and while serving as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s science and technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>,
is known to have antagonized some of the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> by forcing them to make
certain technical purchases.

            Reflecting a week in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesians</ENAMEX> were killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> riots, in
his announcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying, "It has become extremely
difficult for me to continue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." Then he employed
the non-apology apology style so favored by discredited Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>,
expressing his "deepest sorrow if there were any mistakes, failures or
shortcomings." But he added something no Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> says--at least not
until he's at his sentencing--he asked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> to "forgive me." Only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's story and headline include this anomaly.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> go front-page with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> nearly unanimous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> votes stating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> failed to act in the national
interest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> when he permitted a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> headed up by a
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Included in the votes
was a measure banning all further <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, including current
and pending deals. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> headlines focus on the facts
of these restrictions--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> headline instead goes more for the
political angle: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">House Rebukes Clinton</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>." The LAT mentions
quite clearly, and the WP somewhat obliquely, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">then-President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
also presided over a waiver of satellite technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
story does not. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> does add something incendiary to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
pile: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> blocked the release of a classified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> report holding that
the satellite help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> received under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> harmed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national security,
by upgrading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> missile capabilities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's lead editorial says
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s decision to investigate the export of sensitive technology
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is "right beyond argument."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> staff is upset
over the metro section <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s recent remark that it would be unfair for
female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who take time off to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to be as far along in
their careers as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> is up in arms over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women readers</ENAMEX> are more drawn to emotional stories than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are, and his proposal of a system that would financially reward senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> who ensure stories include more quotations from minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> members
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT op-ed page features a piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Ofari Hutchinson</ENAMEX> on the
recent trend of banning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kenyans</ENAMEX> in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>
from long-distance races, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> wonders if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of affirmative action will protest a policy that
rewards less-qualified white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Well, whether or not they do, it seems
to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" that outrage such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX>'s over the road race policy
tends to support outrage over affirmative action. Letting slower white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> into races just because they're white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> is precisely analogous
to letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> with poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> and low grades into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> just
because they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX>.

            The catastrophic breakdown of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s paging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> and the panic it
has inspired draws both news and feature coverage all around. But leave it to a
brilliant unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorialist to notice that panic was exactly the
wrong way to go. The wise course, he (or she) says, would have been to spend
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at the ballpark. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, was, if we'd only noticed, "a snow day from outer space."

            Privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> uses his column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to state his
positions on some recent eavesdroppings in the news. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s taping of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was, he says, not okay, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">intern</ENAMEX> had a reasonable
expectation of privacy. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> tapes of Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> were okay because
he did not. Safire dismisses the exculpatory remarks by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> concerning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s innocence, etc. as what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> parlance calls "tickling the
wire"--producing self-serving statements because you know you are being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overheard</ENAMEX>. Surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> did not explain how this works by providing the
most famous example of the tactic: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s knowingly taped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>
statement that yes, he could raise money to silence the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> burglars,
"but it would be wrong."

         
      
   
