
   
   
      
         
            Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma</ENAMEX>-cy

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege protects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> from testifying to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand jury about l'affaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Also prominent at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> are
large front-page pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s dedication of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$818</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--an unlikely tribute, notes the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who championed limits on the federal bureaucracy.
Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> front-page
picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caption</ENAMEX> reads, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Of Honors and Overruns</ENAMEX>."

            The no-privilege decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Johnson</ENAMEX>--actually still under seal
and leaked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> involved in the case (who thereby continue
to flirt with sanction by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>)--is deemed a "stunning legal defeat"
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and rated a "major victory" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> by
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> add that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> also ruled against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s invocation of attorney-client privilege to
shield his top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, holding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could not use government-paid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to aid his defense in a criminal investigation. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> point out that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> bid to have some protections extended
to conversations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> was also turned down.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that the ruling dims the chances for the as-yet-unheard
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are also cloaked in a special
privilege.

            At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Olson</ENAMEX> expressing no surprise at
the decision, describing him as a "former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>" official. But this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characterization</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX> seem a little too detached from the matter at
hand, for in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX> is a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front notes the advent of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> available to airplane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assassins</ENAMEX>--a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> posing as a key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. It costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $20</NUMEX> and is
not detected by some metal detectors or airport X-ray machines. The paper
reports that one was seized by airport security in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, and that
others have been confiscated at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. Interpol
says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.32</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">caliber gun</ENAMEX> is readily available in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            The "
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> relations will be one of
the top foreign policy issues of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> hasn't
really decided what to do about it. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> points out, that's
understandable: on the one hand, although political moderation is on the
upswing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is still judged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> to be "the
most active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of state terrorism," but on the other, making nice would
enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian Sea</ENAMEX> oil fields, the world's most
significant untapped <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">petroleum</ENAMEX> and gas reserves.

            Correction: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" was mistaken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in saying that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> broke the story of a black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> being beaten by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skinheads</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. Actually, the story was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            A spat broke out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> between gun-nut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX> and yentl case
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N.R.A. (Streisand</ENAMEX> produced the just-aired tv-movie
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Island Railroad Massacre</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> didn't
like it.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> weighs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and is refreshingly un-coy about it.
Sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> still has fun quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mosaic</ENAMEX> self-description as a
passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>, "that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> stone of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">republic</ENAMEX>." But she also draws a clear, important conclusion: "On the question
of gun control, the mirror has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> face. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX> is right. It is
chillingly easy for crazies and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
