
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>"
interview. The other papers pretend there was something else on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s top story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s crackdown on
oil shipments to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> that violate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
even more transparent in its attempt to appear above pack journalism, goes
with--are you sitting down?--the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> could take over
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' slots of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX>. This is particularly odd in
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's own front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> story states that "even the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> say that if proved true, the accusations of perjury and
obstruction of justice in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter could end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
presidency."

            In her interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> gave a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">paw-by-</NUMEX>paw description of her encounter with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in a small study off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> and charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
lied about it. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>'s comment that she considered
slapping him but decided not to because "I don't think you can slap the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.." And everybody has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s comment that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is "absolutely bewildered" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
allegations, and that there is as yet unreleased information that will undercut
them.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> also said during the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> interview
that she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> about her encounter in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> said
Tripp, whose tape recording of conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> sparked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
investigation, later told her, 'I'm going to get you, and . . . everyone else
in this place before this is all over.'" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> deny that she ever
made such a statement.) This passage leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> wondering why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s
response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s report of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> incident would be anger towards
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>. But what's really going on is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has garbled the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX>" interview. In it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> was angry at her, not about
the alleged grope, but because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> job--which Tripp
attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> lost hers,.

            In its lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gets this right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also points out
that in some ways, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> could be a more troublesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> than
the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> alleging sexual harassment, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> was originally
unwilling to tell her story, her accusation is of a non-consensual act, and she
is hardly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the vast right-wing conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cited, having worked to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> elected.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Ireland</ENAMEX>, as saying, "It's
not just sexual harassment. If it's true, it's sexual assault." The WP
has this too, but in addition notes the significance of the remark: it's a
break with the generally complacent attitude most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> have maintained
toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandals. (Up till now their motto has been: "The devil
you know is better than...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>.") Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> decides to leave out
the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> quote, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> includes: "He put his hand
on her breast; he put her hand on his erection. That is a pretty serious charge
if true and it is a very big problem." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its front page story
also makes the point about the significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s remark, but cuts her
quote just where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> does. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes the other way a little
bit, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "fondled" her breasts and placed her
hand on his "crotch," even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> didn't use either of the words in
quotes.

            In a wise departure from standard newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
doesn't clean up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s quotes, so that its report communicates a good deal
of the emotion of the televised interview: "And then he, then he, then he
kissed me on, on my mouth and, and pulled me closer to him. And I remember
thinking, I just remember thinking, 'What in the world is he doing?' ... And I,
I pushed back away from him and--he, he, he, he, he's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. And he, he had
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, they were tight around me and he, he touched me....He touched my
breasts with his hand and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">I, I, I</ENAMEX>, I was, I, I was just startled."

            There is a dangling thread from the interview that none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> tugs
at: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> says that one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> she saw after she got away from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was then-Secretary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Bentsen</ENAMEX>. Why doesn't
some enterprising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> go ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bentsen</ENAMEX> what his impression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demeanor</ENAMEX> was?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> story says that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case deposition,
he "acknowledged embracing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> and perhaps kissing her on the forehead. He
said he has engaged in similar displays of affection with 'scores and scores of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have worked for me or been my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>.'" Maybe
it's time some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has kissed on the forehead came
forward to support their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
