
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suharto Say Goodbye</ENAMEX>

            The continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> turmoil leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and is the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s surprise announcement that he would step down failed
to ease political tensions, because he described a gradual and vague transition
to a successor, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> want him out now. "If
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> Suharto does not step down, there will be a lot of trouble," one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protester</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says it now seems likely Suharto
will go.

            The papers say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opposition leader</ENAMEX> had called for a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> to take to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>,
primarily via stern television messages, urged them not to. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Richburg</ENAMEX> says the scene at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have
taken over the grounds and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, is "eerily reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>." Mirroring earlier reporting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says relations between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> appear
friendly.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> is quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the WP
saying that because of the upheaval, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> will probably delay delivery of
its next bailout payment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> has already done this.

            The WP confuses with a front-page piece asking whether comparing
health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>' reimbursement handling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> to their handling of birth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> pills reveals a bias towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph of the story says
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> prescriptions are being subsidized by health
plans, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> paragraph says that slightly more than half of all birth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> pills are. Where's the bias? Why do we need this story?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's front reports on the first hard political consequences of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> money-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>-technology charges it aired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> he'll seek to set up a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> to look into the allegations. The story also
makes the USAT front, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is quoted saying, "This a deeper
question than anything that has arisen before in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gingrich</ENAMEX>
also tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should not embark on a planned trip
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> until he answers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            A shocking episode reported in a buried wire story in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> moves up to page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> while playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> near a hospital emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, a fifteen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">year-old boy</ENAMEX> was shot. Emergency room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> were notified of the
situation by a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, but citing hospital policy, they refused to
leave the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to come to his aid--<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty-five feet</NUMEX> away. And refused
to lend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> a gurney. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Ninety minutes</TIMEX> later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was dead. "I will be
finishing my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty-fourth year</TIMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>, "and I have
never seen anything like this."

            The editorials continue to weigh in on the lawsuits brought against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead editorial, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is Wrong," takes exception
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke/Pepsi</ENAMEX> analogy by saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s ambition to have Windows
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">play an integral</ENAMEX> role in virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lifestyle is more like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>
telling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from now</TIMEX> on it will be their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage</ENAMEX>, main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>." (It seems that the law of beverage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> is wondrously
complex--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" recalls not being able to bring its own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dodger Stadium</ENAMEX> and not being able to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX>.) In any case,
warns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> doesn't compromise, it could find itself
being broken up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> into "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby Bills</ENAMEX>."

            Remember that scene in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeper</ENAMEX>" where it's revealed that in the future
everybody knows the only really healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> are red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and cigarettes?
Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a story headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smoking May Protect Some High-Risk Women</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Breast Cancer</ENAMEX>." Seems that for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> that comprise
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> percent of all cases, what's lucky is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">a...Lucky</ENAMEX>.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> feature visits the mercenary mouths
behind political campaign commercials. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coterie</ENAMEX> of voice-over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>, it turns out, earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $500,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> narrating the commercials
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> candidates. New phone technology allows them to do this from
their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with assembly-line efficiency and relieves them of the onerous
chore of actually meeting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite announcers</ENAMEX>,
reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , once inadvertently worked for both sides of a
campaign.

         
      
   
