
   
   
      
         
            Softwar

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> antitrust lawsuits filed against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> states lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The suits are also flagged at the top of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box. They are
the off-lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> (and also covered in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s front-page
"cover story"), which leads instead with the news that in working out the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>
billion highway bill, congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> dropped the provision that
would have set a tough national drunk-driving standard.

            The papers all have the same basic lawsuit details: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> argue that after an abortive attempt at an "illegal conspiracy" deal
with browser rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> violated antitrust laws by using its
virtual lock with Windows to dominate the Internet browser market. Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has already begun shipping Windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">98</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> have asked a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to issue a quick preliminary injunction requiring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to either
take its own browser out of that program or also include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s browser.
And preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> from enforcing contracts with online service providers
that would restrict the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> from also offering their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">browsers</ENAMEX>. (An area, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> was apparently flexible about before
negotiations broke down over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>.) The state suit additionally asks for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to be forced to change the way it sells its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>" software to
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> so that they would be freer to license <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>'
software.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> saying that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> demands
for inclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> is like "requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> to include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cans of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> in every
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial says the analogy is bad because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>
isn't a monopoly.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> internal e-mails and memos as well
as interviews and depositions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, which, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says,
the government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> consider smoking-gun evidence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cites for
instance a memo that says it would "be very hard to increase browser share on
the merits" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s product, and hence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> should
"leverage Windows to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use" it. But none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> explain how
these internal documents came to be possessed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> nor wonder
about the propriety of that. Also, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> list
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> suing, there is no explanation anywhere about what point there is
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to file their own suit, or why the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">thirty states</ENAMEX> are
staying on the sidelines.

            Most of the coverage is steeped in the particulars of the memos, etc. The
LAT however, takes a somewhat broader view. It calls the
move against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, "one of the sharpest legal attacks on big business in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>," and accompanies its lead with an interesting graphic depicting
the relative market shares enjoyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history's other celebrated
anti-trust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Oil</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s is listed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>
percent, but the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> own a home personal
computer and fewer still surf the Internet, the suit could throw the computer
industry and the economy into turmoil.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">107</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were
indicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> on charges of laundering millions
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> drug cartels. The story is also on the WP front,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs it inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> is set to announce a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> designed help the
film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> counteract inroads on its business being made by computerized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photography</ENAMEX>: You bring your film into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> and the
snaps are returned digitally to your AOL account. The program will be called
"You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pictures</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Examiner</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Bronstein</ENAMEX> quotes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> thusly: "He's
big enough for me...for my intense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, my stature in the world."

         
      
   
