
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pre-NATO Care</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> passage and the likely
presidential veto of a bill saddling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> goal of paying up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> dues with
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> anti-abortion provision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s defeat of a proposal for limiting the cost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
of expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> dues bill includes a rider barring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid to international family
planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that perform or support abortions, which, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
"almost certainly dooms" the payback effort. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> note that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> say a
veto means there will be no further action on this. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the
WP remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> attached a similar poison pill
provision to the last attempt at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> pay-up, which was vetoed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The coverage plays into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s unfortunate preference for politics
over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>: there isn't a word about those international family planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> (none are even identified) and to what extent they facilitate
abortions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> discussion concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> continues to be lively, and that
the cost cap was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion amendments the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will consider before it's through. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s debate focused mainly on
whether or not the proposed new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>--can afford to field the level of armed forces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> requires. The
Times notes that expansion cost issues seem paramount to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.
This means many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> don't really trust the official estimates, because
officially, expansion will cost but <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> a year over the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter plane</ENAMEX> a year.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explains that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> are concerned that more and
more new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will be coming in, hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s strength. It occurs to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" though, that here may lie the true solution: Let any country
join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are required to promise not to attack each other, as the
number of non-member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> declines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s military needs would
diminish and hence so would its expenses.

            Economic factoids: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> fronts report that the
booming economy has delayed the insolvency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
additional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2032</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs this on the inside, but
reports on its front that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problem will cost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX>
and worldwide, the cost to business will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just days ago</TIMEX>, the new warm and fuzzy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> was on tour with a book
mostly about diet and exercise. Well, judging from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> second lead,
book sales must have slipped and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> is back on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">red meat</ENAMEX>. The paper quotes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> as
engaged in "the most systematic, deliberate obstruction of justice cover-up and
effort to avoid the truth we have ever seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history, and the time
has come to say to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, 'Quit undermining the law in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Turn over the evidence.'"

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX>, an LAT front-page spread made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> abuses a big story. The
paper stays on the case with a front-page account of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
that disclosed corruption among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was thought to have stolen
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> confiscated luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and another wrote an anonymous
threatening letter to a tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who had testified against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> at
congressional hearings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs the tax hearings inside. The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan Stevens</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, pleaded guilty to embezzling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13</NUMEX> taxpayer
payments totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $77,000</NUMEX> by altering payment checks made out to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>" so that they resembled his initials. The column also includes a modest
proposal for ushering in a simplified tax code: require all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to prepare their own returns without professional help.

            Why is demi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Checchi</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>? Because, he is quoted on the LAT op-ed page, "It's easier to
teach economics to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> than compassion to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" is more than a little mystified by the sudden journalistic
interest in the reality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> show. Pretty soon, the papers
will be breathlessly revealing that talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> conversations are scripted
and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> employs fake hair and real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>. Still, the idea
in a letter to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> med school prof
is a good one: just put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> set. Real fights would meet with
arrests and fake ones wouldn't and hence would be quickly unmasked. Either way,
says the doc, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> would evaporate.

         
      
   
