
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mississippi Learning</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s criticism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> of health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> for making it too difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who switch or lose their jobs
to get coverage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with oil prices hitting a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year</TIMEX>
low. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' proposed budget and its rejection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s domestic spending priorities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> thrift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Savings</ENAMEX> is being
bought by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Mutual</ENAMEX>, creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>-largest financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s off-lead is probably the
bigger story: The earthquake hazard facing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> may only be half
as great as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> had been saying, and it's very unlikely that the region
will ever experience that staple of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> small talk, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX> quake, aka
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big One</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Shalala</ENAMEX> to
look into strengthening a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> law aimed at helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> between jobs keep
their health coverage. The main problem, says the paper, is that the law
doesn't control how much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can charge for such gap coverage, so they
are tending to make it prohibitive.

            Following up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just over a week ago</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that oil prices have gone down into the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX> a barrel
neighborhood, a true boon to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. Adjusted for inflation, this is
the lowest price since the energy crisis in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. The reasons given are
the same ones offered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>: a mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> here and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, a slowdown in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> demand and the unwillingness by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s
biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>, to cut production. A bit further
below in the story is the reason for that: they are trying to gain market share
via low prices.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Budget Committee</ENAMEX> proposed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> fiscal blueprint that,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , rejects nearly all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s calls for
increased spending in such areas as education, child care and health care,
choosing instead to put the proceeds of any tobacco settlement into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>.
But on the other hand, the budget plan provides smaller tax cuts than were
sought by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, and supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s plan to
use budget surpluses to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says
the proposal is likely to be adopted more or less intact.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a piece inside reporting that it
turns out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beardstown Ladies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who
became media darlings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>, have been overstating the annualized
rate of return they're achieving. Turns out that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1983 and 1993</TIMEX> it was
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.1 percent</NUMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23.4 percent</NUMEX>, the figure on the cover of their best-selling
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guidebook</ENAMEX>. During the same period, the DJIA was up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.1 percent</NUMEX>.
Oops, math error, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies</ENAMEX>. (The audit was prompted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> stories in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> .) The oops is also on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front pages.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports on the court-ordered release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">124,000</NUMEX> pages of previously secret files from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that used spy
tactics, intimidation, false imprisonment, jury tampering and other illegal
methods to fight civil rights activities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The files are believed
to provide material for lawsuits against the state and also for the reopening
of long-dormant cases of crimes against civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, along the lines
of the long-delayed but finally successful prosecution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who murdered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medgar Evers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX> papers story is also carried inside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill-Bashing from Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> column
includes the following table of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>:
There's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sexual misconduct mouthpiece, which is
a distinguished position. It is distinguished from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>, his
personal-finance corruption mouthpiece; from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX>, his campaign-finance
corruption mouthpiece; from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Kennedy</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> general scandal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mouthpiece</ENAMEX>; from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>, his 'independent' general scandal mouthpiece;
and from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael McCurry</ENAMEX>, his don't ask, don't tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mouthpiece</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
