
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Break</ENAMEX>?

            The late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> movement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> crisis is everybody's lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> will arrive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, bringing with him an agreement that may avert a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reports the breakthrough came via a dramatic, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX>
bargaining session between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> will present the document he and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> already signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> time) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. Written details were not available at press time (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> aren't sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> could speak
frankly about it to anyone while he remained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> where phone lines are not
secure), but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> are reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> has agreed to open his
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>--the sticking point that has
brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to the brink of warfare. More than the other papers, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
emphasizes that much seems to remain unresolved for the moment--the number of
sites covered may actually be limited, it reports.

            According to the coverage, the newly brokered agreement lacks something the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> had previously insisted on--a time limit on inspections of the
presidential locations. And in return, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> agrees to provide diplomats
from various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> who would accompany the weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>. Even if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> approves the deal, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has
reserved the right to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> is
widely quoted as noncommittal. But, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is confident
that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, will accept the deal. One
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> passes along: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> may not have
insisted on the right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> to make repeat visits to the presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">palaces</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that the agreement apparently does not address the
issue of other presidential properties not on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>'s list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>. The
Times national edition reports that "some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> say" that in only a
matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> inspectors could run into access problems at other sites. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> metro edition is bolder: "The agreement
apparently does not address the issue of other presidential properties not
among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> listed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>." The USAT front
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> cover story">USAT front section cover story is plainer
still: "The problem is that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has also agreed to many
things on which he has not followed through."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes front-page with the news from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> chat show
appearances made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, that she
"absolutely" stands by her affidavit in which she denied having sex with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> sees this as big news. The other fronts
pass, perhaps because, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> has said almost as much
before.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> waited until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX>
opened fire to run its profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX>. Today, it does a little
better in running an interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Ricks</ENAMEX> profile of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
operation's top <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Zinni</ENAMEX>. It seems to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" that such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> should get at least as much advance press attention as second-tier
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> do. (How many column inches, for instance, did the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> spill on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>?) The piece has the good detail that when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Zinni</ENAMEX> headed up peacekeeping efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, he met regularly with local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonists</ENAMEX>, who he discovered, had inordinate influence on the largely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illiterate</ENAMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>. The piece's only real false-step: describing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX>' ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> as a "knuckle-dragging intellectual." Would the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ever call a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> that?

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece notes the trend towards Internet-aided prostitution operations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> doesn't know the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> policy regarding the giving of Web addresses in news stories, but
notes that in this one, the address for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX>-based sex service
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clearinghouse</ENAMEX> called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redlightnet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>" is not issued. But what's the point of
withholding this, since a Web search of that handle will quickly turn up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
