
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon II</ENAMEX>

            Additional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> atomic tests on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
lead all around. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> justified the economic
countermeasures--stopping all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign aid, government credit and most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bank loans and opposing all international bank loans--by citing the
"dangerous new instability" the blasts have created in the region. To head it
off, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> telephoned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> to urge him not to test nukes
too. The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> received no assurances. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> is preparing for an underground test as soon as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> stresses that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
explosions was just as much a surprise to the world as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> emphasizes the defiance of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round. The

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s reporting suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motivations</ENAMEX> are not crystal clear,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vajpayee</ENAMEX> quoted as saying that the tests
were scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX> and were not intended as a rebuff to international
criticism, while another stated, "The news of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> is: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> defies world
opinion." Officially, report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> consider abiding by some of the provisions of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX> and repeated its rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
demand that it sign the treaty.

            An inside story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence failure in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> matter, and editorials at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> decry it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial argues that besides our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spies</ENAMEX>, the policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fell down on the job too,
given that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> talked openly of its
interest in nuclear weapons. There is a real problem here, but the newspapers
aren't exempt. Yes, the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and the national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>
are too readily distracted by the current crisis, whatever it is, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> are also too crisis-oriented in their coverage. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least nine</NUMEX> articles on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , published on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eve</ENAMEX> of trouble, carried exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>.

            Characteristically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> include coverage of an
easily overlooked aspect of the world's tensest nuclear crisis since the end of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>--its impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madras</ENAMEX> stock
markets.

            A piece deep inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> brings news that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> missile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> has warned that the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ICBMs</ENAMEX> aboard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s older submarines
are wearing out so badly that their continued deployment threatens "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chernobyls</ENAMEX>." These comments come, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> on the heels of an
apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nuke</ENAMEX> sub emergency in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Barents Sea</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just over a week ago</TIMEX>.
Despite official reassurances, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub</ENAMEX> was brought back to its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> there
was widespread panic in the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says although <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 17% percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> say they regularly
watch television, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX> plan to watch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Herald</ENAMEX> ran the basic story line for the episode:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kramer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> a carjacking and are put on trial for
failing to report it. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't claim to know how things turn out.
Is it just "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" that wonders how it can be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> testimony
before just about any federal grand jury is on the front page in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and yet a sitcom plot remains a state secret?

         
      
   
