
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Special

            What's so special about special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision to ask that one be
appointed to investigate if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX>'s decision to
reject a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> application opposed by major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party contributors</ENAMEX> had
any connection to subsequent donations they made. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s unprecedented subpoenaing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> detail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> have uncovered evidence that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> had agreed to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
sophisticated equipment that could be used to develop biological weapons. This
disclosure, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , puts a new spin on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s recent diplomatic
efforts to modify the inspection procedures applying to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>: perhaps they are
designed, not to head off a war, but to keep such mass destruction fingerprints
from being lifted.

            Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> may look back at this as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the
Cabinet known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Prosecutions</ENAMEX> started on its way to becoming the
largest single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motto</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Purpose of</ENAMEX>
Government is to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investigate Government</ENAMEX>"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (in
its front-page piece) note this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> request for a special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> looking into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> adds
it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> appointed overall during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. The
Times goes on to observe that this is the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-era outside
inquiry into political fund-raising. (You'll recall <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> declined to go the
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> route over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> coffees and phone calls.)

            The papers all emphasize, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s request is "very narrow in
scope" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's words). And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says any subsequent
broadening of this mandate would be "unusual." Hmmm.perhaps someone should
check this with that key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in 1970s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> real estate deals, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s move on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> raises novel arguments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agents</ENAMEX> have
testified before (most famously about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> taping system), but never
about what they saw or heard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> do. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial points
out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and so shouldn't be any more
silent about illegal activities than say, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> state trooper. But on the
other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> argues that if a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> physically distances himself from his protective detail out of fears
for his confidentiality, security is compromised.

            More <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> news: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Lewis</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second day</TIMEX> of grand jury testimony ended
abruptly, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , when she became physically and emotionally
unable to continue. She's expected back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> will nestle into
that pre-warmed hot seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next week</TIMEX>.

            The USAT front carries word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> is considering requiring
local water systems to issue reports on the chemical contents of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. The story also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which reports
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> is considering requiring similar labeling on bottled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. This
is key: without the ability to know what's in tap water alternatives, knowing
what's in tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> isn't worth much.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece on
the post-affirmative action drive to do away with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> as a college admissions
tool reports that after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> passed a law that in effect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">replaced SAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> with high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> rank, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A & M University</ENAMEX>
found that some high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are reporting that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
are in the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the class.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out there was
something odd in the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> charge in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can't prove his sweeping assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has illegally
leaked grand jury testimony. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> could help
in this regard, since it has run stories apparently benefiting from leaked
information relating to grand jury testimony. But although the topic is
important enough for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial, don't look for any Times
news stories to really dig into such leaks, as they are the lifeblood of the
paper's scandal coverage.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are asked at this point to observe a moment of silence. After
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s nee-saying debacle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mme. Teller</ENAMEX>,
hung herself.

         
      
   
