
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>-up

            Everybody leads with the worsening violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> top fronts feature a dramatic picture of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> hauling away a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> reportedly shot by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX> goes with looters carrying their plunder by a blazing overturned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>, who had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, returned to the riot-riddled capital
and called out <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in an attempt to restore order and
maintain his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year</TIMEX> control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            With the riot toll now standing at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> dead (most shot, some trapped in
burning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> not to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are already in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>, with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 12,000</NUMEX> more in outlying areas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> both capture
the growing political nuance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-level situation with their
observations that some army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were greeted with applause by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rioters</ENAMEX>, and
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, unlike the cops, mingled with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>. The military might
just, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> make clear, tip the scales against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>.

            Despite some strong descriptions of events, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> could have done a
better job of explaining them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>, for instance, waits until the twelfth paragraph
of its fifteen paragraph story to inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> that the unrest was about
rising prices caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s introduction of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>-dictated austerity
measures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> holds that information until paragraph eighteen. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> delays until paragraph seventeen mention of rising unemployment and
economic-based resentment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Indonesians. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gets the
poverty and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Chinese</ENAMEX> angles, however lightly, into its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraphs</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have relied
heavily on e-mail and cell phones to organize their protests. And although the
phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> deny it, says the paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> believe their cell
calls are sometimes blocked to obstruct their planning.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a top-front exclusive: that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> fund-raiser
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX> has provided federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> with their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> solid link
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and questionable donations made to the DNC
during the last presidential campaign. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung</ENAMEX> now
says a large part of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $100,000</NUMEX> he gave to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>/army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> whose father
was at the time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s top military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. At the time, notes the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was
facilitating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> launch of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> communications satellites.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Kennedy</ENAMEX>, is quoted in the piece saying, "We had no
knowledge about the source of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung</ENAMEX>'s money..."

            Everybody's front runs the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> made a surprise
last-minute move to avoid antitrust lawsuits by agreeing to delay its release
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Windows 98</ENAMEX> while it enters settlement talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The talks
start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and the shipments are delayed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least Monday</TIMEX>. It's clear
that government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> feel they're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tells the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "We're not going to be locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to be shown baby
pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts report on the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> marking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s fiftieth anniversary.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> opened fire on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> moving towards <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the dead were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX> is prepared to
testify at her obstruction of justice trial about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s truthfulness
regarding Whitewater matters. The dispatch mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDougal</ENAMEX> arrived at
her plea appearance in a prison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jumpsuit</ENAMEX> and handcuffs. Television footage
shows that the cuffs were manacled to a belly chain as well. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>"
has never seen any reporting about why Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDougal</ENAMEX>, neither a violent offender
nor a documented flight risk, must be trussed about like this. Some paper
should find out: Is this really be an inflexible policy, or is it blatant
message-sending by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>?

Administration's stats for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> are in. Notable numbers: Drunken driving
deaths--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,520</NUMEX>--fell to their lowest level in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>. The total number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fatalities</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> fewer than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder</ENAMEX> how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have had a
number of deaths ending in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three zeros</NUMEX>.) And <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63 percent</NUMEX> of those killed in car
crashes were not wearing seat belts.

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> item in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that at her weekly news
conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> admitted she has become so confused over the computer
system in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that she has forsaken it for paper and pencil. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers" is astounded that not one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in attendance ventured to ask if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> had tried installing a different browser.

         
      
   
