
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorry State of Affairs</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with that schoolyard shooting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, which also makes
the front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
remarks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> about how, with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> wronged <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with the news that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has delayed issuing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of permanent residency permits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> because a new
machine designed to produce fraud-proof green cards hasn't worked right since
it was installed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, says the paper, will suffer dire
consequences but the delay is making many of them panicky.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, all female, died, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> others were injured
at an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 13 and 11</TIMEX>--shot at their
classmates pouring out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in response to the false fire alarm the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> had pulled. It was, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> rampage
nationwide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX>. In recent similar incidents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have killed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and wounded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>.

            Rising to give a speech at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kampala</ENAMEX>, after listening to one
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoweri Museveni</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , launched into what his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> later said were impromptu remarks about the role the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has played in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tragedies</ENAMEX>. "Going back to the time before we were even a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> received the fruits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said. "And we were
wrong in that." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also admitted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> policy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
too often resulted in mistakenly supporting ruthless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> just because
they were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-communists</ENAMEX>.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> point out that previously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had considered and
rejected the idea of making an official apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> for slavery.
It was reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mea culpa</ENAMEX> would distract from the real
tasks of racial healing and could alienate white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist voters</ENAMEX>. And indeed,
reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> repeatedly said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would not issue such an
apology while on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> tour. But, says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was apparently
taken by the "spirit of the moment." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , his
spur-of-the-moment thoughts caused "consternation among his traveling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX>."

            The papers note this vibe but inexplicably internalize it, and generally try
to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech as something besides what it most obviously is: an
apology for slavery. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees, "not strictly speaking an apology, but
a remarkably all-encompassing statement of contrition." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , in its
off-lead, says that with the remarks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "came as close as he ever has to
apologizing for slavery, and in its lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says he "stop[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ped</ENAMEX>]
short of an explicit apology." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager says he stopped "well
short" of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            Perhaps what underlies the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is that the episode
is a clear reminder that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is prone in the heat of the moment to do
things that in cooler moments he very publicly says he wouldn't do. Hoping not
to remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> about this was one of the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> were glad to get him
out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. And indeed, such concerns explicitly followed
him to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> touring the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asked if he was invoking executive privilege in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
matter. Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> responded, even though Museveni
called after them to make sure they heard the question.

            In light of the slavery speech, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" wonders how long it will be
before one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complains that he apologizes for things he
didn't do, instead of apologizing for things he did.

            There's a good-news story in the WP business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX>--let's
hope it's true. It seems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PepsiCo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger A. Enrico</ENAMEX>, has given
his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900,000</NUMEX> salary back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and directed that it be used to fund
scholarships for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>'s grunt-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Enrico</ENAMEX>
intends to do this indefinitely. True, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrico</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> bonus, which he is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surrendering</ENAMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 million</NUMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> says the bonus will not be
enlarged to pick up the slack. The arrangement nearly doubles the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
scholarship outlays.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source"</ENAMEX> column reports that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> were ordered to turn over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> sales records of purchases by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> is quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> with this reaction: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
have now gone from invasion of the right of privacy to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Fahrenheit</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">451</NUMEX> ."

            And on tour with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, Jesse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> his theology of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal: "There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commandments</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
