
   
   
      
         
            Bad Tripp

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech is everybody's lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
desire to use any budget surpluses to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save Social Security First</ENAMEX>" generally
leads the lists of the speech's proposals, which included calls to raise the
minimum wage, expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and child-care subsidies, as well as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 billion</NUMEX>
to recruit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, a "patient bill of rights" for managed-care
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also used the occasion to warn
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today says "threaten") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is determined to
deny him the ability to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction again.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOTU</ENAMEX> an "activist agenda" that is
the "most expensive and comprehensive" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has put forward since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> captured control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
observes that this sweeping program comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declared the
end of the era of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but goes on to note <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alternative
description: "We have a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but a stronger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>." The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> SOTU piece provides a useful
clarification here: "While federal spending has declined as a share of the
total economy, the drop has come mostly in defense spending. Meanwhile, social
spending has grown relative to the gross domestic product, particularly for the
entitlement programs....."

            Noting the scandal context, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times calls <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> "awkward and electrifying," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
declares, "Few other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>--or any other--could have
pulled off a performance like that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>." (The paper
also passes along word that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> was nominated for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>. Hmmmm..that might be what it takes.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a separate front-page piece about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> situation that notes the increasing tempo of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> strike planning. The piece also reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hopes to
get support from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudia Arabia</ENAMEX> for any action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, in the form of
permission to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s air <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>.

            There's a lot of front-page coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks yesterday
on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>" show, in which she described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> as a "politically
motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>" who is part of "a vast right-wing conspiracy." Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dailies</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> dismissed her comments as "nonsense." And USAT
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauch Faircloth</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, responded by calling Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a ""frustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.lashing out without foundation."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page piece reporting on the appearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> are interested in a series of
visits--approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX> made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> when the former
intern no longer worked there. They are also, says the paper, trying to
determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> tried to make contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> on the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was first interrogated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> are moving closer
to some sort of deal under which she would testify about whether she had a
sexual relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as well as--and this would be a big chip
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>--whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> urged her to deny this Date of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> prior to secretly taping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> tried to sell a book about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>,
asking the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Regnery</ENAMEX> for something in the
neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX>. The working title of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-page proposal was, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind Closed Doors: What I Saw Inside the Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> chapter was titled, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>."

            Looking for a college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> that actually doesn't have enough
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correctness</ENAMEX>? Check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Florida</ENAMEX>. There, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lombardi</ENAMEX> got to keep his job
after he described his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Herbert</ENAMEX>, who is black, as an
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oreo</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Legislators</ENAMEX> and powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lombardi</ENAMEX>'s defense.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> predictions: At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time feared to be old hat, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Primary Colors"</ENAMEX> should
now do big box office. And the
round-the-clock-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>-than-
is-compatible-with-healthy-digestion coverage of the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> trial
should reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> proportions.

            If you thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, now back in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "crisis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cabinet</ENAMEX>," was going to make things smoother at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, you don't know
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> quotes the recovering toe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX>'s explanation for why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> might have a wandering eye: ".Let's assume, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.K.</ENAMEX>, that his sexual
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is not all it's supposed to be, let's assume that
some of the allegations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>--sometimes not necessarily being into
regular sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--might be true."

         
      
   
