
   
   
      
         
            Televisionaries

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s grounding of the oldest 737
passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>. The national edition of the New York
Times leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> decision to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> to reply to its proposal that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> undertake a more substantial
withdrawal from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>. But the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> metro edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
leads with news of an imminent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 billion</NUMEX> phone company merger. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>'s overwhelming endorsement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace
deal.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">737</NUMEX> inspections ordered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> alone
led with on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>) were apparently well warranted: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 26</TIMEX> fuel
main fuel pump wires checked showed wear on their insulation, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is a little more reader-friendly about the actual
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> involved: it says every one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> checked
show some insulation chafing (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its front-page story, says instead that this was
true of a majority of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> looked at), and that the grounding
order affects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">179</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">193</NUMEX> others worldwide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">helpfully</ENAMEX> explains that the order only affects <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 16 years old</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one 737</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60,000</NUMEX> flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hours</TIMEX> showed clear signs of
sparking in one location inside its main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> and bare wire in another. This is
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> because electrical sparking inside a fuel tank is now suspected of
having brought down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800. (The story is also front-page at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC Communications</ENAMEX> (formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern Bell</ENAMEX>), the West's dominant local
phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , set to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ameritech</ENAMEX>, its counterpart in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, thus becoming
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest local phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and recreating much of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
phone system. The paper reminds those scoring at home that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 billion</NUMEX>
merger is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest in corporate history, trailing only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion Citicorp/Travelers Group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. (And if you are meticulously updating
your copy of this list, odds are you are not scoring at home.) The lengthy
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> account points out that unlike many of
the recent mergers, which have at least attempted a merger of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> as well,
in this deal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ameritech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> are bailing out (with golden parachutes of
course). The story also makes the USAT front.

            The deep thoughts of television's top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> as they existentially
struggle with life after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> are on display in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page
effort by its TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bigfoot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Carter</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the mental
life of the tube <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> is very complicated, struggling as they do with such
conundrums as the erosion of network share of the total viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, age
demographic nuances, and the thinning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and writing pools. Thank
God for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Iger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, who has worked out what will surely soon
be known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Unified Field Theory</ENAMEX>: "We'd do ourselves a world of good if we
took out the bottom <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of our schedule, which is not only performing in
mediocre fashion but which is often mediocre in quality, and replaced it with a
higher quality program."

            
               Poor word choice or obituary humor ? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> carried the
obit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul G. Hearne</ENAMEX>, wheel-chair-bound his whole life but a tireless
advocate for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> who, among other accomplishments, helped write the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">With Disabilities Act</ENAMEX>. The write-up described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hearne</ENAMEX> as a
"wheeler-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> recently reported that a civilian security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> on duty near
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> accidentally shot and killed a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. A little story, yes,
but leave it to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to see the larger point. Why, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fenton</ENAMEX> asks, in a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> today, does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> of all places
have to contract out for protective services?

         
      
   
