
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anti-Abortion Racket</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s finding in a
lawsuit brought by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NOW</TIMEX> that anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> violated federal racketeering
laws by conspiring to close <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abortion clinics</ENAMEX> through violence, and hence could
be subject to damage claims. The national edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> that's currently relocating nuclear
material from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> to keep it out of the hands of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> or aspiring nuclear powers. The top national story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s decision to hear a case involving
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> ordinance targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang members</ENAMEX> for gathering on city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. (The
story also makes the front at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and is inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> found in effect to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">racketeers</ENAMEX> are
active in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Rescue</ENAMEX> and/or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pro-Life Action League</ENAMEX>. They were fined
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a quarter million</NUMEX> dollars. Throughout the trial, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> claimed that any curbs on the anti-abortion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> would violate their free speech rights. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> carries
this rejoinder from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> has never been found to
protect extortion: someone saying they'll break your windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> or
someone stationing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> outside your business." The story also makes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front, but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> (experts
disagree about whether it's enough to make a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, says the paper) were
originally supposed to be moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, but after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> failed to
follow through, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, concerned about the instability of the region,
typified by the recent assassination attempt on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eduard</ENAMEX>
Shevardnadse, made other plans while keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> informed.

            The LAT front brings word that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>, after staying on the sidelines
while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> still had a case headed for trial, is currently considering
providing support for her appeal of its recent dismissal. Hmmm...maybe they
should be called <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">LATER</TIMEX>....

            The front pages at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that it will not do an
about-face on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine-year-old</TIMEX> policy against funding needle-exchange programs
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, even while acknowledging that such programs reduce the spread
of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> without encouraging drug abuse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has the most detail on
the inside politics of the decision, reporting not only that the
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drug czar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCaffrey</ENAMEX>, is vehemently opposed to lifting the
ban ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has this too), but also that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s policy advisors
were afraid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> might push through legislation taking federal money
away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> providing free needles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Shalala</ENAMEX> said that the decision was made because research shows
that the best programs are designed locally. So why not design them locally and
fund them federally?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor is flourishing
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, because when the economy is strong, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> can't find enough
adult cheap labor. It is estimated, says the paper, that there are more than
300,000 underage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> working illegally in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> on
commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page features a rather moving story about a
black high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> who has her heart
set on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, but whose good-but-not-great credentials
mean a turn-down in the new-post-affirmative action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> there. The story
shows a not-altogether well-thought out applications process: for example, she
decided not to pursue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryn Mawr</ENAMEX> merely because she learned some other black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> were also urged to apply by a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX>, and was interested in another much lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because she
mistakenly thought it was free. And in the course of the story she learns that
her mother voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 209</ENAMEX>.

            There's been a lot of reason lately to question the overall economic
wonderfulness of high national savings rates, but the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USA Snaphot</ENAMEX>" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> is pretty disturbing nevertheless: it says that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> of
working-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX> of working-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>' worth of income or less in savings.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> contained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> anniversary
column, which confirms just how little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WS</ENAMEX> learned from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> says
that on his way out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> he thought about going in to say
goodbye to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, but opted not to. And a good thing, he writes, because "at
that moment a faithless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> was in there talking about a cancer on the
Presidency" and "had I gone in, I would have been taped and perhaps later
charged with being part of a cover-up." In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> still sees <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>, so much so that he can't bring himself to type his name in
this story, and he still seems to think that a lot of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got
caught up in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
