
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America Discovers Columbus</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
all lead with the raucous reception the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> foreign policy figures were
surprised to receive when they appeared at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>-hall-style discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , which runs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> as its off-lead, goes with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> included
testimony about past telephone conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>. The questioning
apparently set off a special conference with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> about whether or not aides
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> are protected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has not invoked it.

            The in-studio <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 6,000</NUMEX> served up what the LAT
calls a "raucous, emotional debate that showed a nation far from convinced of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>." Or as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts it,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen, Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Berger</ENAMEX> came
for a seminar, but "ran into a rumble." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that during
commercial breaks, while the startled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonites</ENAMEX> held whispered conferences,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> fanned out into the noisy parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> to calm those (numbering
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200</NUMEX>, guesses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ) chanting "We don't want your racist war."
Some of the most aggressive hecklers were carried outside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> serves up an acute description of what transpired: the
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reps</ENAMEX> found themselves caught between opposing passions (about
being <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, about not being tough enough) armed only with a
largely passionless argument. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes a simple example of the
predicament: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> waved about a photo of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
chemical warfare while arguing against deposing or killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>.

            The juxtaposition on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> top-front is striking: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top Aides</ENAMEX>
shouted down at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">'Town Meeting</ENAMEX>' on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>" cheek-by-jowl with "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> are
Pumped," over a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> massing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>.

            The pieces make it clear that the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in the auditorium were
highly attuned to an issue that has gotten hardly any attention in the press:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consistency</ENAMEX>. In other words, why should we punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> and support and
reward say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, which has been slaughtering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>?

            But the coverage barely notices that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> protest suggests something
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">squishy</ENAMEX> or downright wrong in all those polls showing extensive public support
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stance. (And probably puts the kibosh on that planned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town hall</ENAMEX> meeting on presidential dating.)

            The WP front reports that a rising number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women poor</ENAMEX> enough to be
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> would like to be sterilized, but because of their own paperwork
errors and stiff bureaucratic requirements, they aren't and keep having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
An additional factor is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who deliver these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> are scared of
being sued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> still in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-bearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> rules
prohibit the sterilization of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 21</TIMEX> no matter how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> she
has.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes a media consequence of l'affaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>: a rebound for
conservatively oriented talk radio. This doesn't just mean, notes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , better numbers for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-man, but also things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
look-alike contests and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million</NUMEX> dollar prizes to any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who can prove she slept with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that most of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> attacked the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News and World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> rankings (due out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to rebut
the listings and sent out a letter debunking them to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93,000</NUMEX> current law-school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of affirmative action often observe that it doesn't exist in
performance-based <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">arenas</ENAMEX> like show business. But a small item in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's TV column makes you wonder
even about that: It seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> has ordered up a full season of episodes for
the virtually all-black "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moesha</ENAMEX>," which as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports,
ranked <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">124th</NUMEX> among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">139 series</ENAMEX> on the air.

         
      
   
