
   
   
      
         
            Roll, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, Roll

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s politically-loaded cancellation of a trip
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> call by several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> to abandon his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> inquiry. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big test for the balanced budget--the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>-lined
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX> bill. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with another in its series
of important stories on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. County Sheriff's Department</ENAMEX>--this time it's
news of a major bribery scheme involving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> contracts for the county
jail.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> was, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to meet with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and "bask in praise for ending the threat of war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>."
But, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> told the paper, he postponed his trip after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> harshly criticized the deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> brokered with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, said
he didn't have time to meet with him. (Idea for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>: report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s
schedule for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. It would be interesting to see how many fundraisers and
meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> he manages to fit in.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead notes that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> yap shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> Rahm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmanuel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Leahy</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to wind up Whitewater, and that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> also expressed guarded criticism of him. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Emmanuel</ENAMEX>
stopped short of saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> should resign, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leahy</ENAMEX> said, "Sure he should,"
adding that he is "totally out of control." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weekend Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> each questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
calling in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> to question him in front of a grand jury about his
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX>. The idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has blown it is explored in a large piece
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and was also the subject of an LAT front-pager
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that the transportation bill before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is such
a big challenge to the balanced budget because it provides goodies to every
congressional district in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The piece points out that among those
who want to make sure the bill doesn't eat into any budget surplus is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also notes that the bill raises several partisan
side issues that could lead to a confrontation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, namely,
proposals to delay new clean air regulations, scale back affirmative action
hiring on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway projects</ENAMEX>, and lower wage levels for transportation project
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front page tells the story of how <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> announced its intent to create a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> system for
allowing commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to use military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Positioning</ENAMEX> satellites for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">navigation</ENAMEX>, the system is nowhere near in place. In fact, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> might end up costing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14 billion</NUMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> would
have to keep paying for the current, conventional system until every airline
had switched over. Meanwhile, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">225</NUMEX> near-misses over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also reports on the trend of professional sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> education programs in an attempt to keep their new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> out of trouble. The programs typically cover how to handle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gamblers</ENAMEX>, groupies and...<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad forks</ENAMEX>. The most elaborate example, run by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX>, even includes role-playing bimbos, and is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euphemistically</ENAMEX> called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Career Development Program</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead reports that, rumors to the contrary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>,
who is scheduled to appear before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand jury on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, has not
requested immunity from prosecution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> also told the paper there
is no rift between his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            "Military rock and roll is to rock and roll as..." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George T. Babbitt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Materiel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Command</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wright-Patterson Air Force Base</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, recently jammed
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ventures</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> he helped form in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
