
   
   
      
         
            Too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Relations</ENAMEX>

            Killer tornadoes hitting the Southeast lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The incredible expanding budget surplus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s decision to try
countering his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s sliding economy by offering tax cuts.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Bragg</ENAMEX>, whose forte is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> atmosphere, on the tornado case. He paints quite a picture of the death (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>) and
destruction. "A ragged line of storms ripped through one little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> after
another in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, burying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> in rubble, even sucking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of their damaged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX> and leaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> dead in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bragg</ENAMEX> notes that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather Service</ENAMEX> gave the twister the most powerful rating on its
storm scale, but all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> knew was that it "was off the scale of their
experience."

            The tornadoes are also top front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> all feature stunning top-front pictures of the
devastation. Oddly though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> puts the story itself deep
inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead drives home the point that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who for all those
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> did such a below-average job of estimating budget deficits also stink at
estimating budget surpluses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> now
says the surplus will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $50 billion</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fiscal year</TIMEX>, up from
recent official estimates of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.M. Hashimoto</ENAMEX> has bowed to a "torrent
of pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, and elite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>" and swapped his trademark fiscal austerity policies for an
economic stimulus package featuring lush tax cuts designed to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to do some spending. The tax cuts are also on the front pages at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> explains, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s increasingly high
savings rate has only exacerbated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis, by drying up a big
export market for the floundering neighboring economies. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
adds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has been advocating some sort of domestic stimulus because
of the risk that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> might try to save itself instead by not only reducing
imports but also by dramatically increasing its exports.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" is somewhat surprised that none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX> reporting
mentions the situation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> when the incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration was likewise attempting to address a sluggish economy. Within
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, there were strong deficit-cutting and economic stimulus
factions. But the deficit cutters got the upper hand and it is now widely
believed that their course of action has been the key to the current good times
here. Isn't this relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> coverage?

            A big LAT front-page piece reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has been secretly
planning a massive media campaign that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, was designed
to influence state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> contemplating further anti-trust action by
"creating the appearance of a groundswell of public support" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
The plan included "the planting of articles, letters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and opinion
pieces" to be commissioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> but presented as spontaneous local
offerings about "how wonderful it is to do business with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>." When the
paper first asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Shaw</ENAMEX> about this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> said
he was unaware of such a plan. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>'s name is on some of the confidential
company documents in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's possession and he later acknowledged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> plan but said it was "merely a proposal." The ad campaign per se does not
trouble "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," but the idea of planting stories disguised as
independent efforts does. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>" hopes that the independent stance of the
previous sentence is not thought by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to in fact be part of a coordinated
company effort to simulate independence (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GREG</ENAMEX>--Was this what you wanted
here?).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Legal Beat"</ENAMEX> column reports that for
main legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, has intervened in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> criminal case and ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to
stay the execution of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Paraguayan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> convicted of murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. The
issue here, one that occurs not infrequently in the case of foreign national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal suspects</ENAMEX>, is that the cops forgot to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> about his right to
talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguayan</ENAMEX> consulate.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page features a satirical piece by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Lampoon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> on the trend of luxury compensation packages being used to lure tenured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty stars</ENAMEX> from one elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> to another. But the piece is anchored
in fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> recently successfully enticed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> econ prof with a
package that included a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> salary, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55,000</NUMEX>-a-year job for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
help getting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> admission to a tony prep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
