
   
   
      
         
            Galluping Off to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with new poll results indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are even
more hawkish about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
go with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> maneuvers to limit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s ability to
independently negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> push for tighter regulation
of managed care.

            In the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT /CNN/Gallup Poll</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> approve
of air strikes, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> go beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> and also
support the use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. And by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, those
surveyed support the idea of removing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> from power over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s goal of merely substantially reducing his ability to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX> destruction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front seems to find a more conflicted public:
"While most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should take action against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, there is plenty of doubt, and almost universal exasperation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX> might once again be placed in harm's way." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> does find
that support for removing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> falls significantly when questions assumed
substantial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>, or damage to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads all report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
was instrumental in keeping the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security</ENAMEX>
Council from endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s goal of going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> to independently
negotiate a settlement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> position is to accept nothing less than total
weapons inspection access.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts continue the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dailies</ENAMEX>' rather unprecedented disclosure of the current thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says that even with a new wavelet of improved
weapons, the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> doubts that the air attacks they're planning can
destroy all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s most terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> or even change <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s behavior.
Among the grounds for doubt ticked off by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> targeters
aren't really sure where the special weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> are, and don't know what to
do about "dual use" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that are also used to produce
biological weapons. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports, based on several unnamed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">well-placed Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, that unlike in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, the preponderance of
planned strikes are now targeted against so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>: not so much air defense <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">depots</ENAMEX>, as,
for example, secret police <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the administration
doesn't want to advertise this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead about managed care reform covers ground
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> staked out by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX>. The reason it's back in
the news is that legislation drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that requires federal
standards for health insurance plans and an appeals process to enforce them
will be taken up when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> returns from recess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. The managed care
industry and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> will fight this vehemently, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says.

            Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s public pledge to cooperate fully with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s
investigation, the LAT front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has been using
"one of the best tools available" for frustrating a criminal
investigation--namely, entering into joint defense agreements with others being
investigated in the case. Such agreements, says the paper, have allowed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to learn what questions are being posed and what
answers given during grand jury sessions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> suggests that both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">steward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayani Nelvis</ENAMEX> have
entered into such agreements with BC. Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> tell the LAT
that they expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to challenge these agreements.

            All too often the contemporary newspaper correction resembles one of those
joke business cards that say, "See other side" on both sides. Witness <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s correction in the WP : "In an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert M. Gates</ENAMEX> said that during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1991 Persian Gulf War</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were "hoping" that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> would be
killed in a bombing raid. The headline on the story incorrectly characterized
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s death." <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> that this doesn't include
either the original headline or an explanation of the way in which it was
incorrect in its characterization. It's only when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> digs out the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> article that he learns the headline referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s death as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
War "goal." By hiding the ball this way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> misses the chance to
explore the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> sophistry at work here. Ordinarily, if you
hope for something and do things that ordinarily could be expected to bring it
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>, then it would count as one of your goals. But because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government operates under a presidential executive order forbidding the
assassination of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> who want to eliminate
a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> have to perfect the mental trick of hoping for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">e.g.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s
death as they plan to e.g. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where they know he sleeps, but at
the same time being genuinely surprised if he were to die as a result.

         
      
   
