
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potted Pol</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a new study indicating that
false positive mammogram results are quite common. This is also the top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> (and is featured on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX> and carried inside at the New York
Times ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes with word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> has
declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> ineligible for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> aid because they may have provided missile
technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> has decided to pull
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX> (formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>) because of the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s harassment and obstruction of their work.

            According to the study of the medical records of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> of its kind ever attempted, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
undergo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> breast checkups for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> can expect to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> false mammogram indication of a tumor. That's if some
of the checkups are physical checks only--if all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> are mammograms, the odds
go <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 50 percent</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hence USAT</ENAMEX> 's alarmist-seeming, but dead-accurate
headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">False</ENAMEX>-positive rate for mammography <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-50</NUMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
calculate that ultimately unnecessary follow-up tests add <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> to the
cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> screening. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> say
that the threat of malpractice suits in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> contributes to the problem, in
that it pressures radiologists to overdiagnose <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>.

            By the way, the study appears in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Journal</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine</ENAMEX> , a fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leaves until the last sentence of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> version of the story. The WP waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">13th</NUMEX> paragraph.
What's that all about? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> put the provenance
high.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead is based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> list, obtained by the
paper, of banned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> to intelligence
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Since it was issued, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have actually
denied funding to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> projects because their proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> were on the list. The move marks the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time specific <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> have been penalized for suspected missile aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a cable-funded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> study of television violence
billed as the largest ever concludes that "glamorized" violence--where physical
and mental consequences are not depicted, the kind considered most harmful to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>--remains rampant, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry</ENAMEX> promises to address the problem. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX> reacted by commenting that
"the study definitively confirms that TV portrays violence in a way that
increases the risk of learning aggressive attitudes."

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> give front-page above-the-fold play to
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> major study of the Internet's economic impact,
released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX>. The information is stunning: Net
traffic is doubling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every hundred days</TIMEX>. E-commerce should reach <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. The digital economy is growing at twice the rate of the overall economy
and now represents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> of GDP. While it took radio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> to reach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and TV took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, the Internet did it in just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>. (At this
rate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> might just break even while there are still papers for
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" to be about.) Both papers mention that Net technology has
served as a brake on inflation, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is clearer about why--the
paper relates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> has saved <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $200 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> by
linking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on an internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and will shave <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> off its
paper costs via making personnel policies and payroll forms available online.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> notes another Net business
trend: Internet stockholder voting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> that allow it include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Richfield</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>.

            The late metro edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is able to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with some
confidence what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> national edition was only able to treat as
a rumor: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> Says." But not everybody is convinced--the
paper quotes a Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>'s reference to the recently announced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
intention to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX> to international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>: "This is certainly a
convenient moment for him to have a heart attack."

         
      
   
