
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Organ Policy</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> proposal for new rules
governing transplant organ availability. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to negotiate a
global settlement with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> by setting up a compensation fund. The
plan does not include the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, whose central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> received the
vast majority of wealth stolen by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and other persecuted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with depressing news about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s second-tier
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college system</ENAMEX>: an overwhelming number of its incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> lack the
basic math and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> skills they should have acquired in high school. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead headline is a hardy perennial,
relating to one of the worst public education systems in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Resigns</ENAMEX>."

            The new transplant rules, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead (and front-page
pieces in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ), aim at providing organs to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sickest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> first regardless of where they live, as opposed to the
current ones, which were conceived when organs couldn't be maintained outside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> for nearly as long as they can now, and hence emphasize getting them
to the closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The private network that coordinates most organ
distribution opposes the shift, because of a fear that this change will atrophy
local transplant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> by diverting organs to a handful of large regional
ones, and also deny organs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't travel. The papers all point out
that under the status quo, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> die <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> while waiting
for needed organs.

            The LAT front reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two days</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">NCAA Final Four</ENAMEX>
tournament game, a federal grand jury in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> has indicted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on charges of
attempting to fix the outcome of games for the benefit of bettors during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994-1995</TIMEX> college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>. This is a "stinging blow" to the sport, says the
paper, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern</ENAMEX> has the reputation of placing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> above
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">athletics</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs the indictments story inside, adding that a
nationwide survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball and football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> showed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
percent said they had gambled on a game they had played in.

            The papers note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>
alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>, but none could be bothered to put their stories about
the appearance--simply unthinkable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as four or five years ago</TIMEX>--on
the front page. All the visit gets is front-page pictures with "reefer"
captions pointing to stories inside. This judgment is especially hard to
understand given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> charges that some spots in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s traveling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> were in effect sold to mega <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> coffers,
making the trip a sort of flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>. By the way, over a
non-descript editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> serves up the perfect headline for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s apology-strewn safari: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guilt Trip</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Front-page</ENAMEX> pieces in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> report that one of the
Jonesboro shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> is asking for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastor</ENAMEX> and the other is crying
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. And an inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece addresses the question raised
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> about what the rules are nowadays governing identifying juveniles in the
paper. Almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> questioned says the crucial fact pushing
disclosure was that the names were already out there, in the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and on
the Internet. This is another example, like the tabloidization of the
mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, where the dwarfs have ended up controlling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> is demanding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> allow its licensees and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to speak with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> despite nondisclosure rules in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>
contracts. Backing the demand is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leahy</ENAMEX>, up to now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MS supporter</ENAMEX>.

            The national conversation on sexual harassment gets curiouser and curiouser.
Now comes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Rosenthal</ENAMEX>, who responds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> op-ed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from earlier in the week</TIMEX> with one of his own. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> had argued that if an
uninvited sexual gesture by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is met with noncompliance by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and then
is not followed up by him, no sexual harassment has occurred. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rosenthal</ENAMEX>
counters with a family secret. Many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, his older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> was walking in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> exposed himself to her. She screamed and ran home, where
she came down with a cold and then <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX> and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days later</TIMEX>, died.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX>'s counter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> is that mere uninvited sexual gestures can
be...fatal. This is a sad, sad story, but legally and morally irrelevant. To
think otherwise is to opt for making coming up behind someone and saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boo</ENAMEX>"
a crime, because yes, it just might possibly scare him to death.

         
      
   
