
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electoral Collage</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s request that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> bypass the ordinary appeals court process and directly decide on
an emergency basis whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> can be compelled to testify in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
investigation. Primary election results lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the metro edition of the New York
Times . The national edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the early edition of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX> to pay a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX>
million settlement for its role in the bankruptcy of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, but later LAT editions focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s primary
results.

            Much of the primary coverage centers on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ballot initiatives:
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> calling for an end to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s bilingual education program passed
(despite the opposition of all the major gubernatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> individually
approve political uses of their dues will probably be defeated, albeit in a
fairly close vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the success of the anti-bilingualism
measure will pave the way for similar "assaults" on other such programs around
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. (An interesting word-choice, illustrative of how in even the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">edited</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, editorial tendencies can creep into a news
story. Would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> describe an attempt to get more money for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unskilled laborers</ENAMEX> as an "assault" on the minimum wage?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts all report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> dismissed her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> medical malpractice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, and replaced him with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> criminal defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, one of whom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Stein</ENAMEX>, is a former independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> immediately sought to
improve their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> by paying a courtesy call
to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> stress another post-Ginsburgian difference: standing
mute with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> before the assembled media.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes into the most detail on the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s legal
connections in town, its dispatch chockablock with law firm names. Everybody
looks down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who pay to advertise in the back of the paper. The goal,
apparently, is to be the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> paid to be advertised in the front of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> interrupts its legal coverage to note that both of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are "well
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tailored</ENAMEX>," with one "favoring customized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-cuff shirts" and the other
stepping out "in a chalk-stripe suit and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator shoes</ENAMEX>." Do most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> know
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator shoes</ENAMEX> are? "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" can only guess they are shoes so
expensive that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> can only look at them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> window, or on
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            That inquiry into the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence to anticipate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
nuclear tests, first tipped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , has materialized on the front at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The findings by
retired admiral <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Jeremiah</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>: the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> so
ignored the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s statements on nuclear policy that only one
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> was assigned to examine satellite photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s test site.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section brings word that the chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FMC</ENAMEX> is
in serious talks with the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shoshone</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bannock Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reps</ENAMEX>
to settle a lawsuit alleging that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FMC</ENAMEX>'s fifty-year-old shale extraction
operation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>'s southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> reservation has left a significant
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX> and other respiratory illnesses.
The case, says the paper, could result in the largest fine in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> history.

            A WSJ front-page feature reports on a virtually unnoticed obstacle to the flourishing of free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">NAFTA</ENAMEX>: There aren't enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, rails and docks to handle all
the additional movement of goods the treaty sanctions. As a result, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of
dollars of goods customarily sit for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> borders involved, a
particular disaster in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s just-in-time inventory economy. Even though the
just-passed highway bill takes a crack at the problem, the real trouble, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , is that any border infrastructure changes face a complex
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX> approval process that for instance, has meant <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one seven-mile</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">road/bridge</ENAMEX> project between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> has generated a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fourteen-foot</NUMEX>
pile of documents.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> gave a speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>. Plunging self-made into all that self-importance didn't seem to faze him.
"All truths begin as hearsay," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> said at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point. "Some of the best news
stories start as gossip. At what point does it become news? This is the
undefinable thing." When a questioner wondered how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> would fare at a news
outlet that requires <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> accuracy, he replied: "I don't know what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> that would be."

         
      
   
