



<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 6</ENAMEX>
Emergence and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story:</ENAMEX>
Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bohr</ENAMEX>?
How brazen a chapter subtitle: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúBeyond Newton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohr</ENAMEX>?‚Äù Yet hints we shall find, for the science of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bohr</ENAMEX> remains innocent of the propagating coconstructing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, of nonequilibrium systems building a biosphere. Yet surely the biosphere is part of the universe and any general laws of the universe must necessarily encompass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bio-spheres</ENAMEX> here, and if a general biology is necessary, elsewhere in the vastness we glimpse.
And ‚Äúemergence and story‚Äù? What manner of foolishness is this? Story? Surely story is not the stuV of science. I‚Äôm not so sure. Story is the natural way we autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> talk about our raw getting on with it, mucking through, making a living. If story is not the stuV of science yet is about how we get on with making our ever-changing livings, then science, not story, must change. Our making our ever-changing livings is part of the unfolding of the physical universe.
Would you rather be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>? I‚Äôm not sure whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> is the more awesome. I come, hesitantly, to believe we need both science and story to make sense of a universe in which we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, part of the universe, get on with our embodied know-how, we who strut and fret our hour upon the stage. Then are heard no more? Hardly. Our successes and failures trickle, tumble, and torrentially build the future of our biosphere. We <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, fearful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sputnik</ENAMEX>, land <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and mass on the moon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parting</ENAMEX>, we leave mass on the moon and thereby change the orbital dynamics of the solar system and beyond. Calculate that, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>, genius that you were. From what initial and boundary conditions would you, could you, start?
But again, we have not had, nor have we yet, a theory of the propagating coconstructing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that is a biosphere built of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and their shenanigans.
Oh, confusion. Perhaps a certain confusion is healthy. We have not tried to embrace all of this at once before.
Hierarchies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autonomous Agents</ENAMEX>
For a start, there appears to be an indefinite hierarchy of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. At least in our biosphere, there is a considerable hierarchy of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Consider first a single-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>, prokaryote, cells without nuclei such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> in your gut. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX>, my canonical autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. Next, consider a eukaryote, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX>, also in your gut, also an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. In the passage from prokaryote to eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, it appears that a collection of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> came to live together permanently. Eukaryotes contain mitochondria, and plant cells contain plastids with chlorophyll. In both cases, these intracellular organelles carry their own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, with a slightly modified genetic code in the case of mitochondria. These facts have suggested to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Margulis</ENAMEX> the now rather well-accepted hypothesis that eukaryotic cells are symbionts of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or more earlier</TIMEX> separate autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> that contributed the mitochondria, the plastids, and perhaps the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of eukaryotes into a single novel reproducing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>.
The eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, then, is a well-behaved society of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> that are now symbiotic, hence, the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is a higher-order autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, comprised of lower-order autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.
But life has burgeoned beyond single-celled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sea</ENAMEX> is filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eukaryotic colonial organisms¬†=¬†multicellular</ENAMEX>, usually capable of sexual reproduction but also capable of asexual reproduction by budding clumps of cells that reform the various organs, feeding tubes, mouths, stinging cells, musculature, nerve system. Blessed proliferating profusion of ways of being.
And of course, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 1.6 billion years ago</TIMEX>, and surely since the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Ediacrin 600 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cambrian</ENAMEX> period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">540 million years ago</TIMEX>, there have come to exist us multicellular sexually reproducing juggernauts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Tyrannosaurus rex</ENAMEX> really was a juggernaut of an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. A blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale isn‚</ENAMEX>Äôt so trifling either. Neither is the wide-flung stand of aspen astride the hillsides above <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>, largest single stand of aspen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, presumably all or most of which is a linked set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> sprouting from the spreading roots of some initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Rebek</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX> now at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripps Institute</ENAMEX>, is fond of saying that the biggest molecule he knows of is Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> coal, a massive hunk of coal <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several miles</NUMEX> long and wide and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of feet</NUMEX> deep. Maybe Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> coal is from a single, clonally linked stand of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspen cousins</ENAMEX>.
So we confront a hierarchy of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. If our definition of an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> should include that it be ‚Äúan <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">individual‚Äù</ENAMEX> capable of reproducing, then maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX> are about as big as such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> get in the current biosphere. That‚Äôs a long way up in mass and molecules from the minimal autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> I sketched in chapter 3.
How far can the hierarchy go? Who knows.
Perhaps the simplest step in this hierarchy would be the hypothetical, and now almost experimentally realized, hypercycle invented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manfred Eigen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Schuster</ENAMEX>. The hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hypercycle</ENAMEX> consists of a set of replicating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA sequences</ENAMEX>, say A, B, C, and D, each of which is actually a plus and minus strand that are template complements. But in addition to A, B,C, and D each replicating individually, A helps B replicate, B helps C replicate, C helps D replicate, and D helps A replicate. Thinking of each plus/minus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> strand pair as a replicating cycle of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> template strands, these replicating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> are linked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABCD</ENAMEX> hypercycle.
In fact, the hypercycle is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> of molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replicators</ENAMEX> that help one another replicate, hence, it is a higher-order molecular replicating system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reza Ghadiri</ENAMEX> has nearly created a peptide hypercycle and probably soon will achieve a real experimental example. While the hypercycle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eigen and Schuster</ENAMEX> does not yet fulfill my definition of an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> because no work cycles are done, nevertheless we have no trouble imagining a hypercycle of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Indeed, presumably, the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is more or less just such a hypercycle.
We have beginning mathematical models that reveal something about this hierarchical organization¬†=¬†although the best current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are curiously limited despite their brilliance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Fontana</ENAMEX> is a theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX> trained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Schuster</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe Institute</ENAMEX> and made a major intellectual step called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúAlchemy</ENAMEX>.‚Äù In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 2</ENAMEX>, I described the emergence of autocatalytic sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">molecular species</ENAMEX> in a chemical reaction graph. By rather independent intellectual routes that began with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCaskill‚</ENAMEX>Äôs eVorts to create a computer soup of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turing</ENAMEX> machines that ‚Äúoperated‚Äù on one another, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> invented ‚Äúalgorithmic chemistry.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Naturally</ENAMEX>, and most naturally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>, where one can be healed by means known nowhere else in the universe, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> nicknamed algorithmic chemistry ‚ÄúAlchemy.‚Äù Unlike the alchemy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newton‚</ENAMEX>Äôs time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walter‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX>.
Here is alchemy: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> borrowed a computer language known as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúlisp</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Lisp</ENAMEX> expressions can operate on one another. So expression <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> encounters expression <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. At random, it is decided if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> will operate on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> will operate on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Whichever way, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, the lisp expression that was operated on typically is transformed into a new lisp expression.
You see the analogy to chemistry. The transformation of the lisp expression to a new lisp expression is rather like a chemical reaction. The operating lisp expression that does the transformation is rather like an enzyme catalyzing a reaction.
So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> let loose a pot full of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> lisp expressions in a computer. These merrily bumped into one another creating new lisp expressions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>, as a good theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eigen-Schuster</ENAMEX> tradition, imagined his algorithmic chemistry in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúchemostat‚Äù</ENAMEX> that would hold the total number of lisp expressions at a constant <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10,000</NUMEX>. So if extra lisp expressions drove the total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above 10,000</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter randomly</ENAMEX> chose enough lisp expressions to eliminate from the pot to keep the total at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>. This pruning back to a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> provides a selection pressure for lisp expressions that are formed more often than average.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> let loose the floodgates of his alchemical world. A torrent of ever new lisp expressions, then, stunningly, a few, then more often, one sees an enlarging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of a subset of already-seen lisp expressions.
What had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> found? The first thing he found were ‚Äúcopiers,‚Äù that is, lisp expressions that could copy any lisp expression, including themselves. Once such replicators emerged, they took over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Walter‚Äôs</ENAMEX> steaming pot of lisp expressions. Indeed, such a lisp expression is rather like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Szostak‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hoped-for RNA polymerase</ENAMEX>, able to copy any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA sequence</ENAMEX>, including itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> called such copiers ‚Äútype-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1‚</NUMEX>Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
Could other self-reproducing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> emerge? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter ‚Äúcheated‚Äù</ENAMEX> and simply disallowed copier replicators to occur. Bereft of copiers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> ripped forward again. Again novel lisp expressions came forth in profusion. Again, after a while, a recurrent set of lisp expressions emerged.
What had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> found? He found collectively autocatalytic sets of lisp expressions, essentially identical to my collectively autocatalytic sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polymers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> called these ‚Äútype-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2‚</NUMEX>Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. In each such collectively autocatalytic lisp set, each expression is formed by the action of some lisp expression on some lisp expression in the set. The set as a whole is collectively reproducing.
But could one find a hierarchy beyond type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>? Further research has gotten as far as a kind of type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, which consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that jointly coexist and create a kind of mutual glue of lisp expressions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX> would not be formed by either type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> alone but is the conjoint construction of the plurality of type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
So a modest hierarchy of algorithmic chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> has been found. The type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> seem analogical to eukaryotic cells that harbor diVerent replicators, mitochondria, plasmids, nuclei, in a common mutual glue of cytoplasm and shared processes.
Curiously, no higher-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has yet been seen. It is deeply interesting to me that no one knows why. What is limiting the persistent emergence of novel reproducing algorithmic systems?
Indeed, there are now a modest diversity of algorithmic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Ray‚Äôs ‚ÄúTierra</ENAMEX>.‚Äù In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tierra</ENAMEX>, computer strings live in the memory core, reproduce, and fight one another for space in the core. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúreaper‚Äù</ENAMEX> kills random critters. Evolution to form a variety of parasites and hyperparasites occurs, including some slightly hierarchical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Interestingly, again the total diversity of types of critters is limited.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCaskill</ENAMEX>, another theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist-chemist</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eigen-Schuster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, points out, no one has succeeded so far in creating an algorithmic system of reproducing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that generates impressive hierarchical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> or persistent, increasingly complex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. Again, no one knows why.
It is possible that the constraint to algorithmic critters may be the problem. Indeed, I will suggest that the biosphere is richer than that which can, in the normal senses I know, be called algorithmic. That which is algorithmic is eVectively constructable by a formal procedure that begins with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">definable input ‚Äúdata‚Äù</ENAMEX> and is operated upon by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúprogram‚Äù</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turing</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Neumann</ENAMEX> sense. But I will argue that we cannot prestate some biological analogue of the input data, nor is there some biological analogue of the program governing the unfolding of a biosphere. I will argue that the configuration space of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biosphere</ENAMEX> cannot be finitely prestated, that persistent novelty occurs in the biosphere and universe as a whole. And I will opine that if we cannot finitely prestate the configuration space of a biosphere, then something is odd with how we have been taught to do our science, for in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newtonian</ENAMEX> physics, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Einstein‚</ENAMEX>Äôs physics, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohr‚</ENAMEX>Äôs physics, one can finitely prestate the configuration space in question. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 10</ENAMEX>, borrowing on joint work with quantum gravity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Smolin</ENAMEX>, I will suggest that if we cannot prestate the configuration space of a universe then ‚Äútime‚Äù is real and necessary, and that the way a universe constructs itself may have analogies to the way a biosphere constructs itself.
Remember, a propagating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that builds itself and persistently ramifies in a nonequilibrium setting is not yet a concept that we understand. We have matter, energy, and entropy, but no clear notion of propagating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the sense we here struggle to articulate. And because the way a biosphere gets on with constructing itself may not be algorithmic, it may be that story is part of how we must, in fact, make sense of the persistent emergence of novelty in the biosphere.
Well, that‚Äôs a mouthful. We‚Äôll have to struggle below to see if it makes sense and might be correct.
I want to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Fontana‚</ENAMEX>Äôs algorithmic chemistry to note an interesting feature. Let‚Äôs define higher-order machines in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs chemistry. We might think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúbundles‚Äù</ENAMEX> of lisp expressions, where an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúinput bundle‚Äù</ENAMEX> of lisp expressions is fed into an ‚Äúassembly-line bundle‚Äù of lisp expressions to yield an ‚Äúoutput bundle.‚Äù Nothing prevents our consideration of such bundles. Given a set of possible initial lisp expressions, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> diVerent expressions, the diVerent subsets, or bundles, that are possible are just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> raised to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nth</ENAMEX> power. This <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2N</NUMEX> set is called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúpower set‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> symbol strings. A bundle acting on a bundle may produce a bundle. In general, this is just a mapping on the power set in which ‚Äúmachine bundles‚Äù act on input bundles to yield output bundles; that is, the set of possible input bundles, machines, and output bundles is the set of possible mappings of the power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">set</ENAMEX> into itself.
Well, obviously one could get bundles of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lisp expressions¬†=¬†complex</ENAMEX> assembly lines of lisp expressions acting as machines on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> ordered sets of bundled input lisp expressions to yield ordered sets of bundled output lisp expressions. Here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúordering‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the lisp expressions would define the assembly-line sequence of operations of the machine lisp bundle, and the ordering of lisp expressions in the input bundle would define the order in which the machine acted on the set of lisp expressions in the input bundle. And just as obviously, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> got type<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-1</ENAMEX> and type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> autocatalytic sets of simple lisp expressions, one could get type<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-1</ENAMEX> and type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-autocatalytic sets of machine lisp bundles operating on one another. And if sets of machines could be ordered into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúunits‚Äù</ENAMEX> to act on sets of input bundles to yield sets of output bundles, still higher-order autocatalytic sets of type<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-1</ENAMEX> and type<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-2</ENAMEX> should emerge.
Why didn‚Äôt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> find these higher-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>? I suspect part of the answer is because nothing in his algorithmic chemistry abets the ordering of lisp expressions into ordered sets treated as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and machines by one another. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">collective properties</ENAMEX> of ordered sets of lisp expressions are not recognized and acted upon as collective objects by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> of lisp expressions.
But such limitations seem not to hinder the biosphere. We do witness the emergence of molecular assembly lines and molecular assemblages whose collective properties are recognized and acted upon by natural selection. The transcription and translation of the DNA code to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">messenger RNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is one example. But there are others. Many enzymes form ordered arrays of multimolecular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> in which a substrate is progressively passed from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to another active site along an analogy to an assembly line. These higher-order <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> of molecular devices arise because natural selection is able to act upon the collective properties of such molecular aggregates when those collective properties augment adaptive fitness. In eVect, natural selection recognizes the life context in which the collective behaviors of these higher-order molecular structures are advantageous.
It is important to stress an obvious feature of the biosphere, in contrast to the algorithmic computational systems of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fontana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, and others. The algorithmic systems manipulate symbols according to discrete, well-defined transformation rules, a kind of algebra-mapping symbols or symbol strings into symbol strings.
In contrast, the biosphere is built up of the doings, the embodied know-how, carryings on of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">agents¬†=¬†real</ENAMEX> physical molecular systems grafting a flow of matter and energy, constraint construction, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> into their persistent coevolution. As we will see below¬†=¬†where I give grounds to think that we cannot prestate the configuration space of a biosphere, hence cannot prestate the adaptations that may come to exist in an evolving <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">biosphere¬†=¬†real</ENAMEX> macroscopic physical systems that are autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> may not be constrained in what they can produce, as is a formal mathematical algebraic symbol system. If so, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúalgorithmic freedom‚Äù</ENAMEX> of a biosphere is deeply important, for the science of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohr</ENAMEX> all suppose prediction by algorithmic calculation.
Indeed, I suspect that the persistent innovations in a biosphere stem in no small measure from the fact that while we cannot prestate the configuration space of a biosphere, the categories relevant to its unfolding novel functionalities, the biosphere is not hampered by our failure at categorization. Unlike the well-defined and formal transformation rules of an algebra or a calculational process such as lisp, the transformation rules of the biosphere enlarge and change in ways that cannot be prespecified. As concrete examples, consider the evolution of the genetic code and consider the structure of eukaryotic chromosomes, whose complex coordinated behaviors underlie both normal mitotic cell division and the astonishing sequence of meiotic reduction cell divisions in which maternal and paternal homologue chromosomes synapse, undergo recombination, and separate such that the final <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> receives, at random, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> homologue of each parental chromosome. The emergence of these complex macromolecular systems has altered the way evolution itself unfolds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Palmer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe Institute</ENAMEX>, has commented to me that physics is used to distinguishing the initial and boundary conditions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúlaws</ENAMEX>.‚Äù But in the evolution of a biosphere, the emergence of systems such as the genetic code and meiosis seems rather like the emergence of new laws. This has led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX> to wonder whether the distinction between initial and boundary conditions and laws is really as clean as it appears in, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newtonian</ENAMEX> physics.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furniture of the Universe</ENAMEX>
All of this has, somehow, to do with the question of ‚Äúthe furniture of the universe‚Äù and with the troublesome questions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúemergence‚Äù and ‚Äúreductionism</ENAMEX>.‚Äù These are contentious issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Philosophers</ENAMEX> and others have struggled with these issues for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. I state merely some of their outlines.
There is a strong form of reductionism, the ‚Äúx is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äònothing but‚Äô y‚Äù</ENAMEX> version. We met an example of this form of reductionism earlier in the eVorts to make good on sense data and logical atomism, where the hope was to build up an epistemology based on the least questionable propositions, namely reports of sense data, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> seem to hear a middle C note now,<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äù ‚ÄúThis</ENAMEX> seems to feel like a hard, flat surface.‚Äù Then the statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúA Windsor</ENAMEX> rocker is in the living room,‚Äù is nothing but a finitely prespecified list of statements about sense data.
On this definition of reductionism, a higher-level concept is reduced to a lower-level language if the truth of a defined set of statements in the lower language is both necessary and suYcient for the truth of a statement in the higher language. If this could be done, then the higher-level statement is nothing but a shorthand for the list of necessary and suYcient statements in the lower, reducing, language. Thus, the truth of the statement, ‚ÄúThere is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windsor</ENAMEX> chair in my oYce,‚Äù would be reduced to the truth of some specifiable set of statements about sense data. As we saw, this eVort failed in the case of statements about physical objects and sense data. While it is relatively easy to find suYcient sense data statements, it appears to be impossible to finitely specify a set of necessary and suYcient sense data statements whose truth would be interchangeable with true statements about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windsor</ENAMEX> chair in my oYce.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wittgenstein</ENAMEX> wrote persuasively that the same systematic diYculty was lodged in attempts to reduce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> language game to another, for example, from a description of a legal event to a description in terms of mere human actions to a description in terms of physical events. As we noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, legal descriptions involve a web of concepts concerning guilt, innocence, responsibility, evidence, admissible procedure that are absent from a description of human actions outside of the legal framework. And descriptions of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">actions¬†=¬†and</ENAMEX>, a fortiori, descriptions of the doings of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, even bacteria acting on their own behalf to get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dinner¬†=¬†seem</ENAMEX> to involve a diVerent language game than mere descriptions in terms of physical events.
Among other critical features of the action-and-doing language game is that, compared to a hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúcomplete‚Äù</ENAMEX> physical description, the action-and-doing description picks out the relevant features with respect to the goals of the autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. Interestingly, once we are at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dennett‚</ENAMEX>Äôs level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Popperian creatures</ENAMEX>, which can have internal models of, and plans for, the future and can have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> die in their stead, we seem to have arrived at a level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in which action-and-goal talk becomes essential. Is there a finitely prestatable set of statements about physical events that is jointly necessary and suYcient for the truth of the statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúThe cheetah</ENAMEX> is hunting the gazelle‚Äù? Like other eVorts, we will find suYcient conditions but be hard pressed to find jointly necessary and suYcient conditions.
The dictionary hints at where our reductionism ideas may go wrong: Every word in the dictionary is defined in terms of other words. How could it be otherwise? Concepts are defined in webs, somehow tacked onto the real world by ostensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">definitions¬†=¬†definitions</ENAMEX> given by pointing to examples. We carve up the world in a variety of ways, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Wittgenstein‚Äôs language</ENAMEX> games, that appear not to be reducible to one another in the strict sense of necessary and suYcient conditions. And this, in turn, underlies the question whether legal systems and human actions are parts of the furniture of the universe, somehow above or in addition to the locations and motions of atoms and fields.
Even at the level of basic physical theory, the same issues arise. For example, classical thermodynamics is a well-defined science in its own right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig Boltzmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willard Gibbs</ENAMEX>, and others struggled to invent statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newtonian</ENAMEX> laws operating on a set of idealized particles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 6N-dimensional</TIMEX> phase space we have discussed. It is generally seen as a triumph that the classical thermodynamic concepts of temperature, pressure, and entropy were reduced to statistical features of idealized sets of gas particles: temperature becoming the average kinetic energy of the particles, pressure the momentum transferred to the walls of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX>, and entropy a measure of the number of microstates per macrostate.
But before complete triumph is declared, we should ask whether statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> constitutes a set of necessary and suYcient statements with respect to classical thermodynamics. The answer appears to be no. While statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> based on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Newtonian</ENAMEX> forces yields a set of suYcient conditions, that statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> is not jointly necessary and suYcient. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gross</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist colleagues</ENAMEX> have confirmed to me that one could construct diVerent, consistent statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> based on particles following non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newtonian</ENAMEX> laws, all of which would be interpretable as reductions of classical thermodynamics. So, even at the heart, where reduction is supposed to have taken place, there seems to be no finitely prestateable set of necessary and suYcient conditions on a lower level over a set of possible statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> that would jointly suYce for a reduction of classical thermodynamics.
The same problem arises with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> theory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX> tells us that evolution occurs by reproduction with heritable variation and natural selection. Our biology, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, is an instantiation, a suYcient condition for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> evolution. Could we now state all possible physical systems that might be capable of replication, heritable variation, and natural selection? I think not.
There is a weaker sense of reductionism, namely the casting of an account of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">higher-level</ENAMEX> object, concept, or phenomenon in terms of a suYcient, but not necessary and suYcient, set of conditions at a lower level. In this sense, statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> surely does ‚Äúaccount <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">for‚Äù</NUMEX> classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>. Many argue that this weaker sense of reductionism suYces. Well, suYces for what? That is a bit harder to be clear about. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly</NUMEX>, the temptation is to say, ‚ÄúTemperature is nothing but the average kinetic energy of the atoms in the system‚Äù; that is, we appear to reduce the ontological furniture of the universe.
I suspect that this familiar ontological move is not always warranted. Let‚Äôs take some cases that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Anderson</ENAMEX> uses to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">exemplify ‚Äúemergence</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Gold</ENAMEX> is a yellow, malleable metal familiar to all of us. Nowhere in the quantum mechanical description of atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> are these macroscopic properties to be found. Moreover, there is no deductive way to arrive at these macroscopic collective properties from the underlying quantum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of atoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. Rather, we observe the macroscopic properties, find lawful features of those properties, then attempt to link them to suYcient conditions in our quantum mechanical description of matter.
Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of cases <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> refers to is broken symmetries. A familiar example would be a pole standing vertically on an horizontal slab on the earth‚Äôs surface. The vertical pole is unstable in the face of gravity and will soon fall. It might fall and point in any direction. Hence, the system has the full symmetry of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> prior to the falling of the pole. In due course, the pole does fall over and points in some specific direction. Thereby, the symmetry of the system prior to falling has been broken. We cannot deduce from the symmetry of the initial state how that symmetry will be broken.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> entitled his article relevant to this issue of emergence <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúMore Is DiVerent</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
Let‚Äôs try it with my definition of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. As I have already hinted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> capable of self-reproduction and thermodynamic work cycles are presumably not limited to our current <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-based cells. Almost certainly, pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and small molecule systems can be autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Almost certainly, pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> and small molecule systems can be autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. But perhaps self-gravitating systems, lasing systems, and a variety of other physical systems can be autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.
Again, we can give several suYcient conditions, but apparently we cannot finitely prespecify a set of necessary and suYcient conditions that would allow us to prespecify all the possible patterns of construction, constraint, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of physical processes and matter flows that would constitute an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.
On the other hand, my definition does seem to aVord a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúpostconstruction‚Äù</ENAMEX> test. Bring us a candidate autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, and we can ask of it: Do you reproduce yourself and carry out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> thermodynamic work cycle? The answer is either yes or no and is an objective fact about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> in question. So <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> begins to see a pattern here. We may not be able to finitely prespecify all the possible systems that constitute an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, but we can recognize <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when we see it. We can give suYcient, but not necessary and suYcient conditions, for all physical realizations of an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, and we can check any specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> case. Further, any specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> case either is, or is not, an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. The statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚ÄúThe bacterium</ENAMEX> is an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>,‚Äù is either true or false.
Based on this, I want to say that autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are parts of the ontological furniture of the universe. I also want to say, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Anderson</ENAMEX>, that emergence is real and utterly nonmysterious.
On this view of emergence, the autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is more than the sum of its parts, but not in the sense that the behavior of the autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is not explicable as the total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the parts organized into the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in its environment. Rather, an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is more than the sum of its parts in the sense that a wide variety¬<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">†=¬†indeed</ENAMEX>, an indefinite <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">variety¬†=¬†of physical systems</ENAMEX> could be autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in the same sense, self-reproducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> carrying out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> work cycle.
Now we can turn to causality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnothing but‚Äù</ENAMEX> version of reduction, ‚Äúan autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is nothing but¬<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">†¬†¬†</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">¬†¬†¬†</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">¬†¬†¬†</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">¬†¬†¬†</ENAMEX>,‚Äù has tended historically to see causality as running only upward, from the behaviors of atoms to their causal consequences in the behavior of larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>.
But I find myself troubled by this view and will provide an example of why. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the last female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trilobite</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tomasina</ENAMEX>, was hurrying to find a good place to lay her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. Suddenly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomasina</ENAMEX> saw a hideous starfish, named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darthvader</ENAMEX>, dead ahead. ‚ÄúLeft or right? What shall I do?‚Äù she wondered. Tomasina jumped left. Darthvader jumped right, caught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomasina</ENAMEX>, killed her, and devoured her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>.
There are no more trilobites. Moreover, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomasina</ENAMEX> died, she took with her the unique <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and small molecules that were trilobite molecular species. These kinds of molecules are gone from the biosphere. So too are descendant mutant molecules that might have arisen from further speciation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomasina‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, other chemical reactions, which might have been catalyzed transforming some molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> to others that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tomasina‚Äôs</ENAMEX> molecules and those of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> might have catalyzed, have perhaps never come to be in the biosphere that has evolved over the succeeding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eons</TIMEX>.
Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomasina</ENAMEX> is lost as an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> acting in an environment. Yet the causal consequences of her wrong guess of direction to jump have propagated downward to lower levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, namely the molecular species of which the biosphere is composed.
Downward causation is real and nonmystical. There are now more old tires along roadsides than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon wheels</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> has replaced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conestoga</ENAMEX>.
I distrust a reductionism that sees causality as bottom up. In what sense is Tomasina nothing but the atoms and their locations and motions in three-dimensional space of which she was comprised? The concepts of atoms in motion in three-dimensional space do not appear to entail the concepts of an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, self-consistent constraint construction, release of energy, propagating work tasks, and the closure of catalysis, tasks, and other features that constitutes the propagating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that is an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> or a coevolving ecology of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, of course, there is nothing but the atoms in motion in three-dimensional-space in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tomasina</ENAMEX>. But the historical coming into existence of life in the universe, of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, and of the propagating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomasina</ENAMEX> and her bioworld is nowhere accounted for by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newton‚</ENAMEX>Äôs laws. What, after all, do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton‚</ENAMEX>Äôs laws of motion have to do with a suYcient account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomasina‚</ENAMEX>Äôs jump to the left rather than the right? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomasina</ENAMEX> as a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> part of the furniture of the universe? Yes.
Adaptations, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Exaptations</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impossibility</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Finitely Prestate the Configuration Space</ENAMEX> of a Biosphere
One contentious issue leads us to another. And now I hope to trouble you deeply.
Tomasina was but one of many lineages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> evolving much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX> taught us, by heritable variation and natural selection. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Let‚Äôs</ENAMEX> turn to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> account of the function of the heart. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX> would say, the function of the heart is to pump <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. Namely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX> would say, this causal consequence of the heart is the virtue for which it was, and persistently is, selected by natural selection. I tend to think Darwin‚Äôs account of the heart is correct. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> that the form of the account is ontological. Hearts came into existence, somehow, and are sustained because it is advantageous to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> to have a means to pump <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.
But the heart has other causal consequences. For example, the heart makes heart sounds as its valves open and close. Presumably, heart sounds are not the causal consequences of the heart upon which natural selection has acted. Heart sounds are not the function of the heart.
It is precisely this point, that the function of a part of an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> is a subset of its causal consequences, to which I appealed earlier in stating that in an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> discerning the work task done by the constrained release of energy required finding the subset of causal consequences of that work task that were functionally important to the life cycle of the autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in its environment and, therefore, were presumably selected and sustained by natural selection. My point was that we cannot know the functions of parts except in the context of the whole autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in its environment.
But now we come to a more radical issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> preadaptations, or in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen J. Gould‚</ENAMEX>Äôs term, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúexaptations</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Darwin</ENAMEX> noted that in an appropriate environment a causal consequence of a part of an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> that had not been of selective significance might come to be of selective significance and hence be selected. Thereupon, that newly important causal consequence would be a new function available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>.
Take a fanciful case in point. The human heart not only makes heart sounds, but it also is a set of resonant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>. Suppose you were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, felt something odd in your chest, and thought, ‚ÄúMy God! An earthquake!‚Äù You did whatever the right thing was and survived, alone among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>. Your heart happened to be preadapted to pick up earthquake <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pretremors</ENAMEX>. Now suppose you marry and have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who inherit your fatefully preadapted heart, and suppose earthquakes arose often enough for this new capacity to oVer survival advantage to you and your oVspring. Soon a subspecies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homo sapiens</ENAMEX> would arise with earthquake detectors in their chest. Not bad.
Now, evolution by such preadaptations, or exaptations, are not rare; they are the grist of adaptive evolution. Thus arose the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung</ENAMEX>, the ear, flight, presumably most major adaptations and presumably many or even all minor ones as well. It suYces for my purposes that many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adaptations</ENAMEX> arise as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darwin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs preadaptations, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gould‚</ENAMEX>Äôs exaptations.
Here now is my troublesome question. Do you think that you could state, ahead of time, all the possible causal consequences of bits and pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> that might in some odd circumstances or another turn out to be preadaptations and hence be selected and come to exist in the biosphere? Stated more starkly, do you think that you can finitely prestate all the context-dependent causal consequences of parts of all possible organisms that might be preadaptations, hence be selected and come to exist in the biosphere?
I believe, and it is a matter of central importance if I am correct, that the answer is no. I do not think it is possible to finitely prestate all the context-dependent causal consequences of parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> that might turn out to be useful in some weird environment and hence be selected. I‚Äôm not yet certain how to prove that this is not possible, although I will have a try at it below.
Another way of stating what I am driving at is this: Is there a finitely prestatable set of all the possible potential biological functions? Again, I think the answer is no. Yet another way of stating this is to say that there is no finite prestatement of the configuration space of a biosphere. We cannot say ahead of time all the possible constellations of matter, energy, process, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that is a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúbasis set‚Äù</ENAMEX> for a biosphere in the sense that the atomic chart of the elements is a finite basis set for all of chemistry.
It is time for a story. A particularly ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">squirrel</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> was atop a tree <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65,433,872 years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> was ugly because she had folds of skin from her forearms stretching to her hind limbs. So ugly was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> that she was shunned by the other squirrels and was sadly alone atop a magnolia <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> eating lunch. But <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just yards</NUMEX> away, high in a pine, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bertha</ENAMEX> spotted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> and thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúLunch!‚Äù Bertha</ENAMEX> flashed downward through shafts of light toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> looked suddenly up and was terrified. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúGAAAAAAH</ENAMEX>,‚Äù she cried and jumped in desperation from the top of the magnolia <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, flinging her arms and legs wide in terror.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> flew! Yes, she flew away from the magnolia <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, eluding the bewildered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bertha</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> was married in a civil ceremony to a handsome squirrel, as she had become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>, was no longer shunned, and was considered a prize mate. Her odd flaps turned out to be a consequence of a simple Mendelian dominant gene, hence her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had the same wondrous capacity to fly.
And that is how flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">squirrels</ENAMEX> got their wings, more or less.
Now, after the fact, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> jumped in terror from the magnolia <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, we would all say in wonder, ‚ÄúDid you see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> just did?!‚Äù And we would tell the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX>. But could we have said beforehand that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gertrude‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ugly skin flaps would happen to be of use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>? Perhaps, perhaps not. Could we have said it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four billion years ago</TIMEX>? Or said it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about all possible future exaptations? No. Was some known law of physics violated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX>? No.
Now a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractors</ENAMEX>: It is said, and I choose to believe it true, that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> were hard at it trying to invent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúGood idea, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX>,‚Äù was the collective wisdom. Needing lots of power, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> began with a huge engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> and sought to mount the block on a chassis. But the engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> was so massive that it crushed chassis after chassis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> were stumped. Then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> said, ‚ÄúYou know, the engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> is so rigid, we could use the engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> itself as the chassis and hang everything else oV the engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX>. And so that‚Äôs how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX> got its chassis. And the chassis is just another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> preadaptation, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Gouldian exaptation</NUMEX>.
A brief history of the origin of writing: In the early Near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, loans of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> were common. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">borrower</ENAMEX> would give the lender a small, closed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> of baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX>, containing a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> equal to the number of borrowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>. Upon return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> would be broken open and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> counted to make sure as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> were returned as had been borrowed.
But sometimes the clay <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> were broken accidentally by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lender</ENAMEX> before the time of return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> was broken, sometimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> would fall out and become lost. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lender</ENAMEX> could not be sure he had recovered all his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> started making scratch marks near the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> before they baked the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX>, to denote the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> placed inside the closed vessel. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> it dawned on someone that with the scratch marks on the surface of the clay vessel the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> inside were not needed. They smoothed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX> and began keeping notes of loaned <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> by marks baked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuneiform</ENAMEX> writing began.
Do you think you could finitely prestate all the context-dependent causal consequences of human artifacts that might turn out to be useful in some odd environment or for some odd purpose? I don‚Äôt think so. It is not that we cannot finitely prestate some infinite things. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourier</ENAMEX> had a wonderful idea. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúSine</ENAMEX> and cosines, you know,‚Äù he muttered to himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúAll possible wavelengths, out to infinity, down to infinitesimal, all possible phase oVsets.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">¬†¬†¬†</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">¬†¬†¬†</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">¬†¬†¬†</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haha!‚Äù And Fourier</ENAMEX> proved his theorem that any wiggly line on a plane surface could be approximated to arbitrary accuracy with a weighted set of phase-oVset sines and cosines drawn from the infinite basis set of all sine and cosine functions. Fourier finitely prestated an infinite basis set for all continuous diVerentiable wiggly lines on long blackboards.
But can we finitely prestate all possible exaptations for all possible organisms, or even the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>, in our biosphere? Again, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I‚Äôm</ENAMEX> still not certain how to prove my claim, I claim the answer is no. We cannot prestate the configuration space of the biosphere. But notice our failure is not hindering the biosphere from exapting all the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> did it. And every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX> whose molecules wiggle in a useful way that turn out to detect a source of energy or danger or opportunity in some novel fashion tends to be selected for that novel functionality. Look at the rate of emergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> resistant to our antibiotics and the myriad unexpected ways such resistance arises at the molecular level. Who could have foretold the ways?
The example of the common emergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> preadaptations in the biosphere may point to an interesting connection with the diYculty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fontana</ENAMEX> and others have had achieving the persistent emergence of more complexity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">algorithmic</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> such as alchemy and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tierra</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> did fly, and thereby the capacity of her folds of skin to function as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> were selected. Flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">squirrels</ENAMEX> came to exist in the universe. Restated, a property of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gertrude¬†=¬†indeed</ENAMEX>, here a collective property of her atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">constituents¬†=¬†made</ENAMEX> itself manifest in the real physical world in a context that lent survival advantage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX>. Were we to have a formal algorithmic description of a formal simulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">algorithmic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> that did not have as an algorithmic consequence that her skin flaps might function as wings, then the emergence of the higher-order category of ‚Äúwinged squirrel‚Äù could not be derived algorithmically. Similarly, were we to have a formal description of an engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> that did not include its rigidity, we could not algorithmically derive that the engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> could be used as a chassis.
But, we might ask, could we not have a complete physical description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> or the engine block such that all possible properties might be derived from that complete physical description? The answer is almost certainly no. It is an old philosophic realization that there is no finite description of a simple physical object in its context. For example, the coVee table in my living room is made of three wooden planks, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> short squat legs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> between all pairs of legs. The middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has a crack in it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some eight inches</NUMEX> long, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a quarter of an inch</NUMEX> wide at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, narrowing to nothing along a particular curved arc. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> crack, smaller, is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six inches</NUMEX> from the first crack. A cracker is on the table. A personal computer is on the table. The first crack is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven feet</NUMEX> from the door. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> crack is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven feet six inches</NUMEX> from the door. Both cracks are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">256,000 miles</NUMEX> from the moon and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">light years</TIMEX> from the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. A dead grasshopper is on the table to the left of the end of the first crack and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 4.3</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">light years</TIMEX> from the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. A mote of dust hovers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> above the table, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two inches</NUMEX> from a leaf that drifts down from a ficus in the living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
You get the sense that there is no complete description of the table. Why does it matter? Because I myself made an exaptation of which I am deeply proud. You see, I was worried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> might knock my PC oV the table, so I wedged the power cord into the first crack and plugged the cord into a floor socket. Thereby, my PC worked on the table, and couldn‚Äôt be knocked oV easily. You can understand my pride here, as with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rube Goldberg</ENAMEX> device to water my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean</ENAMEX> field.
But even this tiny invention, this tiny exaptation, could not readily have been finitely prestated. How would one, in describing all the context-dependent features of the table, happen to list the crack and its distance to the floor socket that happen to turn out to be relevant for my brilliant solution of a sudden problem? In short, there seems to be no finitely prestatable eVective procedure to list all the context-dependent features of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> and organs that might prove useful for some oddball purpose by some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>. My invention, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX> invention, the cuneiform invention, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gertrude‚Äôs</ENAMEX> invention were all genuine novelties in the universe.
This brings us to a wondrous set of issues. You see, we have indeed been taught by our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist friends</ENAMEX> to do science by prestating the configuration space in question. Consider our now rather tired example of statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avogadro‚</ENAMEX>Äôs number of gas particles in a liter container. First, note that we can finitely specify ahead of time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6N-dimensional</ENAMEX> configuration space of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, that is, all the positions and momenta of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> gas particles in three-dimensional-space inside the liter box. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boltzmann</ENAMEX> assumed the ergodic hypothesis about wandering all over the configuration space, did the calculations, and, lo, statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> is upon us.
Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newtonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>: Prestate the initial and boundary conditions, the particles and force laws, and with them the possible configuration space and calculate away. So too in general relativity: Given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Einstein‚</ENAMEX>Äôs equations, prestate the initial and boundary conditions and seek solutions. Solutions are possible universes. The set of possible solutions is the configuration space allowed by general relativity. And in quantum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>, one talks of specifying the classical conditions of the experiment, and thereby the configuration space of the quantum system, preparing an initial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schr√∂dinger‚</ENAMEX>Äôs equation to propagate amplitudes for the entire future evolution in the configuration space for all conceivable observables. Again in quantum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>, in any specific context the configuration space is to be finitely prestatable, then we follow the deterministic time evolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schr√∂dinger</ENAMEX> equation in configuration space, square the resulting amplitudes to predict the probabilities of measurements, and then carry out macroscopic measurements. We know the configuration space ahead of time.
But what if we cannot prestate the configuration space of a biosphere? In that case, the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> taught us to do science is not the whole story. We cannot calculate as he did. And, in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> do not often do science as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> taught. We carry on an odd mixture of historical analysis of the actual branching pathways of evolution; a dollop of theory about evolutionary landscapes, molecular evolution and coevolution, and ecosystems; and a lot of detailed experimental work to understand how actual creatures develop, how their life cycles unfold, how they assemble into ecosystems, and so forth.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> tell stories. If I am right, if the biosphere is getting on with it, muddling along, exapting, creating, and destroying ways of making a living, then there is a central need to tell stories. If we cannot have all the categories that may be of relevance finitely prestated ahead of time, how else should we talk about the emergence in the biosphere or in our history¬†=¬†a piece of the biosphere¬†=¬†of new relevant categories, new functionalities, new ways of making a living? These are the doings of autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Stories not only are relevant, they are how we tell ourselves what happened and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">significance¬†=¬†its semantic import</ENAMEX>.
In short, we do not deduce our lives; we live them. Stories are our mode of making sense of the context-dependent actions of us as autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. And metaphor? If we cannot deduce it all, if the biosphere‚Äôs ramblings are richer than the algorithmic, then metaphor must be part of our cognitive capacity to guide action in the absence of deduction.
Indeed, in biology itself the ‚Äúnarrative stance‚Äù is gaining in popularity. ‚ÄúDid you see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> pulled oV? That‚Äôs how flying squirrels evolved! Dominant Mendelian gene, you see, easily selected once the right environmental conditions arose.‚Äù The propagating exapting biosphere is getting on with it, and it appears that we crucially need stories to do some of the telling of that getting on with it.
How odd. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. P. Snow</ENAMEX> wrote of the two cultures, science and the humanities, never to mix. Our inability to prestate the configuration space of a biosphere foretells a deepening of science, a search for story and historical contingency, yet a place for natural laws.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forever Creative</ENAMEX>
In this chapter I have been trying to say, argue, articulate the possibility that a bio-sphere is profoundly generative¬†=¬†somehow fundamentally always creative. The cornerstone of this dawning near conviction lies in the belief I now hold with some confidence that we cannot finitely prestate the configuration space of a biosphere. New <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">variables¬†=¬†the</ENAMEX> genetic code, recombination, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gertrude‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX>, writing, the tractor¬†=¬†persistently emerge. New language games and living games emerge. What is the status of my claim that we cannot finitely prestate the configuration space of a biosphere? I do think my claim is true. But why? I am not sure. It is wise to explore some possible reasons.
A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> possibility is that the biosphere, like a complex algorithm, unfolds in ways that cannot be foretold. Recall that for many algorithms the behavior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">algorithm</ENAMEX> cannot be prestated in any form more compressed than simply watching the program unfold. The famous ‚Äúhalting problem‚Äù is the classic example. For many algorithms that are to compute an answer, then halt, we cannot say ahead of time whether the computer will halt in finite time.
I do not think the biosphere is akin to this diYculty with many algorithms. If we consider such algorithms, the building blocks of the algorithms¬†=¬†for example, the binary symbols <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 0</NUMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of addition, subtraction, multiplication, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>, exponentiation, and root taking; and control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> such as, ‚ÄúIf such and such, then do so and so, otherwise do this,‚Äù and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúDo loops‚Äù¬†=¬†are well-stated</ENAMEX>, crisp, mathematical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primitives</ENAMEX>. Our uncertainty about the unfolding of an algorithm does not lie in uncertainty about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primitives</ENAMEX>, but about the consequences of the arrangements of these agreed upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primitives</ENAMEX> in a given computer code. For example, will the algorithm based on those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primitives</ENAMEX> halt or not halt in finite time?
But among the exaptations in a biosphere are those that appear to alter the primitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> and control operations. Thus, the evolution of chromosomes that replicate and partition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> cells, the evolution of the genetic code, and the evolution of controlled recombination all seem to be the evolution of the generative machinery of evolution itself. Insofar as this is true, our incapacity to prestate the configuration space of the biosphere is not a failure to prestate the consequences of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primitives</ENAMEX>, it appears to be a failure to prestate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primitives</ENAMEX> themselves.
Let‚Äôs consider the possibility that the incapacity to finitely prestate the configuration space of a biosphere is related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs theorem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Godel</ENAMEX> demonstrated that for axiomatic systems as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> or richer than arithmetic, given a set of axioms, there were always statements that were true but not formally derivable from the axioms. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godel</ENAMEX> showed that it was always possible to enrich the axiom set, and from that enriched axiom set, it would be possible to prove the formally true but unprovable statements in the formal system. On the other hand, he also showed that the new enriched axiom system would itself have still further formally true but unprovable statements.
I am not persuaded that the uncertainty about the configuration space of a biosphere is analogous to true but formally undecidable statements in a formal system. I base this upon an analogy between formal proof and causal consequences. The same parallel was pointed out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rosen</ENAMEX> in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Itself</ENAMEX>. If we are to represent causal consequences by a formal system, then the concept of a proof derived by formal procedures from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">axioms¬†=¬†or</ENAMEX> more generally, the concept of a trajectory in a state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>, where successive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> along a trajectory are derived by a formal procedure such as integration of the diVerential equations representing the system¬†=¬†is the natural way to represent causal consequence. If this parallelism is taken seriously, then statements in a formal language that are true but unprovable in that formal language can have no causal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathway¬†=¬†that</ENAMEX> is, proof¬†=¬†from the axioms to the desired consequence. But this analogy seems to fail with respect to the evolution of the biosphere. There is a perfectly fine causal account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> and her maiden flight. We can reconstruct that account after the fact, even if we could not have predicted it. Thus, it does not seem that our diYculty in prestating all exaptations is the same as the mathematical fact of formally undecidable statements in an axiom system.
On the other hand, there may be a parallel between the exaptations of which we have spoken and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs theorem and the augmentation of the axiom set such that formerly unprovable statements become provable. That is, the emergence of novel exaptations in evolution do seem rather like the emergence of novel primitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> and primitive control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">operations¬†=¬†hence</ENAMEX>, novel axioms. In the examples above, the emergence of the genetic code and the emergence of chromosomes that duplicate and partition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> chromosomes into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> cells, the evolution of controlled recombination, seem to become instantiated as ‚Äúbiological laws,‚Äù even though they are entirely historically contingent. Changing the biological laws in evolution seems rather like the generation of a novel axiom from which new consequences can be derived.
On this interpretation, my claim that we cannot finitely prestate the configuration space of a biosphere becomes the claim that the biosphere keeps generating new ‚Äúcausal axioms‚Äù from which it generates novel forms. Then just as we do not know where the new axioms of a formal system come from, save as the free invention of the logician involved, so it would seem that we cannot prestate the new generative exaptations that allow evolution to drive in new directions. I am not entirely persuaded by this analogy to finding ever new axioms in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs theorem, but it does have some coherence.
Indeed, the failure to be able to prestate the configuration space of the biosphere may be yet deeper. I will take a stab at a proof. I begin by vitiating my assumption that one cannot prestate the configuration space of a biosphere, then try to show that the implications are that the number of potentially relevant properties is vastly hyperastronomical and that there is no way in the lifetime of the universe for any knower within the universe to enumerate, let alone work with, all the possible properties or categories and their causal consequences.
Let‚Äôs restrict attention to a model of a molecule, a square <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">x 10</ENAMEX> array of magnetic dipoles, called spins, that can point only up or down. So our little system has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> spins. Thus, I begin by vitiating my assertion and telling us what the configuration space is: it has something to do with the spin configurations. Well, how many diVerent spin configurations are there? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> raised to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">100th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX>. Now what might we want to call a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúcategory‚Äù</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúproperty‚Äù</ENAMEX>? A sensible thought is that a category or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is some collection of the possible spin configurations, say, the configuration with all spins up plus all the configurations with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no more than two</NUMEX> spins down. How many such possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> are there? The answer is the power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">set</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> raised to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> raised to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>.
This is a gargantuan number. It corresponds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly to 10</NUMEX> raised to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> raised to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 29th</TIMEX>. That is, the number of possible static categories of our tiny <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-spin system is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX> raised to the power written with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 zeros</NUMEX> after it. By comparison, the estimated number of particles in the known universe is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX> raised to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">80th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX>.
But we have so far considered only static <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">categories¬†=¬†possible subsets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-spin system. Suppose the spins can flip. Then the spin system can pass from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> configuration to another. Suppose that the motions of the spin system are confined to closed cycles in the space of configurations, that is, simple orbits. Each of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> static categories is a set of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more spin configurations. The number of possible orbits through that set is the factorial of the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the set. The number of orbits among configurations that constitute the power set of classes of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> spins is vastly larger than the number of static categories.
On the other hand, arbitrary motion among spin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> may be unreasonable. Instead, the flow among spin configurations may be constrained by the energy couplings among the spins. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicists</ENAMEX> will properly talk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúHamiltonian function‚Äù</ENAMEX> that gives the energy of each spin configuration. Grant such a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamiltonian</ENAMEX>, say a spin-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamiltonian</ENAMEX>, where a spin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> is a disordered magnetic material. Then the system at finite temperature may wander through the square root of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2‚ÅÑ‚</NUMEX>Äö‚Äö <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, hence <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10‚ÅÑÔ¨Å</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in some complex patterns.
Now consider <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> such molecular systems, each merely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">x 10</ENAMEX> spins, each governed by a spin-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamiltonian</ENAMEX> function, and let the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> molecular systems interact in an aqueous medium. As the two touch one another and jiggle near one another, the coupled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> performs some very complex dance of spin motions. In general, the equations describing that motion cannot be solved analytically but would have to be solved by numerical simulation. That is, there is no short description of the behavior of the system of equations, they must instead be solved by an algorithmic system that follows the trajectory in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> of the system by tiny incremental steps. It becomes easy to conjure multimolecular systems, indeed autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are examples, in which even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamiltonian</ENAMEX> for each single system and all the coupled systems were known, it would not be possible to compute the detailed dynamics of the coupled spin system in the lifetime of the universe.
But it is just such detailed wiggling by the coupled system that allows discovery of the preadaptation that a particular wiggling of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> molecule senses a subset of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of another molecule and is useful for some survival purpose. The behaviors of the collective set of molecules among the coevolving autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> stumble upon, then reinforce by heritable variation, the odd molecular motions that capture photons, that sense energy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, that are the fine-grained molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exaptations</ENAMEX> that are the daily stuV of evolution.
We cannot compute it. There is a sense in which the computations are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">transfinite¬†=¬†not infinite</ENAMEX>, but so vastly large that they cannot be carried out by any computational system in the universe. Indeed, one can consider the known radius of the universe at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planck</ENAMEX> length and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planck</ENAMEX> timescale, and can imagine all the events that have happened within any causally connected light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cone</ENAMEX> that might, therefore, carry out a computation. While vast, there are combinatorial problems that are still vaster. Presumably, no physical process in the unfolding universe could have foreknowledge of all features of such problems. Nor would there be an eVective procedure to prepare the cosmic computer in a proper initial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, read in the data, and read out its computation.
My best bet is that the incapacity to finitely prestate the configuration space of a biosphere is deeply related to the incapacity to enumerate and predict all the possible detailed dynamics of coupled molecular systems by any computational system in the universe. In turn, this incapacity is, I suspect, deeply related to the gargantuan nonergodicity of the historical universe that I discuss in the next chapter. And as we shall see in detail, the exaptations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> and others leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">macroscopic</ENAMEX> living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">footprints</ENAMEX>, propagating frozen accidents, on the history of the universe. The universe in its persistent becoming is richer than all our dreamings.



