
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sporting Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Life</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Chris</ENAMEX>--

            Read your lament about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derrick Thomas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebacker</ENAMEX> who was
left paralyzed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in a car accident, and I felt the same pang you did
when I saw the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> that he'd been hurt. I did have the pleasure
of interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> in the past, and the memory of his smile is what's
haunting me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--that smile, and the mischievous light that always shone in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' eyes even though he had to deal with another numbing tragedy before
this. Remember? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet fighter</ENAMEX> crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of decades</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derrick</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years old</TIMEX>. Now this.

            I'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> will be remembered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>,
especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> descend on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> for a
reaction. But I think we both know when reality intrudes in sports, the people
in sports tend to retreat even deeper into the games they play. And they can't
wait for the games to resume.

            To be sure, there's always some sad talk about the infinity of possibilities
that are lost when something like this happens, or when some similar tragedy
comes along. There's been a spate of them recently, hasn't there? How about
that drive<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by</NUMEX> shooting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rae Carruth</ENAMEX>, the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> Panthers wide receiver
was recently charged with after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> was shot and died. How about
that car crash that claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Phills</ENAMEX>' life after he and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlotte Hornets</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teammate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Wesley</ENAMEX>, were drag racing in their Porsches down a city street
after practice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> guessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phills</ENAMEX> was travelling <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">110 miles per hour</NUMEX>
before his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> spun out of control.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rocker</ENAMEX>, the big-mouth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>, had a ride atop the
headlines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> after he insulted nearly every minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> this
country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">harbors</ENAMEX>. But, sports being sports, I'll bet the buzz about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> as part <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Wizards</ENAMEX> will last
far longer, and generate reams more copy--which, again, isn't surprising.

            I've always thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> flock to sports because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who play
them simultaneously defy and define the limits of what human beings can
achieve. You never think someone can throw as hard as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocker</ENAMEX> or hang in the air
as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> until they come along and prove it. And not only that--they
can summon such magic consistently. And on command. That's what's so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transfixing</ENAMEX>. It's like all of us, not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, need to see someone
who's fearless and acts like they're going to live forever.

            It's been interesting to me, for example, that after all the rejoicing about
how nice it is to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after his retirement
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, the next thing that most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> fretted about was whether his
involvement with the sad-sack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wizards</ENAMEX> will eventually cloud his legend.
Clearly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is less worried about protecting his mythic standing than his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> are.

            I think the other thing that something like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' accident does is remind
us how little life actually does resemble sports, try as we might to say it
does. After all, sports have these neat, agreed-upon rules. There's this
comforting belief in sports that no matter what happens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, no matter how
bad a certain game or loss might seem, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> can always be better--and you
can do something to make it better, you know?

            Then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> ends up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> with a broken back, and you
snap back to reality.

            Maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> will bring some better news ...

            Catch you then,
Johnette

         
      
   
