
   
   
      
         
            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fighting Bad Ideas</ENAMEX>

            Was Culturebox calling for censorship yesterday
when she said she blamed the professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin MacDonald</ENAMEX> holds several
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>, as well as the series <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who oversaw publication of
his books, for his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> ideas? How could Culturebox hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX>
Behavior and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evolution Society</ENAMEX> (HBES) in particular and evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> in general responsible for the theories of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>? Isn't
she just being a wooly-headed liberal, scrounging around for ways to condemn a
discipline prone to express politically incorrect ideas?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> at a time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX>.

            Several posters in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray</ENAMEX>" as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Itzkoff</ENAMEX>, believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> stopped just
short of calling for a gag order. "I'm not the series approver or disapprover
of the particular ideas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzkoff</ENAMEX> told her. "I make a decision
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s work is qualified for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>." Indeed, says
Itzkoff, the nonsense quotient in the books could have been higher. "I was
instrumental in having him rewrite a number of passages, because I said to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenwood</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishing Group</ENAMEX>] that these would destroy his book--they
were so beyond the pale in terms of factuality. But I couldn't censor or ask
that he rewrite everything."

            Not wanting to be seen as a censor is the defense of nearly everyone who has
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacDonald</ENAMEX> make his upward climb toward respectability. As it happens,
censorship wasn't an issue with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>'s trilogy,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzkoff</ENAMEX> thought highly of it (that's the book in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> calls
Judaism a "group evolutionary strategy" masquerading as a religion in order to
hide its true purpose--to maximize intelligence and give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> an advantage in
the competition for resources). But even if he'd hated the book, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzkoff</ENAMEX>,
it wasn't his job to pass judgment on its contents--merely on whether it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">merited</ENAMEX> publication. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iztkoff</ENAMEX> didn't think nearly as well of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>'s work in
Volumes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX> (in which he argues that anti-Semitism is justified and exposes
what he feels to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> agenda behind <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX>
intellectual movements), but by then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzkoff</ENAMEX> felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> had "the right
to publish it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> isn't buying it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itzkoff</ENAMEX> is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of a scholarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX>. He has not been asked (as such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> are) to toss as many explosive
subjects as possible into the public domain, as long as they meet some minimum
standard. Nor can he offer a letters page for debate. He is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Press</ENAMEX>, both of whom publish vast quantities of
books, making the task somewhat similar to that of a journal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, although
without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> for debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itzkoff</ENAMEX> is the named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of a small series of
scholarly books. His name is cited on the title page specifically to guarantee
the quality of the work. Under those circumstances, his judgment as to whether
the work is "qualified for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>" is tantamount to saying that he
endorses its conclusions.

            Moreover, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> that owes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> "the right to publish" is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>. Freedom of the press belongs to
those who own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, etc.

            As for blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBES</ENAMEX> in particular and evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> in general:
Culturebox was mistaken to rap the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>' knuckles for letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacDonald</ENAMEX>
hold executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>--he was elected to them, not appointed. That may
reflect poorly on the membership, but it can't be pinned on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. And
perhaps she should have given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBES</ENAMEX> a chance to explain that it has long
embraced an ethos of open expression--until recently, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> submitted to
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBES</ENAMEX> conference were accepted without peer review. (According to
founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leda Cosmides</ENAMEX>, back when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was formed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, this
seemed the best way to combat the censorious hostility directed at most people
working in evolutionary psychology at the time.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> doesn't think
being inclusive gets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBES</ENAMEX> off the hook. On the contrary--accepting papers
without peer review is an abdication of scholarly responsibility under the best
of circumstances and a poor idea for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>, whose discipline is notorious for attracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cranks</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBES</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tooby</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> that he and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBES</ENAMEX> members
did not fail to be alarmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>'s ideas. When a positive review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>'s work appeared in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> about to be acquired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tooby</ENAMEX> and
others thought about sitting down and writing a letter objecting to both the
work and the review. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, however, they decided not to. They didn't want
to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> and his reviewer any more attention than they had received
already.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would reply that if you're going to take the unusual step of
welcoming all ideas, you can't proceed to ignore the bad ones. You have to be
prepared to do battle against them. That is (or ought to be) the duty of anyone
who has staked his or her professional reputation on one particular scientific
approach or methodology. And giving publicity to bad ideas isn't itself
necessarily a bad idea. After all, if you draw attention a bad idea by refuting
it, you also put your refutation on record.

            Here's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>
has to say to all the evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> who feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has
smeared them by association with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> she considers an anti-Semite: If he's
going to lay claim to your methodology and benefit from your systems of
legitimation, it's up to you to distinguish yourself from him. The MacDonalds
of the world won't go away just because you think they're not worth responding
to. Where they'll go is wherever as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as possible will hear them. And
there they will brag--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> has done in a response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Culturebox</ENAMEX> coming
soon to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>, and as he probably will in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> some time in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next few months</TIMEX>--"I have published my views in highly reputable refereed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> in psychology."

            Note for all of you who have stuck with this endless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books</ENAMEX> -style refutation and have yet to flee screaming: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> will
be responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>'s post
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray--in the Fray</ENAMEX>. She hereby promises to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> itself
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>-free--at least for the time being.

         
      
   
