
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More Tail, More Hooking</ENAMEX>

            The top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> detection of an
apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> temperature pattern--much bigger than any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>--that
has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> arguing about whether the world is about to experience a
decadeslong climate change that might include droughts in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> fronts this weather whether but goes
instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>--as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and part owner
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Wizards</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> does a front-page "cover story" on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
but leads with the deadly fire at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seton Hall University</ENAMEX> and the general topic
of campus fire safety. The paper points out some facts of the tragedy that are
typical: an older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> not required to have sprinkler systems and a lulling
frequency of false fire alarms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> fronts the weather
up radio to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of small broadcasting operations via its approval of
non-commercial low-power FM radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. The story says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> are opposed to the plan but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
champions it as promising to bring many new voices to the airwaves that have
not previously had an outlet. All of which makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> wonder if the
Times has ever heard of cable access TV, which has no affect whatsoever
on major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> and is execrable.

            The LAT fronts the growth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> of union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX>, which is
noted inside elsewhere. The paper explains the swell--the biggest increase in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX>--as a function of the booming economy's job creation and of
the slowing down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '90s</TIMEX> of the flight of manufacturing jobs to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            The WP fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> tops its front-page news box with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s unveiling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110 billion</NUMEX> health-care
plan, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> investment in health since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, the plan, which extends the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidy
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are now covered and employs subsidies
and credits to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get coverage between jobs or prior to
qualifying for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, is much more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s, and
in any case is not likely to get much <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> support.

            The WP fronts another in its series on presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>. (By the way, why does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> rate only a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-parter, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> got many times that?) The main point of the story seems to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
has long been fiercely stubborn, as exemplified by his shunning for 27 years
the fellow POW who he admits saved his life, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> accepted an early
return home from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Skakel</ENAMEX>, was charged with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> beating and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stabbing</ENAMEX> murder of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. The crime had been the
subject of a novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX> and more recently of a nonfiction effort
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Fuhrman</ENAMEX>, the latter concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skakel</ENAMEX> was the likely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big issue in the case, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>: Should the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skakel</ENAMEX>,
who was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, be tried as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> or as a juvenile? A hearing on this
issue will be held shortly. The coverage is mum about whether or not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has ever ruled on this issue, which surely must have come up
before, no?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and other papers had arrangements with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
anti-drug office similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> had with the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. The
story quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howell Raines</ENAMEX>, as saying
that he knew absolutely nothing about this when he recently wrote an editorial
excoriating the TV arrangement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
announced that, while the financial incentive program for TV anti-drug messages
will continue, the practice of prior script review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> anti-drug office
will not.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> announced it was
restoring its ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tailhook</ENAMEX>, the private naval aviation booster <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> whose
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> convention was the scene of rampant sexual misconduct by numerous naval
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aviators</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> ahead there will be much discussion about whether or not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> has in the interim become fairer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but let's see if the papers
also get on top of the re-emergence of another scandal: the amount of taxpayer
money and military flight time used to send naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aviators</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> for most of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> features an op-ed primer on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>
speeches by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> speechwriter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Waldman</ENAMEX>. Cutest nuance noted:
The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delay Delay</ENAMEX>"--the amount of time it takes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Dennis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> to figure out whether he finds something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says should
be applauded or not, so-called because apparently the key step in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s
process is being able to see what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whip</ENAMEX> thinks.

         
      
   
