
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: A Comparison

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CEDAR RAPIDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> I hopped from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.S. Gore</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
battered dinghy. The contrast between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, and between the two
campaigns, could hardly be more striking.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> glides across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> in a sleek <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential motorcade,
with a plush <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, black wagons full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>,
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>. For longer distances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> hops aboard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
Force Two. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> shambles through traffic in a ragtag caravan.

            Here's the scene at the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> event of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, a huge rally in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waterloo</ENAMEX>: A cheering, sign- and flag-waving throng of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many hundreds</NUMEX> fills the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bleachers</ENAMEX> and floor of the basketball arena at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern University of Iowa</ENAMEX>. A
marching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> blares out "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Twist and Shout</ENAMEX>" as an enormously bloated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jiggles</ENAMEX> to the music. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> a rasping stem-winder of introduction.
"He has the potential for greatness," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> thunders. "He has the potential
to be one of our greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> assumes the stage like a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>,
dressed in his best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> casual--deep-blue sport shirt, cowboy boots, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">khakis</ENAMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Pilot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holster</ENAMEX> attached to his belt. The vice president
introduces another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, the jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbie Hancock</ENAMEX>, before launching
into a feisty pep talk to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> watches from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> raised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">platforms</ENAMEX>, but throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> has no direct access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.

            Here's the scene at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s only event <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, a talk to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cedar Rapids</ENAMEX>:
Perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in headscarves, sit
listening to stand-ins for the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> as they wait for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to
arrive. Occasionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wander to the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, where there are
platters of raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> introduces
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as someone who "knows how to listen and acts on what he thinks."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> turns up late, wearing a blue suit, red tie, and black shoes. He
delivers a restrained chat and then mingles with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. Any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> is free to walk up and ask an awkward question about his heart
condition or his downward drift in the polls.

            But the biggest contrast between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> isn't a matter of style,
standing, or policies. It's the entirely different attitude the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have
toward politics.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> presents himself as someone who once lost faith in politics but who now
embraces its potential. In his speech, he says that his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam-Watergate-</ENAMEX>era
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disillusionment</ENAMEX> gave way to a sense that by running for elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> he could
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. He boasts about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has accomplished,
mentioning the low unemployment rate and the passage of pro-union legislation,
among other things. He promises more money for public education, universal
health insurance starting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and "tax breaks to speed up the
purchase of new technologies." He slams <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Confederate Flag</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. "I want to fight for you," he resounds, again and
again.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> presents himself as someone ill at ease with the way politics is
currently practiced. He says that he's running on the "radical premise that you
can tell people what you believe and win." He talks about the power of example,
being a "good steward," and leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in "a world of new possibilities
guided by goodness." Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> boasts about his accomplishments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> says
he's trying "to find a balance between modesty and confidence." Almost every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comment Bradley</ENAMEX> makes contains an implicit criticism of the way politicians
ordinarily behave. And where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> promises specific benefits and improvements,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> reaches for something grander and less tangible, saying that the
fundamental challenge for someone running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "find
some meaning in life that is deeper than simply the possession of material
things."

            At the end of his speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> implores <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to vote for him. "Feeling
enthusiasm is great but you gotta be there and you gotta bring
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> thunders. "I need you. And I want to fight for you
and I want to fight for the future of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>! I need you to fight for
me--<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>!"

            At the end of his speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> says that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> share his vision of a
virtuous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, they are welcome to support him. "What my campaign is about is
asking good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come forward and join us so that our voices can be
heard," he says. "I am behind. But there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> left. ... We could
surprise a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter/scholar</ENAMEX> distinction has taken root because there's a lot of
truth to it. When you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, you see a thoroughbred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who is simply
running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and running as hard as he can. When you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, you
see a naturally diffident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> talking about how he would like to run for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and fretting about the distance between his ideal campaign and the
real <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. This is the decisive distinction. It explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is almost
certain to defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in the caucuses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night:</TIMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> prefer
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of action to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of ideas. Because they prefer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> to
the civics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. Because they prefer the probably better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to the
possibly superior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
