
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of months ago</TIMEX>, I described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s attempt to create a
lose-lose situation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. Through the use of relentless, often
unfair attacks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> thought they could trap <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> between a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> and hard place. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> remained on the high <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, emphasizing his
positive message and ignoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s hectoring, the unanswered
criticism would damage him. But if, on the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> responded to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in kind, he would be descending to his opponent's level, dispelling his
aura of moral superiority in the process.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s tactic has worked perfectly. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
has remained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>-like on his mountaintop, dismissing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s attacks as
politics-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-usual, but not criticizing his opponent directly or even answering
most of his complaints. The result has been ebbing momentum for the challenger.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has suffered from both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s specific charges--such as the distortion
that he opposed flood relief for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>--and from the general sense that
he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>- or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX>-type of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. As if to
underscore the unhelpful
comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tsongas</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign has been running
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> TV ads in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niki Tsongas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is
falling prey to the kind of smear that undermined her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            So with Plan A plainly failing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has finally switched at to Plan B.
His own revised strategy was on view in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WMUR/CNN</ENAMEX> debate, in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> pointedly went after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in a way he has not done previously. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
repeatedly called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> (though he only used the actual l-word after the
debate), sneakily compared him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, blasted him
for pandering to every special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> under the sun, and wondered how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would muster enough public credibility to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> if elected.
"And my question to you is, why should we believe you that you will tell the
truth as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> if you don't tell the truth as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> asked,
in one of many direct confrontations. He also accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> of having once
opposed abortion, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">distorting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care plan, and of being too
cozy with corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and special interests.

            After the debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> congratulated himself for finally taking the
gloves off. "I thought I was doing pretty well counter-punching <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, quite
frankly," he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>, in a post-game appearance. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> at a rally in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> described his performance as a "fresh start" to his
campaign. "Last night I decided I'd had it," he declared. "We're going to call
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> on what he's been doing."

            I expect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s satisfaction will be short-lived. His newfound
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pugnacity</ENAMEX> plays into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s hands as much as his earlier pacifism did. In the
debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was completely ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, turning every accusation of foul
play back on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>. "If that's not negative, I don't what it is," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
said, in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s charge that he is a favorite of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> also brought up the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> injected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Horton</ENAMEX> into the campaign and was forced to apologize for an unfair ad.
"I have never mentioned your name in an ad, I have never used your picture in
an ad," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said. "There is nothing I have said in this campaign that is in
any way mean spirited." Every time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> took a whack at him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> appealed
to the ref: "I didn't foul him-- he fouled me!"

            Many who saw this debate judged the nonstop quarrelling about who started it
to be childish. But that's fine with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, since it reduces the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to the
same level. The point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s litigiousness isn't to establish that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
campaign behavior really is worse than his own--though he claims it is. It's to
establish that there's no real difference in their behavior. If they're the
same, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is better because he doesn't hold himself out as a paragon of
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saintliness</ENAMEX>. By his own rules, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can go negative so long as he
doesn't make it "personal." But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> goes negative, he's a sanctimonious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypocrite</ENAMEX>. "If you're going to talk about a higher standard, you're going to
have to live by them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said, clearly delighted to be yanking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> off
his high horse. He knows that once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has thrown even a few punches, he
can't reclaim the status of a conscientious objector.

            Is there any way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to escape from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s box? Not that I can think
of.

            
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> 
               here for
Ballot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>'s review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> debate.)
            

         
      
   
