
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Sections</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Minivan Revolution</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnette</ENAMEX>--

            You're right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> story is terrific. Why don't we hear more of these
stories? Is it because they are so rare? Or because sportswriters don't spend
much time searching for them? I hate to say it, but I think the answer might be
the latter. Don't get me wrong. I'm not saying there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Warners</ENAMEX>
out there. Not at all. This is rare and heart-warming and really quite nice.
I'm just wondering out loud if some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>--us even?--miss great
stories in order to continue to pump out the continual steam of game stories
and side bars and advances and follows that have inspired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
to put down their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and run to the Internet.

            I continue to be amazed at the lack of creativity in our sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>,
especially regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports and features that will attract women
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> saga. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> need new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> desperately. The
sports section in many ways is the gateway to the paper, especially for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. (It was for me.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX> now love sports almost as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who buy products. And yet, pick up the New York
Times , or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Herald</ENAMEX> , or even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> (which covers more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports than any paper I know), and
it's all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s sports. Or almost all.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> and guts. X's and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>'s. My God, some papers still use the headings
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>." Can you imagine? Like one's real and the
other's fake. Of course it should be "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s basketball" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
basketball." It's little stuff, but it means a lot.

            Because of all this, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> (unless she's a total sports nut
like you or me) slides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> back across the breakfast table, goes to the
computer, and clicks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Hamm</ENAMEX>'s Web site. Good-bye to her, probably
forever.

            Here's my new favorite quote:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Flutie</ENAMEX> is watching <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>'s wildly popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup soccer</ENAMEX> tournament with his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexa</ENAMEX>.

            A commercial comes on, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatorade</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anything You Can Do, I Can Do Better</ENAMEX>"
ad featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Hamm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>.

            When it ends, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexa</ENAMEX> looks at her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and asks, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's the guy with Mia?</ENAMEX>"

            I'm not making this up. How many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-to-12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> know Mia but don't
know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>? Apparently, a few. And how many of them are being lured into our
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>? Zero.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup soccer</ENAMEX> tournament became the sports story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> won every major end-of-the-year award. And yet the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> who chose to cover the event is far less than the
number who chose to not cover it.

            Huge papers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Chronicle</ENAMEX> for instance, didn't send a staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. Another major metropolitan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> told its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that it
would not pay her airfare or expenses. She went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> final in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
anyway. When the paper used this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s stories on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A1</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> consecutive
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, she came home and submitted the expenses. The paper reimbursed her.

            Can you believe this?

            The minivan revolution has hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but most sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> refuse to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX>. Don't these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> drive by soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> on their way to work? Don't
they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>?

            Why didn't every sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> start devoting even a little
more space to skating after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonya-Nancy</ENAMEX>, which was a fiasco, absolutely, but
also was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>-highest-rated TV program in history? Not sports program. All
of television.

            The top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>: The last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M*A*S*H</ENAMEX> , Who shot <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">J.R.?</ENAMEX>, an episode of
Roots , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowls</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonya-Nancy</ENAMEX>.

            This is why skating is on TV all the time. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that covered it
even a little would attract scores of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. As you know, I've found
skating to be a worthy news subject--<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, pushy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, eating disorders, you
name it. You could tell me to shut up and go back to my little <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic world</ENAMEX>
if--if--newspaper circulation numbers weren't plummeting. But they are.

            I'm on a roll here. Don't stop me. Another thing: Why do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-something male
columnists criticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> as being "overhyped," when, in
fact, that story was the complete opposite of hype (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> packing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> and
surprising everyone, forcing sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to scramble to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to
cover a burgeoning story)? Some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> have been supporting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights and liberal issues for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, yet when something this refreshing
and fun comes along in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports, they invariably begin to attack it.
Why?

            (I don't sound like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, do I?)

            Why aren't we thinking differently as an industry, before we're not an
industry anymore?

            Send answers, and fast.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
