
   
   
      
         
            All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacon</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>--

            Allow me to share a portion of a missive that came my way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> from our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>: "Let us in on the process of how you mine the news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, what
strikes you as funny, how MAD chooses its targets, etc. We'd also love
to hear your reviews of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>' attempts to be funny, from political
cartoons to columns from the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen D</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ivins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Barry</ENAMEX>,
etc."

            As long as it doesn't involve me having to dance in public, I will do just
about anything to please a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, so here goes ...

            Like anyone who has the good fortune to have a job where they get to spoof
current events, I do my best to stay, well, current. That is, I read a lot of
magazines, pore over a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, and watch a good deal of
television--particularly Ready, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Set</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> on the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Network</ENAMEX>, which,
admittedly, doesn't help me stay abreast of world affairs, but I now know how
to make a hell of a coq <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">au vin</ENAMEX>! (The secret? Capers!)

            Anyway, from there, the subjects pretty much suggest themselves, and it's
just a matter of coming up with the right hook and good lines. For that, I rely
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pico</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Elf</ENAMEX>. I type up the subjects I want to spoof and put them
under my pillow. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poof</ENAMEX>! The jokes are there! I can't
speak for the other MAD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. I think they rely on
talent or something.

            As for the aforementioned newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>, well, I have to admit that
with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> (who I'm not sure is a humor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in the
strictest sense, although she can be savagely funny), I don't really read the
newspaper humor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> on a regular basis. Again, this is mostly because I'm
spending my free time watching the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Network</ENAMEX>. (Have you seen Taste
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rosengarten</ENAMEX>? I believe he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gourmet</ENAMEX> , which is a
pretty upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, and he comes on and you think he's going to be the
biggest stuffed shirt in the world ... and he proceeds to do <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX> show
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX>! Just <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX>! Unfortunately, I missed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few minutes</TIMEX> and never
found out what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> best accompanies <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX>.)

            Wait. I also read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ficarra</ENAMEX>'s frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Op-Ed</ENAMEX> pieces in the New York
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> . And not just because he's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAD</ENAMEX> .

            Anyway, I've relied on you in the past to introduce me to new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queenan</ENAMEX> comes to mind), so let me ask you: Which newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>, if any,
do you find funny?

            And before you answer, remember that technically, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lockhorns</ENAMEX>" doesn't
count as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
