
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art of Strategic Annoyance</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>--

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nope</ENAMEX>, I never went to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp. Or, rather, never to a sleepaway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. I
went to day <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, and hated it: To me, it was like an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8-hour</TIMEX> session of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>. I
grumbled so loudly that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't send me back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>. Which is
how I wound up sewing sneakers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> at the tender age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>.
Oh, sure, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> were long, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> were dark, and the machines claimed
both my pinkies, but at least I never had to play dodge ball again.

            As for the smoking story, what's gone unreported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is the
tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' proposed "compromise" wording for the warning label:
"Smoking will kill you. On the other hand, we are all mortal." Actually,
diseased lungs and rotting teeth could be quite attractive packaging,
particularly if you put a little cowboy riding in front of them. In any case,
I'd imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> can shortly look forward to many fine gallery
displays and public-television programs on the sexiness of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>,
underwritten by the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>.

            The cigarette-packaging thing reminds me, in an indirect way, of a larger
issue I've always found interesting: the deliberate effort to frustrate or
annoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>. I once talked to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> who told me that the key to
designing a successful shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is to include lots of angles, so that you
can't see clearly from one end of it to another--that way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> walks
and walks, always convinced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> he's trying to find is just around
the next corner. In the meantime, of course, he might stop in at any one of a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozen</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clearing House</ENAMEX>, I remember
reading, makes its contests difficult to enter ("Go find the red stamp and put
it on the entry form. Now find the yellow sticker and put it on the envelope.
Now include a tail feather from a bald eagle. Now sing!") for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons:
First, obviously, is so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> will spend more time combing over the
materials and is therefore more likely to order one of their magazines. But the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> reason is that they've found that there's a much higher response rate
for every bell and whistle they add. And finally, there's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX>, where every
aspect of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>'s design is meant to keep you inside--hence the confusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">layout</ENAMEX>, the paucity of exit signs, the lack of clocks, etc.

            In other news, did you see the story in the far-left column of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ? My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> pointed it out to me; here's the headline
and the lead:

            

               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dancer, a Dream--Still, It's a Long Slog to Broadway's Lights</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SEVILLE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>--When the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gypsy street</ENAMEX> legend Torombo dances, his feet are on
fire and his head is often in the clouds. For he dreams and when he dreams, he
dreams of this: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>.

            

            Oh dear God.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
