
   
   
      
         
            Retooling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Scene</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Chris</ENAMEX>--

            Had to laugh at that image you conjured up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> sitting in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Wizards</ENAMEX> locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> by himself, dressed and ready for practice long
before anyone else on his newly purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> showed up. There's a bit of a
geek factor there, isn't there? Something that's not usually associated with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, even though he always tells those stories about not being able to get a
date in high school.

            But I do hope that your characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> as the wily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> who
takes a wrecking ball to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-something, multi-millionaire, 'What? Me
practice?' sports world" is what happens. But I wonder. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> didn't
have that impact when he briefly tried coaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>. He
found many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> incorrigibly apathetic or self-absorbed. He quit in
disgust. (Now he's playing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>--honest to God--against whom, I don't
know. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flying IKEAs</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm Saunas</ENAMEX>? Who? And what do they give away
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">halftime</TIMEX>--snow-blowers?) And did you see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX> said
he's interested in joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Mavericks</ENAMEX> but, quote, "his calendar is
booked through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>"? Essentially, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> would love to join the
Mavericks but playing those pesky games just gets in the way.

            Clearly, the whole sports scene needs some retooling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> here in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> have dubbed this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl the "Mayflower Bowl</ENAMEX>" because both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, deserted their original <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. Word just got
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebastian Janikowski</ENAMEX>, the pudgy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>-born kicker at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State</ENAMEX>,
may be deported if he's convicted of trying to bribe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to get a friend
released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>, which we both consider the most
wonderful, stirring, spectacular sports event there is, was tainted by that
payola scandal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Remember? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> from the host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> wannabes
were funneling payoffs and jobs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            What astounded me most was the cheesy stuff the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> requested.

            Lawn equipment.

            A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$524</NUMEX> violin.

            A pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKC</ENAMEX> registered bulldogs, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$673</NUMEX> worth of door knobs.

            I'm not making this up.

            Arrangements were made for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Un</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yong</ENAMEX> to rehearse with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Philharmonic</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> was seeking the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
Games. Though described as only "modestly talented," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> also
performed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melbourne Symphony</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> when that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was chasing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olympics</ENAMEX>, and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Symphony</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'95</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Utahans</ENAMEX> even paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">her $5,000</NUMEX>.

            Presumably to go away.

            How many times can you hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chopsticks</ENAMEX>?

            Still, the undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of graft seems to have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Ganga</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">influential IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Congo</ENAMEX>, who asked for medical
treatment for himself, and a free knee replacement for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eugenie</ENAMEX>, received free cosmetic surgery.

            Now seriously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>, if you had a bunch of well-heeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> ready to
fulfill your every whim, wouldn't you ask for something better than a titanium
knee or a riding mower? Whatever ever happened to craving a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX>? A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speedboat</ENAMEX>? A villa on the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>? How about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>?

            I'm ranting, I know. Perhaps this is just bitterness on my part. When I read
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eugenie</ENAMEX>'s cosmetic surgery, I was stricken by a thought: "You mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can demand just about anything in exchange for their votes on an
Olympic host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, and I chose to be a sportswriter ? I've settled for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>' pre-game buffet all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> when I could've had a free nose
job instead? What was I thinking?

            Johnette

         
      
   
