
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that's
voting on his renomination as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> chair, and he turned in a bravura
performance. Of course, it's probably easier to turn in bravura performances
when you know that everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> listening to you believes that you are
a true Zen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> was surprisingly interesting on
subjects like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> hostility to genetically modified food and the
persistent anxiety that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> feel in the face of technological
change. He also remained definitively non-committal on the question of where,
exactly, we are on the curve of that technological change, keeping open the
possibility that there may still be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> ahead of rapid economic growth
propelled by rapid improvements in productivity.

            Of course, as always when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> appears before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, it was fun to
watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> try to make their own dubious economic views appear to be
harmonious with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> chair's. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s labyrinthine speaking style
serves him well in those situations. He can begin with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>" and
end with an effective "so, actually, no," without ever making anyone look bad.
Which is, perhaps, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> definition of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> announced that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last quarter</TIMEX>, its earnings missed
estimates and its revenue grew <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 2 percent</NUMEX> . So you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
will have to pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> for the foreseeable future, that
gets dragged into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> (and sometimes loses) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> , and that keeps
seeing the price of its key product rise because of taxes, and that's
making less money than expected. It's all <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider 's</ENAMEX> fault, no
doubt."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> reported that among the myriad class-action
lawsuits filed against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s finding is
a brief claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s principal place of business is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and
another describing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> of 'generic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.' That
brief adds that the term API stands for 'active pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredient</ENAMEX>.' (It
doesn't.) I'm waiting for the brief accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> of running Area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> and
being responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell Incident</ENAMEX>. In that brief, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">API</ENAMEX> will presumably
stand for 'alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> investigation.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Before entering into negotiations for a possible three-way deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter & Gamble</ENAMEX>
reportedly made an unsolicited bid for razor giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>. An article in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TheStreet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> said that 'the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>' had rebuffed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P&G</ENAMEX> . Well, we always thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. But who knew that it was actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "The best ad for financial advice right now is one for something
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dines Letter</ENAMEX>, which will cost you only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$195</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. At the top of
the ad, in capital letters, are the words 'Buy Internets!' And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dines</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX>, is called '"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Original Internet Bug</ENAMEX> "
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TOIB</ENAMEX>)!' You could not make this stuff up if you tried."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX> announced dazzling earnings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the latest quarter</TIMEX>,
propelled not only by a much-anticipated boom in its investment banking
business but also by a remarkable influx of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36 billion</NUMEX> in new assets from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. The odd thing, of course, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> keep pouring money into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> , even though its market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> have been among the most
bearish--and therefore most wrong--of any major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. Never
underestimate the power of having a bull as your corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "Latest sign that the apocalypse ... no, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> came and went, so this is
just the latest sign that things are getting too weird : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall</ENAMEX>
Street Journal headlined a recent article : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Web Frenzy Sweeps Firms</ENAMEX>
Selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goods for Cleaning</ENAMEX> .' Let's pray the last word in that headline
never gets changed to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'Burial</NUMEX>.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben & Jerry</ENAMEX>'s ice-cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> from across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> rallied
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to protest a possible takeover of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben & Jerry</ENAMEX>'s by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that has yet to be identified. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchisees</ENAMEX> fear that the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> will wreck <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben & Jerry</ENAMEX>'s commitment to 'social responsibility,'
presumably by doing things like changing the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cherry Garcia to Bing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherry Crosby</ENAMEX> and the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rainforest Crunch to Burn the Rainforest To the</ENAMEX>
Ground Surprise."

         
      
   
