
   
   
      
         
            Take <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Tabloids and Call Me in the Morning</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>--

            Oddly, in midtown, it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a balmy 72 degrees</NUMEX>. You really ought to come up here
for a visit; it's lovely.

            OK, so it's actually freezing cold here--colder than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s heart, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> like to say. Or as I like to imagine they like to say.

            Since there seems to be no earth-shattering news in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s papers, let's go
right to my favorite story: the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doorman</ENAMEX>, retiring from the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Plaza</ENAMEX>
Hotel. What I like about this story is that it's a perfect tabloid story--a
heart-tugging human-interest piece, with lots of celebrity names--and, since
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> were clearly tipped off to it, it provides an ideal opportunity
to compare and contrast the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>

               News . As it happens, their coverage confirms a long-held belief of mine:
You don't mess with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gersh Kuntzman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuntzman</ENAMEX> is, as best I can tell,
responsible for something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the text that appears in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>. You can find his byline all through a typical day's paper, usually
appended to a few news items and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> human-interest story, written
with all the tough-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>-with-a-heart-of-gold panache you expect from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>, but so rarely get. I like to imagine him as the sort of newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> you'd see in movies from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>, pounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dusk</ENAMEX>, picking up tips from shoeshine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and calling his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>."

            For an object lesson in the magic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gersh Kuntzman</ENAMEX>, compare the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Plaza-doorman</ENAMEX> stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> do a
fine job of hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s career highlights (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Gleason</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana Turner</ENAMEX>). But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> glosses over the reason for his retirement
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Szorentini</ENAMEX> decided that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> would be his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> ..."). Gersh,
however, gets the scoop: "'I wouldn't be leaving this job if it weren't for my
heart.' ... 'I feel like I've lost everything,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Szorentini</ENAMEX> said, crying ..."
Advantage: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            This actually ties in with my earlier thought, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, about the division
of labor between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s papers: It's actually far more finely nuanced than
I initially said. It's not just that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> handles the serious news,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News and Post</ENAMEX> handle the fun, frivolous stuff. There are
also subdivisions among the tabloids: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has better gossip, more
celebrity coverage, and, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gersh Kuntzman</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> has better
TV coverage, better city-news coverage, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doonesbury</ENAMEX>." You really have to
buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> if you want to make one whole one--and the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , if you'd like a business section, plus lifestyle pieces on how to
spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> in a hurry.

            As for the character issue, it seems to me to be a convenient canard to
distract attention from the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' real differences run the
gamut from A to... well, pretty much A. It's not so much that they're all
saying the same thing--there are some substantive differences in their
approaches to policy--as it is that the public has by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> picked up the sense
that those differences won't necessarily result in substantially different
outcomes in the long run. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is not, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>--he has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to contend with, and even once a law has been passed, it doesn't
necessarily mean that it'll be enforced. The barriers between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s
rhetoric and his achievable results mean that the two bear the same relation
that an original document does to its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 th</NUMEX> photocopy. So, like I
said, the character thing is a canard. Which means "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>." Perhaps, instead of
focusing on the character issue, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> should groom a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> to be his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, and we could all grade them on grooming, behavior, ability to
do tricks, and the like. I'd like that.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
