
   
   
      
         
            Early <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Recently Uncovered</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>--

            You're absolutely right about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' trying to frustrate and annoy their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. It's the best explanation I can come up with for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuahua</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, all those things you criticized about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>--the pumped-in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">windowless rooms</ENAMEX>--are to me the very things
that make them special, magical places.

            So, I was thinking about our discussion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of which newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnists</ENAMEX> makes us laugh, and I forgot my favorite--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>'s ramblings in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . Now, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> cracks me up. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, he name-drops so
often even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cavett</ENAMEX> is embarrassed for him, and his commentary is so
lightweight it makes our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>" read like a dialogue
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX>. (The philosopher, not the dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diff'rent Strokes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.) Anyway, that got me to thinking: What would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> have done if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> had existed in, say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>?

            

               I saw The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graduate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. I don't get it. Looks like my good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend William Daniels</ENAMEX> blew it on this one. ... I walked down the aisle
recently and I have to tell you, if there's something greater than the sanctity
of marriage, I have yet to find it. Well, maybe a pack of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lucky Strikes</ENAMEX>. ... If
you're looking for a good laugh, check out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accidental Family</ENAMEX> , starring
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Van Dyke</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>. ... I was talking to family friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Nixon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and he's making rumblings about coming out of
retirement and running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. If he wins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, I guarantee
he'll bring real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and leadership to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. ... I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with him
back when he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassius Clay</ENAMEX>, but now that he insists on going by "Muhammad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>" and dodging the draft, we're not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> any more. ... Speaking of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam Conflict</ENAMEX>, I say we put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vietcong</ENAMEX> up against my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King Kong</ENAMEX> and let
'em <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX> it out--my money's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just heard Sgt. Pepper</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Hearts Club Band</ENAMEX> . I don't get it. Good thing I'm not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX>. ... Is it just me, or has anyone else noticed that fashions are
getting a little wacky <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>? I'm going to have to give my ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> Coco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanel</ENAMEX> a call. ... My inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> tell me we'll have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the
moon no later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. Book it.

            

            Thanks for indulging me there, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>.

            So, are you as geeked up as I am about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s return to
basketball? I can't wait for the clips on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boo yeah</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> just signed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zagrav Pitroyviakch</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian League</ENAMEX> to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-day</TIMEX> contract!" "Did you
see how high up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> as he walked to his executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skybox</ENAMEX>?"
Anyway, I have no idea if you care, but I wanted to bring a little sports radio
fun to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
