
   
   
      
         
            Keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Education Vital</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ann</ENAMEX>,

            How can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> get and keep excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>? Good question! I do
think that a good curriculum is part of the answer. And I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Core</ENAMEX>
Curriculum is a good start. From what I've read, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirsch</ENAMEX> has sane ideas about
reading, which is no small thing. I like his emphasis on biographies and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mythology</ENAMEX> in the younger grades. He gives an important place to music and art,
a good idea from my point of view. His curriculum is fairly new and is
currently used in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and I suspect that in time, and
as more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> adopt the program, the curriculum will evolve. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirsch</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> are open-minded, and they seem to be, they will want to
experiment with variations.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s credit, he has chosen to promote a pretty solid curriculum. He
could have picked one of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>-proof" regimens that have teachers
reciting scripted lessons <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long. I understand that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are
relieved to have such a script, but I am sure that with guidance, most of them
would be happier using a more open-ended approach. The question is, how to give
such guidance? Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> can certainly help. I agree with you that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> does not draw a satisfactory picture of what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX>'s role should
be.

            By the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> play an important role in attracting good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.
Decent wages and working conditions are not a side issue. I suppose it's not
surprising that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> would be hostile to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, considering that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> usually support the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. But I wish he had
recognized how many helpful things the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> do, not just in regard to wages
and working conditions. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> runs a program called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dial-A-Teacher</ENAMEX> that answers homework questions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haitian-Creole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, which is really quite
useful. (Give it a try: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">212-777-3380</ENAMEX>.) This sort of program is much more than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> gimmick. Not that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> are perfect.

            I have to make a confession about school choice. I became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in the
1970s because I was deeply affected by the books of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Kohl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
Kozol, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Dennison</ENAMEX>. At that time, I believed that the public schools
were hopeless. The conditions were too dreadful. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> were too racist. The system was intractable. What to do? For a
lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> like me, the answer was to start our own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--which at the time meant private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Now the
sides have changed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX>, like me, understand that our society had better
make the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> have given up. I was
wrong--<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mea culpa</ENAMEX>--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is wrong <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Farsighted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> have shown that you can make superior public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> even in poor
neighborhoods. There is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the public-school system, more than there used
to be, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with ambition and ideas. True, there is a risk that in
promoting public-school alternatives, neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> will be left with
the most difficult-to-educate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and not enough resources to meet the
task. As for charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, I don't think we have enough information yet.
Charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that operate outside of the bureaucratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, and in some places that might be good, in other places not so good.
Concerning vouchers, my fear is that they will undermine a sense of the public
good in education.

            I agree with you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is promoting a get-it-for-your-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> attitude.
So what if some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are left in the lurch, is the implication. It is not
a very attractive idea of what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society should be like. Still <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s
book has some good ideas, too (as you and I agree) and it has given us the
opportunity to bat around our own ideas, which has been fun.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Peggy</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
