
   
   
      
         
            The <i>Times</i> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Job</ENAMEX>
            

            You know, one of the consequences of watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blazing Saddles</ENAMEX> many
times, at an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>, is that I can never see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hedy Lamarr</ENAMEX>'s name without
recalling this classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> from that movie:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Front of Grauman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Theater</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>! I'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hedy Lamarr</ENAMEX>'s
shoes!"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Korman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Playing a Character Named Hedley Lamarr:</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irritably</ENAMEX>.) "That's
Hedley!"

            

            It is much, much funnier than it seems here. I guess, for the joke to work,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Korman</ENAMEX> has to say it. And how often is that the case?

            So, I think our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>" time is winding down. One final item: Did
you see that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Rosenthal</ENAMEX> now has a column at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> ?
I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> I'd least like to have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>--aside from Hedy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamarr</ENAMEX>--is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who had to report this story. I have this
image of him wandering around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX>, saying, "So, what word do I use to
describe the circumstances under which he left? Do I ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX> about whether or
not he's bitter? Do I make it seem like a coup for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> ? Can I use
the term 'widely unread' to describe 'On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Mind'?</ENAMEX>" (The answers, as best I can
tell from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Collins</ENAMEX>' story: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Departed</ENAMEX>." No. Yes. No.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> is quoted
as saying that he doesn't know what his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> column is going to be about. I'm
wagering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks it's titled, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Max Frankel Is a Wuss</ENAMEX>." Any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
