
   
   
      
         
            Surplush

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with a surprisingly large revised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX>
estimate of the federal budget surplus, now thought to be as much as a
boom-driven <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.9 trillion</NUMEX>, nearly, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> estimate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> gives its whole above-the-fold space to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s snowstorm, pushing the surplus down below the fold. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' top non-local story is the research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bombshell</ENAMEX> that the standard
long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">estrogen</ENAMEX>/progestin replacement therapy for menopause substantially
increases the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, a story also fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box is topped by
the new surplus estimate, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stuffs to Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>.

            The coverage states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the leading presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> quickly weighed in on how they would variously divvy up the surplus
among tax cuts, spending, debt reduction, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
reinforcement. But the front pages contain a built-in reminder not to spend the
money just yet: The surplus stories are juxtaposed with reporting about how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Coast</ENAMEX>'s blizzard was such a surprise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather Service</ENAMEX> used a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> supercomputer and enhanced software to
predict a "total accumulation less than one inch."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and LAT make it clear that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> study
was quite extensive--conducted over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> and covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 46,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says high up that it impacts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.6 million</NUMEX> post-menopausal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> doesn't mention menopause until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>
paragraph and never mentions the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at risk. Both stories mention
that progestin also reduces the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX>, which prompts a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX>: It would be helpful if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> would get in the habit of
accompanying stories about the particular potential cancer risk of a given
substance with a graphic summarizing all its known <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> plusses and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">minuses</ENAMEX>.

            The papers go inside with the latest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli√°n Gonz√</ENAMEX>°lez saga: After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> threatened the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
with revocation of his permission to temporarily reside in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relented</ENAMEX> and agreed to allow his visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> to see him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">feds</ENAMEX> also made it clear to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>-moms that they will not be allowed to take
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eli√°n</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> at this time.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> dispatch saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is implementing new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vetting</ENAMEX> procedures designed to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Web sites from containing state
secrets--which in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the paper explains, means virtually any information
not specifically approved for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> follows up its report
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> would require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> doing business
in-country to reveal their encryption software. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s development is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s spy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will help ensure compliance. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the paper
explains, are worried that providing this information will lead to rampant
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knockoffs</ENAMEX>. Although technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> aren't saying much officially
about this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says some will, rather than surrender source
code, simply halt exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that all the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> submit to
interviews about their pre-political lives in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> special airing
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where Were You</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>? All, that is, except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>,
who instead dispatches a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to sing his praises. The result,
says the paper, is that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who comes across like he's
got a closet bursting with frat house skeletons."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Guy Tucker</ENAMEX>, who had
been pressured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> into cooperating with their
investigation as part of a guilty plea deal, was hired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> cable TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX>. This is
significant, the paper explains, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riady</ENAMEX> was previously suspected of
paying large consulting fees to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s silence on
various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> topics.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an editorial and a letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> bearing on the
controversy sparked when a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> said that cabdrivers should
for their own safety refuse to pick up "dangerous-looking" young black male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and avoid taking fares to "dangerous neighborhoods." Both the
editorial and the letter (from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> cab commission) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that
failing to serve potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> because of their race and redlining of
neighborhoods are both banned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> rules. As they should be. But
there's a complication here that both the editorial and the letter overlook,
but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> cannot: Although the local rules say a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> cannot
ignore a fare on the basis of "personal appearance," this obviously can't mean
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> must see threatening behavior before refusing to pick someone up.
Imagine for instance that you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and around the corner from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">county</ENAMEX> jail you are peacefully flagged down by a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a bright orange
jumpsuit stamped "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">County Jail</ENAMEX>." You'd be nuts to pick him up and no
law could possibly make it otherwise, even though he only looks like
trouble.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> writes a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that poses a good question:
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> have discounted his recent heart episodes,
would a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> examining him to determine eligibility for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> health
and disability policy agree? Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> ought to pose this question to
some insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> docs.

         
      
   
