
   
   
      
         
            Smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Very Bad for You</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>--

            Did you go to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp? I went for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, and the one thing I could
never get used to was that awful feeling I got in my stomach on the last
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. I would wake up--the final bars of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stairway to Heaven</ENAMEX>" still running
through my head from the last dance, the smell of smoke still in my hair from
the last campfire--and my heart would be filled with despair, knowing that in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a few short</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> would arrive to transport me from the warm
nurturing womb of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp back to the harsh, unfriendly place that is the
Real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>. Well, that's how I felt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>."
So let's make sure we exchange numbers and stay in touch ... you know, even
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>. And we'll see each other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, right? Right, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>?
Sigh. Oh, and sorry about participating in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tie Tim Down</ENAMEX> and Beat Him on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stomach With Soap Wrapped in a Towel Night</ENAMEX>," but everyone else in the bunk
went along with it.

            Now on to the news.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> you expressed a desire to antagonize the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray</ENAMEX>" and I don't know
about you, but I've been somewhat disappointed in our results. Despite our
attempts, almost zero outrage. So let me try with this one: Smoking is very bad
for you. And, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> government
agrees with me, as it proposed radical new cigarette packaging rules yesterday
that would force <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to create cigarette packs that carry color
photographs of diseased hearts and cancerous lungs and lips.

            Look, I think everyone should be warned of the dangers of smoking. I think
every cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> and ad should have a warning label, and a straightforward
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at that. (I propose: "Smoking is very bad for you.") I'm glad they've
banned cigarettes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and public spaces in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so I don't have
to breathe in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Butts</ENAMEX>' secondhand smoke. But I think that as long as someone
is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> (key word there; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scumbags</ENAMEX> who sell cigarettes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should be
treated to a heavy dose of state-sponsored torture), then let them enjoy their
pack-a-day trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlboro Country</ENAMEX>. They know what they're getting into. It's
not like the story about the smoking/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> link got buried on Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C27</TIMEX> under
an item about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary Club</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawn sprinkler</ENAMEX>.

            Oh, and let me say that my feelings are not based on some sort of
well-considered, long-held libertarian principle. I just came up with this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> an hour ago, because I have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>, and when I go to
visit them I don't want to stop at a convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> for a pack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> and
have to look at a display case of diseased lung photos. It's worth noting that
the redesigned cigarette packs would also carry a warning: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigarettes</ENAMEX> may
cause sexual impotence due to decreased blood flow to the penis. This can
prevent you from having an erection." Yeah, and so can looking at pictures of
diseased hearts and lungs.

            On the other hand, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wants to force <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> to
print time-lapse photos of a nail dissolving in a glass of their product, then
go for it. Are you with me on this?

         
      
   
