
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Lots of impressive earnings reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> from the usual suspects
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gateway</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, among others), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tech</ENAMEX> stocks remained fairly strong. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> took it on the chin, perhaps
because (if you're feeling cynical) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who invest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> stocks are the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who still worry about things like rising interest rates or perhaps
because (if you're feeling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>-school rational) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> has more stocks in
it that will be hit hard by a cyclical slowdown than does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>. The truth
is it's hard to say.

            In any case, the merger wave continued, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glaxo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SmithKline Beecham</ENAMEX>
announcing engagement plans. The news sent both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' stocks down sharply,
but their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> never stopped smiling. The thing is, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, we were
supposed to have understood that most mergers don't work, and that when the
stock market punishes both stocks, the merger really won't work. But
then I remember: Even now, the stock market doesn't run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> who like
the idea of running as big a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as can be imagined do. And so, on to this

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Products</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter & Gamble</ENAMEX> are trying to concoct a three-way
deal to 'foil' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$78.9 billion</NUMEX> hostile bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> used the word 'foil,' but surprisingly, it did not run a
photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> twirling his black mustache."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "The interest rate on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bond is now actually lower
than the interest rate on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bond. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
think it's safer to lend money for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> than for a short time
(relatively speaking, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX> the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> was still
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>). Apparently bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> are now anticipating a steep decline in the
already low inflation rate, beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter of 2007</TIMEX>."

            2a. "Do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soylent Green</ENAMEX> will really be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>? I hope
not."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>-page response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s finding of fact in its antitrust case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> compared its
desire to control the presentation of Windows on PC screens to 
                  Monty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Python</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flying Circus</ENAMEX>
               ' desire to avoid having its shows edited
without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX>'s input. This means, of course, that if the case ever gets
to the penalty phase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> will have to demand, before everything
else, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX> bring him a shrubbery, lest he have to
say 'Ni!' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Best headline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>: 'Mannesmann, Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Attack</ENAMEX>, Looks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> .' Presumably praying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petain</ENAMEX> is running some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecom giant</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schumer</ENAMEX> is taking a lot of heat for
supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to extend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to prescription-drug
coverage after taking campaign contributions from a couple of big drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> . But since the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have firmly opposed the expansion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> before semi-caving recently, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> did was take their money
and then sell them out. With <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s campaign-finance system, that's probably
as close to clean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as we're going to get."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Berger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Investment</ENAMEX> hedge fund, admitted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> that he had been lying about his annual performance to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in his fund for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past four years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> was a well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bear</ENAMEX>,
and over that same period often published letters warning that the stock market
was on the verge of a crash, but despite the fact that the crash never came,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> kept giving him their money . Well, I guess there were
Millerites even after the world didn't end in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "Oil prices jumped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, due to cold weather in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> . That's certainly sensible. After all, who really knows if this
winter thing is really a pattern or just a statistical fluke<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
