
   
   
      
         
            These <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boots Are Made for Measuring</ENAMEX> Snowfall
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey Johnette</ENAMEX>--

            Oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, you're going to get me started on those money-grubbing old geezers
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>, aren't you? Oh well, here goes ...

            I cringe when I hear someone refer to "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> scandal," because,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLC</ENAMEX> weren't right, the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">culprits</ENAMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> members
with their hands out, palms up. As you know, I've written <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a half-dozen</NUMEX>
times that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Antonio Samaranch</ENAMEX> should resign. Obviously, he disagrees.

            I can't believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> are letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> get away
with this recent charade on, ah-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hem</ENAMEX>, reform. Those new gadgets and gimmicks the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> put into place so a scandal like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s doesn't occur again are so
much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> and mirrors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> still runs everything, even its new ethics
commission. The outside influence is minimal. And yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> don't scream
and stomp their feet; they simply want it to go away--and, maybe in our hearts,
all of us do too. For even as I cover the "reform" package and rant and rave
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> deception, I say: Get me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>. Get me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> trials.
Get me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, and to their remarkable and emotional stories.

            It's kind of like getting all worked up about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> is doing if
you love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Flutie</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> Bills. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> is to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flutie</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samaranch</ENAMEX>
is to, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion Jones</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX>, figurehead, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. But
invisible on the field of play. And of no interest to us whatsoever once the
game or race begins.

            This scandal did produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my favorite anecdotes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>'s
crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> of all the bribe-taking and other nonsense was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Pound</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who got into big trouble on the
bribe-front was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Coles</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. And, I might add, a
very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Pound</ENAMEX>'s.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pound</ENAMEX> has to interrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coles</ENAMEX> to find out what he did and, ultimately,
whether he stays or goes. The question-and-answer session occurs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lausanne</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one afternoon</TIMEX>.

            When it ends, everyone heads off to dinner.

            And who does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pound</ENAMEX> go to dinner with?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Coles</ENAMEX>.

            I know it will shock you to find out that, even as we speak, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Coles</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in good standing of the venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX>.

            Yeah, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> trial was bizarre, but as far as I know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ito</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> never, ever, fought over a check at the dinner table.

            As I said, get me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>, get me to the opening ceremony and the torch
and the hymns, and I'll be fine.

            Before I go, I must share this Snowstorm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> media story:

            A TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> standing in a suburban neighborhood <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: "Some people
use yardsticks to measure how much snow we've had. I use little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Come
here, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>. Here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, hold this microphone."
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> takes microphone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> picks up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and plunks him down
softly in the snow. Then pulls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> right out and examines his boots.)

            "According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s boots, we've had <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about six inches</NUMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
