
   
   
      
         
            Something <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Talk About</ENAMEX>
            

            I'm sort of ashamed to admit, I don't often read newspaper humor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>--or newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> in general. My memory, from the time when I
did read <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> regularly, is that even the very best of them tend to bat
around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.300</NUMEX>. This is not, I suspect, their fault: The economics of newspapers
and the tastes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> more or less dictate that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> has to appear
at least twice, and preferably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,400</NUMEX> words. Very
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can turn out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,400</NUMEX> words of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">penetrating insight</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. As a
result, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> often tend to turn to filler--mock outrage over the scandal
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>; rants on solidly uncontroversial topics (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie Gallagher</ENAMEX>, I noticed, devoted an entire column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to advancing
the rather daring notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> should not have sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>); and,
in certain cases, paeans to the comforts of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. I'm pretty sure that
there are few fates worse than being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> struggling with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> and a deadline. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, I could easily imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>
Quindlen turning to one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and saying, "Please, for the love of God,
say something innocent yet wise! And if it could have some bearing on a
contemporary issue, all the better!"

            Again, I'm not really blaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> here: They have a deadline to
meet; they have space to fill. They do what they have to do. But I do think
they're symptomatic of a larger problem: Journalistic overcapacity. Which is to
say, we now have so many news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>, with so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, that we are now
saying far more than needs to be said, covering far more than needs to be
covered. I might suggest that many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>scandals that pop up and
dominate the news for a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> do so not because anyone's legitimately
upset or outraged over them but because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you and (especially) me
need something to talk about. Thus, all the silly debates over, say, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flag-burning</ENAMEX> amendment, or the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" show. Sure, the discussions tend to
be reductive and overheated. But at least they're something to fill <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour of</TIMEX>
Hardball .

            (This, in turn, ties into a favorite fantasy of mine: I am invited to appear
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardball With Chris Matthews</ENAMEX> to debate, say, flag burning. I am
introduced as being for it. I give my little speech: "They give such warmth,
and oh the rosy glow ..." And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>--let's imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>--lights into me: "An outrage ... should be ashamed to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ...
an enduring symbol of our national freedom, freedoms which you so clearly don't
deserve ..." And so on. To which I reply, "You know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton</ENAMEX>--may I call you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton</ENAMEX>? No? OK--I never thought about it that way. Never thought about it
that way at all. And now that you mention it, you're quite right: It is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">travesty</ENAMEX>. I agree with you completely." We are now about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> into the
broadcast. What we do with the remaining <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">55 minutes</TIMEX> is a mystery to me.)

         
      
   
