
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crook</ENAMEX>?
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18</TIMEX>, amid revelations that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Democratic Union</ENAMEX> accepted
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.4 million deutsche marks</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX>) in secret contributions, former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> resigned as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kohl</ENAMEX>
claims he used the funds for legitimate "party-building" activities, but
refuses to name a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> to clarify the situation. Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> done anything
illegal? If so, what would the punishment be?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> campaign-finance law places no limit on contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>,
requiring only that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 20,000 deutsche marks</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,500</NUMEX>) per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> be identified in an annual report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>. (Contributions to
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are unregulated.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX> committed a civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> by
ignoring this law, and now faces punitive fines totaling twice the undisclosed
contributions, in addition to having to forfeit the actual contributions to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fines</ENAMEX> are deducted from the campaign subsidies the government
gives to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.) 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> must also report expenditures on broad categories like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>" and "political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>" in their annual report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX> failed to report expenditures of the undisclosed contributions as well, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> insists he used the money for building the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>'s refusal to name names is not illegal--the only illegality surrounding
the funds was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s original failure to disclose them. For political
reasons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX> may try to force him to talk by suing for "breach of trust,"
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> would still have to pay the fines.

            While an internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX> audit has now uncovered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.3 million</NUMEX> worth of
undisclosed contributions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1989 and 1998</TIMEX>, much of the money trail
remains obscured by secret bank accounts. So secret, in fact, that the scheme
came to light only by chance, when a tax probe of a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasurer</ENAMEX>
revealed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$550,000</NUMEX> in contributions from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arms dealer</ENAMEX>. The dealer
allegedly sought to ease the sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Panzer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>.

            The scandal continues to widen. Allegations have emerged suggesting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
conglomerate paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$44 million</NUMEX> in bribes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX> to encourage the sale of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> government-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refinery</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 22</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> television speculated that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> transferred <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15.4 million</NUMEX> of that amount to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX> as
part of the transaction.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> could face criminal prosecution if it turns out he accepted bribes for
specific government action. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> would have to establish an exchange
of money for the desired action.) He currently enjoys parliamentary immunity,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> would almost certainly suspend it at prosecutorial request.

            Some say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>'s handiwork reflects an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> fund-raising style
unprecedented in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> politics. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law prohibits individual
contributions in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> per year (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $20,000</NUMEX> to a national party
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> to state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given year</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $1,000</NUMEX> to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given election</TIMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law also prohibits contributions from any individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> or
partnership doing business with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and requires a "best effort" to
obtain the name, address, occupation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> of every individual
contributing over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>. 

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl-Heinz Nassmacher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl von Ossietzky</ENAMEX>
University in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oldenburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.
            

            Next question?

         
      
   
