
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Modernist Ice Sculpture</ENAMEX>
            

            Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> could start a regular feature: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On This Day</ENAMEX> in
(fill in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King Said</ENAMEX> ..."

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12, 36000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>: Caught an elk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. It was very tasty. ... If you
ask me, this fire thing isn't gonna last. ...

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 26, 0</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> born <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. Seems like a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. ...
How 'bout them Magi?. ... What is myrrh, anyway?

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 8, 1601</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s latest, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> , is a pip, but
it's no "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faerie Queen</ENAMEX>." ...

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16, 1865</TIMEX>: A pity about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln</ENAMEX>. ... I like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>. ...

            

            By the way, speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>, where has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey Adams</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just for Laughs"</ENAMEX> column gone? I know he's dead and all, but
still.

            In other news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has made up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> story with a whole slew of wonderful news items. For instance,
according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s "Business Bulletin," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Boat</ENAMEX> parties, casino <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>, and
mashed-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato bars</ENAMEX> are out." A corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner</ENAMEX> explains that potato
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bars</ENAMEX>, which feature "martini glasses filled with whipped mashed potatos and
accompanied by an assortment of toppings," are declining in popularity, which
astonishes me, because I'd never heard of such a thing in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Have
you? I've never been handed a martini glass full of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> in my life. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner</ENAMEX>, the delightfully named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Feely</ENAMEX>, also explains the drop-off in
casino <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and events held on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are tired of being trapped."
Sounds about right to me.

            The same column also features the following news item: "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plymouth International Ice Sculpture</ENAMEX>
Spectacular is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Wakar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX> He wins with an 'abstract' ice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carving</ENAMEX>, which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> described as indescribable." These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sentences
have made me happier than anything I've read in a very long time.

            Meanwhile, did you see that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedy Lamarr</ENAMEX> has died? News like this always
seems to me to be twofold: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hedy Lamarr</ENAMEX> has died; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hedy Lamarr</ENAMEX> was, until
very recently, alive. Who knew? Whenever I read an obit like this--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myrna Loy's</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, comes to mind--I always have the same, irrational thought:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey</ENAMEX>! I could have called her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>!" Not that I would have. But I could
have, if I'd wanted to.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
