
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Learn Liposuction</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>--

            Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Now you've done it. You've brought up my single favorite TV show
name of all time: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shasta McNasty</ENAMEX> . It's just fun to say: Shasta
McNasty, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shasta McNasty, Shasta McNasty</ENAMEX>. Say it loud, and there's music
playing; say it soft, and it's almost like praying. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shasta McNasty</ENAMEX>.

            Yeah, I saw that story about the placement of anti-drug messages, and, while
I agree with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> in general that this has the potential to devolve
into propaganda, I also happen to believe that anyone who does anything just
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blossom</ENAMEX> told him to gets whatever he deserves.

            In other news, I neglected to mention yesterday my single favorite sentence
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, from a story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>-in-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box Corp.</ENAMEX>'s annual report: "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> report opens with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> pages of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">verse</ENAMEX>, narrated by fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO 'Jack</ENAMEX>,' a sometimes-evil clown with a head
that resembles a ping-pong ball." I'm sure 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can fill
in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gergen</ENAMEX> joke here.

            As for my favorite sentence from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s papers, there's no contest. From a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> story on the dangers of plastic surgery, a quotation from
plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Rohrich</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> should assume nothing. Anybody can do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liposuction</ENAMEX>. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> have been doing it." Which, to me, suggests three
things: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, from here on out, no matter what procedure I go in for, it's
local anesthetic for me. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I foresee a boom in correspondence-school
"learn liposuction at home!" programs. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, of course, is that this
suggests a new lyric for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX> standard, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let's Do It</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let's Fall In</ENAMEX>
Love)": "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Birds</ENAMEX> do it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> do it/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> should assume nothing, even dentists
have been doing it/ Let's do it, let's fall in love."

            By the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is bad. May I have my check now, please?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
