
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bitchiest Debates</ENAMEX>
            

            Hmmm. I see a way to kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stone here. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> recently,
imprudently, trimmed the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">McNasty</ENAMEX>" from the title of Shasta
McNasty , rendering it a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shasta</ENAMEX> . Here's a way for them to boost
their ratings, repair their grievous show-naming error, and still save face:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley McNasty Smackdown</ENAMEX>!" I'd watch.

            Actually, your point about the taunting in presidential debates brings up an
interesting point: There have never been any presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> possessed
of great wit. Or even medium wit. Even the best moments from presidential
debates, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s "I paid for this microphone," were transparently
scripted well in advance. More often, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> throw around canned
insults that were a) written by ghostwriters; and (b) aren't very good. The
best example of this that comes to mind is the clumsy taunt aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>, that answer was about as clear as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Harbor</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ooooooh</ENAMEX>. The
closest we've come to a great moment of unpremeditated nastiness during a
debate was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Bentsen</ENAMEX>'s "You're no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX>" line, and that has at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> caveats: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, it was during a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential debate. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I'm
guessing that it probably was scripted well in advance, but at least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bentsen</ENAMEX>
had the ability to make it appear off-the-cuff. And finally, it was used on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, which is sort of like using a sledgehammer on a drugged baby seal.

            I know that there are those who say politics have become too nasty and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">personalized</ENAMEX>, that debates should be thoughtful discussions of policy issues.
And, ideally, I suppose that would be the case. But it isn't. Instead, what we
tend to get are safe, silly bromides--"I believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s best days are ahead
of us," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> say, waiting for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> to jump up and scream,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liar</ENAMEX>!"--mixed in with ad hominem attacks. So, these being the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>, couldn't the debates at least be amusing? Couldn't we get some ace
script <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in there to write bitchy, scathing lines for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>? Are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine May</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Rudnick</ENAMEX> really too busy to come up with bon mots for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>: "... and finally, I'd support a massive tax cut for the middle
class, enabling us to continue our proud tradition of freedom in this great
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of ours."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>: "I heartily endorse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s proposals. They make a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal of sense. (Beat.) If you've been smoking crack, that is. You
haven't, have you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>? Lately, I mean? Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, I know you probably
weren't paying much attention in college--that was, after all, during your
reckless youth, which lasted until you were, what, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>?--but a basic rule of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> is that you can't spend what you don't have. Or, to put this in terms
you'll understand, you've got a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> bill, and you're trying to buy a dime bag.
Are you following me now? Nod your head yes if you understand me. Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>."

            

            Admit it. You'd be appalled for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but you wouldn't be able to
take your eyes off the set.

            In other news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> 's "Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>" reports that a movie
produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Corman</ENAMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> has received an NC-
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> for a nude scene featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Sheffer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psycho</ENAMEX> has also received an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX>, also for a nude scene. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> thoughts:
First, when is the MPAA going to begin charging distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> extra
for handing out <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17s</ENAMEX>? They are, after all, the single surest way for a movie
to get reams of advance publicity, and yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> doesn't make a dime off
them. The cost of taking out an ad proclaiming, "We've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock</ENAMEX> in a
nude scene!"? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>. The cost of having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> announce it?
Practically nil. Seems to me there should be some way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Valenti</ENAMEX> to make
some change off of this.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question is, of course, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock</ENAMEX> is doing in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corman</ENAMEX> movie. I'm worried about her. Speed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope Floats</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Forces</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> . Now this. Should one of us call her, make sure she's
OK?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
