
   
   
      
         
            What's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Op-Ed IQ</ENAMEX>?

            
               Questions are derived from the op-ed pages of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27, 2000</TIMEX>. Be sure not
to click on links till after you answer all of them:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Which of these passages was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, and which was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "In popular imagination, this has always been a white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>: block after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> of pale marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that glow even whiter at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, when the
floodlights come into play. Under snow, its classical shapes--<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX> and
pediments, octagons and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>--are linked in a geometry that remains
generally pure, thanks to the speed with which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shuts down at the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sight of falling flakes."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swinburne</ENAMEX> insisted that even the weariest river winds somewhere
safe to sea. The same cannot be said of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s presidential candidacies. All
but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of which will soon end, in an atmosphere out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poe</ENAMEX>."

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. What adjective does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Hunt</ENAMEX> use to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Murphy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "energetic"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "shrewd"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> "irrepressible"
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> "seasoned"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> "smart"

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Stearns</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Offices</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Vision</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Christian Humanitarian Organization</ENAMEX>," has an op-ed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> pegged to what
event:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The State of the Union</ENAMEX> address
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. The U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX>'s choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Blix</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">inspector</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> The announcement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Award</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E. A</ENAMEX> planned anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarzana</ENAMEX>

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Fill in the blank from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Goodman</ENAMEX>:

            "If all we do is save a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> for display, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">panda bear</ENAMEX> will become
nothing but _________ from an extinct world. But, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindburg</ENAMEX>, 'if you
protect the panda, you're protecting the golden <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>, the monal pheasants,
the takins.' An entire environment."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "a cuddly memory"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "an adorable artifact"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> "a precious puffball"
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s stuffed animal based on memories"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> "a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>-confined rarity"

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. What is the only thing that could bring back the oil shocks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Chapman</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "an outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "the death of reason in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> "revitalization of that sleeping monster, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> "an unhealthy obsession with oil industry profits"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> "revival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> BTU tax proposal"

            

            
               Answers are printed below. If you scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> correctly, call
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creators Syndicate Inc.</ENAMEX>; you've probably found your calling. If you scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
correctly, you may appear on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX> . If you scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
correctly, you may appear on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> letters page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. If you scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> correctly, you may deliver a paper at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s
you may post a message on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray</ENAMEX>" page. If you scored none
correctly, you may phone in a question to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early-morning call-in</TIMEX>
show.
            

            Answers:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B</ENAMEX> is Will
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. C
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. B
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. B
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. A
            

         
      
   
