
   
   
      
         
            One <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">System Does Not Fit All</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ann</ENAMEX>,

            As I see it, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> separate issues--what topics are being taught,
how much homework <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get, and what approach is used for teaching. With that
in mind, let me continue for a minute on the question of what topics are being
taught.

            The debate between covering-a-smaller-number-of-topics-in-depth versus
getting-all-the-facts-into-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid-heads</ENAMEX> has raged, is raging, and will rage as
long as there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to teach. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> wants to believe that you can
teach in depth and in breadth at the same time. But when I read him, I can't
help thinking that the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of education has never actually been a
grade-school classroom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, at least not for long. I know that many schools
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Core Curriculum</ENAMEX>, whose emphasis is breadth, are doing a good job. I'm
willing to bet, though, that the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> prune the lists
in order to spend more time on specific topics--diminish the breadth for the
sake of depth. (This is usually the secret of first-rate education: No matter
how radical a new curriculum may be, the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have always quietly
moderated it.)

            My worry about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s lack of teaching experience struck me especially
while reading the math section in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Educated Child</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> presents a
perfectly reasonable sequence of math skills. But he also launches into a
rather startling anti-math rap. Math is hard work, he says. Math is not fun.
You shouldn't expect it to be fun. You must practice, practice, practice. He
assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will not like learning math and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will not have
the foggiest idea about what is going on. He even provides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> with the
solutions to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-grade math problems. I suppose this is necessary, in his
mind, since he makes a math error or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> himself. In his list of basic math
facts, he can't seem to get product and quotient straight when it comes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multiplying</ENAMEX> and dividing integers.

            I'd like to suggest he spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> polling <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-graders</ENAMEX> about their
favorite academic subject. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Math</ENAMEX>, he will soon discover, is far and away the
favorite of a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in particular, but that's another
discussion. Just as there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who have a seemingly natural affinity
for reading and others who have an amazing ability to imagine historical
events, there are those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> who just get numbers.

            Now to homework. You suggest that public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> assign more than private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. But in my experience, there are private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that assign a lot and
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that assign a little, and likewise with the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, some of the more traditional private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> load on homework. I
tutor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifth-graders</ENAMEX> who are at it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three, four</TIMEX>, and sometimes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five hours</TIMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Literally. Not wise, from my point of view. The load is lighter in
private progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, but there, too, by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knapsacks</ENAMEX> usually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bulge</ENAMEX>. In some of the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get a rigorous curriculum--with
homework to match. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is right about many of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. They
don't demand enough from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. I work next to a public high school and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to and from with sunken backpacks--when they have backpacks at all. The
new testing requirements for high-school graduation may change that, but I
haven't seen it in the backpacks yet.

            Leaving homework aside, though, which method is superior, progressive or
traditional? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> clearly sides with a traditional methodology that employs
some aspects of progressive thinking. That can work. I also think that for the
right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and with the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, an old-fashioned traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classroom</ENAMEX> can be a great place to learn. Personally, I prefer teaching in a
progressive style. But some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> require something more traditional. I
remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who needed help in math. I tried hard to give him insight
into the concepts that underlie addition and subtraction. I used blocks. I used
money. I used graph paper--progressive methods all. Finally the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> said to
me, "Just show me how to do it, and I'll figure out why I'm doing it later." It
was a light-bulb moment for me. Although most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> I work with learn best
when they go from the concept to the rote process, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> learned best
when I reversed my usual system.

            I have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, an exceptionally bright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, who was enrolled in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most prestigious traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. A real
drill-the-skill kind of place. He was floundering. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> he moved to a
progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and he is sailing along without problems.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> cannot fit all. And so,
although I can see standardizing the curriculum, at least to a degree, I worry
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> standardizing the approach to teaching. What does this mean about school
choice?--not that we can discuss everything.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Peggy</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
