
   
   
      
         
            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Careers Gone Bad</ENAMEX>
            

            I stand corrected, and hope that Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bullock</ENAMEX> can find it in her heart to
forgive me. Or acknowledge me, for that matter.

            Still, I think the larger point holds: Something bad has happened to her
career. It's like it had some tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> or something. Did you see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Practical Magic</ENAMEX> ? And have you seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> for her next movie, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Platt</ENAMEX>? It's rare to see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> such likeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in
such a shoddy-looking film. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: I haven't seen the movie. I've only
seen the trailer. The movie could be a work of staggering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. But somehow,
I doubt it. How often is the movie better than the trailer?)

            Along similar lines, what's happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX>? Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Phantom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menace</ENAMEX> , he's looked increasingly grim--he seemed to spend most of the
running time of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Haunting</ENAMEX> trying to visualize himself in another,
better movie. And now, there's this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock</ENAMEX> movie.

            And now that I come to think of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Platt</ENAMEX>, a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> of mine,
has gone from a terrific performance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulworth</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Placid</ENAMEX> ,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tango</ENAMEX> , and now, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock-Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> movie. I smell
a conspiracy here.

            In other news, any thoughts on who might win big at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globe</ENAMEX> awards?
Apart from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Press Association</ENAMEX>, which gets to pretend it's
a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, if only for a night? There's a part of me that's sort
of amazed and outraged that a small handful of mostly unqualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
throws an awards ceremony--a ceremony in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are notoriously
susceptible to the influence of personal meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, lavish luncheons,
and other perks--and everyone pretends that the whole thing is legit. But
there's another, larger part of me that's convinced that such a ceremony is
really the only appropriate way to honor achievement in the movie business. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> like to look down on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globes</ENAMEX> as
representing a triumph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist-mongering</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage maneuvering</ENAMEX>, and
star-worship over quality and substance. And I, for one, wouldn't have it any
other way. Any awards ceremony in which a trophy can't be bought for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pia</ENAMEX> Zadora
isn't being true to its industry.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
