
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Dependents</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
debates, which it describes as "personal and combative." The debates also top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with an
exclusive: the belief of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> that there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (one
of whom is now in custody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX>) who are connected to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>
and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Algerians</ENAMEX> arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last year</TIMEX> apparently in the midst of
carrying out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more bomb plots against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. The Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>'s
definitive position on the issue of what sort of home work activities must
comply with federal workplace health and safety regulations, a position taken
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first</ENAMEX> said all such activities were covered and then
later said in effect, never mind. The new rule: Ordinary white-collar work in a
household is not covered, but hazardous manufacturing work there is. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the latest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s mushrooming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> scandal:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>'s call for the quick dismissal of the cases against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
which the arrests were based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>' documented illegal activity, ranging
from lying to unprovoked shooting. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least three</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are in jail
right now.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's lead includes new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> polling that finds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent to 36 percent</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> ahead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 percent to 44 percent</NUMEX>. The story states the margin of error (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>
percent for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>) but forgets to tell
the size of the sample. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> have gotten
together to form a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polling Review Board</ENAMEX> that will monitor and discuss the flood
of political polls expected during the upcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election season</TIMEX>. One focus of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> will be scrutinizing and debunking online polls.

            The headlines over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' debate stories suggest that the press can
detect sub-atomic levels of emotion. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fire Broadsides</ENAMEX> in Testy
Debate," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sparks Fly in Two Candidate Debates</ENAMEX>," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli√°n Gonz√</ENAMEX>°lez with his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> puts it inside. But
all the papers front a picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's pic shows him
smiling. The picture used by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has him
looking positively exuberant, making what looks like a peace sign with each
hand, although, let's face it, at that age, it's probably bunny ears. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, runs a shot of him looking glum.

            
               USAT fronts, and the other papers stuff, the finding announced
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> that maintains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s home and the
preponderance of documentary materials relating to him, that, yes, he almost
surely fathered one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and probably all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> has admitted that nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> pages about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> designs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s and '60s</TIMEX> were
mistakenly declassified and that on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> occasion were accessed by an
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>. But the outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> was not apparently a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>--the story doesn't say when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> were released nor who got a
look at them.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> is demonstrating good
sense in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> concrete area: He's been wearing a hat while campaigning
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, while, judging by newspaper pictures, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seem to go hatless there. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> has a suggestion for pool
reporters scratching their heads about what to ask the front-runners: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sir</ENAMEX>, you
say you're willing to do the right thing even if it makes you look bad in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. How can we believe that when, even in freezing weather, to look good you
won't wear a hat<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
