
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kurt Warner Story</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>--

            You know sports are getting crazy when the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> movement looks tainted by
wretched excess and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> is actually providing the inspirational
story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>.

            Have you been following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis Rams</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>?

            It's hard to remember another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> who went from nowhere to his sports'
summit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single season</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> has. There was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Valenzuela</ENAMEX> during
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rookie</ENAMEX> season with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Dodgers</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Becker</ENAMEX> when he won <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX>
at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 17</TIMEX> as an unknown wild-card entry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Sanders</ENAMEX> was a supermarket stock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and backup running back at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> who won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heisman Trophy his</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only year</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starter</ENAMEX>.

            The only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> example that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> keeps getting compared to is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unitas</ENAMEX>.

            When I was growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there still talked about how
badly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steelers</ENAMEX> erred when they drafted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unitas</ENAMEX> and cut him before he'd even
played a preseason game or broke training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
already had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Finks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Marchibroda</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> then. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unitas</ENAMEX> had no
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>, so he played semi-pro football with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> sandlot team
named the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomfield Rams</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> signed him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next season</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, and
he was on his way to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> career.

            But even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unitas</ENAMEX> didn't have the season for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> had this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> while winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Valuable Player</ENAMEX> award and leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unitas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> wasn't even drafted out of college,
though he had sent highlight tapes of his best games to every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
did wrangle an invitation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Bay Packers</ENAMEX> training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'94</TIMEX>. But he
was promptly cut. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three seasons</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> didn't get another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>
invitation, so he played for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Iowa Barnstormers of the Arena Football</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> finally signed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> before the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, then thought so
much of him (not) they shipped him overseas to play a year for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European League</ENAMEX>.

            Crass as it may seem, we both know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> would rather loan out their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> than loan their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> to someone. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX>' apathy about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> didn't stop there. They signed another young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Green</ENAMEX>,
to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX> contract and installed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starter</ENAMEX>. You
probably know the rest: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> got hurt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this season</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> got to play.
Soon he was showing everyone why they loved him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>.

            (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> probably loved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> too. They just don't remember
any of it. Between the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you can get there and the constant runs to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-11</ENAMEX> for munchies, I'm confident any survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> football fans
would show they've never seen a complete game. And if they do remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,
it's usually only later. Much, much later. As a flashback.)

            But it's all ended well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of pluggers
everywhere--every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> who never got a mailroom promotion, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> who
never made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX>. His heroic loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is constantly shown on TV clutching
her heart or anxiously clasping her hands during games (she's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the
k.d. lang early-career haircut.) And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Vermeil</ENAMEX> is acting like he
knew what he was doing all along, even if he didn't protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> in last
season's expansion draft.

            It's a great story, the kind the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> used to give us all the time.

            Makes you want to watch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s game just to see how it turns out.

            --Johnette

         
      
   
