
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Trees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tomboys</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seat Belts</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hi</ENAMEX>--

            I, too, have my share of pre-Title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX> sports injuries. A question: Were all
girls growing up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid- to late '60s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '70s</TIMEX> swinging from trees
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarzan</ENAMEX>-style?

            Or was it just you and me?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toledo</ENAMEX> version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tomboy</ENAMEX>-in-the-tree episode is pretty basic: I'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and reaching for the rope as I prepare to leap. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who are in
charge of pulling the rope from below yank it too soon. And I go thudding to
the ground.

            The plaster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> for my broken right wrist reached all the way to my
shoulder. At first I was chagrined, to say the least. It was late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, and
there still were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> of sports remaining before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> started
again.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> did come in helpful with some of the bullies on the block.
Defending my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, I conked a few bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on the head
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those weeks</TIMEX>. That was fun.

            You know, some injuries aren't humorous. And some are downright sad. I don't
know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derrick Thomas</ENAMEX>--I've never interviewed him, never met him--but I can't
stop thinking about him.

            Who can imagine what that poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is going through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>? He's a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-time <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bowl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebacker</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>, and while going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>,
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> hits a patch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and he's not wearing his seat belt and he's thrown
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and he's paralyzed from the waist down. I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> don't know
if it's forever or not, but it doesn't sound good.

            You picture these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> grunting in the weight room for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours a day</TIMEX>, lifting,
running, sweating. You've watched them. I've watched them. And then he doesn't
put on his seat belt (such a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> thing, eh?) and his spine snaps in two
places and that's it.

            Apparently, he's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who is great about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> and really into his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. And I read that the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was
thrown from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> ran <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' charity golf tournament. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> died in the
accident.

            This makes me sad.

            Do you think this has quieted any of that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> bluster down there in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>? Do you think even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro athlete</ENAMEX> who didn't wear his seat belt
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> wore it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? Probably not. They're all fearless. They'll all live
forever. Right?

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
