
   
   
      
         
            In Praise of Cluelessness

            According to a study in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personality and Social Psychology</ENAMEX> (not available online, but the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Goode</ENAMEX> deftly summarized it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18</TIMEX>), a fundamental
characteristic of incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is their inability to recognize that they
are incompetent. The study begins with the following slapstick anecdote:

            

               
                  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McArthur Wheeler</ENAMEX> walked into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and robbed
them in broad daylight, with no visible attempt at disguise. He was arrested
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later that</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than an hour</TIMEX> after videotapes of him taken from
surveillance cameras were broadcast on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 o'clock</TIMEX> news. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> later
showed him the surveillance tapes, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheeler</ENAMEX> stared in incredulity. "But I
wore the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX>," he mumbled. Apparently, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheeler</ENAMEX> was under the impression
that rubbing one's face with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lemon juice</ENAMEX> rendered it invisible to videotape
cameras.
               

            

            To test the principle of which the endearingly clueless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheeler</ENAMEX>'s story is
an extreme example, the study's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Kruger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Dunning</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX>, took a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and had them perform <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> tasks and
then estimate how well they'd done at each. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, they were asked to
assess how funny they found a series of jokes of markedly varied funniness (as
graded by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedians</ENAMEX>). In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, they were
asked to take a logical-reasoning test. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, they were asked to take a
grammar test. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, they were given another logical-reasoning test,
but this time some of those tested were subsequently given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 minutes</TIMEX>'
worth of training in logical reasoning and then asked to re-estimate how well
they'd done on the test. In every instance but the last, the worst scorers
guessed that they'd done better than average. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> study
were able to assess their abilities more realistically, but only by becoming
less incompetent.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kruger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunning</ENAMEX> compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s inability to recognize their
incompetence to a neurological disability called anosognosia. Sufferers of anosognosia are paralyzed on the left
side of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> but don't seem to understand that fact; when asked to pick
something up with their left hand, they will decline by saying they're too
tired, or didn't hear the question, or don't want to. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kruger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunning</ENAMEX>'s
finding also calls to mind the quotation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soren Kierkegaard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sickness Unto Death</ENAMEX> that serves as the epigraph
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker Percy</ENAMEX>'s novel The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moviegoer</ENAMEX> : "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of despair
is precisely this: it is unaware of being despair." Substitute the word
"depression" for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">despair</ENAMEX>" and you have a cornerstone of modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychotherapy</ENAMEX>.

            What the study's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> don't examine is whether cluelessness, while quite
often a bad thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, is a good thing for society. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kruger</ENAMEX> and
Dunning are careful to point out that in certain circumstances, it's impossible
for all but the clinically deluded to ignore evidence about one's relative
competence: "We doubt whether many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> would dare take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> in a game of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX>, challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Clapton</ENAMEX> with a session of
dueling guitars, or enter into a friendly wager on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX>." These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>' superior skill, regularly demonstrated in public, is
simply too great to ignore. And as their study showed, when incompetent people
are given a chance to wise up a bit, they do acquire some
retrospective understanding of their limitations.

            The benefits of cluelessness come from living in a society where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take an optimistic view of life. Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speechifyers</ENAMEX> are always
marveling about the bounteous opportunity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. What rarely gets
discussed frankly is how much the economy depends on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> perceiving
that opportunity to be somewhat greater than it really is. Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX> in his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More Like Us :</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overoptimism</ENAMEX> is in fact the common theme in many of the most purely
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> phenomena: the myth that anybody can grow up to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, that you can turn your
franchise into a fortune, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> can make it on a smile and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handshake</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClelland</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Achieving Society</ENAMEX> ] said that the "famous
self-confidence" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>--really, their refusal to face discouraging
facts--was an important tool for economic development. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best examples
was the completion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s transcontinental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX> in the nineteenth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. "When they were built they could hardly be justified in economic
terms," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClelland</ENAMEX> said. "They would never have been economically justified if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> had not been 'swarming' ... with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of small entrepreneurs
who repeatedly overestimated their chances of success, but who collectively
managed to settle and develop the West while many of them individually were
failing."
               

            

            The Internet economy is a more contemporary example of this phenomenon:
Surely most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to strike it rich in this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> rush will fail, but
right now their buoyant optimism is keeping the stock market high and making
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> wealthier. Long live <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cluelessness</ENAMEX>!

         
      
   
