
   
   
      
         
            <i>Shasta McCrackhead</i> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Lost TV Shows</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>--

            In an editorial on its editorial page <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, the New York
Times editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> editorializes about an important editorial issue;
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> magazine, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the last two years</TIMEX> television
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> have been secretly submitting scripts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>,
who awarded credit for anti-drug messages in the shows. Each <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> a network
receives in credit means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more dollar's worth of public-service time it
doesn't have to give to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for free and can instead sell to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salon</ENAMEX> gave examples of several shows that added anti-drug
themes in exchange for credit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , of course, is critical of the
policy, noting that it could eventually lead to government censorship and/or
"state sponsored propaganda."

            Well, I've spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> doing some research and have uncovered
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of pages of evidence that reveal that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' worst fears
have already come true, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s propaganda campaign in effect for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, and with a far greater reach than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>
originally reported.

            To wit:

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my favorite episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilligan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Island</ENAMEX> is the one
where the castaways get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpowers</ENAMEX> after consuming irradiated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>. You
know what those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> were in the original, pre-censored draft of the
script? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methamphetamines</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>: Everyone remembers the famous episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diff'rent Strokes</ENAMEX>
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> teaches <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arnold</ENAMEX> to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Say No.</ENAMEX>" But few know that
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">censors</ENAMEX> insisted on the removal of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lines of dialogue that they
found to be not only pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> but a potential embarrassment to the
administration--

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WILLIS</ENAMEX>: "C'mon, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arnold</ENAMEX>, let's go snort a couple of lines of blow, just like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>!"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARNOLD</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whatchoo</ENAMEX> talkin' 'bout, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>?"

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Full House</ENAMEX> agree to change an episode in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">little Michelle</ENAMEX> (portrayed by various <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olsen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>) discovers and uses older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.J.</ENAMEX>'s bong into a more benign story in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle</ENAMEX> discovers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reads D.J.</ENAMEX>'s diary.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX>'s potential breakout hit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shasta McCrackhead</ENAMEX> , is tamed into
the disastrously dull <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shasta McNasty</ENAMEX> . Look where it is in the ratings
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.

            And that's just what I was able to uncover since <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 this morning</TIMEX>. You may
want to put your investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> skills to work on this one, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
