
   
   
      
         
            Political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dough Nation</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucus victories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> off-lead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and go instead with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6-3</ENAMEX> upholding of dollar limits on political contributions, a
story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> top-fronts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> also off-leads <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, leading instead with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3 percent</NUMEX> drop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.2 percent</NUMEX> drop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>. The
paper observes that such drops no longer provoke the anxiety they did just a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. As if to dramatize this point, none of the other papers fronts
the move, and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> business and finance news index puts it
below <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter & Gamble</ENAMEX> breaking off merger talks.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> outpolled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
percent, adding that this result was a "setback" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, "who had
campaigned aggressively." On the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> side, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> got
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
percent. That the latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> together outpolled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is
taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> to be a sign of the potency of the abortion issue in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> describes an "ebullient" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and immediately points up the
contrast with his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> presidential campaign when he skipped the caucuses,
calling them "madness," and referred to "the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>." Another bit
of history comes when the paper points out that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of a contested <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caucus</ENAMEX> has gone on to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the paper
points out high up that the overwhelmingly white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is hardly representative
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Another important piece of perspective should have been higher
up: Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8 million</NUMEX> registered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 166,000</NUMEX> participated
in the caucuses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> continues to challenge the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> emphasis on the
op-ed page, with former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Collins</ENAMEX> separately
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advocating</ENAMEX> (he more seriously than she) rotating among small-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> states
the honor of being the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to weigh in on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s campaign contribution ruling
"provides some legal ammunition" for efforts to curtail soft money. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> sees things more strongly, leading off its piece with the claim that
with the decision, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> "strongly endorsed the cause of campaign reform."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> remind high up though that the decision actually
perpetuates a dichotomy from an earlier decision: Donation limits do not
impinge on free speech and hence are OK, but spending limits do and aren't.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-leads the revelation, sourced to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> now believes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> military supported the terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that carried out
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> hijack. This puts into play, the paper explains,
the possibility of putting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> watch list of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that support terrorism, which would reduce its ability to get
international loans--an idea being resisted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> because of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s aid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> incursion into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.

            The WP fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>'s warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
screen all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for heart problems before prescribing the popular nighttime
heartburn drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Propulsid</ENAMEX>, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> has been linked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
cardiac-related deaths. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> also said the drug should only be taken as a
last resort.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> preparations had
diverted computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> at many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from other projects, which are
now back on the front burner. According to an item in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> isn't so supple--the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that regulates credit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> is resisting attempts to eliminate any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> jobs it created to deal
with Y2K problems. Here's a story idea for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>: Find out how many Y2K
jobs were created throughout the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and track what's happening
to them.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front-page "cover story" is headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NEW WEALTH</ENAMEX> IS MAKING
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'DEATH TAX' HIT HOME</ENAMEX>," followed by the subhead "Next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> faces a burden
of prosperity." The idea is that although historically very few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">estates</ENAMEX> have been subject to the tax--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 1 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent times</TIMEX>,
says the paper--the wealth creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s historic boom is liable to
change all that. But if you read the fine print stashed in a couple of the
piece's crannies, you learn that "next generation" and "hit home" are rather
off: the furthest available projections posit that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2017</TIMEX>, a whopping
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of all deaths would be subject to the tax.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a very weird little report on the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Book</ENAMEX>
Critics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> awards. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linton Weeks</ENAMEX> story merely enumerates the
just-announced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX> in the various categories without commenting on their
merits. That is, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weeks</TIMEX> gets to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> in the criticism
category--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shields</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Planet: Facing Race</ENAMEX> During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>
Season . For this book, he abruptly hauls in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> book critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX> for some special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> dissing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yardley</ENAMEX> is quoted saying that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>' effort "is an amazingly bad book, right up there at the top of my list
of all-time stinkers." This seems pretty irresponsible, and there's probably a
back story. What could it be?

         
      
   
