
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World of Women's Sports</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine</ENAMEX>--

            Now you've got my mind racing. ...

            I love the story you told about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Flutie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexa</ENAMEX> looking at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Hamm</ENAMEX> in that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anything You Can Do, I Can Do Better</ENAMEX>"
commercial and saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's the guy with Mia?</ENAMEX>"

            Stories like that are one of the reasons I'm unfailingly optimistic that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> the sports pages or TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> aren't the way they'll stay.
The traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> isn't changing quickly enough for either of us. But they
are going to change. They have to. The Internet is going to make traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> change because it allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to choose the content they want,
completely bypassing the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">SuperEditors</ENAMEX> who run traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> now and
determine the what we see. Business reasons--not just ethical arguments--are
going to prevail on the media to rethink how we cover all sports, not just
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports. Because the sports landscape has already changed whether some
laggard sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> fail to staff something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> games. Or
not.

            I think part of the lag has to do with sexism, of course. But I also think
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and the like rarely start trends. We report them only after
they come along--and often, quite a long, long time afterward.

            But this absence of coverage doesn't mean change isn't happening all around
us. Only that it's not being accurately or presciently reported. That's a huge
distinction.

            If there's any lesson that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> should take from the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports, it's that--like the history of the civil rights movement, or
the gay movement, for that matter--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to resemble their dreams long
before the powerbrokers grant us permission, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of public opinion
ever catches up.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flutie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is a great example. Somehow she filtered out the avalanche
of attention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> receives but felt a kinship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamm</ENAMEX>.

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> has a lot of imitators. Despite those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that don't cover
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports regularly, the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> final at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Bowl</ENAMEX> last
summer still drew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90,185</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> ever to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports
event. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiffeny Milbrett</ENAMEX>, was dead right when she said
lives were changed by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>--and not just here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but around the
world.

            Stupid as it sounds, sitting as we are on the cusp of this new millennium,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> still lead sharply circumscribed lives trimmed in by mean-spirited
nonsense that's meant to keep them down. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> talked about being told soccer "ruins" a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who wants to have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> talked of being told that soccer "isn't for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>." But they still played on. They still showed up.

            Female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> like them and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamm</ENAMEX> have always had to shoulder the added
freight of having to invent themselves. Much like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> women's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>-medal <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic hockey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> had no female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors</ENAMEX>. When they began playing, they never thought soccer careers would
amount to anything like the month-long <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> extravaganza or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>'s debut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the '96</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Atlanta Summer Olympics</ENAMEX> before that.

            You now could argue both events were watershed moments for female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>
because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> simply love a spectacle. But there's something more powerful
at work, too. I also really believe that what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were responding to during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> was the spirit of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. And not the sport they play.

            In the increasingly cynical world of big-time sports--which are businesses
that try to pretend they're just games, peopled by too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phonies</ENAMEX> who get
passed off as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were precisely what they appeared to be:
An authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> whose deportment and pursuit of excellence are worth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emulating</ENAMEX>.

            They're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who fell in love with something and became determined to
exhaust that love to its potential. And they're not "just" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> --that word
is too benign. They're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>. They're doing nothing less than
changing the world's ideas of what being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> means. That is a profound
thing to be able to say.

            Now, you asked what bothers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> so much about that. And I think the answer
is this simple:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> aren't used to envisioning a world in which they're not essential.

            That's why some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> hate the attention lavished on the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>.
That's why they hate it when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> make fun of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s
successes in non-traditional sports like soccer or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice hockey</ENAMEX> have underlined
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports are not merely spinoffs of games that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have been playing
forever. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s sports are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">provinces</ENAMEX> unto themselves--distinct places with
their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> and rich histories, their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and ethos and
culture

            I can't stop thinking, too, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> force us to invent
a new language to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. And that's thrilling, too. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamm</ENAMEX> can score
from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 yards</NUMEX> out on a shot struck with either foot on a full gallop, or tennis
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">player Venus Williams</ENAMEX> can hit a serve <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">127 mph</NUMEX>--faster than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Agassi</ENAMEX> was
serving at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>--doesn't that force us to reconsider what it
means to "play like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>"?

            Suddenly it's no longer a slur, is it?

            Perhaps the best thing is, as I said, there's no turning back. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>
was about ideas and how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are changing their place in the world. Now, like
a boulder rolling down a hill, the process can't be stopped.

            The best thing to do is admire its gathering strength. Or get the hell out
of the way.

            Johnette

         
      
   
