
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Gig</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hi</ENAMEX>--

            Interesting you mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>, because I was reading a story in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> about his first practice with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wizards</ENAMEX>.
What does it say about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> when its best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> is its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>? A lot,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX>?

            So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> or whatever he is) puts
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wizards No. 23</ENAMEX> practice jersey (love that) and sits around waiting for the
real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to show up for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> workout.

            Here's a quote: "I was one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Murray</ENAMEX>
tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "and when he (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>) saw me, he said, 'What are you
doing showing up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late</TIMEX>?' I said, 'Late. I'm early.' But he was already dressed
and ready to go."

            This is going to be fun. Here's the story: The wily old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> as wrecking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ball</ENAMEX>, crashing into the infrastructure of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-something,
multi-millionaire, "What? Me practice?" new-age sports world. Fabulous.

            As you know, I've never covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> reading this must be saying,
what does this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> cover? The answer is the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">chick soccer</ENAMEX>--as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>--and, of course, the most entertaining sport on
the planet, figure skating. Among other things). So I've never reported on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>. Ever. But then I got the call about the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> press conference at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI Center</ENAMEX> and so I made it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> column.

            I went in thinking I wouldn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>. I don't know why I thought this;
probably because of all the MJ hype and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MJ</ENAMEX> adoration and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MJ</ENAMEX> this and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MJ</ENAMEX> that
and a lingering feeling that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> SportsCentury totally blew it and should be
renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN SportsDecade</ENAMEX>: The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'90s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX>? Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>? Come on.
(And where was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billie Jean King</ENAMEX> on that list? <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">59 th</NUMEX> ? Thanks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>.
That's what that was: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> picking their favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> who play
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports</ENAMEX>.)

            But, get this, I loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. I loved the way he came into the news
conference and didn't mince words (mince words? This was a scorched-earth
policy). He called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wizards</ENAMEX> "underachieving;" said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Falk</ENAMEX>,
was "a pain in the ass;" wondered how "scared" his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> would be to practice
against him; and called all his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> "disposable."

            When was the last time you heard such honesty? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ditka</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Knight</ENAMEX>? (But who
wants to listen to either of those tired old misbehaving bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>?)

            What I love about this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> thing is that he has embraced an opportunity
that could lead to his total failure on a basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Golf and baseball</ENAMEX>
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing. Now he's putting that golden image of his on the line in the
sport that matters. He left us the last time with that wonderful picture of
hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX> to win <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Game 6</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> championship in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.

            He nails the shot. He wins the title. He walks away. Perfect. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Williams</ENAMEX> even.)

            And then he's bored--obviously carpooling wasn't for him--and so he comes
back for more.

            Lucky us, we get to watch.

            See you,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
