
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> at the Movies
            

            Johnette,

            As you may remember from your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, there is nothing
quite like a snowstorm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> Just the word "snow," the very mention of it,
sends the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> into a delightful panic. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delightful</ENAMEX>, and a bit confounding to
we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northerners</ENAMEX> who can't believe what a sleepy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> this still
is.)

            I was just watching one of the local TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>:

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">STORM 2000</ENAMEX>! [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catchy</ENAMEX> name.] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STAY TUNED</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">FULL AND COMPLETE TEAM COVERAGE</ENAMEX>!
[Full and complete!]"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporter</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant Food</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>: "There's been a
run on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>!" (What, is everyone making <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> toast?)

            These TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> live for this. And the weather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are positively gleeful.
And it becomes a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator</ENAMEX> sport. I'm going to turn it into my next
column.

            Now, if I were chatting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> outside that movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connecticut Avenue</ENAMEX> at this moment, we'd be stuck in a massive snowdrift.

            On that subject ...

            Listen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. Let's get this straight. I wasn't working as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mole</ENAMEX> ... plotting his demise." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOL</ENAMEX> ... had to do that at least once in this
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breakfast Club</ENAMEX>" thing.) Here's the story: I interviewed him when I was still
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Atlanta Olympics</ENAMEX> (he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic Pooh-Bah</ENAMEX>), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months later</TIMEX>, there he was,
watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The English Patient</ENAMEX> at the same theater I was on a rainy
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.

            So, as he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper</ENAMEX> walked out, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and I were right behind them, and
I took the opportunity to say hello and reintroduce myself--as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, I
might add--and we chatted about the movie for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>. Both of us gave it
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> thumbs up, by the way. We briefly discussed the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> angle"; neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has called to ask for details of our conversation.

            On this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> thing: Of course I'm "out" as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. How else
could I perform the valuable service of being everyone's only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>?

            Hope you're not traveling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. You know there's snow out there. So says my
TV.

            As for me, I'm going to make some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> toast. Like most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washingtonians</ENAMEX>, I
have all the ingredients.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
