
   
   
      
         
            More <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Un-Bubblish Behavior From the Market</ENAMEX>
            

            This is a strange time in the stock market. On the one hand, prevailing
wisdom among the chattering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> has it that current stock prices,
especially on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>, represent a bubble, and that the best we can hope for
is for that bubble to lose slow air slowly, rather than in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> giant burst. I
started collecting examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> saying things like "this overvalued
market" and "Does anyone remember <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Japan in the 1980s?</ENAMEX>," but I stopped because,
well, I got bored. At the same time, though, no one seems to be actually
selling their stock, perhaps because everyone's succumbed to the siren song of
long-term investing or perhaps because everyone always thinks they'll be the
ones who can get out just before the crash.

            

               Or it may be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are staying invested because for a supposed bubble
in which prices are driven ever higher by indiscriminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, this market
is actually quite discriminating, and its standards for corporate performance
remain quite high. In an earlier
column, I wrote about the segmentation of Internet stocks into winners and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> we've seen a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mediocre Christmas</TIMEX> further segment the
Net sector by taking a real toll on Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> recently
announced that its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> numbers would fall well short of expectations, the
stock dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qualcomm</ENAMEX> saw its stock price drop <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> of after-hours trading despite the fact that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> announced that it had grown profits by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">213 percent</NUMEX> in the latest
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>.

               Now, one way of looking at these sharp turns in market sentiment is to
dismiss them by citing them as evidence of that much-dreaded "volatility." But
a more accurate way of looking at them is to see that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are thinking
hard about what news means for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s future earning prospects and are not
interested in rewarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that fail to live up to expectations. (For
further evidence of this, look at the market's reaction to all the recent
merger announcements.) It's also the case that those expectations are very
high, as the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qualcomm</ENAMEX> suggests.

               Of course, the market's expectations should be very high, what with the
prices <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are paying. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qualcomm</ENAMEX>'s profits grew by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">213 percent</NUMEX>, but its
stock is up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 1,400 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, so it may have a ways to
go (down, that is) before it's fairly valued. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> numbers
were more worthy of a slow-growing consumer-products <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> than of a
high-priced tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>, so the market's reaction was hardly surprising. But
what's interesting is that it isn't just stocks trading at stratospheric levels
that are punished, nor is it just stocks that fall well short of
expectations.

               Take, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC Communications</ENAMEX>, the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bell</ENAMEX>, which
announced earnings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> right in line with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' estimates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX>'s profit
and revenue growth weren't staggering, but they weren't disappointing, either.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> showed strong growth in its wireless business, which remains one of
the hottest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> around, and it issued a bullish forecast for the coming
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Pronto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> effort to roll out DSL Internet
access to its local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, fell well short of expectations. Since
high-speed Internet access will soon be a crucial, perhaps the crucial,
business for local phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to dominate, this was not good news. On a
day when the market rebounded sharply in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX> finished the day
down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>. And this was not after a big run-up. On the contrary, the
stock had already been down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 12 months</TIMEX>.

            


            The market's judgment was, I think, the right one. (Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX>'s stock
deserves to drop just on the basis of naming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSL</ENAMEX> initiative "Project
Pronto," but that's neither here nor there.) But the important point is that
the judgment was made. In a pure speculative market, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Sea Bubble</ENAMEX>,
it was enough to exist to coin money. And even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> leading up to the
Crash of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, or during the rapid rise of the Nikkei in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, corporate
performance seemed to matter less and less. Say what you will about this
market. There are no byes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that are playing in it.

         
      
   
