
   
   
      
         
            Slap Happy
            

            You know, I've never been able to figure out what it is about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil Clowns</ENAMEX>
that makes them so darn funny, but the mere mention of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil Clown</ENAMEX> makes me
giggle like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> watching a nudie flick. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> cutting off
homeless benefits. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> singing opera at a ... ah, you get
the point. So I salute you, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, for bringing up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil Clowns</ENAMEX>. Makes me
want to eat at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>-in-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil Clowns</ENAMEX>, I've been reading a bit about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s debate
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> that's gotten all the play is the one
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to march into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> sign an executive order to end racial profiling by law enforcement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> snapped back, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "doesn't need a lecture from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>." Is it just me, or do these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> come up with rejoinders that the
average <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> would be ashamed to use? My prediction: Before it's all
over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> abandon the electoral process and have a slap fight to
see who gets the nomination, and that could mean big bucks for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>. Think about it--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has a huge war chest, and what better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to fill the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>'s coffers than to air a slap fight between a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on pay-per-view. With the right
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promotion</ENAMEX>, this could be the biggest thing since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rave Un2 the New</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>" millennium special. (OK, bad example. I could air home movies and draw a
bigger pay-per-view <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.) Wanna get in on the ground floor with me?

         
      
   
