
   
   
      
         
            Weatherbox: Call <i>This</i> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blizzard</ENAMEX>?

            
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read about the
snow shenanigans of our diarist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX>.)
            

            Among the duties of this column is to put weather events that cause
momentary media alarm into historical perspective. (See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>'s
heat-wave-inspired "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weatherbox</ENAMEX>"
and "Weatherbox:
Part II.") <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, a "fast-developing storm hit almost the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern seaboard</ENAMEX>, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and mountains from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> blanketed with the heaviest snowfall since a blizzard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>," according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . Chatterbox, who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>--a
place that's routinely paralyzed by snow flurries--isn't denying that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snowstorm</ENAMEX> was disruptive. It was even more impressive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, where
the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> that fell set a local record. As usual, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> feels impatient with the provincialism of local records and asks:
What's the most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> that's ever fallen, anywhere ?

            This data isn't as easy to keep track of as temperature extremes, partly
because snow melts and drifts and does all sorts of other things that make it
difficult to measure, and partly because the world's extreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snowfalls</ENAMEX> tend to
occur at very high elevations where there aren't a lot of climatologists
hanging around. However , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, appears to have been certified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>
record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for "the most snowfall ever measured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> presumes that means the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>] in a
single season." This occurred during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the snowfall season</TIMEX> that stretched from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn 1998 through spring 1999</TIMEX>. The snowfall amount was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,140 inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>.
(The previous record was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,122 inches</NUMEX>, which fell on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Rainier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971-72 season</TIMEX>.) Fully <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">36 inches</NUMEX> fell on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mount Baker</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2, 1998</TIMEX>.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months of January and February 1999</TIMEX>, there were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only eight days</TIMEX> when
it didn't snow. It even snowed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of inches</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5, 1999</TIMEX>. Now
that's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>.

            This information must, of course, be placed in context. In most places,
heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snowfalls</ENAMEX> are considered a troublesome (albeit picturesque) natural
phenomenon. In places that depend heavily on revenues from ski <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>, heavy snowfalls are considered manna from heaven. Chatterbox
doesn't mean to suggest for a minute that the misery of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, when it
snows there, is in any way preferable to the jubilation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>
Moreover, the very fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mount Baker</ENAMEX> is a place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pray for
heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snowfalls</ENAMEX> makes it likelier that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> will collect potentially
record-setting data more energetically than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in other places. Surely this
skews the data, even assuming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mount Baker</ENAMEX> is scrupulously honest in its
record-keeping. Nonetheless : The quantity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> that fell on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eastern</ENAMEX> seaboard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was a pittance compared with the quantity that fell
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mount Baker</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
