
   
   
      
         
            The Ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> contest felt a lot like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> cast involuntarily in the role of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX>.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tsongas</ENAMEX> was a high-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> who appealed most strongly
to educated, affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>. He cultivated a similar image as
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> brave enough to level with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. And like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, Tsongas
tried to make his inverted charisma into a virtue. After he won the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tsongas</ENAMEX> transcended his status as a media darling and got
taken seriously as someone who could actually win the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination.
But within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>, he was knocked out of the race by a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s effective demagoguery on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and concerns about his
medical condition. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is now suffering the effects of a similar one-two punch. Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has pummeled him using demagogic attacks straight out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> playbook, beating him up over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>. And
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> acknowledged that his irregular heartbeat, a condition known
as atrial fibrillation, has been acting up. At a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> said he has had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> episodes since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late December</TIMEX>. He said that this
was nothing to be concerned about, but it sure doesn't sound like nothing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has been looking a bit pallid lately, and the fact that he's just
getting around to revealing the problem raises suspicions that he is being less
than fully candid about it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is acting like someone who remembers what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX>. His
demeanor on the stump reflects the growing consensus that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">floundering</ENAMEX> and that the battle for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination is, if not quite
over, now a largely foregone conclusion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX> points ahead in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, and he has erased <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s lead in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> according to a couple
of different polls. This has had a subtle effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s public persona. The
somewhat desperate, insecure-seeming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> who assaulted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in an excessive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> in the early debates has receded, at least for the time being. In his
place, the confident, dullish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> unconcerned about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> running against him
in the primaries has returned to the fore. A piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign propaganda
handed out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign in the past tense,
as in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> believed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Caucus Critical</ENAMEX> to His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> himself is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">treating Bradley</ENAMEX> less like a threat and more like a future <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX>.

            To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> still takes the odd swipe at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> is
not an academic exercise," he declared <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of "family
farm" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, using one of his favorite lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> also
couldn't resist highlighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s impolitic remark that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucus
rewards "entrenched power." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> says, by contrast, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucus is
"about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.") But there's not much edge to these jabs, the way there was
even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX> when the campaign was a more plausible horse race. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is no
longer going for the jugular the way he did in most of the debates. Instead,
he's trying to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-pervasive expectations game in his favor by noting
how much more money <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has spent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> than he has, and trying to feign
a belief that a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-vote win is still a big win for him (in fact, it would
constitute a catastrophic reversal).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> who isn't really worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> is a much more
appealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Speaking without notes or a teleprompter, he displays a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">truly Clintonic</ENAMEX> depth of knowledge and a command of policy. At <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s first
appearance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, at an environment conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX>, he talked
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> global warming and drift-net fishing in a way that was truly informative
and mostly lacking in pedantry (though he did go on a bit). After that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
visited a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, where he gave an equally well-informed analysis of health
care problems. Finally, at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> swapped his gray suit
and tie for khakis and a barn coat, turned up the treble on his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accent</ENAMEX>, and strutted his ag-stuff, explaining that he wanted to step up
antitrust enforcement against industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>. "We need to enforce the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Stockyards Act</ENAMEX> vigorously," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> remarked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> might
mention something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Packers and Stockyards Act</ENAMEX> too. But with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> would suspect he knew what he was talking about.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> will continue to file
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>. Check back here for the latest.
            

         
      
   
