
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX>, It's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX> Outside
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>--

            I don't know what it's like outside your midtown-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, but in
downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> it's cold. As in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> degrees cold. As in
so-much-for-global-warming cold. As in

                  Slate
               -doesn't-pay-me-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly</NUMEX>-enough-to-go-outside-and-freeze-my-private-parts-off-to-get-the-newspaper
cold.

            So that leaves me without much in the way of research as I try to comment on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s events. But fortunately, I have a copy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s New York
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> crumpled up in my gym bag. Let's see ... the front page story is
... it's cold outside. OK, well, I covered that in the paragraph above. Hmmmm
... not much else on the news front so let's see what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">horoscope</ENAMEX> says: "Quiet
time between you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> is very important. ... A new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> may break a
date, but try to be forgiving." Well, that's no problem, because if my new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flame</ENAMEX> stands me up, I'll have more time to spend with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> instead of
running off and cheating on her. See, this is the problem with reading
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s horoscope--it never makes any sense.

            OK, maybe I should try the Internet ...

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today /CNN Gallup</ENAMEX> poll finds that with no dominant issue amid an
economic boom, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s election could turn on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">qualities</ENAMEX>, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> the likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> say a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s leadership
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skills</ENAMEX> and vision are what counts. The story goes on to say that if the
election turns on personal characteristics, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should get a boost
in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>? Wasn't that what they said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> when, let's see, there were no
issues amid an economic boom and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> had supposedly grown tired of all
the scandals surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? Yeah, we got so tired of him and his
philandering ways we put him right back into office, and we knew what we were
getting into. (OK, I didn't predict the whole impeachment thing, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
getting caught in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-term sex scandal had about all the shock value of
your typical episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scooby Doo</ENAMEX> .) The article then quotes a retired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amherst</ENAMEX> who said he was angry at the poor example <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has set for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and that since he is making character his top priority, he's voting
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is at best a reformed party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy/cokehead</ENAMEX> who didn't work very hard in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, wouldn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-</ENAMEX>nerdy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overachiever</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> fulfill the whole "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>"
requirement a little better?

            OK, now I'm off to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray</ENAMEX>" to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to note that this entry is
just another example of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table"</ENAMEX> 's pseudo, misinformed political
commentary masquerading as humor, but before I go, I would like to leave you
with this quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlize Theron</ENAMEX> on filming in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX> is very clean and very lovely. You have
to use <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> money there, though. It's very strange." I'm not sure, but I
think the rest of the quote was: "I mean, just look at it. [points to picture
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>] Who's this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>? How come <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canadites</ENAMEX> don't worship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> like we do? Weird. Very weird."

         
      
   
