
   
   
      
         
            Ballot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>: Release the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Codes</ENAMEX>!

            Whenever someone complains about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s opting out of the
voluntary federal spending limits in order to raise the unprecedented sum of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$67 million</NUMEX> (and counting) for the primaries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> have an
answer ready. Actually, they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> answers. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that, thanks to the
antiquated contribution limit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>, even the maximum donation is a minute
drop in the bucket--something on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.0015 percent</NUMEX> of the total
collected. Their other answer is that the campaign goes well beyond what the
law requires by making prompt and complete disclosure of all contributions on
its Web site.

            A story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> gives the lie to both
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> discovered that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> has devised a system
for keeping track of how much various special interests are collecting for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. These amounts are far in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>. And they aren't publicly
disclosed at all. In his own way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> stands to advance the cause of legal
corruption as much as the groundbreaking work of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign
did.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>'s technical innovation is the use of "tracking codes," to
monitor how much money is coming from its big fund-raisers. Though the
euphemism sounds as harmless as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fedex</ENAMEX> delivery, this practice allows the
campaign to stay fully informed about who is giving what. It also appears to
stir a sense of competition, if not competitive panic, among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> and fund-raisers. Here's a link to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> fund-raising letter obtained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that shows
how the system works. In it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Kuhn</ENAMEX>, who runs a utility trade association
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edison Electric Institute</ENAMEX>, tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of his solicitation to
make sure to "incorporate the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1178</TIMEX> tracking number in your fundraising
efforts" according to the instructions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Evans</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Oliver</ENAMEX>. Doing so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuhn</ENAMEX> notes, "does ensure that our industry is
credited, and that your progress is listed among the other business/industry
sectors."

            Pause to consider what is happening here. A trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> that would be
allowed to contribute a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $5,000</NUMEX> through its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>--not to mention
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that aren't legally allowed to contribute at all--are performing
an end-run around federal campaign-finance law by bundling a large number of
contributions from individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. Of course, "bundling" is nothing new.
What is new is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign's handy-dandy system for sorting out
the bundles, so it knows just how much it has gotten from the electric
industry--compared with how much it has gotten from lots of other
"business/industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>," trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. (Coming
soon: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> able to locate your precise up<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-to-the-minute</TIMEX>
contribution record using a handheld wireless device.) But more important,
communicating the secret pass code ensures that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> in the electric
industry know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> knows how much they've given. The only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know who is really giving how much are the rest of us.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> database is searchable by individual name, but not
by "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>," or "tracking code."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s answer to this complaint is that the tracking codes aren't a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of keeping score or encouraging competition among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> but rather a
benign device for making sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> "are not stepping on each
other's toes," according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott McClellan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClellan</ENAMEX> gives the
example of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s business-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> who are raising money. By
using a tracking code, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> can avoid bothering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> who have
already given the maximum legal amount.

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClellan</ENAMEX> tried patiently to explain it to me, I can't for the life
of me understand how tracking codes help with the problem of repeat
solicitations. Presumably, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> split up the list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
business-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and asked everyone for a check. If one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s b-school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> had already given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> in his capacity as, say, an electric
utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, his contribution would have been counted under "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">#1178</ENAMEX>" as
part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Kuhn</ENAMEX>'s tally. This notional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> might also want his gift counted
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> contribution. But I don't know how his business-school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> would find out from having a code of their own that he had already
given at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Of course, they could find out by searching for his name
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> database. But you don't need any codes for that.

            If the codes really are an innocent bookkeeping exercise, there's any easy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> to dispel suspicion. They can do what

                  Slate
                asked them to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: Release the codes!

         
      
   
