
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dope: A Chatterbox Exclusive</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WASHINGTON</ENAMEX>--A forthcoming biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> and presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hopeful Al Gore</ENAMEX> challenges yet another key assertion by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marijuana</ENAMEX> use.

            As previously reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRCNet</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the new book, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Turque</ENAMEX>, suggests that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marijuana</ENAMEX> use was more extensive than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has alleged
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, when he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> admitted having experimented with the illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>.
The allegation comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Warnecke</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has denied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warnecke</ENAMEX>'s account, and the reliability of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warnecke</ENAMEX>'s story may be questionable because he is, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "a recovering alcoholic" who "has voluntarily been hospitalized
for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> a number of times" and is "now living on disability."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has learned from another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> may not have
been truthful when he made the separate claim that he "never got high enough to
get the munchies," as he told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Grizzleslope</ENAMEX>, a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bagger</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Piggly Wiggly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grocery</ENAMEX> in
Murfreesboro, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, said that she spotted Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, purchasing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> bags of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorito's</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> boxes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hostess</ENAMEX> cupcakes.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the cupcake boxes was already opened when it arrived at the counter,
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzleslope</ENAMEX> said, and the icing was missing from one of the cupcakes. Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s mouth, she said, was smeared with a substance that may have been
chocolate.

            "A little piece fell onto the cash register," Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzeslope</ENAMEX> recalled
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. "Ah wish t'heck ah'd thought to scoop it up and taste it. Ah just
didn't realize how important it would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 years later</TIMEX>."

            Although Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzleslope</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> had several painful bouts of
toenail <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fungus</ENAMEX>, she insisted that this had not affected her powers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recollection</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buford Elso</ENAMEX>, a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piggly Wiggly</ENAMEX>, said he
thought it doubtful the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would still have a copy of the receipt this
long after the purchase. "Heck, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, we didn't even have computerized
cash registers," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elso</ENAMEX> said.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign, flush with its victory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses, moved
swiftly to deny the latest allegation. In a statement released <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> said, "I told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> that I never got the munchies. I never
said that I didn't work up a powerful appetite doing other things, like playing
basketball or memorizing passages from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Structure of Scientific Revolutions</ENAMEX> ."

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few hours later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, made
available for inspection by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> a battered paperback copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuhn</ENAMEX>'s landmark book with a dark stain in the margin beside the underlined
sentence, "One final example of scientific discovery, that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leyden</ENAMEX> jar,
belongs to a class that may be described as theory-induced."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said that the stain "may be chocolate, and may have been
made on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzleslope</ENAMEX> describes." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said the
campaign had not yet formulated a response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
challenge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> submit the paperback to an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> for testing.

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, in an appearance on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , said he had sent a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> urging
her to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> seize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuhn</ENAMEX> paperback immediately so it can be examined
by its own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>. If she fails to respond, he said, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will have no
choice but to call for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s impeachment." Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> said he
was flying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murfreesboro</ENAMEX> tonight to meet with Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzleslope</ENAMEX>, and that he
will begin hearings of his own on the matter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
