
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Kibbitzer</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WINDHAM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEW HAMPSHIRE</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> likes to say that his campaign rejects
"politics as usual." But out here on the campaign trail, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> who
is the true radical. A day with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> is a marathon of candor
without precedent in modern presidential politics.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> with a town meeting at a high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raymond</ENAMEX> --
his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">108 th such</TIMEX> event in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. After speaking, he fielded
every question and comment the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> could muster. After that, he held a
press conference in the snow outside. After the press conference, he got on his
bus and took more questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> -- until the next <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meeting,
where he began the cycle all over again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> talks until your notebook is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX>, your tape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> is out of batteries and your pen is out of ink. After a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">couple of hours</TIMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> has the same, enviable
problem: too much good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s bull sessions on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Straight Talk Express</ENAMEX>" have become the
hottest ticket on the campaign trail <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who wanted to kibbitz than there were seats on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. But other
than the need to take turns sitting next to him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with the press remains remarkably similar to the one I wrote
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> during his announcement tour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>. Surprisingly, the increased
scrutiny and intensity of a closely fought race haven't changed the tone or
style of his campaign. It remains low-key, free form and fun as hell.

            After finishing a town meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> embarks, washes his hands with
germ-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> and assumes his swivel throne in the front section. Reporters
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cluster</ENAMEX> around, attaching microphones to his lapels, and sticking tape
recorders and cameras in his face. In a flash <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is off, wisecracking,
talking seriously about his campaign and his life, engaging in badinage with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> and teasing his good-natured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, who sits a couple of seats away,
trying to talk to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> back home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> about her lacrosse game
on a cell phone. It all feels like a collegiate road trip, with running jokes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cuisine</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunkin Donuts</ENAMEX> and the odd unscheduled stop to shop for local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handicrafts</ENAMEX>. Here's a sample of the dialogue:

            -- Asked about
the recent spate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> endorsements, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> says: "I
want to say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> is off my short list for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">postmaster</ENAMEX>
general." 

            -- Defending
his liberal-sounding concern about income inequality: "We know in the inner
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Reservations</ENAMEX> and other places they do not have the
opportunity to receive the kind of education and training necessary to give
them the ability to take advantage of this prosperity. It seems to me that all
of us as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> or libertarian or vegetarian
should be interested in addressing that situation."

            -- On how much
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee he drinks</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> cups a day. But sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>."

            -- In response
to a question about whether his politics have evolved: "All of us should change
and evolve over time.... In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, I voted against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday</ENAMEX>. I ended up being one of those in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> who fought hard for recognition.
I don't claim not to have evolved as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> and in my philosophy and my
views. I think it would be an incredible waste of time if I hadn't grown and
matured in some of those areas."  

            -- Joking
about his marriage: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX> and I are getting divorced. The grounds are, I found
out she doesn't love me as much as I do."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Inevitably,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> run out real questions and start asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> why he likes talking
to them so much. "It's fun. It's intellectually stimulating, " he says. "Some
of the last of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trotskyites</ENAMEX> have been on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. It's hard to find them
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>." 

            After the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meetings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> pulls off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> called the
Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quilter</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCains</ENAMEX> go in to chat up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and buy a
blue-and-white patchwork quilt. Back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy McCain</ENAMEX> passes the quilt
around for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to autograph with a magic marker, high-school yearbook
style. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCains</ENAMEX> plan to have it framed as a souvenir after the campaign.
Here is what some prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national reporters</ENAMEX> wrote on it:  

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>, You
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Cindy</ENAMEX> -- Are the greatest -- I had the time of my life

            Thanks for the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Straight Talk</ENAMEX>"

            It's been fun
hanging out with you on your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last mission.

            From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunkin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donuts</ENAMEX> to gummy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bears</ENAMEX>, it's been a memorable journey

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>, you
gave new meaning to the term road trip. Hope it ends at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX>.

            I'll never eat
another pink-frosted donut as long as I live. Best of luck

            Best of luck
-- no matter what happens, it's been great

            I love the
shades! Keep talking straight. All the best

            You sure show
your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trotskyist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX> a good time

            The last
comment, I'll admit, was mine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s relentless openness certainly
encourages favorable press attention (as well as increasing the risk of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gaffes</ENAMEX>). But I don't think that the wish to curry favor explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has
chosen to run his presidential campaign as what one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> on the bus
described as a traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Truman Show</ENAMEX>. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> simply had to find a way
of running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> that he found pleasurable. And for whatever reason, he
finds non-stop public interaction both stimulating and therapeutic. Where the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX> schmooze would exhaust another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, it seems to renew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
energy and keep him sane.

            In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> doesn't treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> so specially. His table talk on the bus is not
very much different from the way he conducts his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meetings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> starts
these events with a comic monologue, ramps up to a serious pitch about
repudiating the power of the special interests and motivating young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
then takes questions the floor. From time to time, he fertilizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rickles</ENAMEX>-style, abusing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> questioner as "ugly" and mocking another for his
"expensive sweater" (sure enough, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> asks him about cutting the capital
gains rate). By the time he winds down, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> are as glutted with
access as his traveling press.
Even the hecklers get their due. At an event in high school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> in
Windham, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> spots the global warming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> who have been stalking all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> with posters that ask, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WHAT'S YOUR PLAN?</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> some of them
are dressed in elaborate costumes that include giant smokestack hats with
ribbons of flame and smoke spilling out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> doesn't wait for them to
interrupt him. "If you're committed enough to wear a funny hat, I'm committed
enough to listen to you," he says. "We had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX> suit last night." 

      
   
