
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bridle</ENAMEX> of Frankenfood

Times lead with the adoption in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> of an international trade
agreement on genetically altered food products. The cornerstone of the treaty
is its support for the "precautionary principle," which allows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to ban
the import of genetically altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> without conclusive scientific proof
that said products are hazardous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> off-leads with the Montreal
agreement, and leads with an article exploring the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prison Litigation Reform Act</ENAMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Under the act, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are suing to take control of their
prisons back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">localities</ENAMEX> have sued successfully, with at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> more suits in the works.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> talks were focused on reducing
biotechnology's impact on the environment, and didn't address <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) potential
risks to human health caused by biotechnology products <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) regulations on human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">treaty</ENAMEX> also requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exporters</ENAMEX> to secure permission from
target <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> before importing "living modified organisms" such as
genetically altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX>. The most contentious issue was the establishment of
a notification system for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> produced with genetically altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> claimed that such a system would be a bureaucratic nightmare,
and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> of intense negotiation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> agreed to table the
issue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberties Union</ENAMEX> and other advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> mourn the
effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prison Litigation Reform Act</ENAMEX>, saying that it leaves no way to
prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> from backsliding into the inhumane conditions that warranted
judiciary intervention. Some also maintain that the act is unconstitutional:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> agreed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to review a case claiming that the law, in
effect, allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to dictate judicial policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of the claim
that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> had overstepped their authority, and that overly strict
standards made it very difficult to end court intervention.

            A story fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>, reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>, and
stuffed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> relates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s admission that his stance on
abortion has "evolved" throughout his career. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> had attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
previous claims that he always supported abortion rights, and produced letters
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> calling abortion "arguably the taking of human
life." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> now maintains that while his view of the morality of abortion has
evolved, he has always stood behind <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe v. Wade</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has good
evidence disputing this claim, but buries it below the fold: in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
backed a proposal to broaden the definition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>" in civil rights laws to
include "unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from the moment of conception." The other big news
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> has finally pulled out the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>:
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front pictures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes</ENAMEX> on
the stump <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that, faced with a tough New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> contest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> finally overcame his reluctance to flaunt his political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pedigree</ENAMEX>. As this story went to press, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> was still unsure whether
it was endearing or alarming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> the elder referred to the 53-year-old
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> of the Free World as "this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>."

            The LAT fronts the latest from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s controversial
far right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX> may join a ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, which
finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>'s general elections, is currently negotiating with
the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Party</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> tuck the
story inside, but everyone mentions party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeorg Haider</ENAMEX>'s infamous
statements praising the employment policies of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>
negotiations between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Party</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Social Democrats</ENAMEX> broke down
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front notes that the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, which has nearly doubled
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX>, is inflating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, heating, and airline ticket prices. The
raise in prices are a result of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> production cut, and
diminished domestic stockpiles of heating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, brought about by milder winters
and stricter regulations on storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Given the overall health of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, no one believes that the price hikes will cause a recession.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs a front-page obituary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Greene</ENAMEX>, a "legend of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX>, who fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>, helped
draft the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act of 1964</ENAMEX> and presided over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1981</TIMEX> breakup of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>.

            Unable to afford hefty bribes or airfare to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are
looking for other ways to finesse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> draft laws and keep their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sons</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> conflict. According to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are looking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> deferral, adoption, and a battery of illnesses
and injuries to keep off the front line. Some plans sound like they've been
hatched by sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> said that she would divorce her invalid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to keep her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. He could then legally claim to be his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s only able-bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> and evade the draft, even with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> living
under the same roof. There's just one problem: What are they gonna do if Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roper</ENAMEX> shows up?

         
      
   
