
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> Test Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metal</ENAMEX>

            During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>
criticized his fellow conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> for flinging himself
into a mosh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pit</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">music of Rage</ENAMEX> Against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machine</ENAMEX>.

            In case you didn't actually watch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential debate
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, this really did happen. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> raised a number of
urgent questions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) What was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> doing in a mosh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pit</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Answer</ENAMEX>:
trying to secure the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX>, the left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX>.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> listen to a lot of heavy metal? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Answer</ENAMEX>: Apparently not, since he
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Machine Rages On</ENAMEX>.") <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Why is either of these
no-hope religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealots</ENAMEX> still in the race? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Answer</ENAMEX>: For the same reason
they're flinging themselves into mosh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pits</ENAMEX> at the behest of radical documentary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmakers</ENAMEX>; because they're running to get attention.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) What does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>, think about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korn</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Answer</ENAMEX>: We may never know.)

            If you really want to get into it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> had a bit of a point. Keyes, who in
a previous debate accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> of lending aid and
comfort to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Inch Nails</ENAMEX>, was participating, however facetiously,
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasian</ENAMEX> version of the gangster culture that he thinks is destroying
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. At the very least, moshing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> was the height of
hypocrisy. But if you start to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> seriously enough to criticize him in
this way, he has already won his battle, which is to not be ignored.

            With the exception of this and a few other sideshows, the debate was once
again mostly about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. As the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> took potshots at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the pack for (according to them) coddling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, wanting to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federalize</ENAMEX> education policy, equivocating on abortion, and endangering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security with a huge tax cut, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ducked, smiled and declined to take the
charges entirely seriously. His dodging was as artful as ever. What makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s brush-offs so effective is not what he says at a substantive level,
which is usually pretty evasive, but rather his jovial, confident demeanor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> survives debates in which he is the constant target by refusing to get
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">riled</ENAMEX>. You can insult him, you can mock him, and you can patronize him, but you
can't ruin his fine, front-running mood.

            This attitude was on display when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> made his usual assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> grinned broadly, cocked his head back, and pointed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>,
as if to say, "Bang, bang, I'm dead. NOT!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was even more disarming when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> went after him with a long and squirrelly question that accused him of
increasing the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, lowering educational standards, and
supporting a fraudulent tax cut--before compounding the indictment by asking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> if he intended to do to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> what he did to his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was
slow on some of the particulars of his defense. He didn't remember until the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> pass, for instance, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores might be down because more
underprivileged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s facial expressions and
body language made the point that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> was full of hot air with perfect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eloquence</ENAMEX>.

            Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s split screen, you could watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> went after him.
Right away, you saw the notorious smirk cross <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s face. But it was a
suppressed smirk that said, "I'm trying to hide my contempt, but I can't hide
it completely." Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> turned away from the question, as if resisting the
effort to laugh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">questioner</ENAMEX>'s face. Then he looked back at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>, his
semi-smirk giving way to the subtlest of eye rolls before the eye roll gave way
to a set of blinks suggesting disdain. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> finished his question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squinted</ENAMEX>, smiled broadly and gestured by opening his arms as he said, "So many
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-stories, so little time." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> looked altogether different while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
was answering him. His pained, awkward expression suggested someone sucking a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lemon</ENAMEX> while receiving a proctologic exam. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> is one of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who is better on radio than television. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is sort of the opposite
extreme. He's most effective on TV, with the TV set on mute.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s performance was mixed. He had some effective rejoinders, such
as when he told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> to buzz off when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> asked him a question about how he
would handle his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> wanting an abortion. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> also had some weak
moments, especially in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of the debate, when he seemed to be
playing back his greatest hits. "Feckless photo-op foreign policy" is a good
line, but less good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the 150 th time</TIMEX> you hear it. The most striking
thing to me about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> of late is his continuing dalliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX>- type liberalism. When all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> were asked about the
"digital divide"--the notion that poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> are suffering from
their lack of access to computers--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> gave an answer that could have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s, lauding efforts to connect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> to the Internet and
decrying "the growing gap between the haves and have-nots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> suggested that fast-changing technology would quickly make any government
program obsolete, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> interjected that it was a government program that
invented the Internet. This sort of response might be dismissed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
effort to connect with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX>, who can vote in either
party's primary. But I am increasingly getting the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal positions</ENAMEX> represent a change of heart, or at least an ongoing evolution
in his views. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s evolution.)

            After a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">36-hour</TIMEX> trip back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> that ended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few hours ago</TIMEX>, I'm too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zonked</ENAMEX> to say anything coherent about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Check this space for
comments about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
