
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment Works</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyberspace</ENAMEX> Too
            

            Having read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>'s valedictory, I am
impressed more with his plaintive, rhetorical ploys than his substantive
argument. It is not that he is a failed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who cannot convey the sound
message to a slow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. It is that he is a skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, or at least
advocate, who has tried to sell an alarmist message that just does not add
up.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> problem that I see is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> cannot distinguish between a
change and a problem. Of course the proprietary systems will loom larger on the
Internet with the rise of commerce. But that makes sense for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. If
the system turns out to be filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who plant traps along the way,
there are responses to deal with them, whether they are the next generation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> or the old bait-and-switch techniques. We have rules that regulate the
full-time surveillance of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> on land, and these can be carried
over to the Net as needed. And should we worry if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
right have their gates to filter information? Yes, if they can impose their
will on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who do not join in their cause; but no if the service is
requested and disclosed in advance. But whether it is done online or in person,
it does not count as censorship (or at least censorship worthy of scorn) if
requested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> in question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> seems to think that public and
private controls are the same, but they are not, at least when the private
areas give choices and allow for new entry.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> problem that I see with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>'s approach is that he assumes that
there is some selective, legal void in cyberspace. Take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his examples. If
I give my information to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Site 1</ENAMEX>, and then it is transfered without my consent
to an affiliated site, that could well amount to a breach of duty that exposes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> to serious liabilities. Just think of the roar that
went up when it was found out that some public radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> gave their lists
out only to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> for recruitment purposes. We could protest with the same
intensity for illicit sharing that takes place over the Net.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> thinks that the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> had this virtue, that "it embedded,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">architecturally</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>." He laments that the new one does not. But
it is not as though once we shift to a partly restricted Net that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Amendment claims cannot be brought against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> that seek to regulate
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> in ways they could not regulate other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. So here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> tells us
that "it becomes possible for local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to begin to impose regulation
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the Net, by forcing local servers to condition access based on the
features of who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are." But the painfully obvious answer is, not if that
kind of restriction violates the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> could not condition
the power of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> to sell its paper on the willingness to sell its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> list, so why here?

            Let's be clear about one thing. My position is not that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can do no
wrong on the Net, or that private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> can do no right. My view is that the
standard set of legal techniques, from contract to legislation to
constitutional protection, carry over well to this new environment, even after
it ceases to be organized as vast public space, as it was at its outset.
Markets survive only if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> value what they get for more than it costs.
They require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> protection of property rights to work well. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> can abuse their powers and should be subject to constitutional
checks. All agreed. But nothing about the Internet, no special brand of
cyberspace liberty, changes these fundamental relationships and the problems
they pose. The reason it is so difficult to come to grips with what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> says
is that his threats are diffuse and often hypothetical. His down-to-earth
analogies are more instructive and less alarmist, because they do not ignore
the sensible constitutional, political, and market counterstrategies that are
available. Of course there will be problems on the Net, just as there will be
problems in any space to which any of have to venture. No one should be
Pangloss, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassandra</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Au</ENAMEX> revoir .

         
      
   
