
   
   
      
         
            Masculinity, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Fragile Flower</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">JAN. 17</ENAMEX> (APE)--The boom in business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is damaging male self-esteem, a
new study shows.

            The study's findings were unveiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at a news conference in lower
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> co-hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALE</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men's Association for Label Evaluation</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> devoted to challenging negative stereotypes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> who performed the research. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Smith</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Cohen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>, interviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> between the
ages of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 and 45</NUMEX> over a period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>.

            "It's a wake-up call," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> of the results. "We are losing our
brightest young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to a devastating disorder. They are squandering their
enormous potential for growth and personal happiness on a meaningless obsession
with dot-coms, bandwidth, relative net worth, and the fleeting indices of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>, such as stock overvaluation."

            The study suggests that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> may be so affected by the proliferation of
business television and financial services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that they fall prey to
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> call an obsessional disorder. Said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, "They binge and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">purge</ENAMEX>, or rather, purge then binge. Because they feel worthless, they punish
themselves by coming in too early to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and staying too late, whether
they need to or not. Then they waste time on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless day</TIMEX> trading and deplete
their bank accounts on frivolous items--watches, suits, cell phones with Web
browsers, huge bouquets they'll send to girlfriends alienated by their long
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and tedious business gossip, even though the girlfriends will just throw
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> in the garbage."

            The periods in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s life when he is most vulnerable to the condition,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, are "troughs"--moments of transition, such as
leaving high school and entering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and entering the job
market, hitting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, and so on. In a trough, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> may develop an emotional
attachment to "aspirational media," which traffic in celebratory stories and
photographs of highly powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and the symbols of their success, such as
the corporate titles they have acquired and shed, the venture capital they
haven't spent yet, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> they have married and divorced.

            These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> and programs also contain how-tos about getting rich
quickly and yet investing wisely that may make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> feel confused and
inadequate, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>. "For instance," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, holding up the
current issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> turned to an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Bing</ENAMEX>, "he humorously dismisses the typical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s resolutions, then
pledges to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'make</NUMEX> a lot of money.' It's role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> like him that are laying
waste to an entire generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who could have had richly nurturing
relationships with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and gone on to be perfectly happy
and productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and summer
rentals in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>."

            Several noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> confirmed that this disorder had become
increasingly evident among their male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. "More and more young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in
their late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">20s</ENAMEX> are exhibiting signs of distress," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurston</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of neuropsychiatry at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale University</ENAMEX>.

            "These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> have gone from being bright young things on their way to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> degree and a promising career to feeling broke, hopeless, and doomed to
professional failure because they haven't started and walked away from their
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> yet," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurston</ENAMEX> said. "It's as if they've been brainwashed by all
the admiring profiles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> into thinking that their own
considerable achievements aren't big enough."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurston</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> that oversees the publication of
whether to expand a previous category of addiction in order to cover the new
condition. "Let's face it," he said. "What we're talking about is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> getting
hooked on the pornography of success."

            Contacted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stiffed: The Betrayal of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> , agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurston</ENAMEX>'s definition of business media and said
it amounts to a plot against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
