
   
   
      
         
            Dollars <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">& Sense</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TheWashington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the restoration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> rule
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>, following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s bloodless coup led by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-man <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">junta</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustavo Noboa</ENAMEX>, was sworn in as president
under intense pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and other foreign countries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>
story but leads with an exclusive report on the frenzy to adopt health-care
legislation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> are bearing the
brunt of reform: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,400</NUMEX> health-care bills <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, and another
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> proposals have been introduced for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times scoops the other papers with a proposed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20-billion</NUMEX> deal between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMI Group</ENAMEX> and fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuadorean</ENAMEX> crisis below the
fold.
            	The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead highlights the role the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> played in convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>
to reinstate its elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> strong-armed the opposition by
threatening to cut foreign aid and discourage investment in the economically
devastated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamil Mahuad</ENAMEX> was toppled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days ago</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX>, supported by military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, stormed the congressional
building. At issue? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahuad</ENAMEX>'s economic policies, specifically a plan to replace
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>'s currency with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> dollar in an effort to slow inflation and
restore confidence in the economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of the plan claim it would hurt the
poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including a large majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> provides extra details about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis,
including the facts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahuad</ENAMEX> froze the life savings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecuadorians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> defaulted on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> foreign debt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , for its part, offers the
most information about the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustavo Noboa</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rector</ENAMEX> and
law-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> who has pledged to open a dialogue with the disgruntled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are no happier
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noboa</ENAMEX> than they were with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahuad</ENAMEX>.
         	
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the deal between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMI</ENAMEX>, expected
to be announced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, will create the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest music
conglomerate in the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> will bemoan the decrease in number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in the market (which could undercut the diversity of music
produced), but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> suggests that such criticism might be offset by the
acceleration of online access to music. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>'s merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Online</ENAMEX> is complete, the deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMI</ENAMEX> is expected to revolutionize the way many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> buy music. Rather than shop in record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> will eventually
download entire albums directly from the Internet.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off leads and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> are expected to clean up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s caucuses.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the anticipated outcome, which is understood to be
a foregone conclusion, economic prosperity, and ideological similarities
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> has led to voter apathy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the
"spirited contests" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> isn't enough to spark much enthusiasm
for the old-fashioned exercise in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>: though presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopefuls</ENAMEX> have
stumped tirelessly throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> (save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, who is skipping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
to concentrate on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s primary in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> of
registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are expected to turn out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to stand up and
nominate their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off lead, an exhaustive analysis of a
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> poll, jumps ahead to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, where the poll has found
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> commanding a sizable lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> locked in
a dead heat.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off leads with the federal investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s terrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> claim that bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>, implicated in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> bombings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, has recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accomplices</ENAMEX> and used international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> -- including a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> --
as fronts for terrorist activities. Surprisingly, letters found by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
use codes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> could crack -- bin Laden is referred to as "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Sam</ENAMEX>" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Beverage Industry</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
points out that it's not clear whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> has any direct evidence that bin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> attacks, though there is evidence, apparently, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX> is connected to violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX>.
         	
The WP fronts and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stuffs the continuing saga of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, whose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>
met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to lobby for the return of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>
friendly but unable to reassure them that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian</ENAMEX> would be going home anytime
soon. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Late yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> released a statement saying that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> had made "a very compassionate and heartfelt plea" to be
reunited with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian</ENAMEX> but that the matter is now (read "tied up") in federal
court.
         	
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> : Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is compared
to his "famously tongue-tied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, when comparing the foreign
policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paradigm</ENAMEX> of yesteryear, when the number one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, to foreign policy threats <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, he said: "When I was coming up .
. . it was a dangerous world and we knew exactly who they were. It was us
versus them, and it was clear who them was. Today, we're not so sure who they
are, but we know they're there." Let that be a comfort to them. Or us. Or you.

      
   
