
   
   
      
         
            Neck and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neck</ENAMEX>

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> address. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> also tops the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box.) "Never
before has our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> enjoyed, at once, so much prosperity and social progress
with so little internal crisis or so few external threats," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said,
asserting that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> has never been stronger." Most papers
note that the speech was surprisingly ambitious for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in his last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> in office. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposed new tax credits for college tuition payments
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $10,000</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> minimum-wage increase, a plan for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to
cover prescription drugs, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in tax incentives to help spur the
development of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, photo licenses and safety tests for
gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $3 billion</NUMEX> in education spending, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
billion for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Head Start</ENAMEX>. True to form, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also triangulated some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
issues, most notably a proposal to end the "marriage penalty" as part of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> tax cut (about the same amount as he unsuccessfully pushed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes) and a plan to encourage charitable
contributions through tax incentives. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">89 minutes</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes, it was his longest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOU</ENAMEX> , and included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> mentions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ /NBC News</ENAMEX> poll shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> in a statistical dead-heat with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s most competitive showing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. And
he has nearly doubled his national lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54 percent</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64 percent -22 percent</NUMEX> now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, for his part,
increased his national lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> slightly, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s increased
competitiveness could begin to hurt his standing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> field, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes. Potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> drew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 5</NUMEX>
percent.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comptroller</ENAMEX>'s
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One Israel</ENAMEX>, illegally channeled
large donations from domestic and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> through nonprofit front
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> leading to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s victory over former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the donations totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.1 million</NUMEX>
out of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22 million</NUMEX> campaign budget; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $1.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> pleads ignorance of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising details, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comptroller</ENAMEX>'s fine and initiation of a criminal investigation is expected to
hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s credibility at home during negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tal Zilbersteiin</ENAMEX>, runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultancy</ENAMEX> headed by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> Stanley
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Shrum</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> moment: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's Internet edition runs a
marvelous photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, post- SOU , embracing nonogenerian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> hulks over the former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dixiecrat</ENAMEX>--who,
it should be noted, ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 years old</TIMEX>. ... 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudian</ENAMEX> slip? At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in his speech, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spoke about the "liberal" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> envisioned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. He then corrected himself with "livable."

         
      
   
