
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>, Continued

            
               Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin MacDonald</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX> with nauseating ideas or just a
misunderstood evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX>? If he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX>, should the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who published his scholarly work and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who welcomed him
into their professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> be held partly responsible for his
ideas?
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of psychology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California State University at</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long Beach</ENAMEX>, is about to testify in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Irving</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> who is suing another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> over her charge that
he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revisionist</ENAMEX>. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evolutionary</ENAMEX>
Psychology's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Anti-Semite</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> gives a foretaste of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>'s
testimony, drawing from books in which he argues <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX> is a conscious
strategy of eugenicism designed to maximize <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> intelligence, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX> is therefore justified. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Fighting</ENAMEX>
Bad Ideas," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Behavior and Evolution Society</ENAMEX> (HBES), of which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, archivist, newsletter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, should never have let him get as far as he has without refuting
him.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> disagrees strongly with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>, as do several evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> who feel it is unfair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> to call them to account for
someone else's ideas. Click here to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>'s letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culturebox in The Fray</ENAMEX>. Click here to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s reply. Other notable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Fray</ENAMEX> include

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald reviewer John Hartung</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> selection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Sloan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Horgan</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Undiscovered Mind</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How the Mind Works and Words and Rules: The</ENAMEX>
Ingredients of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language</ENAMEX> ).
            

            
               Tune in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> for the continuation of the debate in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
Dialogue between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBES</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tooby</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
