
   
   
      
         
            In the Name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian</ENAMEX>

            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug</ENAMEX>
Administration's suspension of all programs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Human</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Therapy</ENAMEX>. Independent investigations by the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> into the death <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Gelsinger</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in the program, raised questions about the ethics and procedures at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s board meeting at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter & Gamble</ENAMEX> that revolved around a
possible merger with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> large pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>. The merger would make P & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> one of the most formidable
consumer products and drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the world. Although the deal is far
from certain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> reacted skeptically and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P & G</ENAMEX>'s stock fell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
percent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reefers the gene therapy story and leads with
the forced resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamil Mahuad</ENAMEX>. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indigenous protesters</ENAMEX> and several disgruntled military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> seized the
congressional building and the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahuad</ENAMEX> fled to an unknown
location. The protest against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahuad</ENAMEX> centered around his inability to implement
structural economic reform for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s ongoing neglect of
its indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stuffs the story but fronts a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-column
photo of the protests.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> front the investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX>'s gene therapy program.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> focuses on specific violations of the program. Most damning is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gelsinger</ENAMEX> was technically ineligible for therapy in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place and
should never have received treatment at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>. In addition, none of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> enrolled in the gene therapy program had filled out eligibility forms
to participate (which should have been routine), nor were they ever made fully
aware of the risks involved with what they had submitted to. The WP
closely scrutinizes the ethics of for-profit scientific research, highlighting
the fact that the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn's Institute for Human</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Therapy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M. Wilson</ENAMEX>, had a significant financial stake in the results of the
study--a circumstance that may have compromised his judgment. The LAT
reefers the story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off leads and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front the
investigation into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> smuggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, a vast
syndicate that included prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party officials</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military, and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, smuggled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated ten billion</NUMEX>
dollars worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, and high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> through the port
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xiamen</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> views the smuggling as a breakdown of political
order and therefore as a grave threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> rule. It has vowed to prosecute
without leniency all those involved. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that when a similar
smuggling operation was recently uncovered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the ringleaders were
sentenced to death.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s revision of his abortion stance as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses approach. Responding to the accusation of his main challenger
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, that he hasn't taken a strong enough stance against
abortion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> more firmly asserted that he "disapproves" of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe v. Wade</ENAMEX>. But
he stopped short of saying that the decision ought to be overturned, suggesting
instead that it is an issue best ruled on by state legislatures.

            The LAT fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>' expression of
concern that the global economy has become precariously dependent on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-valued <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dot-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">com</ENAMEX> stocks. A sudden downturn could result in a world-wide
economic contraction. Nonetheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> is unlikely to issue any grim
warnings for fear of instigating a sudden and violent panic.

            The off lead in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag is causing
all sorts of problems for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, especially in his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. If he
doesn't renounce the flag he risks losing the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>. If
he does renounce it he'll infuriate those who cherish it as a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
history. If he withholds his opinion and remains opaque on the issue--as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports he has--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> risks the accusation that he's incapable of
making tough decisions.

            The WP fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian Gonzalez</ENAMEX> story, exploring the mythology that
has arisen around the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. Anti-Castro <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expatriates</ENAMEX> have inserted
him into a messianic narrative in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian</ENAMEX>, plucked from the sea, stands as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> discovered among the bulrushes: Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> out of slavery
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, so to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will Elian</ENAMEX> free <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s rule. The LAT
stuffs the story but fronts a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-column photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> upon their arrival from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> to ask for the return of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also stuffs the report on the arrival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>. With
political negotiations at an impasse, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> made emotional pleas at a
press conference for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian</ENAMEX>'s return to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. By noting that both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women shivered</ENAMEX> in the unfamiliar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> degree cold as they got off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> pointing to the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian</ENAMEX> has been removed from his native
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">temperate</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to suggest that perhaps he ought to be returned there?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> have broken their
agreement to refrain from negative campaigning and "attack politics." The truce
was shattered when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ran an ad that assailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s proposed tax plan. To
paraphrase the explanations of how the hostilities resurfaced, each man
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vehemently</ENAMEX> asserted that the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> started it.

         
      
   
