
   
   
      
         
            Demonizing the 1970s

            A
wellspring of conservative ideology for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three decades</TIMEX>--perhaps
the wellspring--is the conviction that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> went to hell in the
1960s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frum</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How We Got Here</ENAMEX> , diverges from this hypothesis and
designates as the true culprit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strategically</ENAMEX>, it's a very shrewd
move. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frum</ENAMEX> points out in his book, almost nobody who actually lived
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> (as opposed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, who re-experience it as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX>) have much regard for it:

            

               
                  My more leftish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> looked backward to the heroic 1960s; those
of more conservative outlook exulted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980s</TIMEX>. All of us agreed that
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1970s</NUMEX> were a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">slum</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. Right or left, we delighted in the narrowing
of neckties, the demise of disco, the restyling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camaro</ENAMEX>, the extinction
of the fern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> (high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'76</NUMEX>, college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'80</NUMEX>) sort of liked
the fern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, and took no notice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camaro</ENAMEX>'s restyling, but otherwise won't
quibble: Good riddance to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, tacky <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> of my youth! Nothing makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX>'s point more forcefully than the jacket-cover art for his book--a garishly
mod typeface (dig those concentric circles on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>'s!) against a background of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orange</ENAMEX>, the unfortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> color of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that decade</TIMEX>. It's a testament to the
1970s' cultural dreariness that even the good things about it--as Frum
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">generously</ENAMEX> concedes, it was the best-ever <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> movies--didn't
become apparent until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> afterward.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frum</ENAMEX>'s political demonization of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> is ultimately just a
gimmicky way to restate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the neoconservative</TIMEX> indictment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. As Frum
rightly points out, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> when the provocative ideas and
styles of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> spread from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite enclaves</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northwest Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, to the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Particularly if you
focus (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX> does) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of the 1970s</TIMEX>, the prevailing mores of
the period were largely indistinguishable from those of the second half of the
1960s. True, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>; but few of his policies
(the most notable exceptions were <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam and Watergate</ENAMEX>) bucked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
liberal mood. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> often argue that "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>," defined as a time of
political and social turmoil, really began with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s assassination
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> and ended with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s resignation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. And indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX>'s
various "social decline" indexes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> tend to have as their starting
point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>.

            What this means is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Evil 1970s</ENAMEX> are really just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> 1960s
with a little more narcissism and a lot more inflation tossed in. Anyone who's
ever glanced at an issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> will recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX>'s targets: the rights
explosion, the loss of faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, the sexual revolution, the rise
of the underclass, license, rudeness, etc., etc. (Interesting sign of the
times: legalized abortion gets only a glancing mention, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> was handed down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>.) Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decter</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX> can't seem to work up much passion for
decrying these things. In part, this may be because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX> is a bit of a snob;
practically the only argument in the book that strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> as truly
passionate is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frum</ENAMEX>'s withering denunciation of the old-line northern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>
sects for failing, in trying to make Christianity more "relevant," to attract
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX> doesn't much care for the showy and evangelistic Baptists
who displaced the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Methodists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Presbyterians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Episcopalians</ENAMEX>.) Another
obstacle is the book's vaguely newsmaggy format, which requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX> to move
quickly from example to example and to abbreviate his arguments. (Apparently
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> are trying to pass this book off to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> as neutral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> history.)

            The most intriguing handicap, though, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frum</ENAMEX>'s own conflicted feeling about
how good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the good old days</TIMEX> really were. At the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How We Got Here</ENAMEX> ,
Frum recites the neocon catechism that the main trouble with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1960s/1970</NUMEX>s
was that ungrateful punks didn't appreciate the virtues of mid-century social
order. But then he puts some distance between himself and the Commentary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> by questioning whether that mid-century social order was all that
wonderful to begin with:

            

               
                  Like them or loathe them, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle decades</TIMEX> of the twentieth century
were an entirely anomalous period in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. Never had the state been
so strong, never had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> submitted as uncomplainingly, never had the country
been more economically equal, never had it been more ethnically homogenous,
seldom was its political consensus more overpowering. You can see now why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might pine for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>. But would they pine for them if they
remembered more clearly that the top rate of federal income tax was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>?
... To ship a crate of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trucker</ENAMEX> needed permission
from a federal regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Almost one-third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s best jobs
were off-limits for anyone who refused to join a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            Like many contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX> is torn between his allegiance to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> conservatism and his allegiance to libertarianism. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frum</ENAMEX>'s
conspicuous inability to reconcile these feelings will persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>
to stop building their politics around the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was banished
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> leading up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> presidency.

         
      
   
