
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> Knows What "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regatta</ENAMEX>" Means!

            My first reaction on learning Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s verbal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> score--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX>--was, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, that's pretty low." My second
reaction was that this proves that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX>, at least back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, really
were culturally biased. I've interviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> (as part of a group of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>) a couple of times--he seems like a smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with a lively sense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s absurdity. If, as an achiever from a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, he
scored lower than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> did as an unfocused rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connecticut/Texas/Maine WASP</ENAMEX>, it shows how skewed the tests were in favor of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich WASPs</ENAMEX>. ...

            My <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> reaction was, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, that's pretty low." ...

            
               Where Are the "
               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Conspiracy</ENAMEX>
               " When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Need Them</ENAMEX>? It's been obvious that
the press has doing its best to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a boost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. ("Former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> was a candidate transformed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, stumping with renewed
vigor ..."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> needed a new story
line--the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Gore</ENAMEX>" story having been done to death. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Battles Back"</ENAMEX> is
the story they've wanted desperately to write. ... More important, we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are terrified the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary campaign might actually end
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Tuesday</TIMEX>, stopping all the fun and giving us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as much to cover in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next six months</TIMEX>. We signed up for a race , dammit! If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> fails to
give it to us, as looks likely, the reaction against him by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> will be
vicious. Don't expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to get the usual "He Raised Important Issues"
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eulogy</ENAMEX>. ...

            
               Who Speaks for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Paranoid Center</ENAMEX>? The appearance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Gore</ENAMEX>
suggests he may do to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> what he's doing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>--methodically chew him
up. And it's hard to believe that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> wins the presidency the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
won't pick up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX> seats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. So there's now the distinct
possibility, maybe even probability, that my own chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> will control both
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. It's hard not to be at least mildly alarmed by this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX>.

            Think of all the mischief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means</ENAMEX>) and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unreconstructed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> could make if freed from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> constraint.
Goodbye welfare reform, hello Urban Development Action Grants! I sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trusted Clinton</ENAMEX>, for all his faults--or maybe because of his faults--not to
give in totally to the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dems</ENAMEX> most clichéd instincts. Even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hadn't run as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX>, he's self-confident and slippery enough
to avoid giving anybody more than he has to. It's not easy to have the same
confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--one reason his gratuitous gay-litmus-test
pander was so disturbing. ...

            
               Actual <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inside Dope : Where</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s long-awaited book on "race"?
Nowhere to be seen, that's where. There are still some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrats</ENAMEX>
left in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. ...

         
      
   
