
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Toobin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hypocrite</ENAMEX>, Part III!

            It's one of
those gifts that keeps on giving! New evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Toobin</ENAMEX>'s hypocrisy
(in his book, A 
               Vast
Conspiracy ) arrives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost daily</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s installment focuses on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aspersions Toobin</ENAMEX> casts on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>, whose reporting of the Flytrap
scandal won a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Magazine Award</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .

            Toobin
writes that "greed," in the form of a "desire to write books about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sex life" motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> ...to act as
they did." In a deceptively-crafted passage on pages <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">130-131</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> quotes a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September, 1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> tape in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> was "working
on a book deal. He's doing an all-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> kind of deal." Toobin
then flatly asserts, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> was using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> as a source for the [book]
project he had started with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Simpson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> , who had by this point dropped out of the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Isikoff</ENAMEX>
had apparently even shared the working title of his volume with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>, as he
had with others"--the title, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX>, being All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX> then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blasts Isikoff</ENAMEX> for trying to talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> into cooperating with him. According to
Tripp, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> told her, "If I were to, uh, work with you and, you know, allow
some of this to get out into the mainstream media, then that would set you up
for a [book contract]." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> writes:

            

               If events
unfolded as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> said they did, this was dubious ethical territory for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> were both stoking the story so they could profit
from it in the form of book deals--and not disclosing that fact to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, as he had not in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> story--that would have been inappropriate
to say the least. Likewise, it would have been wrong for him to advise <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tripp</ENAMEX> on
how to position herself in the marketplace of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex books. In the book
that he did write on the case, which was entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncovering Clinton</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> "invented" this
conversation with him, If she did, it is curious that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> knew the precise
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s planned book; moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> was obviously not lying about
her own interest in writing a book.

            

            There are
many, many things wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s argument.

            First, note
the clever use of the word "if" in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> sentence. "If" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> had been
writing a book, he might be accused of mercenary motives. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> says he
wasn't writing a book. He confirms (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncovering</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> , and to me) that he had talked about co-writing a book with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX>, but says that they had dropped this idea over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> before the Tripp
tape, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> ran a screaming headline suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> was
holding back juicy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> details (which even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> concedes he
wasn't) for a book . Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> himself, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
pages before the above passage, writes that after the mid-summer Drudge
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Simpson</ENAMEX> decided to put All
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s Women aside for a while."

            What
evidence does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> have that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> isn't telling the truth and that the
"while" had ended by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>--with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> back to "using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> as a source"
for a book, as opposed to reporting a possible article for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> had told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> the "precise title"of his
book! Except that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> got the title wrong. The title of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s proposed book, according to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>, was
Secrets and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lies</ENAMEX> , not All
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> . "The notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> and I would be so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> as to
use a cliché like All The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> is
perhaps the most insulting part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s mistake," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX>
also told me that after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>'s report <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> "was fairly petrified that he
would be pulled into a conflicted situation" and that their book project was
"most emphatically" dropped.) Isn't it likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had simply read the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> and erroneously believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>
was working on a book?

            Given that,
what was so terrible about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> is alleged to have told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>? He told
her she shouldn't publish her story herself, but that she should let him have
it. In other words, he's trying to talk a source into giving a story to him,
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>. That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> do, and what they're paid to
do.

            What's so
terrible about writing a book anyway? As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> says, "Any big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> can
always turn into a book." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> would have to be a moron not to have that
thought somewhere in the back of his or her mind. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> is right to
think that "such incentives did not even exist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation ago</TIMEX>"--although I
suspect the incentives do more to bring out relevant truths than distort them,
and it's not at all clear that prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the incentives even applied
"books about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sex life." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> got rich off <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>.
But what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> got rich writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s sex life, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s--or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX>'s for that matter?) It's easy to believe that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> would have done exactly what he did even if his only possible
publication outlet was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> (and his only
remuneration his salary) since all of his reporting was supervised and
supported by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX> is,
of course, being massively hypocritical here, given that he too is now
profiting from enclosing his reporting in hard covers. How dare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> write a
book, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> in his book! Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s own judgment distorted by his
presumably large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> advance? Has he donated the money to
charity?

            In
fact , kausfiles has learned, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> story
broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> approached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> (who had no deal in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">works</ENAMEX>) to write a book about it, but then backed off because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX>, a big name
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, was already interested in doing one himself!

            It gets
worse. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May of 1998</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, when both he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> had
publishing deals, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX> actually proposed over lunch that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> join
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">their Clinton</ENAMEX> books. At that
point, of course, most of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> now criticizes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s reporting
(including the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> in advancing the scandal) was
well-known. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> was such a disreputable sleazemonger, why would Toobin
want to write a book with him? A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> story on this incident reports that, "Toobin
said through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> ... that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> had approached him."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> insists it was the other way around--he'd invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> to lunch, but
only to pump him for info on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Kirkland</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>.
He remembers being surprised when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> suggested they write the book
together.
            

            I believe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> on this. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neither Toobin</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> returned my repeated calls.)
Anyway, whoever suggested the arrangement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX> doesn't deny considering it
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a day</TIMEX>. Why, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s so bad? And shouldn't Toobin, by his own
standards, have disclosed his book dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Isikoff to Vast Conspiracy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>?

            There's
more! Let's not forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who now decries the baleful
influence of book deals, first made his mark betraying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Walsh</ENAMEX>, for whom he worked as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, by quitting to publish
a book about the case before it was even over! There's not enough room on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's server to fully analyze <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s possible
psychological motives for indulging in the ridiculous innuendoes of
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vast Conspiracy</ENAMEX> . But one is obvious: he's
projecting!

            
               P.S.: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, as I've written earlier, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine.
In my experience he's honest and conscientious. Am I motivated to criticize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX> in part by a desire to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> from the slime in Vast
Conspiracy ? You bet. But I wouldn't do it if I wasn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convinced Isikoff</ENAMEX> is right and Toobin wrong. I'm not that loyal a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>.
               
            

         
      
   
