
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Dues</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don'ts</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with an
exclusive: extensive corruption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> union document. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s decision to
follow the example of numerous other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> by filing a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX>
lawsuit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s major handgun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with fresh polling indicating that despite close races in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> have "huge" leads among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> nationwide. The poll shows that among
likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> beats <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> decisively and beats <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> too, although by
less of a margin. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> beats each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> as well. The top
non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is the expected announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that his proposed budget will include a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> increase
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in federal science funding.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> report describes corrupt activities by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, mostly misappropriation of union funds, totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.6 million</NUMEX>.
A particularly disturbing note: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> as
saying it is "cleaner than most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>." It should be noted that the
Times says high up in its story that the report was "made available by a
union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> eager to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">federation</ENAMEX> take a tougher stance on
corruption." This exemplifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s admirable general policy when dealing
with unnamed sources of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least communicating</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>'s
motivation and personal connection to the story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead notes that municipal anti-gun suits have suffered a
series of legal setbacks recently, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> throwing out several of them.
Another obstacle, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , is unique to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, which
overseas the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s budget, can step in to prevent the funding of a lawsuit.
And, indeed, the story goes on to quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> calling the action
"utterly frivolous." But still, the paper reminds, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1992 and 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
were used in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> homicides.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> front <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> visit/speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gist</ENAMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has the right to dictate conditions that must be
fulfilled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> before it receives <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dues. The main condition
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> seemed to have in mind was for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> not to impose its "utopian"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Even so, the reporting shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>--said by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> to be the most powerful foreign policy voice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--had much
more productive contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> than he'd
ever had before.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts report a rather striking sign that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> is in disarray: A senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> general leading
forces attempting to capture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grozny</ENAMEX> is missing in action. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> say that he has been
captured alive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> explains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> are making this claim
on their Web site. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is to be commended for including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>,
which is <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kavkaz</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions the Web site in
another connection, but doesn't give out the address. What's up with that?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>'s launch of a
full-scale investigation into the financial dealings of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> and the political party he led for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times puts it at the top of its front-page world-wide news index. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reefers the news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's headline makes no mention of a
tragic turn--the apparent suicide death of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>. And, hey,
how come nobody fronts the similar investigatory ratchet-up in a similar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">financial</ENAMEX> scandal involving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> goes high in its front-page financial news box with the
record <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade deficit posted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, which it attributes to higher
imports of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and other consumer goods as well as Y2K stockpiling and rising
oil prices. Everybody else stuffs this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the search for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">druglords</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> border has ended after having yielded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corpses</ENAMEX>--on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>. Contrast this to the front-page treatment accorded by many
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> to the first stories claiming that there might be more than 100
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> at the site.

            A front-page WSJ feature celebrates the return to fashionability of
the mustache. The story doesn't note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one quarter</NUMEX> in which upper lip layering
seems permanently out of fashion: presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. What possible
explanation is there for no presidential mustache since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taft</ENAMEX>? Another challenge
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
