
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial-News Fad</ENAMEX>

            I believe it was the
transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Bartiromo</ENAMEX> into a household name that told me that
something new was really afoot. Granted, she's only a household name in certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>, but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX> 
               Center
has enjoyed a precipitous ascent up the fame ladder, seeing herself featured in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and interviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Letterman</ENAMEX>.
Bartiromo, in short, has been anointed the new face of the new boom in business
news.

            The
boom can be seen in the arrival of business news on the front pages of daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, the rise of business coverage at mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> --and, above all, in the new attention
being paid to television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX>. The buzz, at least, is
that the growing diffusion of stock ownership has made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> care much more
about the stock market than ever before, while the uncontested authority of the
free market has placed business at the center of the culture.

            
As it happens, it's difficult to figure out
whether business news really is much more popular, or whether network
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> have just decided it should be . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>'s
business shows have an average viewership of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">somewhere between 120,000</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s viewership peaked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just over a million</NUMEX> when the market
crashed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, still gets hash marks instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX>
ratings, which means that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is so small that it can't be measured.
And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moneyline</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> business roundup hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Dobbs</ENAMEX>,
who's also in charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX>--often draws <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close to half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>,
that's still insignificant next to anything the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> do.

            Of
course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> is hindered by the fact that so few cable systems carry it--it's
available in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 8.9 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. For its part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> insists that its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the trading day</TIMEX> is underestimated by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 40 percent</NUMEX>,
because a significant number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> supposedly keep their
televisions tuned to it as they go about their business. This may well be true,
but even if it is, it doesn't tell us very much about the broader impact of the
financial-news "boom," since those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> presumably have always paid serious
attention to the market.

            
Nonetheless, it seems likely that the growing
importance of the stock market to the retirement plans of middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> has translated into stepped-up coverage of business news and a
greater willingness on the part of mainstream news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
and network television--to showcase pieces on market turmoil. The problem is
that the new wave of business news doesn't really illuminate the workings of
the system all that well. In fact, most so-called business news isn't really
news about business--the creation and distribution of goods and services--at
all. Instead, most of it is "market" news--fruitless attempts to explain what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> are going to do in the near future, or somewhat-beside-the-point
explanations of why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> did what they did in the near past. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> are the sports pages of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX>, the way they cover the stock
market is analogous to a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> worrying more about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s
popularity than about its won-lost record.

            To be
sure, if you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> all day long you'll pick up some interesting news about
particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and the economy as a whole. Unfortunately, to get to the
useful information, you have to wade through reams of useless stuff, with
little guidance on how to distinguish between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. The basic reality of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">all-news</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, after all, is that there is a huge amount of time to fill
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX>. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> both offer a hodgepodge of
fundamental analysis, technical analysis, macroeconomic news, trend spotters,
and the occasional hard-news story. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A day</TIMEX> spent watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> is an object
lesson in what the word "pastiche" really means.

            
From <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> angle, of course, this might seem to
be the ideal expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX> approach to understanding the
world--or, in this case, the stock market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> doesn't offer just one angle on
the market. It offers multiple perspectives, in order to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> choose for
themselves. ("I'll have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pounds of technical analysis, one pound of momentum
trading, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half-pound</NUMEX> of fundamentals. Thanks.") So first we get a
"technical" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> who believes that if you look at the charts of a stock's
movements over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, you can discern coherent patterns that will guide
you in predicting when that stock's price is due to rise or fall. That analyst
is followed by another who believes that the key is to seek out and buy those
industries currently in favor with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. She, in turn, is followed by an
advocate for a more conventional approach: looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with strong
earnings growth that are currently trading at low stock prices.

            The
problem here is not that the technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> is crazy, although he is. The
problem is that these analyses of the market are presented as if they're all of
equal value--when, in truth, for any one to be correct, the others (with some
minor exceptions) must be incorrect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>--often the same
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--talking to these various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> never says: "Your argument directly
contradicts the one we heard <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just 15 minutes ago</TIMEX>. Why should we believe you?"
Instead, there's just a lot of nodding in assent.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way of averting this problem would be for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> or CNNfn to feature discussions among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of different approaches to
understanding the market. But that sort of open conflict would run the risk of
revealing the inherently futile nature of the project these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are
engaged in, namely, trying to make sense of the stock market's movement in the
short term. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each day</TIMEX>, after all, there are lots of different reasons why the
market does what it does. But you'll never be able to summarize them all--and,
more importantly, whatever reasons you find <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> aren't going to help you
understand what the market will do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. In the short term, investing is
really just a random walk.

            What's really wrong with
the financial-news boom, then, is that by creating the illusion that the walk
is other than random, it depends upon and encourages a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>'s approach to
investing. The point of having a stock market, after all, is not so that people
can buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX> when it's on its way up and sell at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX> to reap a quick
profit. The point is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are supposed to direct capital toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will make productive use of it and direct capital away from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will not. Just as index-fund investing defeats this purpose, so
too does trading based on anything other than an evaluation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
underlying prospects for the future. That's why ideally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> would feature
nothing but informative pieces on publicly traded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, with occasional
glances at the overall economic climate. Of course, its ratings would soon be
turned into hash marks. Which might suggest that real business news is
no more popular than it ever was.

         
      
   
