
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Cost of Crippling Castro</ENAMEX>

            A joke making the
rounds in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Q:</ENAMEX>
What are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> greatest accomplishments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX>'s revolution?

            
               A:
Health, education, and sports.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Q:</ENAMEX>
What are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> greatest failures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX>'s revolution?

            
               A: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast</ENAMEX>,
lunch, and dinner.

            On a recent trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, I
walked through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX>'s crumbling neighborhoods to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital Nacional</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermanos Ameijeiras</ENAMEX>. I found myself in a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> with the size and feel of
a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport terminal</ENAMEX> and, with my feeble <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, talked my way into meeting
some fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeons</ENAMEX>. I asked them to show me around. I was interested, I said,
in what they could do. But what I really wanted to see was what they couldn't
do--and why.

            For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has resolutely tightened the screws on trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuba</ENAMEX>
in an effort to topple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. However, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weeks</TIMEX> since the pope
spoke in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> embargo, the pressure seems to have lessened.
Not long after the papal visit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> allowed humanitarian flights and the
sending of money to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. Congressional legislation to end bans on
the sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and medical supplies is gathering bipartisan support, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote is expected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>. Embargo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, however, say the harm
is more rhetorical than real. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> can get supplies elsewhere, they argue, and
trading with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> is immoral. Here I had a chance to see the effects for
myself.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX>'s best, was
impressive. It has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> beds and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> specialties and offers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of a top
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. Its surgeons perform microsurgery, neurosurgery, and organ
transplants. And ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> seem to have no trouble getting access to this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>. Later on my trip, for example, I met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had no special
connections but had been sent here after she developed frightening stomach
pains. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> gets a sense of the priorities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who couldn't put
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> on her table (what little she finds she gives to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>) was able to
obtain a full medical work-up including endoscopy and biopsy of her stomach. A
parasite from the drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> had invaded her stomach lining.

            Still,
for all the resources <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> provides, the system <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> from an unreliable
supply of materials. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nilo Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, a cardiac <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>, told me, "We can do
any kind of surgery, but not always."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> appeared to be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 50s</TIMEX>. His office
was spacious, but his bookshelf was bare except for a single textbook
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>), a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> files, and some knickknacks. Like the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">met</ENAMEX>, he was quick to brag about his high-tech accomplishments. He described the
heart transplants and complicated valve replacements he performed. But I
wondered how he, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>, could spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> meeting with me at the spur of
the moment. He admitted that, for all he was capable of doing, he operated on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> per week.

            Was the
problem getting time in busy operating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>? No. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Rooms</ENAMEX> were free as we spoke.
Was it a lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>? He laughed and said that he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with failing hearts in the hospital awaiting surgery. The problem was
the constant struggle for supplies. Yes, they were costly, but that wasn't the
biggest issue. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> lacked for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> would have money for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ventilators</ENAMEX> and heart valves. The problem, he said, was the embargo.

            
Cardiac surgery, like every surgery, is a
series of interlocking steps, each requiring specialized materials. You need
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anesthetic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> tubing, blades for the bone saw, and so on. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> must halt surgery because he can't get one or another material
through the embargo. Among the sickest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> waiting were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 12</NUMEX> who needed
new heart valves. He had been able to get some Chinese-made replacement valves.
They are not that reliable, he told me, but they get the job done. Sometimes he
can get <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> valves sold illegally through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> at inflated
prices. "Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">CarboMedics valve</ENAMEX>," he said, his eyes shining, "is beautiful."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That week</TIMEX>, however, he didn't have the suture he needed to sew in the valves.
And a lack of perfusion fluid to prime the heart bypass machine had held up all
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> was reluctant to admit anyone would die waiting. We are strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, he told me. But "maybe sometimes" it happens.

            
Once home, I learned the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United States</ENAMEX> cuts off
supplies in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. First, sale of goods with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-made or patented
parts--which include most new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and medical devices--is embargoed under the
Trading With the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Enemy Act</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> merge with foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>,
the ban covers more and more. For example, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> acquisitions removed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> for pacemakers and several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemotherapy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> can seek a permit for medical sales, but hardly
any have because of the unmanageable requirements.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Torricelli Act</ENAMEX> cut <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> supplies by prohibiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> from entering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shippers</ENAMEX> are willing to lose
access to the world's largest market for the sake of this tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The act
also outlawed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> faces a similar ban. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> can at least barter for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.)

            
It's disingenuous to argue that the embargo
doesn't actually hurt many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. After all, the point of the ever-tighter
provisions is to cut off goods--including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>. But imposing
suffering can be justified if it averts greater suffering or serves a larger
good. And the embargo once served worthwhile purposes--forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
to spend resources propping up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> and denying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> resources to foment
revolution elsewhere. Now, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> poses no threat to anyone.

            It's conceivable we could
justify continuing to cause pain and death if the embargo fueled enough
discontent to cause <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s overthrow. But it shows no sign of doing so. The
relationship between political freedom and economic conditions seems far more
complicated than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of free trade or the embargo seem willing to admit.
I doubt that either policy can bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> down. Meanwhile the embargo
continues to exact its human costs.

            The names of patients
waiting for surgery at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> are kept on a computerized list.
The sickest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are at the top. When supplies are obtained, they get
surgery <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. On a walk through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> was unwilling to take
me to the intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> to see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. He claimed he was too
busy, and by the end of our conversation, he had grown reticent. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point
he admitted that he feared he had said too much, that I could use the
information to write anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> propaganda. He steered me to a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with
a new valve and a vigorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> recovering from a heart transplant. We finished
walking the wards and shook hands as medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. Then we parted ways,
the list of the sick scrolling through my head.

         
      
   
