
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Baby Mystery</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1949</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Noe</ENAMEX> bore died. One was stillborn. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> died
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> just after birth. And the others expired at home, just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>,
in their cribs, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe</ENAMEX> said she found them blue and either limp or gasping.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX>, including some of the most respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologists</ENAMEX> of the time, could
find no explanation for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> crib deaths. Indeed, the medical community
came to recognize that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of seemingly healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> inexplicably died
in their beds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, and they coined the name <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sudden Infant Death Syndrome</ENAMEX>,
or SIDS, for these cases.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX>
unexplained deaths in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> do not sit easily. We expect more from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and cops. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">District Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX> seemingly satisfied our expectations when she cited new medical
evidence to allege that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe</ENAMEX>, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX>, had smothered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with a pillow.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>, "has been solving old, unsolved
cases." She charged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noe</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> counts of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> degree murder.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX>'s claim puzzled me. How did she determine the
deaths were homicide and not SIDS? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> is not really a disease but rather the
name we've given to one of the great medical mysteries of our time: Any sudden
infant death that remains unexplained after a complete post-mortem
investigation is defined as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX>. Typically in SIDS cases, a previously healthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> is found dead in bed. No cry is heard from the infant prior to its death.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> may be found with clenched fists or frothy, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-stained fluid
issuing from the nose and mouth. Although <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SIDS</ENAMEX> deaths occur by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months of age</TIMEX>, older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> can die spontaneously and unexpectedly as
well.

            One early
SIDS theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> simply stop breathing has been discredited. Two
suggestive findings are that sleeping on soft bedding and sleeping face down
both increase a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s risk of sudden death. A successful campaign to get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> to bed on their backs or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> has been associated with a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38 percent</NUMEX> drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> deaths over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. Perhaps SIDS will turn out to
be a kind of freak accident in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, unable to turn over, are smothered
by their own bedding. The findings raise questions about how in the world you
could accurately distinguish suffocation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX>--especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Noe</ENAMEX> cases
in which the original autopsies showed no marks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> are
probably now nothing but bone. Forensic pathologists and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> I
contacted confirmed that there is no distinctive autopsy finding or new test
that could distinguish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> from homicide by suffocation.

            
So what was the basis for charging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noe</ENAMEX>? An
official close to the case who requested anonymity admitted that there was no
evidence that supported the charges of homicide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> involved simply
reviewed the old medical evidence. Had the previous pathologists missed
physical signs of suffocation? No, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said. It appears that the
critical factor was the pattern. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> deaths in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspicious</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe</ENAMEX> was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> present when each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> died.
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX> reopened the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Noe</ENAMEX> cases after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">March Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
magazine story about them.)

            In child
abuse cases, science often can only provide circumstantial evidence.
Occasionally, we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> find convincing evidence of abuse: cigarette burns,
X-rays showing multiple fractures of varying age, bruises that trace the
outline of a coat hanger, a stockinglike burn suggesting a foot plunged into
and held down in hot liquid. However, most cases do not come with such obvious
signs. In deciding whether to sic the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of social services on a case,
we have only vague indicators to rely upon. For example, according to
guidelines used at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, any bruise, facial
laceration, or long bone fracture in an infant is considered evidence of
possible abuse. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to tell us much more
than any physical evidence can.

            Not long ago, my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was playing unsupervised
in an adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when suddenly, she screamed. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> found her lying on the
ground, her right arm bent midway between the elbow and the wrist as if she had
an unnatural extra joint. As near as we could figure, it seemed she had tried
to climb onto our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our 2-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had pushed her over, and her arm
had got caught in the slats. As she fell, the bones of the forearm broke in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. When I took her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, I was grilled by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different people
asking me over and over again, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX>, exactly how did this happen?" It was, I
knew, a suspicious story--an unwitnessed fall resulting in a bad fracture. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> were looking, just as I do when I see young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trauma victims</ENAMEX>, for any
inconsistencies or changes in the story. It's easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to feel
self-righteous when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> ask questions as if they're cops, but as advanced
as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> has become, questions are still our main diagnostic test for
abuse.

            
Ultimately, I must have allayed any concerns. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> got a pink <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, and
I took her home without incident. I couldn't help but think, however, that my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> status played a role in all this. As much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> may try to avoid
it, when we decide whether to involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in a case, social factors
inevitably play a role. For example, we know that single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have almost
double the risk of being abusive, poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> almost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> times the
likelihood. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One-third</NUMEX> of crack-using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are found to abuse or neglect
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. (Race, by the way, is not a factor.)

            
In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noe</ENAMEX>, these factors played to her
advantage. She was married, middle-class, respectable. But the fact of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
deaths must mean something, right? As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coroner</ENAMEX> involved in the case said,
repeating a maxim that has gained currency among pathologists, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> SIDS death
is a tragedy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> is a mystery. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> is murder."

            The real answer, however, is
that science can't tell us what happened beyond reasonable doubt. Bucking his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh Medical Examiner Cyril Wecht</ENAMEX> says that multiple SIDS
deaths in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> do not automatically mean murder. The numbers certainly
make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noe</ENAMEX> deaths suspicious. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> now believe that losing one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> does not increase the likelihood that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> will lose another.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wecht</ENAMEX> points out, there have been cases of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and three unexplained
infant deaths in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in which homicide was ruled highly unlikely. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> have been wrongly accused in the past. And most troubling, as I
said before, we don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> is in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. We may have lumped
several different diseases together in describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>. Perhaps
multiple natural deaths in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are possible.

            Although science often
cannot prove even fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse, it is not without its power. Confronted
with the medical "proof" of homicide, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe</ENAMEX> admitted to suffocating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. She apparently couldn't recall what had happened to the others. Her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, however, is questioning the reliability of the confession, obtained
during an all-night interview. He says she will plead innocent to the
charges.

         
      
   
