
   
   
      
         
            Buy This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad Agency</ENAMEX>!

            Nike announces it's slashing
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> from its marketing budget and plans to re-evaluate all its ad
campaigns over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next six months</TIMEX>. Ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells BDDP</ENAMEX>, which came up with
the legendary "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Can't Believe I Ate the Whole Thing</ENAMEX>" campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alka-Seltzer</ENAMEX>
and convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braniff Airways</ENAMEX> to paint its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> a fluorescent fuchsia, goes
out of business after losing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> accounts at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bristol-Myers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Gamble</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi's</ENAMEX> puts its account up for review after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of declining
sales, even though its current award-winning ad campaign is simply some of the
best television on television. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX> announces that real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
going to start appearing in its ads again, though thankfully, the lizards and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX> will not disappear entirely.

            In other
words, it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a typical couple of weeks</TIMEX> in the advertising industry of the
1990s.

            Actually, it's tempting to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of perpetual
turmoil that characterizes advertising <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> has characterized the industry
since the modern era of advertising began sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1920s</TIMEX>. After
all, the underlying theme of just about everything honest written about the ad
game is fear--fear that your creative powers are going to dry up all of a
sudden, fear that you'll be stuck doing hand-cream ads the rest of your life,
and fear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> will pull the account. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederic Wakeman</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>
novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hucksters</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Gable</ENAMEX> in the film
version, is a tough-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> who gives up on advertising as soon as he
realizes that he's genuinely afraid of losing the big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX> account. And in the
1970s, legendary '60s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Della Femina</ENAMEX> wrote simply, "Most account <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
live with fear in their hearts." So it may be a mistake to think that
advertising in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> is more chaotic and stressful than it's ever been.

            On the
other hand, it may not be a mistake. For while the peculiar way advertising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> do business--any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is allowed to fire an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> with just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>' notice--has not changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 50 years</TIMEX>, the willingness of clients
to take their business elsewhere has. Even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX>, the average
business stuck with its ad agency for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX>. Today, the length of tenure
has shrunk dramatically, and even long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> feel free to put their
accounts into review, which essentially requires their current ad agency to
compete against a host of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX>. It's like an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> being forced to
audition over and over again in order to keep a part.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just the last two years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Lite</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bristol-Myers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">P&G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz</ENAMEX>, and
Toys "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>" Us (as well as a host of others) have switched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. At the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have started dividing up their advertising budgets. Instead of
a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> offering soup-to-nuts services, one will do the media buying
and another will do the creative. The creative budget is often parceled out as
well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wieden & Kennedy</ENAMEX>, for instance, handles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike's</ENAMEX> shoe advertising and
has given us the genuinely terrific "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Can</ENAMEX>" campaign that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> is now thinking
of killing. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodby, Silverstein & Partners</ENAMEX> handles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>'s apparel and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sports advertising, and has given us the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F.I.T.</ENAMEX> campaign, with endless
shots of the skin of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gabrielle Reece</ENAMEX>. Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, in other words, are not necessarily as big as they once were.

            In some ways, this probably
isn't a bad thing, though you'd have a hard time convincing most ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> of
that. The reason advertising is governed by fear, after all, is that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> rely on just a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to bring in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of their
revenues. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> knew that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-tenth</NUMEX> of its sales and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-eighth</NUMEX> of
its profits came from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, you can bet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> would be constantly worried
about keeping those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> happy. Insofar as fragmented budgets make
each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> less important to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s overall financial health,
then, it's better for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, though it does mean that more energy has to
go into finding new business.

            That
search is, needless to say, a difficult one at a time when there are literally
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> alone and, more importantly, when
the creative differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have narrowed considerably. Perhaps
the most curious thing about advertising <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, in fact, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that
spend all their time helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> build strong brand names and distinct
corporate identities have a very difficult time building brand names for
themselves.

            This wasn't always the case. To take only the most famous
example, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle Dane Bernbach</ENAMEX> came up with its brilliant ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>, no other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> would have made those ads. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ogilvy</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mather</ENAMEX> ad looked one way (usually a very boring and uptight way), and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDB</ENAMEX> or
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Wells</ENAMEX> ad looked another. And this was arguably true even through the
1980s. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBWA Chiat/Day</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wieden & Kennedy</ENAMEX> certainly exaggerated their
radicalism, as advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are wont to do, but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> ad
and the original "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Do It</ENAMEX>" ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> did look qualitatively different
from what had come before.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it's
far harder to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> apart. Look at the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Can</ENAMEX>" campaign, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> ads
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kobe Bryant</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surrealistic Levi</ENAMEX>'s ads. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could have
made them. More troubling, from the perspective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> themselves:
Watch a sneaker ad with the sound off. It will be next to impossible to discern
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoes</ENAMEX> are being pushed. Advertising, in that sense, is feeling
the impact of commoditization just as other industries are. But where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
in other industries can resist commoditization through technological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breakthroughs</ENAMEX>, better assembly lines, and--ironically--powerful branding, ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> seem at a bit of a loss.

            
What we'd all like to believe, of course, is
that an advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is ideally placed to resist commoditization, because
its main asset is the imagination of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, something that cannot be
duplicated. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful exec</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Age</ENAMEX> recently,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creativity</ENAMEX> is the anti-commodity." But while creativity may exist, it doesn't
necessarily exist over and over again. And at a time when ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all seem to
be drawing from the same palette of colors and styles, creativity and
distinctiveness are, oddly enough, not synonymous.

            In a sense, the advertising
industry is reluctantly moving toward a business model much closer to the
so-called free-agent economy than to the traditional idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. As
advertising budgets become more fragmented, it's easy to imagine a situation in
which ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> serve primarily to orchestrate production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, bringing in
art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and copywriters for specific ad campaigns rather than keeping a
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> on hand. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> lose major accounts, they often fire nearly
everyone involved with the account. How much longer can it be before agencies
decide that operating on a free-lance basis is simply more efficient?

            What keeps the older model
intact, in part, is the importance of relationships to the business.
Advertising is still a world where glad-handing and drinking with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> is
important to keeping their accounts. But the studio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
disappeared while studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> remained important as deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>, and the same
could happen in advertising. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> grow increasingly less committed to
their ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, the economics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> will have to change. In his
immensely tiresome memoir, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confessions</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Advertising Man</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ogilvy</ENAMEX> wrote, "If you can make yourself indispensable to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, you will
never be fired." No doubt. But for the ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, indispensability turned out
to be a hard sell.

         
      
   
