
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bat</ENAMEX>

            We're a month into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> has yet to rename his newest acquisition
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melrose Place Dodgers</ENAMEX>. Had he done so, it would probably not have surprised
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> who saw the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$311 million</NUMEX> purchase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> as final evidence of the sacrifice of the national pastime
to the greed and disloyalty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> went so far as to
suggest that before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> were sold, "there was hope baseball could pull
itself back from the brink. But now even those hopes are being dashed."

            In the
particular case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX>, of course, these lamentations were particularly
inapposite, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter O'Malley</ENAMEX> made
a coldblooded business decision in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX> to abandon <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> in favor of the
sunnier clime of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chavez Ravine</ENAMEX>. But the larger indictment of the changing
nature of team ownership is similarly misdirected. If anything, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> needs
more corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, particularly those, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>, that have major
investments in the game as a whole rather than a stake in a single
franchise.

            In the long run, the more corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, the less likely
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s current approach of limiting expansion and migration will
endure. Defending either the expansion of the number of baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> beyond
the current <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> or the movement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> to new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> is, of course,
enough to get you branded as an uncouth money-grubber. Defending both is enough
to get you shot. Expansion, it's argued, debases an already thin talent pool,
lowering the overall quality of play. The migration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX>, meanwhile,
breaks the hearts of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and rips the hearts out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>--generally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northern</ENAMEX> industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>--that can't afford to compete against the new
metropolises of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbelt</ENAMEX>.

            It's no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coincidence</ENAMEX>, of course, that the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of the status quo are always in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that already have baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. The unstated premise is that people
in, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> deserve the chance to attend a major league game more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> do. Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> are only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Senators</ENAMEX> moved there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>. But you have to draw the line
somewhere.

            
A less parochial view shows that change would
be good both for the sport and for cherished local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. Expansion would
obviously expand--duh!--the sport's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> base. And it, like migration, would
help eradicate <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s most persistent problem--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> between small-
and large-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. In essence, baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are able to reap what are
called monopoly rents because they face little or no competition for the local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>'s dollar. Other things being equal (and new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> with high-profit
luxury boxes can make a sizable difference), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in big markets are able to
reap much larger rents because the pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> from which they draw attendance
and TV viewership is much larger. Even with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>
are far more profitable than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh Pirates</ENAMEX> because there are so many
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> for their product--an advantage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirates</ENAMEX>, unlike a regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>, can't overcome by marketing their goods in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            The
reason this is a problem, obviously, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> are much richer than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirates</ENAMEX> and can therefore afford to pay more for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, which means
they'll be able to lure the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. But the revenues of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> as a whole will be hurt if just a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> dominate play, so the
greater wealth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> leads to the long-term decline of the game.

            This dilemma has occasioned anguished breast-beating ever
since the introduction of free agency into the player market <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years ago</TIMEX>. But
even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> could not freely sell their services on the open market, the
richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> still got the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. They just did so by buying them from
the poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas City Athletics</ENAMEX>, for example, were essentially a
farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1960s</TIMEX>, and not
coincidentally the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> won pennant after pennant. What free agency has done
is transfer those payments that would have gone to small-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> themselves.

            But the
answer to this dilemma is not a return to the old system nor is it a salary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX>. The real answer would require allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to move where there's
unsatisfied demand for the game, whether that be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> itself or in some
region that has no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. This might mean, in the short term, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> would lose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX>. But if there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> rents exacted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> would
decline, which means they wouldn't be able to pay so much for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, which
means it would be easier to run a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> successfully in a small market. The
problem, in that sense, is not that there are big and small markets but that
there are too few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in the big markets. Supply is not being allowed to
match demand.

            
Of course, existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> don't want new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
in their markets. Similarly, they don't want new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in general ,
because an important chunk of their current revenue comes from national
television and licensing contracts that are divided among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, fewer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> (though that's actually more complicated than it
may look, since expansion might open up TV markets--like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>--where
ratings have been traditionally low). Until <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s antitrust exemption is
removed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> don't have to worry about intruders in their current markets.
But a mechanism already exists for making expansion mutually beneficial:
revenue sharing of all local TV contracts and gate receipts. Revenue sharing
alone would solve many of the competitive-balance problems between small and
large markets. Green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX> has built a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> despite playing in the
smallest market in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>, in no small part because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> share <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> percent
of their total revenue.

            The point is that for all
their rhetoric about looking out for the best interests of the game, baseball
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> have been interested only in looking out for themselves. In an ordinary
business, that's fine. But in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, where the long-term
health of any one franchise depends on the long-term popularity of the game,
the pursuit of short-term self-interest--in the form of the protection of the
benefits of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX>--brings about collective harm. The exemption of
baseball from antitrust law is predicated on the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Baseball</ENAMEX> is one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> rather than an industry such as semiconductors or
computers. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> don't act like competing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice presidents</ENAMEX>. They act like
competing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, each seeking to maximize their local profits.

            In that sense, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>--which owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX>--could hardly be more venal or short-term in
focus than the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. In fact, it may well be that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>,
which is building a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> by stringing together a series
of local sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, is more likely to work for the best interests of the
game as a whole. That's precisely because it has a stake, through its TV
channels, in baseball rather than just in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the realities of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, after all, is that they're somewhat isolated from local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>.
Traditionally, that's been seen as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>. But in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, the
addition of a global--or at least national--perspective should be seen as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
