
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shortsighted Search for Synergy</ENAMEX>

            Visions of multimedia
synergy dance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner Redstone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of media conglomerate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>), television (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX>), video
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>), books (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> owns them all, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX>
keeps believing that someday they will all work as one. Imagine a best-selling
novelization of a hit film based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> series The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real World</ENAMEX> , a
film that then becomes the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-selling videotape at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>, and you get
some sense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">oasis</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX> keeps glimpsing just over the next sand
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dune</ENAMEX>.

            In the
past, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>'s dogged pursuit of media synergy led it to overpay for everything
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Studios</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>, and burdened it with a debt load worthy
of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. It also led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>--at a time when corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was
casting doubt on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> model and stressing the virtues of playing to
core strengths--to cling to the things it bought with a discomfiting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tenacity</ENAMEX>.

            The announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> wanted to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S</ENAMEX>'s
educational and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>--textbooks, computer books, professional
books, and reference books--then, came as something of a welcome surprise, at
least to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> were profitable (more
profitable, in fact, than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S</ENAMEX>'s trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>), they didn't fit very
well with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX>'s idea of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. More importantly, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> started
talking about getting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $4.5 billion</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> and using the
money to cut its debt in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, the words "fiscal responsibility" suddenly
sounded less improbable than they once had. There remains a great deal of
skepticism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> can get its price, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S</ENAMEX>'s
educational and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> are the largest in the world, and the
divisions have done adequately under a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for which they were but an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">afterthought</ENAMEX>. In the hands of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with a real investment in publishing,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed Elsevier</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGraw-Hill</ENAMEX>, they have the potential to be cash <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>.

            
Potentially a win-win deal all around? Perhaps. Still, it's odd that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>
went public with its plans before lining up a prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> company
source points out, saying "I'm really anxious to sell. Make me an offer" is
hardly the best strategy if you're looking to drive a hard bargain. It's also a
little surprising that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> has chosen to sell in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, rather than taking
advantage of the big tax savings that the law provides had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> waited a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and then spun off the publishing assets into a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX>'s desire to remake the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--and to placate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>, who have
been disenchanted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> now--outweighed tax
considerations.

            
What's most interesting about the deal is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> will be holding on to the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S. Book</ENAMEX> publishing is not
generally a high-profit-margin business, and it's also not as jazzy as
television or the movies. The decision to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S</ENAMEX> only makes sense,
then, in the context of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX>'s synergistic hopes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>, he says, is now
going to "focus on software-driven entertainment," which is the inelegant 1990s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> wants all its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> to be oriented toward
mass-market entertainment. And he points to the success of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX> book imprints and of books tied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX> film releases as
evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s parts add up to a stronger whole.

            But the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S</ENAMEX> publishes books based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> series--like the dreaded
Real World books--isn't, in and of itself, evidence of any real synergy.
After all, even if some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> published these books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> would reap the
benefits of licensing, royalties, etc. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> wouldn't have to worry about
what happens when that next <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road Rules</ENAMEX> book tanks. Similarly, publishing
books based on your own movies is a great idea when the movies are doing well.
But if you put out a few box-office duds, publishing books based on those duds
means you pay for the failures twice.

            Real synergy, in other words, only happens when you are
able to take lessons from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> business and apply them to another. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>
were using its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX>-induced expertise in appealing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9-year-olds</ENAMEX>
market to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books better, or taking what it's learned from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> to
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> out of disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, the idea of synergy would make more
sense. Now, it's possible that this is, in fact, happening behind the scenes.
But if it is, no one at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S</ENAMEX> seems aware of it.

            Actually,
at this point no one at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S</ENAMEX> is sure that they're aware of anything.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> got S & S when it bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>, but it wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>, not a
book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. And even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & S</ENAMEX> is probably the most profitable trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, the book market is essentially a stagnant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, at least
in terms of profits. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there imagine that the trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> will be
the next to go. The joke going around S & S <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>, which is handling the sale for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> that it could get
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 billion to $4.5 billion</NUMEX> if the trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> were included and ... well, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion to $4.5 billion</NUMEX> if the trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> weren't included.

            
The problem with this analysis is that it
assumes that the book industry is somehow in worse shape than the rest of the
entertainment industry. This assumption seems intuitively right--we no longer
live in a print culture, right?--but there's actually very little evidence to
back it up. The weird thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy, in fact, is that at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> when mass-marketed leisure and entertainment are supposedly more and more
important to our economic well-being, the entertainment industry as a whole is
barely growing at all. If, as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The X-Files</ENAMEX> would have it, we're now ruled
by a military-industrial-entertainment complex, the "entertainment" part of
that complex needs to take some quick lessons in management and profit growth
from its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>.

            On the
face of it, this seems crazy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner Redstone</ENAMEX>: These are among the most prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX>.
They end up on the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wired</ENAMEX> . They
foreshadow the world in which we're all either symbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> or hamburger
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flippers</ENAMEX>. But look at the numbers. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the music industry saw sales
decline slightly. Movie attendance was down. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> sold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>
fewer books than they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for cable
television seems to have plateaued at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 70 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> households,
while viewership of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> has, of course, continued to drop. Is
everyone watching videos instead? Hardly. Video rentals dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, which is part of the reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX> is only worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> paid for it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>.

            None of this is to say that there aren't successful
entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, although the short list would probably include only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si Newhouse Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advance Publications</ENAMEX>, and perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> (because of its
radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>). But these individual successes can't disguise the very curious
reality that we're living in a world that is somehow saturated by the media
without actually paying all that much attention to it. For most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, success depends on selling more of your product <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> than
you did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can sell as much of
their product <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> as they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, they should count themselves
lucky. If you want to know what a real myth is, don't bother with synergy. Just
look at the entertainment industry's self-image instead.

         
      
   
