
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell Factor</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell Computer</ENAMEX>, laid his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on his pillow <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 25</TIMEX>,
he must have been one tired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous seven days</TIMEX> he had
made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$830 million</NUMEX>, enough to exhaust anyone (in the best way, of course).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> was
not, however, the most tired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> in the land that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. And in fact, his
income for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX> was not even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fourth</NUMEX> that earned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">own Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, who was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.8-billion</NUMEX> richer when he fell asleep on the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> than he had been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week before</TIMEX>. (It has to be difficult
resisting those impulse purchases of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Porsches</ENAMEX> when you're able to say to
yourself: "What the hell, I made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. I can probably splurge a
little.") Still, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$830 million</NUMEX> is no shabby performance, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> certainly
slept the sleep of the innocent--or at least of the successful--<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>.

            Of course, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> actually saw any of these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>, since their gains were reaped entirely on
paper in the form of sharp increases in the stock prices of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. We've grown accustomed, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> being worth
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>. But actually this is a relatively recent development in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business, and while the financial success of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX> is a fine
expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dream, the lessons the business world has drawn from
that success are less salutary.

            The curious phenomenon that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' enormous wealth points to is a resurgence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
business of what's often called "proprietary capitalism"--a system in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are also the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who own them. The traditional
story of industrial capitalism's development in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is that it
had its roots in family-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, but that it quickly evolved into a
system where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> delegated the responsibility for
running them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business, in fact, lay in this
embrace of managerialism, of the idea that you didn't actually have to own
stock in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to do an excellent job managing it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Sloan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motors</ENAMEX>, who never made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$830 million</NUMEX> in his life, owned only a tiny sliver of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>, but he still managed it as if it were his.

            There were
always exceptions to this reign of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, to be sure, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>,
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kept tight control at least through the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, which was run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Watson</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> for most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century; and DuPont</ENAMEX>. But even these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> saw the authority of the
founders dissipate as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> grew larger and more ambitious in their
appetite for capital. The more money you borrow, and the more shares of stock
you issue, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you give a share in your business. As a result,
except for the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, where many large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are still owned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have fit a particular
model. The ownership of stock has been diffuse, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has been professional, in the sense that it has had no substantial
personal stake in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>.

            
What's striking, then, about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is that they, and their enormous personal fortunes, hearken back to
an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, where a personal stake in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was a guarantee of one's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">devotion to it.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell Computer</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> owns
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Ellison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX>, has a sizable
minority stake in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Jobs</ENAMEX>, having learned his lesson at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>, where he was forced out by professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sculley</ENAMEX>, owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX>
percent of his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pixar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toy Story</ENAMEX> ), thereby
ensuring that no one will ever push him around again. In the financial-services
industry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelity Investments</ENAMEX> is still run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schwab</ENAMEX> is the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shareholder</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that bears his name.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> owns a sizable chunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Knight</ENAMEX>, founder
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>, owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Of course, that means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knight</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$310</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>, but such are the perils of ownership.

            The older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">managerial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is certainly still alive and well, as proved by the
extraordinary number of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> who have been hired from outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>. But the return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> model is real. In
part, this is a function of the enormous entrepreneurial boom in the computer
industry over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two and a half decades</TIMEX>. The key word in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>
has always been "equity," and the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have clung to as much of
it as they could. In fact, with the notable exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>--there is,
shockingly, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with the last name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>--the best technology companies
have been those in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who started the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> have continued to
run it and to own much of it. Not coincidentally, these are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
have made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into billionaires.

            But the return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> model is also connected
to an important transformation in the way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business understands
incentives. During the glory days of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX> boom, it was assumed
that a high salary and meaningful responsibility were enough to motivate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to do the best they could. In the wake of the near-collapse of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> began to think that the real
problem was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> needed to be more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. That helps explain the
explosion in the use of stock options since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. Give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> a stake in
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the thinking went, and they'll perform better. After all, look
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.

            Insofar as
it assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> already being paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> will work
extra-hard only if given still more financial incentives, the options boom was
a glorious product of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> era. The idea of linking an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>'s pay to
performance is, on its own terms, obviously a good one. But too often stock
options are just gravy, tossed in on top of a huge base salary to satisfy the
demands of executive privilege. Piles of options by themselves do not make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>
act like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>--though they can make them ridiculously wealthy.

            
There's a dramatic difference between someone
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX> and someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>'s financial health is
completely wrapped up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> he started and still owns. Dunlap, for
his efforts in wrecking--that is, restructuring--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, is rewarded with
huge chunks of options that he immediately exercises so he can pocket the cash,
not so he can invest in the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. More than that, the lesson
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>'s success has been misunderstood. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX> has been a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and has made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have imagined that he's
been a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> because he's made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>. But it's
more likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> has been a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> because he's been running a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that is, in some important sense, his. Not that he's walking away from
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>, of course.

            True, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>-manager
model, successful as it has been, is not the only possible model for success.
But in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>'s case, it's clearly the ownership, not the accompanying financial
reward, that has really mattered. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, with their skyrocketing
pay to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, seem to have turned that formula on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, believing that they
can compete successfully only by duplicating the enormous financial gains
someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> has reaped. In confusing stock options with ownership,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> confuse trappings with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, these are
trappings that come with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX> price tags attached.

         
      
   
