
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Downside of Downsizing</ENAMEX>

            Somewhere along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX> a railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is lost. Actually, somewhere along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> coast many
railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are lost, rolling along <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">between freight yards</NUMEX>, attached to
locomotives they're not supposed to be attached to, carrying goods that will
arrive at their intended destinations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> late. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> belong
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific Corp.</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> built
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroad</ENAMEX> that joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>, though, it's had
its hands full trying to make the trains run on time.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, is having a very hard time making sure that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' claims get
paid. Unpaid claims have been piling up in its back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> the
insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> announced that its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-quarter</TIMEX> earnings had fallen
significantly because of all the administrative problems. Medical costs, at
least at the health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> deals, have been rising, but
since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> wasn't paying its bills, it wasn't able to figure that out until
recently.

            
On the surface, these might seem to be two
unconnected stories of corporate miscalculation. But you don't have to look too
deeply beneath the surface to recognize that the problems <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> are facing stem from the same cause, namely overhasty and overaggressive
job cutting, and that together they represent what you might call the downside
of downsizing.

            Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> have consummated large-scale mergers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half</TIMEX>, and both are therefore attempting to deal with sizable increases in
their everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX>, which has spent much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>
acquiring smaller rail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Pacific</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.9 billion</NUMEX>,
adding <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15,000 miles</NUMEX> of track to its inventory. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, shelled out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Healthcare</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April of 1996</TIMEX>, which left it with more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in its various health-care plans. One might have imagined
that, in the face of a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> base and the difficult task of integrating
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, computer systems, and cultures, slashing
payrolls would not have been Job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>. But then one would, of course, have
imagined wrongly.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> waited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> after its acquisition
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Healthcare</ENAMEX> to announce that it was cutting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,400</NUMEX> jobs and consolidating
its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> national service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. The stock market,
needless to say, applauded the decision. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> put it, "Any time you
have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to $9 billion</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that others
wouldn't have paid nearly as much for, it's natural that they're going to look
for substantial cost reductions to justify the transaction." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX>'s
job cuts were smaller--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were offered buyouts. But they
were even more dubious strategically, since the rail-freight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> was
booming nationally, and losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Pacific</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> meant
that UP now had <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of miles</NUMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> and very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who had
any experience with it.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retrospect</ENAMEX>, the results of these job cuts seem predictable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> discovered
that, in the words of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, "We miscalculated how valuable the
experience level was, and is, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> that works in these service
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is now hiring back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> or so claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to speed
up processing, but it remains unclear how much long-term damage was done, in
terms of alienated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> has spent essentially flying blind. What's more, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock
price has tumbled sharply.

            
The consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX>'s problems
have been rather more severe. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> serious
accidents--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two weeks</TIMEX>--that have taken <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> lives and
caused <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> in damage. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A month ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Railroad</ENAMEX>
Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> sprang surprise inspections on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. They found overworked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, brakemen, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX>
turning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80-hour weeks</TIMEX>, working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven days in a row</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Regulators</ENAMEX> called
UP's safety record "a fundamental breakdown," and things have not improved
since then. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surface Transportation Board</ENAMEX> declared "a
transportation emergency in the West," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRA</ENAMEX> announced that it would
step up its monitoring of crew fatigue and track safety.

            Oddly,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRA</ENAMEX> has yet to come up with a firm policy to solve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>-fatigue
problem, though it has promised to produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty days</TIMEX>? How
long does it take to say, "Um, we think you have to hire more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> right
now"? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> has, in fact, announced that it will be adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> estimate that the crisis has already cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shippers</ENAMEX> more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in delayed shipments and delivery snafus. UP <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> has said he wanted to have "the right number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" running the
railroad, since "it's a safety issue, not a financial issue." But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> suspects
that we got something closer to the truth when, in the midst of the crisis, a
UP <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said, "Nobody's budget is safe when it comes to doing more with
less." Didn't anyone tell him he worked in public relations?

            
What both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> stories
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">illuminate</ENAMEX> is the degree to which downsizing has become simply a reflex
decision for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. The stock market's instinctively positive reaction
to job cuts surely makes it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to justify their decisions to
themselves. But the reality is that job cuts have more to do with an
ill-considered definition of the bottom line than with placating Wall Street.
In other words, it's easier to look at the reduced labor costs from cutting
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,400</NUMEX> jobs than to anticipate the potential chaos those cuts will bring. And
that's particularly true when the concept of the lean and mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> has
attained the status of dogma. In his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Passion for</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Excellence ,</ENAMEX>
the sequel to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Search of Excellence</ENAMEX> , still an enormously influential
business book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Peters</ENAMEX> wrote, "There is, then, a lot that can be said for
simply cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. We find so many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that do so much better with so
many fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> can issue a revised edition, with chapters
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>.

            The
point is not that downsizing is in and of itself a mistake. The fact that
industries wax and wane is a reality of any economic system that wants to
remain dynamic and responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s changing tastes. Jobs lost in one
place are often created in another (although there are serious questions about
whether the jobs will be as good, particularly for industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>). And a
number of large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have downsized successfully, most obviously <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric</ENAMEX>, which cut an astounding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170,000</NUMEX> jobs worldwide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX> while
simultaneously tripling its sales.

            
But too often downsizing means what it has in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> case: fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing more work. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> now pull
more overtime than they did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have embraced
required overtime as a way of ensuring that work gets done. In theory,
downsizing should be a way of matching the size of your work force to the size
of your business. In practice, downsizing is too often about cutting your work
force while keeping your business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same</TIMEX>, and doing so not by investments in
productivity-enhancing technology, but by making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pull <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">80-hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and
bringing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temps</ENAMEX> to fill the gap. Downsizing itself is an inevitable part of
any creatively destructive economy. But overworked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> and sleepy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX> aren't creative, they're simply destructive.

         
      
   
