
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.R.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Triple Hex</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of months ago</TIMEX>, when
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> surgical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and I went around a table divvying up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> on
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> duty, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one March date</TIMEX> sat conspicuously unpicked--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C'mon</ENAMEX>, I thought. This is ridiculous. So when it was my turn
again, I put my name down for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13</TIMEX>. Rest up, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> told me. You'll
be in for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long night</TIMEX>. I laughed and dismissed the thought.

            But
looking at my calendar a while later, I noticed that the moon would be full
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. When someone noted that a lunar eclipse would be occurring
then, too, I felt my skepticism slip a little. Perhaps I would be in for a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">miserable night</TIMEX>, after all. Trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> such as myself, however, do not
succumb easily to superstition. Like any self-respecting rationalist, I asked
the obvious question: Isn't there a study on this?

            It turns out there is one reputable study that has tried to
assess whether or not luck actually does go bad on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> .
(I'm not sure which is more surprising: that someone actually spent time
researching this or that I could find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> such study. This is, after all,
a world that has studied even how chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> distributes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX> around the
compared hospital admissions for traffic accidents on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> with those on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 th</NUMEX> in a community
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. Despite a lower highway traffic volume on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
than on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 th</NUMEX> , admissions for traffic accident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> increased
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52 percent</NUMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> . "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlucky</ENAMEX> for
some," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> concluded. "Staying at home is recommended." How you escape
the bad luck at home they didn't explain.

            You really
can't make much of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
Lots of other factors could have caused that surge of crashes. Still, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> phobia is widespread. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Dossey</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
behavioral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, has coined a term for it: "paraskevidekatriaphobia,"
which he derived from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> for fear of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> . He
estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 17 million</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> suffer mild to
severe <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX> or change their activities--performing rituals before leaving
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, calling in sick to work, or postponing flights or major
purchases--and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750 million</NUMEX> in revenues because of these
fears.

            
Superstitions about the moon may be taken even
more seriously. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, and in disparate civilizations around the world,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have suspected that the cycles of the moon have a powerful influence
over us. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> poll found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still believed the moon
alters individual behavior. And mental health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> believed it more
often than anybody else. The centuries-old word "lunatic" derives from the
connection thought to exist between the full moon and madness.

            The idea
of lunar human cycles seems more plausible than a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday the 13</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> once dismissed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> biological cycles as preposterous, but
they now widely accept that body temperature, alertness, memory, and mood all
fluctuate according to a predictable "circadian" rhythm. Evidence also shows
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> effects on mood and behavior.

            Ifound some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> studies testing for "circalunidian"
cycles. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> study of self-poisoning at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Wales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Journal of Australia</ENAMEX> .
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1988 to 1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> admitted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,215</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for overdosing on drugs
or poisoning themselves with toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> checked to see
whether peaks in such events occurred not just according to the phase of the
moon but also according to one's zodiac sign or numerological readings (as
"calculated according to the formulas contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zolar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encyclopedia</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden Knowledge</ENAMEX> "). To no one's surprise, self-poisoning
rates were not affected by whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was born a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virgo</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libra</ENAMEX>. Nor
did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zolar</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Name Number</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Month Number</ENAMEX>," or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birth Path Number</ENAMEX>" for a person
make any difference. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (but not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>) were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 25 percent</NUMEX>
less likely to overdose around the time of a full moon than around a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moon</ENAMEX>.

            That
self-poisonings decrease at the full moon actually correlates with the results
of other studies. If any link between psychology and the full moon exists, it
seems to be protective. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> study of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> of suicides in
Dordogne, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, concluded, in charmingly ungrammatical <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, that "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> dies less in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Full Moon</ENAMEX>, and more in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Moon</ENAMEX> period." Studies in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuyahoga County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dade County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, also found a drop in suicides at
the full moon. These studies don't quite clinch the full moon's happy effect,
however. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 10</NUMEX> other studies have been done, and they have not confirmed
a lunar cycle for suicide.

            
As for other forms of craziness, the moon seems
to have no effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> have reviewed logs for calls to police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>,
consultations to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX>, homicides, emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> visits, and other
measures of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> burden of madness. They found no consistent relationship,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> way or another, with the moon.

            Somehow, however, the moon
does have an effect on human beings--at least on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menstruation</ENAMEX> typically
occurs on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 day</TIMEX> lunar cycle. And even the phase of the moon matters. In a
study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">826</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 percent</NUMEX> began menstruating during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the four days</TIMEX> around
the new moon, whereas <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">no more than 13 percent</NUMEX> did so during any other <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four day</TIMEX>
period. This puts the peak of ovulation at the full moon. (Could this provide
an evolutionary explanation for the romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> we have with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moon</ENAMEX>? I'll leave that to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               's resident
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwinian</ENAMEX>, to sort out.) How this happens is baffling. The lone hypothesis I've
found proposes that the moon generates tidal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
percent of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> that is water. But that only raises more questions--such
as how tides are supposed to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> menstruate.

            The evidence satisfied me
that neither the full moon nor the inauspicious date threatened my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
Nonetheless, I came on duty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX> to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> from whom I was
taking over swamped with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. He stayed late to help me catch up. Just
after he left, a new trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> rolled in--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28-year-old</TIMEX> who had been
knocked unconscious in a high-speed head-on collision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramedics</ENAMEX> said he had been stalking his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> with gun in hand. He fled
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when cops arrived and led them on a chase that ended in the massive
crash. The rest of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> was no better. I was, as we say, "slammed." It's
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full moon Friday</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> explained. I was about to say
that studies showed no connection. But my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pager</ENAMEX> went off before I could start.
I had a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> coming in.

         
      
   
