
   
   
      
         
            The Stock Spinners

            The problem with venality
in business is that getting outraged about it makes it easy to miss the
systemic problems that venality often disguises. And that's exactly what's
happened in the uproar over the Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> called "spinning."

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spinning</ENAMEX>" has, apparently, been common on the Street for as long as anyone can
remember, and yet it had never really been written about until a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1997</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> broke the story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of it
are simple: An investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that's underwriting an initial public offering
gives shares in that IPO to corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with which the
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> is either doing business or would like to do business. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can then "spin" the shares, which is to say, sell them for a quick
profit as the stock's price bounces higher, something most IPOs have tended to
do on their opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of trading. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robertson Stephens</ENAMEX>, for instance, gave one
client <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> shares in the IPO for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pixar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toy</ENAMEX>
Story ; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> spun those shares into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2-million</NUMEX> profit. The
assumption, of course, is that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who receives a gift like this will
be more likely to direct his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s business toward the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that
proffered the shares. Quid pro quo.

            
If that's not unsavory enough for you, in some
cases the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> don't give the shares to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> until the
stock has started trading well above the offering price. In other words, if an
IPO's opening price is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>, and within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> of the opening bell
it's trading at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> will choose that moment to allocate the shares to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>'s account. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> gets the shares at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> and sells them at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX>, all in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fell swoop. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> are able to do this only by abusing a
regulation that permits them to cancel a mistaken allocation of IPO shares
before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first trading day</TIMEX> ends. The conversation, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> imagines, goes a
little bit like this: "Now that the stock's price has risen, I realize I didn't
mean to give them to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s account. I meant to give them to you! Now,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that deal we were discussing ..."

            Well,
it's probably not quite that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, but spinning does seem unquestionably to
violate state laws that prohibit corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> from taking personal
advantage of financial opportunities that they get because of their position at
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> recently wrote that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s unique strength has
always been that the path to success isn't totally rigged, that it's not simply
about being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of some inner circle that cuts you in on the action for
life," and that spinning threatens this strength. But though he deserves a nice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pat</ENAMEX> on the back for the graduation-speech rhetoric, thinking in terms of
fairness doesn't really get us very far. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinning</ENAMEX> is unfair, but then so is
life, as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> told us. To see why spinning really should be eliminated,
you have to look at the question from a hard-nosed efficiency angle.

            
Why, after all, do we have laws against
bribery? If someone really wants my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s business, why shouldn't he be
able to do everything he can--including paying me off--to get that business?
Because bribery encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to make decisions based on the wrong
criteria, which means in the business world that it distorts the efficient
allocation of resources. Absent the bribe, I would decide to give my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
business to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment Bank</ENAMEX> A. But because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment Bank</ENAMEX> B allowed me to spin
shares in a new Internet IPO, I give my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s business to them instead.

            This is
bad in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different ways. First, I'm violating my fiduciary responsibility to
my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, because I'm making a decision based not on what's best for it, but
rather on what's best for me. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that already do a lot of
IPO business will tend to get more business, simply because they have more
shares to spread around. The rich get richer, not because they're more
efficient but because their ability to bribe is greater.

            
Ordinarily, of course, bribery tends to be
somewhat self-limiting, in the sense that you don't want to spend more on
bribes than the revenue that you generate through them. But spinning costs
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> nothing at all. Once an investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> has underwritten an
IPO--which means that it has committed to selling all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s available
shares at a set price--all it has to worry about is making sure those shares
get bought. Needless to say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are anxious to buy shares when they know
they can sell them <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> later for an easy profit. So while a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
bribes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> is typically hurt by the fact that money that could have gone
toward profitable investments instead goes toward bribes, in the case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spinning</ENAMEX>, both briber and bribee win.

            The fact
that some investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are getting more business than they otherwise might
is a good enough reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to step in. But spinning has still worse
consequences. The practice works only if the price of an IPO bounces
significantly higher on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX>. That gives investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> an incentive
to set opening prices lower than they should be. Instead of taking a company
public at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> a share, and watching it trade at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long, an investment
bank can take a company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> a share, watch it jump to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> right after
the opening bell, and allocate those now-profitable shares to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.

            
It's possible, of course, that investment banks
just keep getting surprised over and over again by the strong demand for IPOs,
and that they really make their best effort to match opening prices with market
demand while giving themselves reasonable insurance against getting stuck with
unsold shares. But somehow it seems unlikely that spinning would have become
such an institutionalized practice if investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> didn't have a pretty
good sense that a stock's price was going to jump on its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">opening day</TIMEX>. And that
means the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> whose IPOs end up underpriced.

            Underpricing an IPO, of
course, deprives the newly public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of capital. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pixar</ENAMEX> went public,
the money raised from that very first sale of its shares was what it used to
run its business in the future. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pixar</ENAMEX> went public at a price <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX>
lower than the highest price <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> paid for its shares on the opening day of
trading. And while it would be a mistake to say that the stock could have
opened at that highest price, it's safe to say that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robertson Stephens</ENAMEX> had
done a better job of gauging demand, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> that went into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>' pockets would have gone into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pixar</ENAMEX>'s vaults instead.

            What's frustrating about
all this is that the moment when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> goes public is when the stock market
should function most efficiently. That's the only time when the money you pay
for a stock goes right to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, rather than to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>. The price
of an IPO, then, should reflect as nearly as possible what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> really
think about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s prospects. And yet everything about the IPO
process--from spinning to the fact that shares are distributed mainly to large
institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to the fact that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are fed information
before the IPO that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> never see--works against the market's
efficient operation. Wall Street has come a long way from the insider-dominated
world that was blown apart by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>. But spinning is an
excellent reminder of how far toward real transparency the Street still has to
go.

         
      
   
