
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organ Meat</ENAMEX>

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> clearly are
itching to do it. Consider this classified ad from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Sparrow</ENAMEX>, a 55-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> short for a needed gallbladder operation, which ran in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17, 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> under "medical supplies":
"<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">KIDNEY</ENAMEX>--Runs good, Taking offers. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000/obo</NUMEX>."

            Someone
must have called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, because it pulled the ad after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>,
noting that organ selling is against federal law. That didn't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Curtis</ENAMEX>,
though. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> managed to slip this ad into the
same newspaper on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10, 1998</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">BRITISH MADE Kidney</ENAMEX> shaped item; will swap for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>' motor/sail <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>." When it came out that he was selling one of his kidneys,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> pulled his ad, too.

            Awful, right? Not at all, some say. Organ selling--click
for more examples--is gaining a respectable fan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. Recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> posted an article on its Web site backing organ markets, and former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">du Pont</ENAMEX>, policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for Policy</ENAMEX>
Analysis, has endorsed the idea. Its most sophisticated defense, however, comes
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Epstein</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epstein</ENAMEX> is
pursuing an honorable but difficult mission. He wants to alleviate the enormous
shortage of organs for transplantation. He also wants to bring libertarianism
into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> in which few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX> survive. In his book Mortal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peril</ENAMEX> and a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> op-ed, he stakes a simple
claim: Even in health care, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be allowed to do what they wish with
their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> (as long as they don't hurt anyone else). And that includes
selling their body parts. It's not just because he believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have the
right. It's because he thinks giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that freedom will save lives.

            
It's harder to refute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epstein</ENAMEX> than you might
think. He is probably right about saving lives. The transplant waiting list
currently includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55,560</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four thousand</NUMEX> of them will die
waiting. Healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could conceivably sell their eyes, some skin, a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bones</ENAMEX>, a kidney, a portion of their liver, and even a lung and still survive.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epstein</ENAMEX>'s organ market opened for business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with the resources
would certainly bid up prices enough to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>. Perhaps, as he says,
charity will even raise money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who can't pay the going rate. ("If
you could spare just a couple of dollars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ma'am</ENAMEX>, we'll have enough to buy
someone a beautiful cornea.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Epstein</ENAMEX>
has a ready response for the arguments. Won't organ selling draw down-and-outs
with lower quality organs? So what, he says. The market will reduce the price
for their organs, testing will weed out unacceptable risks, and the risks will
outweigh the lives saved anyway. What about the risk that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coerced</ENAMEX> or will act impulsively? He says that we can do careful screening and
require waiting periods. Aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who sell their organs out of desperate
financial need acting involuntarily? No more so than when they stoop to
cleaning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX> for minimum wage, he says. You might reply that this isn't
just cleaning out toilet bowls. But, he says, if you're really worried about
exploiting the poor then we can require a minimum income for anyone who sells
their organs.

            Well, I am no philosopher, and I remain unencumbered by
legal training, but I still believe the whole idea is warped. My opposition
stems from exposure to ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as they make decisions about whether to
undergo surgery, to take their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>, and so on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Libertarians</ENAMEX> have great
faith that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> nearly always make rational choices and that having more
choices can't be bad. But any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> can tell you that's not true. In <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>,
you come to recognize how unreliable the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> of reasoning is and how
susceptible it is to subtle forms of exploitation.

            Consider a
common decision faced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with asymptomatic carotid stenosis, a
blockage of the carotid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about an 11 percent</NUMEX> chance
of a stroke or death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. Surgery to remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">blockage</ENAMEX> carries a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
percent risk of causing immediate stroke or death, but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> risk is
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 5 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> must decide whether the upfront risk of surgery is
worth cutting their overall risk of having a stroke in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. It's not an easy
task. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> must define what's most important in his or her life,
then calculate the best course to meet these goals. I can tell you that a lot
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fail to reason through the options very well. Even when they
understand their goals clearly, they often pick a choice that runs against
their aims. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">academician</TIMEX>'s terms, they fail to maximize their
self-interest.

            
Studies have shown that the brain has
systematic faults in reasoning, especially when processing risk information
like this. For example, the order in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> presents options can easily
sway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Also, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are fine <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX> of the time after surgery
can lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> one way, while saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> experience strokes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of
the time can lead them in the other direction. Yet there is no right way to
frame the options. Another quirk, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">con artists</ENAMEX> know all too
well, is that the brain is not good at weighing small chances of big gains (or
losses) against large chances of small losses (or gains).

            When an
organ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> is trying to decide whether the terrible dangers from kidney
removal or the certain loss of sight from surrendering an eye is worth a sudden
cash infusion, his effort to identify his best interest will be confused by how
the question is framed, by difficulties sorting out the statistical risks, by
the vision of all that money, and many other factors. These vulnerabilities are
easily exploited. But even when not taken advantage of, plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get
serious decisions wrong--enough that we should question libertarian beliefs
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should do what they want and live with the consequences.

            Some options are so terrible and irrevocable, so unlikely
to be in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s self-interest, and so open to exploitation and flawed
decision-making that society outlaws them. In human experimentation, for
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> cannot pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> so much that the poor could be
exploited. Rules limit how much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> you can donate or sell at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sitting.
And while we allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to give a kidney to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, we do not allow them
to donate their heart. Likewise, hawking an organ would be right for so few, if
any, that permitting the option makes no sense at all.

            Isn't this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paternalism</ENAMEX>? Yes. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epstein</ENAMEX> seems to recognize we need some when he accepts
laws stopping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from selling themselves into slavery or selling a vital
organ such as their heart. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> will argue about where to draw the line. Some
think seat belt laws, for example, go too far. But few would discard laws
against organ selling.

            
Iknow that I could find myself on that
transplant waiting list someday. But I'll take my chances. It's certainly
better than living in a society that allows money to entice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to convert
their own health into a commodity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> can be weak, and money is all too
often the way to their heart.

         
      
   
