
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook</ENAMEX>

            "It is easier to get out of
bed in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> if you know you are going to make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> at the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, I think, would agree with this. "[B]uy stocks in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have a good chance of going up." Again, as opposed to the
alternative, this seems wise. Finally, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> is too fluid to predict." Unless,
apparently, you're predicting whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock will be going up enough
to make you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> in a day.

            These
trenchant statements of the obvious can be found in the collected works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>, former real estate prophet and current stock market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of , whose only business is marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s books, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cassettes</ENAMEX>, and his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Workshops</ENAMEX>, in which you can enroll for
the piddling sum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX>. He is also, at last count, author of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> books on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> business best-seller list, including the original
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">classic Wall Street Money Machine</ENAMEX> , and the recent Business Buy the
Bible . (That is not a typo.) The books offer an almost self-parodic mix of
motivational rhetoric, complete confidence that nothing will go wrong, and an
utter lack of anything like an understanding of economics. Not coincidentally,
they also promise enormous returns, fast--returns of, at the very least, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> and perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as between 600 percent</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">800 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. "I make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> writes. "I'll teach you to do the
same."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> is more than just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> of the
investing world. He's also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> example of the speculative mania that
long bull markets often engender, the froth that rises to the surface in
turbulent times. Even more importantly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s methods--which in their essence
rely on the purchase of options on margin--underscore the almost complete
divorce between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> financial markets and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. After
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wading</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s texts, you begin to understand why it seems so natural to
call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> "parasitic."

            Well, yes,
I know you're saying, but do his methods work? What, after all, is the label
"parasite" next to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s definition of being rich)?
The short answer to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question is: Probably not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> insists he's been
inordinately successful with his strategies, and his later books are filled
with testimonials from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying things like: "I just sold the calls at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13.50</NUMEX>. It's only a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.5 percent</NUMEX> return, but annualized it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4,562.5 percent</NUMEX>"
and "I started with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> and my account is now at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$177,000</NUMEX>." But he doesn't
offer any systematic accounting of his trading record; and we do not hear from
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ended up gambling away their life savings. ("I started with
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> and I now have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52</NUMEX>. Thanks so much.")

            
One also wonders why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> spends so much time
selling books and seminars if he can make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> a day with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just 15 minutes</TIMEX> of
work. Actually, we know the answer to that question: His "real passion is
helping others improve their lives."

            It would
be easier to believe in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook's</ENAMEX> dedication to our well-being and the
truthfulness of his claims if his past record were more reassuring (click for a
look at that record). When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s get-rich-quick-in-real-estate promotions
failed, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Business Alliance</ENAMEX> holding worthless
paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> simply moved on to bigger things. And <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' newfound passion
for stock investing provided the perfect opportunity.

            To seize that opportunity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> counsels strategies that,
despite his simplistic truisms, are both complicated and risky. He recommends
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> leverage their existing capital, so that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of their
investments are purchased on margin (that is, loaned to them by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX>).
He urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to pay an inordinate amount of attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
announce stock splits. And, most importantly, he recommends buying and selling
complex arrays of options, often at the same time.

            Whether or
not this is really the best way to make money in the market, it is certainly
the best way to ensure a steady supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s home-study
materials and workshops. Of course, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> says more than once (actually, he
says it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 25</NUMEX> times), what's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> for a workshop next to the veritable
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> you'll make as soon as you've learned the sure-fire techniques of
buying options on margin?

            
True enough. But how do those techniques work?
Here's the very short version: There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of options--calls and
puts--both of which you can buy and sell. When you buy a call, you purchase the
right to buy a stock at a given price. If a stock is at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and you buy
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> calls at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>, and the stock never gets to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>, your options expire
worthless. But if the stock gets to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX>, you can make a nice profit. Buying
puts is the same, only in reverse. You buy the right to sell a stock, obviously
in the expectation that it will go down.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>,
though, isn't really interested in exchanging the options for actual shares. He
just wants to buy and sell the options themselves, because options are both
cheaper and more volatile than stock, and therefore offer the prospect of much
larger gains. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s entire strategy is built on the principle that it's
possible to predict, in the short term, when stocks will rise and fall. A surer
recipe for disaster has never been devised. His strategy is also built on the
assumption that, if you've got a sure thing, you should bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on it,
which is why you buy on margin. But he never makes clear that buying on margin
means that you stand to lose a lot more when you make a mistake. And because
you're buying options, you're left with nothing. There are no shares of a stock
that might someday come back, just piles of options as worthless as those
shares of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Business Alliance</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>
if you missed the previous link to it.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> refers to his strategies as evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
dream is still alive. But if so, that dream has become the feeblest of ideals.
Stock options, after all, serve no useful purpose in the real economy. Unlike
commodity futures or even currency futures that allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to
do a better job of projecting their future business, stock options contribute
nothing to the smooth functioning of capital markets. The stock options market
doesn't make it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to go public, or for existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to
raise money. It's simply a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> might just as well be gambling on
what color tie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will wear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stock Market</ENAMEX>
Miracles , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> writes that "the way to wealth is to enlarge the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>." It's
an odd maxim for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose work is dedicated to the idea that the way to
amass wealth is to take it, not create it.

         
      
   
