
   
   
      
         
            Lessons From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>

            Long-standing oral
traditions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean Stud</ENAMEX> video-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> machines apparently don't mix that
well. Or so I'd like to deduce from the recent decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Navajo Nation</ENAMEX> to
reject casino gambling on its reservation land in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. After
all, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Navajo</ENAMEX> culture is replete with stories cautioning against the dangers of
gambling, and this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navajo</ENAMEX> have said
no to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>.

            At a time
when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s model of economic development, the Navajo
vote may seem a grand self-defeating gesture. But while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is certainly
a tremendous economic success story, it's not clear that the story can be
easily duplicated elsewhere.

            That's not because playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>'s role in a gambling
operation requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Feynmanian genius</ENAMEX>. The economics of casino gambling are
pretty straightforward: Every day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walk through the doors, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> around
for a while, and eventually leave, and when they leave they have--as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>--somewhere <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 78 percent and 81 percent</NUMEX> as much money as they had
when they came in. That's it. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, of course, lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX>
percent of their money, and in doing so effectively transfer their cash to
those who lose less or who--rarity of rarities--actually win. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>'
cut of the "drop"--the total cash that's converted into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chips</ENAMEX> or tokens--is
remarkably unvarying. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Puzo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fools Die</ENAMEX> puts it:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Percentages</ENAMEX> never lie. We built all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> on percentages. ... The
percentage will always stand fast."

            (There is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> real exception to this rule--the high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roller</ENAMEX>, and it is only a
short-term exception. Click for some examples.)

            
What this means is that running a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> is not
really about gambling at all. You do have to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from cheating, and you
do have to keep deadbeats like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adnan Khashoggi</ENAMEX>--who bankrupted the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sands</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> by not paying his markers--from skipping out on their debts. But the real
business of casinos is not about what happens once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> sits down at a
blackjack table or in front of a slot machine. The real business is about
getting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> to sit down at your table and not the table at the
casino across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.

            In that
sense, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> is like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, except that there's
one crucial difference: Every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> is selling the exact same product. There
are minor variations in the kinds of slot machines you'll find, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> are
always coming up with mindless variants on the classic table games, but in
essence what every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gambler</ENAMEX> is buying is simply opportunity. Or, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
has said, they're buying "time." Time to win and, of course, time to lose.
Whether you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus Circus</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luxor</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM Grand</ENAMEX> or the Golden
Horseshoe, though, the time is the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> can sell a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX> to
distinguish itself from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage</ENAMEX> can't advertise
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blackjack</ENAMEX>!" to distinguish itself from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrah's</ENAMEX>.

            What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage</ENAMEX> can and does advertise instead is itself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is often described as the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> because its entire
existence depends on a service economy. In another way, though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has
already defined <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s present. From the start, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> couldn't
compete on price or essential product, they competed on the basis of their
brand names. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> is a global version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesars</ENAMEX> vs. the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropicana</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Branding,</ENAMEX>
in fact, has driven the curious evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>' paradise
to neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> industry has certainly supported endeavors like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>'s theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excalibur</ENAMEX>'s medieval jousts (and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance</ENAMEX>-a-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lotta Pasta</ENAMEX>) as a way of attracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> who might otherwise gamble
at their local riverboats. But a more important factor behind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>'
ever-more-elaborate themed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> is the competitive pressure to set oneself
apart. I'm not convinced that knowing that there's a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150-foot</NUMEX> replica of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX> in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> makes the
experience of playing blackjack inside any different, but the statue is not the
product. The statue is just the advertising.

            
And it's advertising that has worked very well.
Much as we <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rat Pack nostalgists</ENAMEX> might mourn the loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flamingo</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sands</ENAMEX>, there's no quarreling with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>' economic performance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has
led the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in job growth for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each of the past 15 years</TIMEX>. Casino revenue from
gambling has risen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year since 1982-1983</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> are now deriving a
greater percentage of their revenue from their hotel and restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>.
Something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> in new construction projects are currently underway
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, which will feature a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-story replica of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eiffel Tower</ENAMEX>. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> have struggled for
profitability since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has proven itself almost
impervious to recession.

            In part,
this is because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has itself become one of the world's most powerful
brand names. And in part it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>'s business climate is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supply-sider</ENAMEX>'s dream: no corporate income tax, no personal income tax, no local
earnings tax, no inventory tax, no capital-stock tax, no franchise tax, no
admissions tax, no inheritance tax, low property tax, and a right-to-work
state. Difficult not to make money when you're the only game in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in a Third
World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>-state.

            It's a flippant comparison, to be sure, but it's one that
illuminates the reasons why gambling has not been an economic panacea for other
parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, parts where the New Deal actually had an impact, for
example. More than that, the comparison also gets at what may be the most
interesting thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, namely that it's the economic equivalent of
an exporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powerhouse</ENAMEX>. In this particular case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>
to purchase the goods rather than having them shipped out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> are the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Casinos</ENAMEX> thrive not because of the business they do with
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, but because of the business they do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from around
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and around the world. Call <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Far West Tiger</ENAMEX>, and you
wouldn't be too far off the mark.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branded</ENAMEX>, service-driven,
globalized, and unhindered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> do sound
uncannily like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for the economy into which we appear to be moving. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Thompson</ENAMEX> once said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus Circus</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> where craps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flying trapeze artists</ENAMEX> mingle beneath a billowing canopy, that it was what
hepcats all over the world would be doing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> had
won <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. But it might be that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus Circus</ENAMEX> is already a version of
what we all do, not just on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> but rather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day of the week</TIMEX>.
All of us but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navajo</ENAMEX>, that is.

         
      
   
