
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Japanese</ENAMEX> Mythology

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Up-and-coming</ENAMEX> challenger to
undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> to complete basket case in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>: The
saga of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy looks more and more like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-1940s</TIMEX> boxing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melodrama</ENAMEX>--though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> imagines that if this were <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> would
demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> ultimately get up off the canvas and retake the title.
Where's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Garfield</ENAMEX> when we need him?

            While
that narrative may be accurate enough in broad outline, on the level of actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> it tells the wrong story. The current stock market's infatuation with
all things Internet has led to indefensible overestimation of the actual
strength of most Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. So too has the prevailing picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">sclerotic</ENAMEX> economy of tightfisted oversavers and corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> led to a
dramatic underestimation of the crucial role the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
still play in the global economy.

            There's no denying the short-term macroeconomic picture for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is dismal, though it's hard to resist the thought that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> just ran its printing presses and dumped piles of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">yen</NUMEX> out onto the
street, things would be OK. But it's probably true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> who picked
up the yen would immediately bank it, instead of buying a brand-new suit or
power mower as any patriotic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> would. As a result, until the
long-promised overhaul of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s financial sector is complete and its web of
subsidies and regulations is simplified, it's hard to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> getting
the dose of creative destruction it sorely needs. The impact of domestic
stagnation on large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> has, of course, been dramatic. In the
auto industry, for instance, sales have declined to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
peak. The same is also true, albeit to a lesser extent, of the
consumer-electronics market.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have
also been hit much harder than their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> by the crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>.
While much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> relies on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> for sales growth in the future, most
important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have been relying on it for growth in the
present. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> own <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 80 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> car market,
excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, and are dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in most other industrial categories.
As a result, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thais</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysians</ENAMEX> are forced to slash purchases of new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> or investment in earth-moving equipment, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> feels it long before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> does.

            Add to
this the fact that, for most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>, the cost of capital in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
actually went up, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> lending was cut back, stock prices declined, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> began to dismantle its elaborate system of cross-institutional
shareholding. In real terms, that means it has cost <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> more to
do business--to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, develop new products, and market. Even with
near-negative interest rates, the cost of capital in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is now much closer
to what it is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            
Nonetheless, the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>
still occupy places in the global economy remarkably similar to those they held
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>, for instance, continues to be the pacesetter in the world
auto industry, and most other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> and parts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> are
thriving as well. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for more details.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> is,
if anything, more influential than ever. Its successful integration of its
entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> into its core manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>--in stark
contrast with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matsushita</ENAMEX>'s experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA/Universal</ENAMEX>--has made it one of
the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that can be plausibly described as horizontally integrated.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> makes not only the televisions and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discmans</ENAMEX> but also the movies and
music that play on them. Given the track record of most diversification
experiments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> should have a "do not try this at home" label attached, but
its adaptability and innovation belie the traditional critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> as hidebound and conformist. The same might also be said of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX>'s rise from the dead and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canon</ENAMEX>'s emergence as a key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in
what's now called the "imaging" market, thanks primarily to its aggressive
introduction of new technology and its relatively unusual alliances with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            The fact that successful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have not
rolled over and died with the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s economy is hardly a
revelation. After all, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were able to export <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and televisions
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> even when the yen was trading at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX> to a dollar. Now that
the dollar is worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> again as much, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> goods are correspondingly
cheaper in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> markets, business is that much easier. Still the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are
suffering guilt by association with the generally failing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy just
as the Net stocks are prospering for precisely the opposite reason.

            An
important consequence of this dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> business is the dramatic
revision of our understanding of what has happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--especially manufacturing--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX>. In the
1980s, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> were beseeched to adopt "the art of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>," to pay more attention to quality and market share, to push
authority down to the factory floor. Of late, that whole phenomenon has been
the subject of considerable mockery, along the lines of "Remember when we
thought we should emulate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>? How foolish we were!" Dramatic improvements in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> manufacturing productivity, as opposed to simply corporate profits, are
attributed to greater emphasis on "shareholder value" and improved cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consciousness</ENAMEX>, not to the impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.

            
What's ironic about this revisionism is that
it's easy to dismiss the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> vogue for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> strategy and techniques only
because so many of those techniques have become part of the fabric of everyday
life at many, perhaps most, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The cords that assembly
line <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> can pull to stop the line are now ubiquitous, as are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
quality control standards. Continuous improvement, which compels <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to
look for ways to make their jobs more efficient, is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">de rigueur</TIMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>. And just-in-time production is not
simply the goal to which all manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> now aspire. It has also
spawned an entire new business model, exemplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell Computer</ENAMEX>, that is
reshaping the entire personal-computer industry. Much that was said about
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> management style in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>--with its supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zen</ENAMEX> focus and greater
sense of process than outcome--was pure buncombe. But the value of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
manufacturing practices was, if anything, understated.

            Insofar as the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are not the global hegemons we once thought they would be, it may
be because everyone else has learned from them, which is of course exactly how
competitive markets are supposed to work. In this moment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
triumphalism, it's hard to resist the temptation to rewrite recent history as
the narrative of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s self-reliant, inevitable rise, and to see the future
as the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s continued ascent into the higher reaches of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX>. Recognizing that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> business is not down for the count--and
remembering the role it played in getting us to where we are--is a necessary
step toward a saner appraisal of where this economy might be going.

         
      
   
