
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collision</ENAMEX>

            In the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 billion</NUMEX> acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Corp.</ENAMEX>, simply the latest in what has
become an unending series of massive mergers, it seems increasingly likely that
this is all the fault of that ad campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> . Tell people
often enough that size matters, and look what happens. (Feel free to insert
your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> joke here.) At this rate, it'll be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> before
too long. But each of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will offer a full range of financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instruments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car models</ENAMEX>, and computer chips. It'll be just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, only
better.

            Actually, that's far too
harsh a verdict on the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX>, particularly since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> has
spent the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> shedding noncore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and refocusing its
energies on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>, which now account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of its revenues. In
addition, as I've pointed out here before, the auto industry is facing severe
problems with excess capacity, so reducing the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the global
marketplace may decrease the chance of dramatic overbuilding. Finally, unlike
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> will not try to merge
fundamentally different product lines in an elusive quest for super market
glory. Economies of scale do exist in capital-intensive industries, which means
there are opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to be simultaneously bigger and more
efficient.

            Still,
it's not clear those conditions will exist in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance,
in fact, it looks as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> got taken. That may seem an odd
conclusion, when you consider that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> is both more profitable than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX>--earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.8 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$61 billion</NUMEX> in sales, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX>
earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 billion</NUMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$69 billion</NUMEX> in sales--and vastly more efficient. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> is adding all the resources of a low cost, lean manufacturing
powerhouse to its already impressive collection of assets, how can it be
getting the raw end of the deal?

            In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, as impressive as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s comeback
from the debacle of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1970s</TIMEX> and from the disastrous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iacocca</ENAMEX>'s reign was, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is hardly the jewel of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> manufacturing
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s press accounts made it out to be. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
earnings slid by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s both rose; and its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
market share is just <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> are
excellent, it doesn't make a single passenger car of note, aside from the
limited-release <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Viper and Prowler</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
definitely did a brilliant job of reinventing itself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, taking
advantage of the fact that it operated tax-free until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> (because of
carry-over losses) to streamline its operations and rework its design and
manufacturing processes. It also slashed payrolls, cutting the white-collar
work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and the blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a quarter</NUMEX>. As a
result, it halved the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> it had to sell <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> to break
even. More recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s tough-love approach has given its parts
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> a financial incentive to cut costs--with resulting savings to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7 billion</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. But how all this is really relevant to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> remains somewhat unclear.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> is not, after all, getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> at
no cost. Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> will be paying--depending upon what its own stock
price does--something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 billion</NUMEX> more for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> than the stock market
had thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> was worth. That's a huge premium and, in exchange for it,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> must be expecting to receive more than just the opportunity to include
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s sales with its own. It must be expecting "synergy."

            Certainly
"synergy" is the word on the lips and the word processors of everyone who has
commented on the deal. But not all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> seem to understand what
synergy means. For instance, there's very little overlap between the product
lines of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> sells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SUVs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, and
mass-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> sells luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedans</ENAMEX> and sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. This doesn't
mean synergy is automatic. All it means is that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complementary</ENAMEX>, that there are no redundancies. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX> will
be able to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to the full spectrum of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>, the current lack of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overlap</ENAMEX> also means there aren't any easy cost savings to be found by
eliminating duplication. It also means the deal's effect on the overcapacity
problem will be negligible, unless you believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> is going to cut back on
production of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-class</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedans</ENAMEX> because it's also making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neon</ENAMEX>.

            To repeat a point made here too many times before, synergy
occurs only when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> together can make and market products more
efficiently than they were able to do apart. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> is going to have to be
able to make and sell more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> more cheaply because it has acquired
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>, and vice versa, for the deal to make sense. And with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 billion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">premium</ENAMEX>, the deal has to make an awful lot of sense.

            From
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s angle the possible synergies are fairly obvious. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>
percent of its sales from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> will give it immediate entry
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> market, and presumably some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> cachet will rub
off on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> abroad. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> feature safety innovations that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
will be able to incorporate into its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and, most intriguingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX>
has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> in fuel-cell technology, which means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> will
immediately become the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in developing
noncombustion-engine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>.

            
But what will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> get? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s expertise
in front-wheel-drive engineering will be a nice addition, although it hardly
seems likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> is suddenly going to abandon rear-wheel drive. And
there is the hope that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s lean manufacturing style will help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX>
shake up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that is still heavy with layers of middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than half</NUMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and although there are good reasons for this--luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> require more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> is diversified into other labor-intensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>--much of
the difference does stem from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX>'s bureaucratic approach. The addition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> may help change that approach, but how remains to be seen. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s
elaborate system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealerships</ENAMEX> might, in theory, help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> crack the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
market, where its share is now <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1 percent</NUMEX>. But, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> recognizes,
selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>--with all the memories of the Volare
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-Car</ENAMEX>--could damage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s treasured cachet.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX> will
probably be big enough to run harder bargains with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, although there's
no real evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> has enjoyed huge cost savings on parts because
of their size. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> may also benefit from merging warehousing and
inventory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and ideally there will be joint production of components
that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> use. But size brings disadvantages as well as benefits, and
never more so than when it's the result of cross-national mergers. If being the
biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was a guarantee of success, we'd all be using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> computers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">driving GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> were great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on their own,
productive and profitable, making quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanted to buy. Now
they're risking that present for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ozymandian</ENAMEX> future, at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX>. Size matters, but sometimes for all the wrong reasons.

         
      
   
