
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX>

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">occasional Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> based on the premise that who wins in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is often determined by how the issue is framed. The author neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endorses</ENAMEX> nor condemns any of the views expressed, however laudatory or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repellent</ENAMEX>.
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> has arrived, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> on both sides are
eager to tell you what the debate is all about. It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 25 years</TIMEX> of
struggling to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, say the pro-lifers. It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 25 years</TIMEX> of
defending reproductive freedom, say the pro-choicers.

            Actually,
the debate has been about persuading you what it's about. Most of us are
ambivalent. For example, we may agree with pro-lifers that abortion is wrong
while agreeing with pro-choicers that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are entitled to make their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reproductive</ENAMEX> decisions. Where we ultimately come down on the issue--and how the
political war turns out--depends on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> can get us to focus on the
viewpoint we share with them. This debate revolves around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fundamental
axes.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Realism</ENAMEX> vs. idealism: This axis
dominated the debate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. Several lines of argument hinge on it.

            
               Legal pragmatism vs. legal
moralism: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifers</ENAMEX> regard the law as a moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>
infuriates them in part because they think it teaches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that abortion is OK.
Conversely, they think that an abortion ban, even if it can't be enforced, will
teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that abortion is wrong. Unfortunately for them, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 25 years</TIMEX>
have destroyed the public's faith that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can do much of anything, let
alone improve our morals by passing laws. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> resigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> . Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> screwed things up. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> persuaded the country
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> always screws things up. Now we're more susceptible to the
pro-choice argument that banning abortions would just divert them to the black
market.

            
               Illegal abortions vs.
legal abortions: When abortion was illegal, pro-choicers focused national
attention on the gore and repugnance of coat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hangers</ENAMEX> and back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>. After
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> , pro-lifers turned our attention to the gore and repugnance of many
legal abortions. The longer abortion remains legal, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> read about
casual abortions, the more they forget how gory and repugnant abortion was when
it was illegal. That's why pro-choicers constantly moan that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> is in
jeopardy and that abortion will soon be banned again. To gain the upper hand,
each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> needs to convince you that the other side has the upper hand.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditionalism</ENAMEX> vs.
radicalism: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro</ENAMEX>-lifers equate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way with traditional ideas,
threatened by relativism. Pro-choicers equate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way with pluralism,
threatened by radical fundamentalism. Pro-lifers had the better of this
argument in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s and 1970s</TIMEX>, because pro-choicers got mixed up with
the sexual revolution and the anti-war movement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiro Agnew</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, amnesty, and abortion." As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> took root, however,
pro-choicers became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of the status quo, and pro-lifers resorted to
protest-movement tactics such as civil disobedience. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, pro-choicers
call pro-lifers "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of abortion rights with tradition
and national stability helped persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> to reaffirm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            
               Capitalism vs.
socialism: Most pro-choicers make an economically rational argument. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s inability to spare the time or the money to raise a child properly is
an acceptable reason for aborting her pregnancy. Such practical logic helped
draw mainstream civic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> into the pre- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> movement to relax
abortion laws. By contrast, many pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifers</ENAMEX> insist that society protect and
sustain life at any cost. They apply this argument to neonatal hospital care,
lifelong disabilities, and assisted suicide, as well as to abortion. Absorbing
this pro-life socialism is a long-term problem for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            

               Technology vs. self-restraint: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro</ENAMEX>-choicers count on technology to
prevent unwanted consequences of sex. Pro-lifers reply that self-restraint is
the only effective solution. This debate began with birth control in the late
1960s (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> earned the nickname "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rubbers</ENAMEX>" for sponsoring family planning
legislation) and continued through abortion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>.
Today, pro-choicers advertise <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU-486</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norplant</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovral</ENAMEX> as
solutions to the abortion problem, while pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifers</ENAMEX> depict abortion as a
culture of callousness that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> can only obscure.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, the
focus of the abortion controversy shifted to the relative rights of the
prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and her potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>.

            
               Zoom-out vs. zoom-in:
Ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe</ENAMEX> , pro-life posters and pamphlets have depicted isolated
fetuses. The public-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masterstroke</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, a pro-life film called
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silent Scream</ENAMEX> , featured ultrasound pictures of the dismemberment of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, pro-lifers have used fetal diagrams to illustrate the
horror of "partial birth" abortions. Pro-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">choicers</NUMEX> point out that these close-up
images literally cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>'s context--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--out of the picture. They
offer alternative pictures--in the "partial birth" debate, for example, they
used a photo of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had gone through the procedure, surrounded by her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--to emphasize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s humanity and obscure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equality</ENAMEX> vs.
motherhood: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, pro-choicers attached the abortion issue to the
emerging feminist movement. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, this combination proved doubly
vulnerable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Right</ENAMEX>'s critique: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's</ENAMEX> careers bore the bloodstains of
abortions. Today, feminism remains a bad word, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have adjusted
their philosophy of motherhood to accommodate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s political power (hence
their attention to "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> moms"). Accordingly, when pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifers</ENAMEX> advocate
measures that would make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> information designed to dissuade
them from having an abortion, they call these measures "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s right to know"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX>. Conversely, pro-choicers accept the culture of motherhood and accuse
pro-lifers of defiling it by forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to bear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> not of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> but of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Persecution</ENAMEX> vs. civil
rights: Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who seek <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>-funded abortions are black or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>. From this, pro-choicers conclude that restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>-funded
abortions are racist because they target black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Conversely,
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifers</ENAMEX> argue that pro-choicers are racists because they use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and
abortion, to exterminate black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> fetuses. Pro-choicers defend the
right to abortion as an extension of the "civil rights" granted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Pro-lifers reply that "civil rights" should be extended not to women
seeking abortions but to their fetuses, "the most defenseless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slope</ENAMEX> vs. slope: Much
of the debate turns on which issues are associated with abortion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>
was based in part on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griswold</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
decision that upheld the right to use contraceptives. By arguing for abortion
rights in the context of birth control, pro-choicers persuaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to
treat it as a sexual-privacy issue. In subsequent cases, they have argued that
anti-pregnancy measures (such as high postcoital doses of birth-control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>)
blur the distinction between birth control and abortion. This raises the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specter</ENAMEX> of a slippery slope toward regulating sex. Recognizing this trap, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Right to Life Committee</ENAMEX> refuses to talk about birth control.
Pro-lifers focus instead on the "partial birth" procedure and discuss abortion
in the context of "life" issues such as assisted suicide. This raises the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specter</ENAMEX> of a slippery slope toward decriminalizing murder.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murderer</ENAMEX> vs. murder: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> say that killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is
murder, but few regard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who participates in the killing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> skewered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for enshrining this
contradiction in law. Nevertheless, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> continues to exploit <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one end of</TIMEX>
the paradox while ignoring the other. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> presidential debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> portrayed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> as a human life but said he hadn't "sorted out the
penalties" for taking it. His pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>, ignored the
question of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>'s humanity and instead accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> of threatening to
treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> for choosing abortion.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Who decides vs. what's done: While the
other lines of argument continue, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> the question of whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX> should count in the abortion decision has come to the fore.

            
               Medicine vs. morality:

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> struck down abortion laws in part on the grounds that they
interfered with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' professional judgment. This scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veneer</ENAMEX> neatly
obscured the ethical dimension of abortion decisions. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>,
pro-choicers have continued to invoke medical expertise, particularly by
rigging polls to ask whether "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>" (as opposed to a woman
alone) should be entrusted with the abortion decision. Pro-lifers, seeking to
reassert the priority of morality over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, always describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> who
terminate pregnancies as "abortionists," not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>." They also dismiss
"medical" allowances for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-term</TIMEX> abortions, such as "mental health," as
pseudoscientific loopholes that let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> authorize abortions for any reason.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>/morality argument has become central to several battles of the
1990s. Pro-lifers have driven abortion out of mainstream medical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and
into specialized, stigmatized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, pro-choicers won passage of
a federal law protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> from obstruction, on the reasoning that
they're legal medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, pro-choicers tried to insulate
abortion from moral challenge by enveloping it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> health-care plan,
but pro-lifers thwarted them. In the "partial birth" debate, faced with
embarrassing data about the nature of late-term abortions and the reasons for
them, pro-choicers again are falling back on the argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> know
best.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: Beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, the National
Abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rights Action League</ENAMEX> executed the most important framing maneuver of
the post- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> era. Guided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Hickman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NARAL</ENAMEX> used ads,
candidate manuals, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> to disseminate a new message: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who decides?</ENAMEX>"
This message changed the focus of the abortion debate from the morality of the
choice (e.g., how late into a pregnancy abortions should be allowed, and for
which reasons) to the identity of the chooser. Whereas the medical-expertise
argument is defensively neutral, the "who decides" question is aggressively
political. By rhetorically stacking their side of the question (to include
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">husbands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and clergymen, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>) and defining the other side
as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>," pro-choicers have won the sympathy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who dislike
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> more than they dislike abortion. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, this
message has deterred pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> from trying to ban abortion.

            The "partial birth" abortion
ban, on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will soon vote again, represents a shrewd
countermaneuver by pro-lifers to push the abortion debate away from "who
decides" and back toward "what's done," toward the humanity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> and
the repugnance of legal abortion. Pro-choicers call the ban a cynical ploy
designed to regain political advantage, not to prevent abortions. But is it any
more cynical than liberal pro-choicers campaigning against big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>? The
25 years of debate since <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe</ENAMEX> have settled only one thing: An issue
that's supposed to be all about principle has become all about positioning.

         
      
   
