
   
   
      
         
            You Name It

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> used to be known as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Ribbon Sports</ENAMEX>. What's now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX> used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consolidated Foods</ENAMEX>. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> was once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Oil Company of New Jersey</ENAMEX>. These were name changes that
worked. But for all the ones that do, there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 20</TIMEX> that don't. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> change their names. In a corporate culture driven
by the mystique of brands, and in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> obsessed by the possibility of
self-invention, that comes as no surprise. What does surprise is just how
irrational are the hopes and how feeble the performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that
decide a new name is all that stands between them and fiscal nirvana.

            Most
corporate name changes are the result of mergers and acquisitions. But these
tend to be unimaginative. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> have tended either to smoosh names
together--thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Marietta</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Douglas Aircraft</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grumman</ENAMEX> became ...
well, you get the idea. The result is straightforward, if not always
felicitous, monikers. Or the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> simply adopts the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
name. For instance, all indications are that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX>
merger will produce a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>.

            One notable exception was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> merger of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sperry</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>, which created a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unisys</ENAMEX>. At the time, the name was
much mocked, violating as it did the precept that you don't choose words ending
in the sound "iss " because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> associate it with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. But
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, its name now looks stylish in a
retro way. At least that's what I imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unisys</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> saying to
themselves when they seek comfort in the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s falling profit
margins.

            The real
debacles in the field of corporate name changes have been utterly self-imposed,
not forced by a merger or other change of circumstance. They are the corporate
equivalents of middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corvettes</ENAMEX>. Almost without exception, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have tried to reinvent themselves as more sophisticated and
complex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, they have chosen names distinguished only by their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obliqueness</ENAMEX> and lack of intuitive appeal. The desire for reinvention seems to
arise most often when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> hear the siren call of synergy and start to
expand beyond their core businesses. And they seem to be guided by one
fundamental rule: What you call yourself should have nothing to do with any
product you make.

            The most unforgettable example of this rule was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX>' baffling adoption of the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Allegis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, just after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX> had spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.3 billion</NUMEX> acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX> wanted Allegis
to become a world travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouse</ENAMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a year</TIMEX> he was gone--cushioned,
to be sure, by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> golden parachute--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> again.
It's tempting to say that only in retrospect does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegis</ENAMEX> seem like such a
stupid name, but the truth is that it seemed like a stupid choice even then.
Hell, to begin with, it violated the "iss " rule. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> randomly surveyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> soon after the name
was chosen, one said, "Isn't that a new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>?" while another insisted, "I'm
sure I've seen that name on my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>." More strikingly, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> study of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegis</ENAMEX> ranked in the bottom <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of corporate
"identities" both in terms of name recognition and in terms of the esteem
accorded to the name by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who recognized it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX>, on the other
hand--the old name the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> threw in the trash--was in the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> in
awareness and the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in esteem. It isn't easy to be that wrong, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX> managed it.

            And he did it with fanfare. What's most amusing about
corporate name changes is the dubious reasoning and overwrought rhetoric that
inevitably accompany them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>--excuse me, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegis</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> explained
at the time, "We are a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, not just a transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The
name change clearly identifies us as the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that can offer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">travelers</ENAMEX> door-to-door service." Of course. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allegis</ENAMEX> = door-to-door travel
service. How could we have been so blind? Even better was the explanation
offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippincott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margulies</ENAMEX>, the "identity-management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>" that came
up with the name. It said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegis</ENAMEX> "conveys the central corporate mission
of service and guardianship ... through its relation to the word allegiant,
meaning loyal or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>, and aegis, meaning protection and sponsorship." That
might be more convincing had the word "allegiant" ever, in the history of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English language</ENAMEX>, been used in a sentence.

            Maybe even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funnier</ENAMEX> is when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> celebrate the empty-signifier status of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' new names. Sounding like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferdinand Saussure</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
semiotician, retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lennox</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navistar</ENAMEX>, the name chosen
for the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Harvester</ENAMEX>, "One of the pluses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navistar</ENAMEX> is you
can make it mean whatever your imagination wants it to mean." When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Inc.</ENAMEX> changed its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WMX Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Buntrock</ENAMEX>
insisted that adopting the non-descriptive name meant the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was "growing
up [and] raising our profile." One can only speculate how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Combined Insurance</ENAMEX> explained to themselves their decision to
adopt the name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aon</ENAMEX>.

            
Coming up with a name like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navistar</ENAMEX> is
certainly creative, and trashing a valuable label like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Harvester</ENAMEX>
is certainly destructive, but the process hardly adds up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Schumpeter</ENAMEX>'s
famous definition of capitalism as a process of "creative destruction." And
it's not cheap. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $8 million</NUMEX> in the move to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegis</ENAMEX> and
back. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swift and Co.</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esmark</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> finally decided to
get out from under the cloud of bad publicity created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upton Sinclair</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">exposé The Jungle</ENAMEX> , published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX>--it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2 million</NUMEX>.
Changing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esso</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Standard</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> cost an incredible <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX> on its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> campaign to ditch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Datsun</ENAMEX>.

            The fact that bad names do
seem to hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> is, to be sure, evidence of a sort that names matter. A
rose by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegis</ENAMEX> would almost certainly not smell as sweet.
But it's clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are as faddish in their choice of names as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are. Just as waves of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashleys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brittanys</ENAMEX> are succeeded by hordes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sadies</ENAMEX>, so the postmodern bricolage names of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and '80s</TIMEX> have
been replaced by the retro labels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WMX Technologies</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Inc.</ENAMEX> again. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC Industries</ENAMEX>, which makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chocolates</ENAMEX>, is now
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Brands</ENAMEX> now bears the name of its best product,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiquita</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, I hear, is changing its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Inc.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
