
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mindless Merging</ENAMEX>

            So much for the idea that
small is beautiful. If you thought the advent of the Internet, the spread of
cheap and efficient information technology, and the growing fragmentation of
the consumer market were all going to help smaller companies thrive at the
expense of the slow-moving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> of the Fortune 500, apparently you were
wrong. In the wake of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mergers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX>,
NationsBank-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BankAmerica</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banc One-First Chicago</ENAMEX>--in the banking industry
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two weeks</TIMEX>, the conventional wisdom has quickly adjusted. Bigger,
it seems, is now definitely better.

            The
banking mergers follow a year that saw <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 trillion</NUMEX> in merger and acquisition
activity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> alone. It's easy to overestimate the significance
of that number, which is inflated by the high price of most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stocks. In
fact, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M&A</ENAMEX> activity has stayed relatively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">constant</ENAMEX> as a percentage of the value of the stock market as a whole. What's
really important is not the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M&A</ENAMEX> boom but the fact that
merge-bent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are forging ahead undaunted despite all the evidence that
the vast majority of acquisitions do not add value to the economy as a whole.
Don't bother them with the facts. They're ready to buy.

            
What we're witnessing is a wonderful exercise
in two-track thinking by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> running <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> investing in them. On the one hand, there's a general rejection of
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fordist</ENAMEX>, vertically integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX> divesting
itself of its manufacturing operations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
outsourcing their parts production to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX> running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> that other people
actually own, the idea of doing as little real work as you have to is much
applauded by Wall Street <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. On the other hand, though, there's also a
general acceptance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that promises to do everything, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> or the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX>, with its financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supermarket</ENAMEX>, in banking. For a short time--I think it was when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> started
laying off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--it seemed that the ideas of economies
of scale and scope had been permanently discredited. Apparently not.

            In and
of itself, this is no bad thing. Economies of scale--which mean that a product
becomes cheaper to produce the more of it you make--do exist in industries such
as automobile and semiconductor production. And economies of scope--which mean
that it's cheaper to produce or distribute many different products rather than
just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--obviously exist in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wal-Marts</ENAMEX>, as well as arguably in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>. If a supermarket just sells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, it will probably be
less successful than if it sells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, and so on.

            
Saying that size sometimes matters, though, is
not the same as saying it always matters. And even if size does have its
benefits, a merger may not be the best or lowest-cost way to reap them. Look at
the arguments in favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX> merger. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX>
will now be the "largest financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> in the world," which will make
it able to acquire other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and make expensive investments. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> were already huge. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX> couldn't afford that slamming
new computer system before it was part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX>, and now it'll be able to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> with impunity, but somehow I doubt it.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX> will also be more "diversified," which means that its earnings every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> won't depend as much on volatile sectors, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX>' did on the trading
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salomon Bros.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>'s did on income from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> markets. But if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX> wanted to diversify, all they had to do was buy shares
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX>, and vice versa. They're not any more protected now than they
would have been then.

            
In essence, after all, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX>
merger involves is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> trading <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> their shares--actually
it's a little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> officially acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>--in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Travelers</ENAMEX> for shares in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>. The idea that that swap created value in
itself is nonsensical. The deal is justified only if the merged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> will
grow faster, and be more profitable, than the two separate ones would have
independently. And so we come to synergy.

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citigroup</ENAMEX> case, the synergy is supposed to come from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> selling
each other's products. Now you'll be able to get property insurance from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Travelers</ENAMEX> when you take out a mortgage from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citibank</ENAMEX>, or your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> agent
will be able to badger you into getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citibank</ENAMEX> credit card after he's done
badgering you about life insurance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX> will be your one-stop-shopping
place, your financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>.

            
As nearly everyone has already pointed out, the
record of financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX> is dismal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> failed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean Witter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX> failed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX> when it tried to expand operations, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weill</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX>--failed miserably when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearson</ENAMEX> joined with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX>. And the concept of one-stop shopping does seem oddly ill-suited to
financial services. It's not just that, at least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, there's
no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prefer national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to local ones (if anything,
there's a long history of distrust of large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>). It's also that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take
their financial decisions more seriously than they do their choice of toilet
paper, and that they are unlikely to pick up a home mortgage just because their
insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is hawking it. At a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> comparison-shop for almost
everything, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX>'s privileging of convenience seems oddly outdated.

            Even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross-selling</ENAMEX> makes sense, though, it's not clear why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX>
had to merge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX> could have agreed to market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> insurance or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salomon</ENAMEX> brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>, and vice versa, without actually becoming one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. For the deal to make sense, the costs of working together in a
contractual relationship would have to be greater than the costs of merging.
But the record in this regard is not comforting. In fact, if there's one thing
that is unequivocally true about M&A activity, it's that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
dramatically underestimate how much it will cost and how long it will take to
make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--with their attendant managerial hierarchies, corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cultures</ENAMEX>, and computer systems--into one.

            
That's hardly surprising when one considers how
little time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> take before agreeing to merge. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX> deal, from
beginning to end, took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than five weeks</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 billion</NUMEX>
NationsBank-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BankAmerica</ENAMEX> deal took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> did "due
diligence" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>. How due, exactly, could that diligence have been?
It's true that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> lets a potential merger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> look too closely,
and the deal then falls through, it may have given away its secrets for
nothing. But when you realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take more time to decide what car
they're going to buy than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Reed</ENAMEX> took to decide on a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 billion</NUMEX> deal, a little uneasiness might be in order.

            The truth is that
everything--from the way investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are compensated to the rubber-stamp
role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> to the dominance of publicity-hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>--is set
up to make mergers attractive. And it's hard work to determine the success of
mergers, because you have to compare the performance of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> against
the projected performance of the previously independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. That makes
it easier just to assume success in the absence of complete disaster. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> put it best when he recently said, "You get
big because you're better. You don't get better because you're big."

         
      
   
