
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar's Crawl</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>

            If you saw the ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> floating around the union <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Auto Workers</ENAMEX> voted overwhelmingly to reject a new contract offer from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX>, you could have been forgiven. In an era of quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and
free-agent workforces, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> vote was a throwback to an era of union
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militancy</ENAMEX>. What it wasn't, though, was a throwback to an era of union power. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, as almost everywhere else, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that rules.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar-UAW</ENAMEX> struggle is the longest running labor-management confrontation
of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX> and is also, unsurprisingly, the most bitter. The fight began with
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six month</TIMEX> walkout in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-1992</TIMEX> that ended when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> threatened to hire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement workers</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> since, it has featured picket line violence
by both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>, scores of unfair labor practices by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 17 month</TIMEX> strike from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1994 to December 1995</TIMEX>, and now
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> resounding rejections of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> contracts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Shots have been
fired into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' windows, even as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has fired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> members
for distributing leaflets, wearing pro-union T-shirts, and singing on the
assembly line.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have been working without a new
contract since they returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two years ago</TIMEX>. That
means they have been working under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> imposed terms, and turning down
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX>'s latest offer means they will continue to work under those terms
for the foreseeable future. It's a measure of just how angry <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are
that they would rather toil along without a contract than accept one that feels
as if, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> so bluntly put it in a headline, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX>
gives in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX>."

            The most
concrete reason for the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX> vote against the new contract was the fate
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> had fired for "disciplinary"
reasons during the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. While some were reinstated, often at the
its latest offer the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> said it would reinstate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> of these, and the fate
of the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> would be placed in the hands of independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arbitrators</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> did not, of course, make this offer
out of the goodness of its heart. In exchange for the reinstatements, the union
agreed not to impose fines or other sanctions on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who
crossed picket lines during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1994-1995</TIMEX> strike. Even more importantly, at
least from a financial angle, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> agreed to drop the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">441</NUMEX> complaints of
unfair labor practices it has filed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLRB</ENAMEX>. Even if only a small
percentage of those allegations are true, the cost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in back pay
and fines could be immense.

            Still,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX>'s about-face was not sharp enough for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> rank and file, which
focused not on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> who would be coming back to work but on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> who would
not. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the opposition to the contract told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , "This thing doesn't end until we all go back." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity Forever</ENAMEX>!
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Reed</ENAMEX> somewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?

            From <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> angle, the shortsightedness of the rank and file
seems extraordinary. The new contract, while hardly lavish, did provide for
small pay raises, plus cost-of-living increases. It also offered a considerable
improvement in pension benefits and individual job security through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. For
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to toss all that away because of what might happen to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>
seems to make no sense. But then, it's clear that what's now at stake for many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cat workers</ENAMEX> is not so much another dollar an hour raise as an idea of how a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is supposed to treat its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            Remember,
too, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> also believes those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> important enough to
justify tearing up a perfectly good contract. You can understand viscerally why
it's hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to vote for their own interests while their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
remain in limbo. It's harder to understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> is so insistent
on not rehiring them that it's willing to risk huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLRB</ENAMEX> fines to avoid doing
so. But while from a short-term dollars and cents angle reinstating the workers
may make sense, throughout its struggle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> has made its
decisions with one long-range goal in mind: consolidation of its control over
the workplace. It's overstating the case to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> has sought to
break the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, but it's not overstating the case by much. And in that
context, the symbolism of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> becomes just as important to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> as to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX>. Their fate is a sign of which side has real power.
Unfortunately for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX>, there really isn't much question about which side
does.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past fiscal year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> reported
record profits of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 billion</NUMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1994-1995</TIMEX> strike, the company
kept reporting record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> earnings, in part because so many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> members
became scabs, in part because management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> helped work the lines, and
in part because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a fifth</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX>'s global
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has reinvented itself as an exemplar of lean production
and now dominates its major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> has
announced the opening of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> new production <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. All of them are opening in
right-to-work <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>. What leverage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> has,
then, shrinks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.

            What's
crucial to understand about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX>, though, is that its success in
defeating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> was not simply the product of those larger
trends--global competition, technology, etc.--that everyone points to. It was
also the product of a coherent strategy for creating a more flexible,
lower-cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, a strategy that only worked because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> was willing to
endure a long strike and reduced profits (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $100 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-1992</TIMEX>)
in order to get what it wanted.

            Wall Street also saw the losses as a kind of investment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX>'s share price did take a little hit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, but since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> it has
risen steadily. Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are willing to overlook
short-term losses due to strikes if they feel that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s hard line will
pay off in lower costs down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>, for instance, lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$460</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to strikes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> treated the costs as a kind of
"extraordinary charge" and valued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as if the losses had never
happened. The familiar cliché about Wall Street is that it's only concerned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the latest quarter</TIMEX>. But when it comes to taking on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, that cliché is
a canard. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> have learned, if the stakes are
high enough, Wall Street can be very, very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
