
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Jobs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Totalitarian Vision</ENAMEX>

            "We started out to get a
computer in the hands of everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Jobs</ENAMEX>, co-founder and putative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX>, tells us in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> left out
of that sentence, though, is a word that has wrecked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> in the past and
could wreck it in the future. The word is "our" or, to be more accurate, "my,"
as in: "We started out to get my computer in the hands of everyday
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> was
never interested in having everyone own personal computers. He was interested
only in having everyone own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Apples</ENAMEX>. And this is, of course, the great irony
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s apparently imperishable image as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> of the
counterculture, an image that has been the source of some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>'s more preposterous pronouncements. It was all about freedom,
sure--the freedom to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> on your desk.

            As everyone knows by now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> always portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> in particular, as avatars of a new populist revolution, as
tools of democratization. In this sense, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> ad featuring an
athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> hurling a hammer and destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX> was not so much some
invention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiat/Day</ENAMEX>'s imagination as it was the visual expression of
everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> had been saying since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> began. What you couldn't tell from
the ad, though, was that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>' imagination, what would replace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX>
was not the anarchic space of the market, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> buying computers from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. It was instead the comforting spectacle of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> upon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, all imagining they were pursuing "personal
creativity and individual self-expression"--and all buying that creativity only
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>.

            What's
really interesting about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>' imperial ambition, though, is that the very
immensity of its scope doomed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> to marginality. The problem was not that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> to have a hand in every corner of the personal-computing
market. That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> has always wanted, after all, and that desire
has made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> into one of the world's most profitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The
problem, rather, was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> to be every corner of the
personal-computing market. He wanted to make the computers and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> that ran them--and to be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that did so. And that meant
that, almost from the beginning, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> was confused about its mission. In the
simplest terms, it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware company</ENAMEX> that thought it was a software
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--or vice versa.

            
The difference between making hardware and
making software is analogous to the difference between making razors and making
razor blades. You may make more money on each razor--but your margins will be a
lot higher on the blades, and you will sell a lot more of them. Now, it's
possible to make razors profitably. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> is an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18-billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>
Computer is Wall Street's new darling, and all they make is razors. But it's a
tougher business. Price pressures are constant. It's hard to distinguish
yourself from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s name would have helped its case. And
most important of all, there's no romance in it. No one really talks about how
much better a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> is than a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gateway</ENAMEX>. Computers that cost about the same seem
to run about the same.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, sells only blades. Word, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Excel</ENAMEX>, even
Windows: All these are blades. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> sells those blades to whoever
wants them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> doesn't care what kind of machine you run his software on. He
just wants you to run his software.

            This, of course, is the other path <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> could have taken.
It was actually the path <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> recommended in a now-famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> memo that
suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> license the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> operating system--with its graphical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interface</ENAMEX> and windows--to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three to five</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> who would build
compatible computers. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> OS was dramatically superior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX>,
which was the operating system for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatibles. Going strongly into
software, then, would have capitalized on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really loved about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>,
which was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> itself, but the interface. Had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>, perhaps even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> to build hardware running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> OS, it
might very well have seen its software become the industry standard.

            Instead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> chose to go it alone--in part because it would have been hard to watch
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> selling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> clones of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macs</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> imagined it could
have been selling instead. That was a mistake of short-term thinking, though it
was an understandable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The preposterously high margins <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> was able to
earn in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early-to-mid 1980s</TIMEX>, when it was selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IIs</ENAMEX> to dealers
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times cost and earning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>-percent gross profits on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macs</ENAMEX>, undoubtedly
blinded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> would not ignore price forever.
Those short-term considerations might have been overridden, though, except for
one thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>' insistence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> be the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">standard-bearer</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> revolution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> didn't want to make just blades. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> wanted to make
the razor, the blades, and the packaging. And if he'd had his way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> would
have forged the stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>, too. (According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> account, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> once
"fantasized about a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> in which the raw materials that came in would be
not semiconductors but sand." Insert the appropriate "castles built on ..."
metaphor here.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>' quest for complete control also meant
that he didn't want his machines to be able to talk to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>'
machines. In fact, this hostility to compatibility permeated even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
attitude toward itself. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> was introduced, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IIs</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> was incompatible with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. You
couldn't upgrade; you had to abandon. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> made it hard even for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>, its entry into the business market, to work together, though both were
designed at the same time. It's as if, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>, the basic criterion for an
"insanely great" product was its radical difference, which is to say its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolation</ENAMEX>, from everything else.

            What's truly striking,
though, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> has never really let this idea go. After he left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>, he
founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NeXT</ENAMEX> and tried to go the hardware-software route again, until he had to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> the hardware <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Canon</ENAMEX> and the software to, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>. Upon returning
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>, he began criticizing almost immediately the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> decision
to finally allow a limited number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to manufacture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> clones,
calling these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leeches</ENAMEX>." Somehow I doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> thinks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>
as parasitic because its computers run only on Windows. In this respect,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bringing Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> back to save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> is like bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McClellan</ENAMEX>
out of retirement to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Army</ENAMEX>.

            The remarkable fact is that,
at this very moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX> is a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The
difference is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> did.
Every computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> makes costs a lot to make. Every additional copy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95</ENAMEX> costs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> ... oh, just about nothing. That could have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s world, and it isn't because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> imagined it could be all
things. If only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> had decided to be The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way</ENAMEX> and let someone else be The
Light.

         
      
   
