
   
   
      
         
            Is There Anything <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> Won't Buy?

             

            
               Wonder what's happened
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> covered in previous "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Fool"</ENAMEX> articles in
Slate ? Click to get the update.
            

            Consider it a case of
exquisitely bad timing: Just as stock markets around the world were diving in
response to currency troubles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and general unease about the future
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Telecom</ENAMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cellular-phone</ENAMEX> service--went public. When the initial public offering was first
announced, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> acted as if tickets to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> reunion had
gone on sale, lining up before dawn outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank branches</ENAMEX> to procure the
application forms needed to buy shares. By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Telecom</ENAMEX> actually made
it to market, though, those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> had other things on their mind--you
know, minor things like whether the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> real-estate market was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> to fall to pieces.

            The same
was true, to a lesser extent, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, to whom China
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecom</ENAMEX> must suddenly have looked less like a savvy investment in an infinitely
expandable market and more like an overvalued investment in a region plagued by
dubious financing practices and even more dubious accounting. The result was
predictable. Where most IPOs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> have been strikingly successful--AMF
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Bowling</ENAMEX>, of all things, being just the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to see its share price
jump--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Telecom</ENAMEX>'s shares fell by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three days</TIMEX> of
trading.

            Of course, even with the bad timing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Telecom</ENAMEX> did
IPO. And the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that underwrote the offering took home close to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>. So it'd be hard to call the deal a failure, especially when you
consider that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s shares rebounded sharply when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market
rallied. In fact, from a certain angle, and especially given the turmoil in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Telecom</ENAMEX>'s IPO looks like a real triumph, the kind of triumph, in
fact, that makes you wonder, "What won't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> buy?"

            That
question is especially pertinent here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, because the
combination of a booming stock market at home and the privatization of
state-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> abroad has meant a dramatic upsurge in the number of
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> whose shares are listed on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>. Through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have gone public here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, raising a
total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.5 billion</NUMEX> in capital. Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France Telecom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Canada</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Telecom</ENAMEX> all have been added to the list. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France Telecom</ENAMEX> did it in style,
bringing cancan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> onto the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> for the
first day of trading.) By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>, the number of foreign IPOs
should surpass <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s record <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> offerings.

            
Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, of course, want their shares
listed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for the same reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Sutton</ENAMEX> robbed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> capital market is the world's largest. All the money that
continues to pour into mutual funds has to go somewhere, and the rhetorical
drumbeat of globalization has made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> more comfortable with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telefónica de España</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telebras</ENAMEX>, let alone companies
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> capital market is also exceptionally liquid, and
price-earnings multiples are high. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> listings
both increase trading in their shares and improve valuations. An IPO, then,
becomes a lucrative and relatively painless way of raising capital.

            It's
especially painless because the vast majority of the shares of foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> trade in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in the form of something called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Depositary Receipts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> was invented--as was so much else--by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>, when he created the device so that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> could trade shares
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> department store called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selfridge's</ENAMEX>. Essentially, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>, issued by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>--the depositary--that represents a share in a
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. In most cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> does not have voting
rights. In selling shares in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, then, foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> can
raise loads of money without suffering a dilution of the control they exercise
over their own affairs.

            
"So what?" you might justifiably ask. After
all, the overwhelming majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> never bother with their voting
rights in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and the decline in the practice of paying out
dividends means that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> care about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> thing: the
price of their shares. And you can care about the price of an ADR just as
easily as you can about the price of a bona fide share. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Telecom</ENAMEX>'s
share price is going to double over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>, why shouldn't you buy
it?

            If it is
going to double, then you should buy. There, wasn't that easy? The problem,
though, is that the ADR phenomenon has created a situation where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
are pouring <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> whose standards of financial
disclosure and corporate governance are dramatically different from our own and
which are, in some cases, nonexistent. That means, in turn, that it's hard to
figure out whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will be profitable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, let alone whether
its stock price is going to double. And without full voting rights, there's
nothing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--even institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--can do if things go
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haywire</ENAMEX>.

            
Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tsingtao Beer</ENAMEX>, for instance. It went
public in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, and its shares were quickly snapped up. Instead of using the
money it raised from the IPO to expand, though, it lent the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110 million</NUMEX> to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> and then watched many of those loans go south.
Needless to say, these plans had not been in the prospectus. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecom</ENAMEX> has said that it will "explore opportunities for strategic investments
in [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s] telecommunications industry." But it's not clear whether this
really means "strategic investments" or whether it means "investments to prop
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> run by aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CP</ENAMEX>." Of course, it's possible that the
pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Telecom</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> may keep it on track. That
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competitor</ENAMEX>, incidentally, is a joint venture run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Liberation</ENAMEX>
Army, which brings new meaning to the words "price war."

            The point is not that
investing in foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> is necessarily a mistake. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> investment, in
fact, is likely to improve standards of disclosure and accounting in many
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. And foreign investment is often crucial to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX>, for instance, would not have been built
without <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. But foreign investment takes place in a realm, even
today, where the rules that govern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> markets do not always apply. "It has
been most demoralizing," a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emissary</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> wrote his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1890s</TIMEX>. "Even one of our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, when asked to
give us some information as to what had become of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> capital sent
out--what do you think he said? He told us, 'Well, really, Sir, that is what I
am always asking, but which I can never get to know.' " It's not that hard to
imagine a similar message being sent home by someone investigating what
happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tsingtao</ENAMEX>.

            What the fad for foreign
IPOs ignores is the massive uncertainty still attached to foreign markets, even
as it has led <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to overlook everything they take for granted at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>: regular reports, corporate accountability, open books, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>. After all, transparent and efficient markets are not
natural but rather man-made. And what the triumph of capitalism in the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decade</ENAMEX> has hidden is the reality that in most places, those markets have not
yet been built. Caveat emptor, indeed.

             

         
      
   
