
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taming</ENAMEX> of the Barbarians

            Asked how to respond to a
rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s most recent gambit, the well-dressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> looks out of the
window of his lavish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and says simply, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Napalm</ENAMEX>."

            Thus
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kravis</ENAMEX>, co-founder of the leveraged-buyout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kohlberg Kravis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>, introduced to the viewing public in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> film version of the 1980s
business classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbarians</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> . The story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX>'s successful
but ill-fated LBO of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR Nabisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbarians</ENAMEX> offered an indelible
portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> (and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>) as made up of insatiable deal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">game</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. They flourished on brinkmanship, buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> only
to dismember them and caring only for the chance to crush their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>.

            
What a long, strange trip it's been. Just last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> announced that it would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with upstart LBO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hicks, Muse</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tate & Furst</ENAMEX> to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regal Cinemas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Regal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> will be combined with
those owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Act III</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> bought <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>, and those owned by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Artists Theatre Group</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hicks, Muse</ENAMEX> is in the process of
acquiring, to create the world's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. (Got all
that? There will be a pop quiz at the end of the story.) The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and has plans to
build many of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> multiplexes we've been hearing so much about, the
ones with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 or 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> apiece.

            One can
be forgiven for wondering if what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> really needs is more movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>,
especially at a time when movie attendance is flat and the number of screens
has risen by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>. (For more on that question, click .)
But, setting that aside, what's really interesting about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Regal</ENAMEX> acquisition
is that it is a bona fide long-term investment. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> isn't
buying it to sell off its assets and pocket the proceeds. On the contrary, by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">combining Regal</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Act III</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> is actually using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> acquisition as a
platform for another, much in the way any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> looking to expand into a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> of business does.

            
It may seem improbable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> is interested
in actually building up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. After all, in popular mythology, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> is
thought of as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that pioneered the leveraged buyout and left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
once-proud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> either struggling under mountains of junk-bond-financed
debt or stripped of their most valuable jewels. But in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Regal</ENAMEX> deal, far
from being anomalous, is typical of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> has done in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> since the
LBO craze came to a screeching halt at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 1980s</TIMEX>. More than that,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s performance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX> sheds a new light on its performance in
the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and makes it worth asking, once again, what the real impact of
LBOs and junk bonds on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> was. (If you've forgotten what a junk
bond is, click .)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> is
a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. In essence, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> does
is raise money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--primarily pension funds, closed-end mutual
funds, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>--and then put that money to use in the hope of getting those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> better returns than they could have found in the stock or bond
markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> does so by buying and selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, which is to say that the
firm never makes a deal to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> without plans to sell it eventually or
to take it public or both. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> reap their rewards not by taking out
profits from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> during the time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> owns them but through the
capital gains they reap when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are sold or taken public.

            
The obvious conclusion to draw from this is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> must be hurting these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' long-term prospects by trying to
maximize their short-term value. If you're buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> knowing that
somewhere down the line you'll want to sell it, the argument goes, you'll
shortchange research and development, cut back on long-term investment and sell
off slow-performing parts of the business in an effort to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> look
better in the present. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> gets richer while the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as a
whole ends up poorer.

            The
problem with this analysis is that it assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> is smart while everyone
else is dumb. After all, when deciding whether or not to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX>--as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> recently did with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duracell</ENAMEX>--presumably you'll want to kick the
tires and look under the hood a little bit. And unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kravis</ENAMEX> has magical
powers no one knows about, it's unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> are going to make a
long-term investment in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that's had all the value stripped out of it.
In other words, if you think that markets are even relatively good at
determining a fair price for assets, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> can't hurt its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>'
long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> without hurting itself.

            
What about the question of debt, though? In
part, what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> did when it purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> was replace those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' dividend payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> with debt payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX>.
In principle, one is no better or worse for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s health than the other.
But there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big difference between dividends and debts, which is that if
you fail to pay the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, your stock price gets punished, but the company
stays in business--while if you fail to pay the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> goes under.
And there's no question that the LBO craze led to the destruction of a series
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that took on more debt, often in the form of junk bonds, than they
could handle. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southland</ENAMEX> (home of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7-Eleven</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westpoint-Pepperell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federated</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department Stores</ENAMEX>: They all collapsed because their debt loads were too high.
It's interesting that the one thing those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had in common was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX>
had passed on acquiring them. But even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> overreached itself when it spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR Nabisco</ENAMEX>. The near-collapse of that deal almost sent the
firm out of business, in addition to making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kravis</ENAMEX> a poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> for
unrestrained greed.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retrospect</ENAMEX>, though, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things seem clear. First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> deal was atypical of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX>'s broader strategy. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the whole fiasco was the best thing that could
have happened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. The death of LBO fervor, which in practical terms
meant the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>' willingness to lend freely to almost anyone, forced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> to refocus its business around the strongest deals possible. It also meant
that future buyouts would be less heavily leveraged. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 30 percent</NUMEX>
of all junk bonds went to finance LBOs.) And the continued bull market meant
that you had to look harder to find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> were undervaluing
and that there was a greater incentive to improve those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' bottom-line
performance.

            
The results have been striking. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duracell</ENAMEX>,
bought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350 million</NUMEX>, was sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7 billion</NUMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that same year</TIMEX>, it sold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Re</ENAMEX>, a reinsurer, to a German
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for a profit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 billion</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stop & Shop</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> company
for a profit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 billion</NUMEX>. All these were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> had owned for
an extended period of time during which all had expanded, improved
productivity, and--in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duracell</ENAMEX>--benefited from increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> &
D spending. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s one great flop of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flagstar</ENAMEX>, which
owns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny's</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grand Slam Breakfast</ENAMEX> just never took off.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> familiar interpretation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX>'s success is that it illustrates the disciplining power of debt.
Becoming highly leveraged has forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to think seriously about costs,
trim overhead, and improve productivity. The broader lesson we're supposed to
learn, then, is that it was precisely the takeover mania of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> that
created the lean, efficient profit machines of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. But the truth is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX>'s success illustrates a more mundane--but even more important--point, which
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> perform better when they're held accountable by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> has not succeeded because of the discipline of
debt or even the promise of untold riches. Rather, it has succeeded because it
brought a relentless focus on the bottom line to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> it has owned,
and established standards its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> have had to live up to. For most of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> featured rubber-stamp <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors handpicked
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and uninterested in rocking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. What these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> have
allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to do is, simply, play with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s money. And in some
very basic sense, what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> has done best is get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to take other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
seriously.

         
      
   
