
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends Failed to Foresee</ENAMEX>

            It's been a busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few weeks</TIMEX>
in the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> kitsch. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX> announced it was
hemorrhaging money, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Van Damme</ENAMEX> got cold-cocked in a strip
joint, and now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic Friends Network</ENAMEX> is no more. Its parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inphomation Communications Inc.</ENAMEX>, has filed for bankruptcy, claiming that it has
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26 million</NUMEX> in liabilities and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> in assets. What's next? A
revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney</ENAMEX> really isn't preserved cryogenically?

            The big
loser in the demise of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> is, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chanteuse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne Warwick</ENAMEX>,
who's been the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for the network for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost five years</TIMEX> now. You
might have thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warwick</ENAMEX> would have seen this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming two decades ago</TIMEX>,
when, on the advice of a psychic, she added an "e" to her last name and watched
her singing career go into the tank. But, like so many others, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warwick</ENAMEX>'s faith
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of getting poor and desolate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to shell out enormous
amounts of money they really shouldn't be spending for worthless advice
remained unshaken.

            The economics of the psychic phone business are, in fact,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> as straightforward as that. At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.99</NUMEX> a minute, the goal is to get people
to stay on the line for as long as possible--though not so long that they run
up massive bills they will deny having amassed--and to keep them coming back.
As a result, especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>, the psychic business has tried
to focus on establishing continuing relationships between individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychics</ENAMEX>
and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. ("I don't want just any psychic! I want to speak to
Clarissa!") The implicit therapeutic element to consulting a psychic has thus
been made more explicit. After all, a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> costs ... well, there may
not be such a thing as a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, but you get the point.

            Still, while the psychic
business model is uncomplicated, its very simplicity poses a very real problem
to the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the field, since it means that the barriers to entry
are remarkably low. (The really big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> in the phone-psychic--as in the
phone-sex--business are actually the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, since they take a chunk
of every call and provide only the line.) Since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychics</ENAMEX> work out of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>, you don't even need that archetypal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with a bunch of telephones in
it. All you need is a few ads in the back of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, maybe a commercial on
that cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> that tells you what's going to be on other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour and a half</TIMEX>, plus a gimmick, and you're in. In part, of course, that's
why building customer loyalty to particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychics</ENAMEX> is so crucial. But it's
also why constantly differentiating yourself from the competition is essential.
The threat of commoditization, in other words, is omnipresent. (For more on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commoditization</ENAMEX> scramble, click here.) And here
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic Friends Network</ENAMEX> really fell down on the job.

            "They just
didn't change the product enough," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX>, who recently
detailed his personal adventures as a telephone psychic (for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Believers Network</ENAMEX>) in an article in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s . "If you look at other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, they do ads focusing on the lottery, on romance, on work. They just
keep re-packaging and re-spinning the product. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> was stuck
with these infomercials which just pushed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychics</ENAMEX> generally."

            
Failing to target its pitches--neglecting to
emphasize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychics</ENAMEX> can help you win, or at least tell you you're going to
win large sums of money or find that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of your dreams--was certainly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big mistake. A probably more telling error was getting
locked into the infomercial model of advertising. While its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> looked
to the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60-second or two-minute</TIMEX> ad to push the product, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> remained
enamored of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-minute</TIMEX> pitch, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX> smiling her toothy smile and
everything looking vaguely like it was still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. (Do you really think it's a
coincidence that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Coleman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Diff'rent Strokes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Lange</ENAMEX> of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Boat</ENAMEX> --he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX> the bartender--were <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX>?)

            The
decision to stick with the infomercial model was certainly understandable.
After all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inphomation</ENAMEX>, and its main business was the
production and distribution of infomercials. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infomercials</ENAMEX> had been among the most popular in history. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1993 and 1994</TIMEX>,
they aired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 12,000</NUMEX> times, and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inphomation</ENAMEX> was shelling
out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a million dollars</NUMEX> a week to buy air time on cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. It was
money well spent: At its peak, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> was bringing in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $125</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, most of it through infomercials.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> was not alone. The infomercial boom of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX> was a logical response to the deregulation of cable
television in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>--which means that, like so much else, we can blame Psychic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. As the number of cable channels exploded, so too did
the demand for programming. Infomercials were an ideal cash cow for the cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, since they actually got paid to air them.

            But cable has changed in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, as relatively more substantive programming alternatives have
emerged (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classic Sports Network</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cooking Channel</ENAMEX> may not be high art,
but they are better than another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab Roller</ENAMEX> ad), and as the infomercial market
became saturated. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> programs had probably reached a point
of diminishing returns, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inphomation</ENAMEX> was stuck in an old mindset--a classic
case of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> not realizing that what had made it successful would not keep
it successful in the future. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Welch</ENAMEX> is fond of saying that the key to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> is changing before you have to. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inphomation</ENAMEX> couldn't change even after
it had to. And the fact that this utter failure of foresight happened to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic Friends Network</ENAMEX> takes us, needless to say, somewhere beyond irony.

            I don't
want to belabor that point (though it is fun, as all the "They should have seen
it coming" headlines on stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inphomation</ENAMEX>'s bankruptcy suggest). Still,
it's worth recognizing that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> created as a
response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s uncertainty about the world (it's probably no accident
that it cropped up around the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>). And yet it ended up
foundering as a result of the inherent uncertainty of the free-market system.
Still a larger question remains: Why don't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> ever quit while they're
ahead?

            
Imagine if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lasky</ENAMEX>, the former racing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapper</ENAMEX> who ran <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inphomation</ENAMEX> into the ground, had seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> that
margins were going to decline, that in the absence of any professional
requirements more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychics</ENAMEX> would be entering the market, that the time
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infomercials</ENAMEX> had passed, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> brand name had hit
its peak. And imagine if, at that point, he had liquidated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
instead deployed his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> elsewhere (by buying stock in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> or something).
Today, the memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX> would live on in all our minds as a great
and kooky <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> success story; we wouldn't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychics</ENAMEX> worried
about their futures; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lasky</ENAMEX> would still be ridiculously wealthy.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, it may be that
most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have naturally short life spans and recognizing that life span
and getting out before it's over is a rare but crucial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> Lasky
clearly didn't have). We've been conditioned, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of Fortune 500
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, to see the large, decades-old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> as the model for all
business. But much of the time, striving for longevity means ending up in
bankruptcy. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychic Friends</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>, could have gone out at the
top of its game. Some crystal ball.

         
      
   
