
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay Fray</ENAMEX>

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spoke at a fund-raising dinner for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Rights</ENAMEX>
Campaign. It marked the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has addressed a gay
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. "We are redefining [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immutable</ENAMEX> ideals," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But in the cauldron of politics, ideals are never immutable. It's your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mutation</ENAMEX> vs. theirs. For example:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX> rights vs. "special rights."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s main thrust was to equate gay rights with civil rights. He likened
his speech to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> gathering at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> became the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to address a black civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Birch</ENAMEX> likewise said her cause was "civil rights" rather than "gay
rights."

            The civil-rights analogy
serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> purposes. First, it subsumes an apparently radical idea, gay
rights, under a patriotic tradition: the espousal and gradual extension of
equal rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> traced this tradition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> and called it
"the fundamental story of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it minimizes the burden on
gay-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>. "Civil rights" are basic. You can extend them to gays
(and to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarians</ENAMEX>) without condoning their behavior. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>,
it allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gay-rights advocates</ENAMEX> to avoid mentioning homosexuality. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX> demonstrated this feat when summarizing
the speech for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>.

            Critics
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> want not "civil" rights or "equal" rights but "special" rights.
The S-word has so effectively permeated the gay-rights debate that in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">speeches, both Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birch</ENAMEX> felt obliged, without prompting, to deny it.
This didn't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> from hurling it on television the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> elaborated: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gays</ENAMEX> are demanding "a special category, based on
sexual preference, under our civil-rights statutes." This argument fails
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">logically</ENAMEX> (our civil-rights laws are entirely about special categories
such as race), but it succeeds politically, by giving a fig leaf of neutrality
to what is actually a moral aversion to homosexuality.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolerance</ENAMEX> vs. approval. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX>
long ago surrendered to the liberal crusade for "tolerance." Now they claim to
represent tolerance against the left's demand for "approval" of homosexuality.
It's a strong argument, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> do want approval. One prominent gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech a "message of acceptance." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">described Clinton</ENAMEX>'s message as part of an attempt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> "to
impose their particular viewpoint on us." As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> pundit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Charen</ENAMEX> put it, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
won't ask about your private life, but don't flaunt it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gays</ENAMEX> see it the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> around: If they can't be open about their orientation, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birch</ENAMEX>, they're
effectively "banished to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>." But that's a hard argument to sell to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that doesn't know--and doesn't want to know--what it's like to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gay</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> controversy illustrates how easily open homosexuality can be
construed as aggression. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> boasted that when the
TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen"</ENAMEX> (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen DeGeneres</ENAMEX>) came out as a lesbian,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> "were forced to look at sexual orientation in a more open light."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, exploded at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-</ENAMEX>word. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
learned from the mistake. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX>, when asked on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
whether he agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, he rephrased the point, saying that the coming-out
episode "gave" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> "a chance to see [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">homosexuality</ENAMEX>] in a new light."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outreach</ENAMEX> vs. pandering. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants
to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>' participation in politics appear normal. His idea of normal
politics is cobbling together interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Previewing the speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>
compared it to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian-American</ENAMEX> dinner. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> welcomed that analogy and
asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> should be treated like "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> vote," because exit
polls indicate that they're <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>. This foolish argument
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> dismiss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech as "pandering." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> adroitly
deployed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>-word, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a lackey of the "old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> of a
polyglot of special interests, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>, and of union
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>."

            Gay-rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> compounded the damage by bragging about gay money and political
clout. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">DeGeneres</ENAMEX> depicted her own coming-out as a financial boon: "I became
more famous. So much for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who said that it would ruin my career."
Birch boasted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> had made "significant investments, on par with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency groups</ENAMEX>, into campaigns." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX> advertised that it had contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> had chipped in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.2 million</NUMEX> altogether,
and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s appearance at its dinner would raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
pointed out that "since I've become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, we're spending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times as much
per fatality on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> as [on] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> or prostate
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> gleefully connected the dots: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding Clinton</ENAMEX> in exchange for favors at other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s expense. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-morning</TIMEX> chat shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sesno</ENAMEX> was asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX>, "Is this
just another political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, another bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> that you're appealing
to?"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4 Protection</ENAMEX> vs. pity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birch</ENAMEX> talked about
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> have suffered from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, teen suicide, and hate crimes. But this line
of argument is also dangerous. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> are unhappy, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> in a
debate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s This 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , the "compassionate"
response is to help them abandon homosexuality. This is fast becoming the
respectable anti-gay position. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anti-gay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> picketed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX> dinner with
signs saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God Hates Fags</ENAMEX>," but a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> won better
press coverage by carrying signs saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ellen Can Change</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employment</ENAMEX> vs. marriage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Employment Non-Discrimination Act</ENAMEX>, which would ban job
discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. Chat shows replayed his best sound bite: "Being
gay [has] nothing to do with the ability to read a balance book, fix a broken
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bone</ENAMEX>, or change a spark plug." Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> had to agree. But
neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birch</ENAMEX> mentioned gay marriage. Why? They've used the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> and seen the same polls: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> favor equal treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in
the workplace but oppose gay marriage, probably because the latter involves
sex. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed legislation prohibiting federal recognition of
gay marriages, then bragged about it in campaign ads. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> named it the
"Defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marriage Act</ENAMEX>," framing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> as the aggressors.) Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sign
it again? Yes, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX> speech.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> have attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ENDA</ENAMEX> in several ways--by claiming, for example,
that it entails job quotas (i.e., special rights) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. But defending the
right to discriminate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> is no longer a sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> for them. They're
better off changing the subject to marriage, where they hold a clear advantage.
On This 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> focused on civil rights and job
discrimination, only to be derailed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>'s first question: "Does
basic, equal, civil rights include the right to marry<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" Birch, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
had to give a principled answer--"uh, yes"--at which point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
dragged her through the sordid exercise of distinguishing gay marriage from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polygamy</ENAMEX> and incest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> defend serial and
childless heterosexual marriages, but the whole topic was a loser for her.
Questions, not answers, win debates.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Identity</ENAMEX> vs. behavior. Everyone now
agrees with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be judged by the content
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, not by the color of their skin. The gay-rights debate turns
on whether homosexuality is more like the former or the latter. This is why
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gays</ENAMEX> substituted the phrase "sexual orientation" for "sexual preference."

            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are
fighting back. Their usual tactic is to pepper the debate with references to
sexual vices such as adultery and bestiality. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s war on nonsexual
sins gives them a new angle. Citing the campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
argued that being a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is worse than being a smoker because homosexuality
"takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> off your life."

            To
suppress the image of homosexuality as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> attribute
civic virtues to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. "If they obey the law, show up for work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> or
show up for school, if they're good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, they ought to be treated with
respect," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s criticism of gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> who seek
to marry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birch</ENAMEX> insisted, "They are tax-paying! They are tax-paying!"

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> vs. nurture. This underlies the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">identity</ENAMEX> vs. behavior debate. On the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> chat shows after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> argued that homosexuality involves a "choice," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>
maintained that it's "genetically based" and "hard-wired." The hot-button issue
behind this academic dispute is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are amenable to gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuasion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> can argue that they should be "protected" by
excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> not just from jobs that involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (e.g., teaching), but
also from any legal rights that confer respectability. The extreme argument,
dredged up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> conspire to recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. The more
respectable argument, leveled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are susceptible to
atmospheric social cues.

            The conventional view of last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s frame game is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s words didn't matter because his mere
presence advanced gay rights as a mainstream cause. No doubt it did. But words
always matter, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s exchange proved that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of gay rights
aren't running out of good ones any time soon.

         
      
   
