
   
   
      
         
            When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>

            "We look at it like this:
The big fish eats the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and the small fish eats the shrimp. You buy or
get bought. It's a law of economics," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shi Jianping</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai Rubber Belt Co.</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>.
Merger mania, you see, is sweeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People's Republic</ENAMEX>. Soon, instead of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> all making identical rubber belts there will be one
giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> making all the rubber belts. It'll be just like the market for PC
operating systems in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            As it
happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shi Jianping</ENAMEX>'s description of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> sounds quite a bit like
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Mergers and acquisitions are back in a big way, and the
new buzzword is "consolidation." Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> & A activity has risen to
record levels, both in terms of raw numbers and size. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommunications</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, aerospace, mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>: In all these industries the number of players
has been significantly reduced over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>. Emboldened by a new
approach to antitrust law at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade</ENAMEX>
Commission--one that suggests that unless you're doing something that will
immediately raise consumer prices, it's A-OK with them--giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
previously would never have imagined merging have tied the knot. This
rediscovery of the art of the deal makes it seem like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> all over
again.

            Except that in some interesting and important ways, it
isn't. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, a much higher percentage of these mergers and
acquisitions are taking place within, rather than across, industries, which is
why we hear a lot more about consolidation and a lot less about synergy or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conglomeration</ENAMEX>. Instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USX</ENAMEX> buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marathon Oil</ENAMEX> in a desperate attempt to
diversify into a business it hadn't proved it couldn't run, we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>
buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Telecom</ENAMEX> buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raytheon</ENAMEX> buying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Electronics</ENAMEX>. In addition, the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> & A activity today
is friendly. The big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> may be eating the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, but the small fish seem
more than happy to be eaten. In this new win-win world, there's something
almost unseemly about hostile takeover attempts.

            Of course, that only makes it
all the more interesting, and the more telling, when they occur.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Resources</ENAMEX> is an independent oil and gas driller, which means it
specializes in getting as much out of a given field's reserves as possible. It
used to be part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific Corp.</ENAMEX>, the transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> that laid
railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. As part of its desire to focus on its
core, UP spun off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. The oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is blessed with very
little debt, but it's grown relatively slowly since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spinoff</ENAMEX>, because it
doesn't have many reserves and lacks the wherewithal for massive exploration
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>.

            
Enter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>. Or rather, re-enter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX> makes ... well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX> motor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. It also owns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiffy Lube</ENAMEX>--oil
changes/motor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>; is that synergy or consolidation? And it has a growing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oil-and-gas</ENAMEX> exploration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX> approached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> with an offer to merge, figuring its extensive reserves would fit well
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX>'s intensive drilling. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> rebuffed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX> (actually,
it was more a simple failure to call back than an explicit rejection). And so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX> turned itself around, selling off less profitable fields, expanding
its exploration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, strengthening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiffy Lube</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the company
turned its first profit since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, and earnings for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last quarter</TIMEX> were up
sharply--much more sharply than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX>'s--over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>. Not surprisingly,
that's when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX> decided to come a-calling.

            A little
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX> announced a tender offer of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84</NUMEX> a share--a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">41-percent</NUMEX> premium over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>'s previous closing price--including a
commitment to buy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50.1 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>'s shares at the offer price. If UPR
were to gain control, it would buy up the remaining shares at market price.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>'s shares were tendered by the deadline. Game
over, right?

            Not quite. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>'s management and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of directors
vehemently opposed the takeover. They insisted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s long-term value
was much greater than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84</NUMEX> a share, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX> was trying to pick it up before
the effects of the turnaround had been felt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX> has a
"poison pill" provision, which means that as soon as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s shares are acquired by a hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>, every other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>
shareholder gets to buy newly issued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX> shares at a substantial discount.
Obviously, that would make any buyout attempt prohibitively expensive.

            Now poison-pill plans and
other scorched-earth strategies to frustrate takeovers--like the sale of
valuable assets or the assumption of insane levels of debt--seem to violate the
principle that those who own the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>, should be able to
decide what to do with it. If we want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> to think like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>, taking away that power hardly seems the answer.

            On the
other hand, the way tender offers are structured almost guarantees they'll be
accepted. If you're one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> who doesn't tender her stock,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX> is only going to pay you the market price for your shares, and you have no
guarantee that will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $84</NUMEX>. What that really means is that any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with the financial ability to launch a tender offer--and given the ease
with which financing can be found, that means essentially any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--can
bring about the dissolution of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>. A study in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, in fact, found
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> tender offers resulted in the target being absorbed
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> or another.

            
For free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX>, there's nothing wrong
with this. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s management hasn't done right by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>,
takeovers are an appropriate remedy. For these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> in the efficient
market, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price always reflects its true value. There's only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> problem with this: It makes no sense.

            In a
market of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> stocks, short-term prices will rise and fall for an infinite
variety of reasons, very few of which have anything to do with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s real
productivity or value. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell Computer</ENAMEX>, for instance, would be at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
times as hard to acquire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. But only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>--or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago School</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>--would say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times as valuable to the
economy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. Placing the entire future of a corporation
in the hands of arbitrageurs, which is what a tender offer amounts to, is the
worship of property rights run amok. Yet how to come up with a solution that
would protect long-term shareholder rights while making tender offers less
automatically successful? Wasn't it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffet</ENAMEX> who suggested a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>
capital gains tax on any investment held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a year</TIMEX>? That might work.

            Most scholarly studies of hostile takeovers show they have
little or no impact on productivity, profitability, or on the acquiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s long-term stock price. Plenty of wealth is redistributed, but it's
not really clear that any is created. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> tend to portray
themselves as rescuing ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX> said it was reacting to "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>
of broken promises and poor performance" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>--in fact they almost
uniformly bid for profitable, healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that the market, for one reason
or another, is undervaluing. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> vogue for mergers may be making
the economy stronger, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is still out on that question. But in a
hostile takeover, it seems pretty clear, one plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> generally doesn't equal
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. Often, it doesn't even equal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. Hard as it may be to remember in a
bull market, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> doesn't get any richer when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPR</ENAMEX> exchanges its cash for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX>'s shares. Of course, investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>
do.

         
      
   
