
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commoditization Conundrum</ENAMEX>

            If there's one thing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">microeconomics</ENAMEX> has demonstrated, it is that it's hard to keep your profit
margins high if you're in the wheat-growing business. Wheat is pretty much
wheat, no matter where it grows, and it's pretty easy to grow unless the Dust
Bowl is raging. That means that the supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> rises quickly to meet
demand, which, in turn, keeps a downward pressure on prices. Wheat, in other
words, is the definition of a commodity, and the market for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX>--absent
government intervention--is about as close to perfect competition as you can
imagine.

            The same
would be true, one might think, of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>. If anything, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> is easier to produce
than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> is the same all around the world. It should, in theory, be
impossible for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to charge more for its basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> than its competitors
do. And yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX> actually owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> market, even
though its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> is more expensive--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least a few pennies</NUMEX> more--than other
brands. If <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> is a commodity, and surely it is, then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>
appear not to know it.

            The lesson of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>'s success, obviously, is that even the
most mundane and undifferentiated of products can be made into something unique
with the right marketing strategy. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX> is salt is <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>, except when it comes
in a blue canister with a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> with an umbrella on it and the promise
that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> won't damage its pourability. Yet what's striking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--and in particular about the very industries that we now think
of as the heart of our economy, namely information technology and financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>--is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in charge are not consoled by the thought of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>'s successful "branding." Instead, they are haunted by the specter of
that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> market. Luckily for them, though, we're much further from that world
of perfect competition than much recent hype would suggest.

            What
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> fear is the phenomenon now known, rather inelegantly, as
"commoditization." What the term means is simply the conversion of the market
for a given product into a commodity market, which is characterized by
declining prices and profit margins, increasing competition, and lowered
barriers to entry. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Commoditization</ENAMEX>" is therefore different from
"commodification," the word cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> use to decry the corruption of
higher goods by commercial values. Microprocessors are commoditized. Love is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commodified</ENAMEX>.)

            
Without this fear, corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should be
in its heyday. Profits and stock prices are at record highs, and there's no
sign of any meaningful challenge--regulatory or otherwise. But analyses of the
prospects for the personal-computer industry or the banking industry or even
the clothing industry reveal a permanent anxiety. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> rely on for
profits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> they assume will most likely not be there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, because
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> someone else will be making the very same thing for less. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent, emblematic account.) In this universe, even the paranoid may not
survive.

            Insofar
as commoditization is a reality, it's all to the good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. It is
witness to the enormous distance <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have traveled from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inefficiencies</ENAMEX> and quality-control debacles of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commoditization</ENAMEX> can
only take place, after all, in a world in which second-tier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can
compete in terms of quality and efficiency with top-of-the-line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. And
commoditization, or at least the fear of it, encourages innovation. Those
technological breakthroughs that allow a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to distinguish itself from its
competition and charge a premium for its product are more likely and fruitful
in an economy characterized by price competition than in one dominated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligopolies</ENAMEX>. Finally, and perhaps more dubiously, commoditization has furthered
the democratization of fashion and interior decoration. Whether you deplore or
welcome the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap-ification of America</ENAMEX>, it is happening.

            Still, this supposed ubiquity of commoditization is
difficult to square with one fact: A few large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> dominate many, if
not most, major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have been able to
maintain high profit margins and market share in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that, in theory at
least, should be eminently susceptible to competition.

            In some
cases, with the auto industry being the best example, commoditization has been
fended off by the enormous capital investment required to enter the business.
It takes a much smaller initial investment to make a new word-processing
program than it does to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. In other cases, like the soft-drink
industry, a curious confluence of taste distinctions and brand identification
makes meaningful challenges difficult to imagine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> does taste different
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RC</ENAMEX>, but that taste difference is reinforced by the all-American
mythology that has been wrapped around it. In still other cases--the
personal-computer industry, for example--the brand name becomes a kind of
surrogate for quality and reliability. It's possible, even likely, that XYZ
Computer makes a PC every bit as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>'s. But because I recognize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>'s name, I'll buy its PC without bothering to check out what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XYZ</ENAMEX> is
offering. If I pay extra for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> (which I probably won't have to), it's to
cover the opportunity cost I avoid by not having to comparison shop.

            
The greatest example of a company avoiding
seemingly certain commoditization is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, which continues to charge premium
prices for its microprocessors even though, by all accounts, its Pentium chips
are no more powerful than chips made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro Devices</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrix</ENAMEX>. It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s production lines have been
consistently more reliable and efficient than either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMD</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrix's</ENAMEX>. That
makes PC <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> more comfortable putting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> chips in their computers.
But other factors contribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s success. The mere fact of its
commanding position in the microprocessor market--a position it initially
achieved by technological superiority--has made computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> leery of doing
business with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, lest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> fail to give them access to new, more
powerful chips in the future.

            More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strikingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s successful "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Intel Inside</ENAMEX>" ad campaign has created a brand
name for a product that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> once believed was the very definition of a
commodity. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> less-than-prescient ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exec</ENAMEX> put it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> while labeling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s advertising efforts "awfully stupid": "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that buy computers
don't even know that that chip is in there. They care about the performance of
the computer. It really doesn't matter what the chip is." Oh well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrix</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMD</ENAMEX> are now spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> on TV-ad campaigns in recognition of
the fact that it really does matter.

            More intriguing than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s success, though, is the
continued market domination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>'s razors are technologically superior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schick's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soup</ENAMEX> tastes better than its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>', the quality differences aren't big
enough to account for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' ability to combine premium pricing with
huge sales. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> razor market, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s
has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 75 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> market.) Nor can we simply ascribe
their market dominance to advertising. What's going on seems to be something we
might describe as "the narcissism of small differences." In an odd way, the
more similar products become, the more telling the little differences among
them end up being. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branding</ENAMEX> successfully, in other words, can turn a small
difference between products into a huge difference in market share.

            None of this means that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell's</ENAMEX> are not pushed by their competition, since all the
evidence suggests that they are constantly looking for competitive advantages.
What it does mean, though, is that commoditization does its work not by
becoming a reality (which would entail ever-shrinking margins and stagnant
stock prices) but by remaining a perpetually present threat. It's the idea that
perfect competition might be just around the corner, not the competition
itself, that keeps the paranoid prosperous. And alive.

         
      
   
