
   
   
      
         
            Of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Course You Don't Like Your</ENAMEX> HMO

            Given the increasingly angry
complaints lodged against managed-care health plans by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, you'd think
that the plans would be losing business. Instead, managed-care enrollment is
climbing. A study in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Affairs</ENAMEX> explains why: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosses</ENAMEX>
decide what health plan you will have, and more of them are deciding that you
will have managed care, like it or not. Besides explaining why competition and
consumer ire aren't slowing the managed-care juggernaut, these findings also
suggest that tougher regulations are unlikely to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> serve patients
better.

            
Managed-care programs, which include health-maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and
preferred-practice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, limit member <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. The goal of the plans, of course, is to hold costs down. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are
the most restrictive plans, only covering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who see their specified care
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPOs</ENAMEX> are the least restrictive, offering coverage with minimal
payments if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> visit the plan's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and with larger payments if they
go outside the network for care. Only old-style "indemnity" insurance gives
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> uniform coverage no matter where they go. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, HMOs account for
coverage of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of privately insured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--and that number is rising.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only a quarter</TIMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have indemnity insurance.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> hate about managed-care plans are
cost-cutting mandates that shorten hospital stays and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> visits and make it
difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>. (No wonder popularity polls reveal
that only tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> rank lower than managed-care programs.)
Increasingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are seeking legislative
remedies--currently, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX> bills that would regulate managed-care
plans are pending in state legislatures, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> alone. And early next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will introduce his own legislative package.

            Typically,
the proposals loosen the restrictions. Already in effect are new federal laws
requiring all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> to pay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> stays after uncomplicated childbirth,
and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX> stays after Caesarean sections. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are now
considering bills that would stipulate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> stays after mastectomies, direct
access to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">obstetrician</ENAMEX>/gynecologists without a referral, and automatic coverage
for almost any emergency visit.

            
But what about hospital stays after heart
surgery or a stroke? And after appendectomies, prostate operations, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX>?
We don't really want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> directing our care any more than we want
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> to. What's more, piecemeal regulation is bound to fail. If an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insurer</ENAMEX>'s priority is cheap health care, it will find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> other
unpalatable ways to economize.

            Political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and the managed-care industry argue that the market should be let
alone to sort things out. They believe that the managed-care backlash is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fomented</ENAMEX> in irrationality. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who whine about managed care
refuse to pay the extra cost of indemnity insurance. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, average family
coverage costs under managed care were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,071</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,388</NUMEX> under indemnity plans
(plus deductibles and copayments were usually higher, too).

            But fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are given that choice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Affairs</ENAMEX> study from consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KPMG Peat Marwick</ENAMEX>. The
study found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of small- and medium-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that give
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> health benefits offer just one plan. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent of large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> offer no choice of plan either. What's more, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are
aggressively switching their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to managed care. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, smaller
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> gave few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> a choice, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92 percent</NUMEX> offered indemnity
insurance. Now <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 33 percent</NUMEX> offer indemnity. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where I
practice <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> dropped its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Cross</ENAMEX> indemnity plan and now offers managed
care exclusively.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employers</ENAMEX>
mainly pick <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> on the basis of price, and often switch plans in pursuit
of the lowest cost. So we shouldn't be surprised that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> aren't happy or
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> aren't bending over backward to please them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX> are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> in the health-care-insurance marketplace, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. It's like
when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> picked your clothes for you. The only one happy with what you
got was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX> resist letting some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> pick more
expensive plans and cover the extra costs themselves because most insurers
insist that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--especially small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--deliver all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
to the plan. Also, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> would rather send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big check to their
insurer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each month</TIMEX> than deal with the paperwork hassle of a bunch of different
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>.

            Lost in
the managed-care rumble is this question: Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> provide health
insurance in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? After all, they don't offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> car
insurance. Health insurance became a standard benefit during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. Wage
and price controls then in effect prevented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> from giving raises, but
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> regarded health insurance as a tax-free benefit,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> used it to fatten compensation packages for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. If car insurance
were a tax-free benefit, it wouldn't be surprising to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> picking
low-cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> who make you visit "preferred" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> and skimp on
coverage for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land Rovers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>. Angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> would complain about
cheapo car care. To appease <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> without upsetting the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> would probably require overnight stays after brake and lube
jobs.

            The most straightforward way to put choices back into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>' hands would be to sever the connection between health insurance and
work. If health benefits were taxed as income, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would promptly demand
that the cash be paid directly to them and that they be allowed to choose their
own insurance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Insurers</ENAMEX> would then have to cater to their needs. Short of that
radical change, effective legislation should be passed to increase choices for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have established insurance-buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
can join. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> a selection of plans and reduce paperwork
hassles for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>. Legislation could expand such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Some suggest that
the law require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to offer both a managed-care plan and an indemnity
plan, as it did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> were first created.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> drafting his consumer-protection proposals endorsed a host
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' rights, including the right to appeal mistreatment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> scuttled all concrete measures to return choice to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. The new rights are nice enough; they'll move <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> a few seats
forward on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are still driving, and that's all that
counts.

         
      
   
