
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man With the Bandwidth</ENAMEX>

            In this brand-new digital
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> we're supposedly inhabiting, competitive advantage can be eroded in an
instant, and large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with lots of fixed assets are doomed to being
overrun by quick-moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">startups</ENAMEX> who can adapt better to a world of rapid
technological innovation. By that logic, the cable industry--with its
overpriced services, monopolistic market control, and unwieldy operating
structures--must be headed for the graveyard.

            But as
the recent return to center stage of cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>,
suggests, the cable industry has never been healthier, despite having committed
a rather staggering array of strategic missteps in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>. In the
end, owning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> of infrastructure--such as cable
wires--certainly has its flaws as a business strategy, but it also has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> huge
benefit: Owning those wires allows you to make a lot of mistakes without going
out of business. And in an industry dedicated to gambling on future
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>, that's a benefit that can't be overvalued.

            
Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> did not become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> because
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> owned a lot of cable wires. On the contrary, he was as responsible
as anyone for hyping the digital economy and the transformation of the home
into a multimedia center of information, entertainment, and commerce. Without
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, the whole concept of the information
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superhighway</ENAMEX>--with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, its interactive television, its
high-speed Internet access, and online banking and shopping--could scarcely
have existed. For a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a master's degree in electrical engineering and a
doctorate in operations research, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> has always had a keen sense of how
important futurist rhetoric was to the new media world. Convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
cool things were just around the corner was essential to convincing them that
they wanted those things.

            Of
course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> did temper his visionary side with a hard-boiled business side.
When he talked about the information superhighway, it was always in terms of
collecting tolls on it. The technologies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> championed were designed to
service meat-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> tasks--such as banking and shopping--rather than the
needs of some ideal virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX>'s reputation as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX>
of cable" and "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who knows how to run over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" spoke to his ferocious
ability as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX> and deal-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>. When he joked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1994</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed Hundt</ENAMEX> should be shot
for ordering rate reductions, the idea that the dark side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> was
shaping the digital future was hard to resist.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Afew months earlier</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX>
had announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> planned to merge in a deal that at the
time dwarfed all previous mergers. The result was going to be a massive
vertically integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, offering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> across the country
every communication and information service they could want. Had the deal gone
through, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s media landscape would obviously look very different. But by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX>, the plan had collapsed, and its failure deflated both the
superhighway hype and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX>'s reputation as an irresistible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            It
seems odd that one blown deal could have changed everything, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX> had billed
itself as a growth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which meant it had to keep getting bigger in order
to remain valuable in the eyes of Wall Street. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>'s rate rollback,
which happened around the same time, put a real dent into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>'s cash flow.
Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has always carried a huge debt load--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's north of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion</ENAMEX>--slowing cash flow was hardly a recipe for success. What's more, the
truth was that the technology could not live up to the hype. In retrospect, in
fact, what's most interesting about that time is how little progress we've made
toward the kinds of things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> assured us were just around the corner. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> channels, on-screen banking, on-screen shopping, interactive news: None
is available via cable television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Even cable modems, which would make a
qualitative difference in the experience of using the Web, have minuscule
market penetration, though that's supposed to change--wink, wink, nudge,
nudge--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year or so</TIMEX>.

            
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following three years</TIMEX>, the cable
industry was everyone's favorite selection as the industry most likely to fail.
Either the regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were going to take away the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>'
business, or satellite television was going to steal it, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were
going to collapse under the weight of their own debt. In fact, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
hadn't invested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> in cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comcast</ENAMEX>, that might
still be the conventional wisdom. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> did invest that money--pointing
once again to television as a gateway to the digital future--and almost
overnight cable was hot again.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comcast</ENAMEX> drew attention to the obvious--that the name
of the game in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> economy is bandwidth. Amazing leaps in digital
technology are largely irrelevant unless you can bring them inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
And no industry is better positioned to provide that bandwidth than the one
that has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences wired</ENAMEX> with high-bandwidth coaxial cable.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> believed that all along, which is why he never moved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX> out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> business and why, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> sought to make its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> base
more manageable, it traded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> for minority stakes in other cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            
The Street's new love affair with cable has put
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly every day</TIMEX> and back in visionary mode.
This is more than a little ironic when you consider that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX> has become the
least technologically advanced of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX>
slashed capital spending in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> in order to keep the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s finances in order. But with the digital set-top box, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX>
sees as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> that will finally deliver high-speed Net access,
interactive television, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> channels, he's found his latest
can't-lose gizmo. And everyone from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX> has
jumped on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.

            The digital box may well be
the harbinger of a truly wired future, once the struggle over which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> will be included in it is resolved and the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> figure
out how to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> to pay for it. But even if the set-top box is not
the answer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> will just wait until the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> appears. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> and minority stakes in everything from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Learning Channel</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>, he has the resources to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, and the experience of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> shows he has the will to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> as well. The myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malone</ENAMEX> was
built around the image of someone able to see the value inherent in a future
that no one else could grasp. The reality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malone</ENAMEX> is that he's someone
able to see the value inherent in a mundane present--the present of cable wires
and the E! Network--that everyone else was too quick to write off.

         
      
   
