
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juicy Journals</ENAMEX>

            Forget books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>.
Turn off the television. Put down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report. If you really want the
lowdown, something that will tell you almost anything you want to know about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are where the action is. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>'s hidden
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleasures</ENAMEX> is that while there is a fantastic amount to learn about human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>, most of it is already spelled out in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
alone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library of Medicine</ENAMEX> added references to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">519,012</NUMEX> new
articles from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 3,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> to its Medline database. The fact that all
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> can survive and multiply should be a clue that there's something
compelling about them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subscribers</ENAMEX> are willing to pay dearly to keep their
favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> going. Rates run to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or more for some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>.
As a result, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the
scientific publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elsevier</ENAMEX> put out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and made a
whopping <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> profit on them.

            To be sure, for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, the interest
in a given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is purely parochial. Even the smallest ones--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elsevier</ENAMEX>
produces some with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>--can be the prestige publication
for a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>. Moreover, behind the glossy covers and stilted prose, many of
these little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> function as the gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rags</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>,
for the science niches. My pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Affairs</ENAMEX> (circulation
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> that all health policy wonks get and therefore write in.
It's how we keep tabs on what everyone is up to. An infectious disease
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist friend</ENAMEX> of mine reads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Virology</ENAMEX> (circulation
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>). My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of the American Association of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians of Indian Origin</ENAMEX> (circulation <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26,000</NUMEX>).

            But people
should not let all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkanization</ENAMEX> and technical-sounding talk scare them
away. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poke</ENAMEX> around in a few medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, and you're bound to find material
as absorbing as anything you'll find in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> .

            
The names alone are worth perusing. Many
journals follow the standard "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Annals of" or "Archives of"</ENAMEX> or "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> of"
approach--you know, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Journal of Leprosy</ENAMEX> . But the
best are the direct, in-your-face journal names: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Placenta</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gut</ENAMEX> ,
Brain , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood</ENAMEX> . When you pick up Placenta , you know exactly
what you're getting. What's more, you get the impression that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> are
proud to give it to you, that they have no second thoughts about the field they
have chosen. Consider, by comparison, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ankle International</ENAMEX> . It's
a terrible name. It conveys embarrassment, a sense that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> thought
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foot</ENAMEX>" alone wasn't good enough for them. Even adding "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ankle</ENAMEX>" was still too
minor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> for their ambitions, so they had to tack on that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>."
You want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> more willing to glory in its small, arcane world.

            Clearly,
however, the cool stuff is what's inside, and a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> always have
the cool stuff. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> of Sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marital Therapy</ENAMEX> is, not
surprisingly, reliably fascinating no matter what your profession. A recent
issue I browsed through at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> (while hiding it in a copy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> ) had such topically relevant reports as "" and "Penile
Erections: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shape, Angle, and Length</ENAMEX>." A quirkier favorite of mine is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Emergency Medicine</ENAMEX> , which is replete with oddball
articles--such as the recent one from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Tennessee</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> cases
occurring over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks</TIMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> reported swallowing razor blades
and other metal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for more details.) Not long ago, however, I
discovered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> that never fails to amaze: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Forensic Medicine and Pathology</ENAMEX> . A typical issue contained an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> suicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> with multiple gunshot wounds to the head
(complete with photos from the death scenes; one poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> shot himself <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
times before he finally died), another on improved methods to determine the age
of an unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, and yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> on the homicide rituals of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>. You'll never go wrong picking up a copy of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>.

            Each of these specialized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> offers an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obsessive</ENAMEX>'s-eye view of the world around us, a new look at the seemingly
familiar. International medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, however, can do the opposite. They
tend to share the common language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> everywhere and so can make the
unfamiliar reassuringly accessible, while still conveying a revealing sense of
their national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> . I recently picked up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annals of Saudi</ENAMEX>
Medicine , for example, and discovered, to my surprise, the telling
obsessions of a modernized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ulcers</ENAMEX>, a growing epidemic of obesity,
smoking, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Journal of Medical</ENAMEX>
Research , on the other hand, despite all the press reports about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
burgeoning middle class, is currently filled with reports on infectious
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.

            Sadly, few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> appreciate the refined charms of medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. Occasionally,
however, I'll come across a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> junkie. We'll exchange tips like
frat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> do. "Have you seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Personality and Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychology ?</ENAMEX>" one such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> asked me not long ago. "That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is
hot ." I looked it up at my next opportunity. It did not disappoint. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue I read, for example, had a study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">219</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> who were
instructed to put on a specific facial expression while looking in the mirror.
What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> found was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> told to do nothing more than
put on a happy face developed a significantly more positive mood than those
told to adopt a neutral expression. And those made to assume an unhappy
expression had the worst moods of all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> was full of strange little
studies like that. I made a mental note to check it out again. And, when I left
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, you can bet I had a smile on my face.

            
               If you
missed the sidebar on adultery, click . If you missed the sidebar on
razor-swallowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, click .
            

         
      
   
