
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Redemption</ENAMEX>

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale University</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> books are cataloged under the heading "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>." Of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
are cross-referenced under "bribery," "corruption," or "military-industrial
complex." Other appropriate subheadings might include "cost overruns,"
"bailout," and "crash and burn."

            For a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> whose history, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> angle, looks to be an almost uninterrupted
record of malfeasance and incompetence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> has done rather well for
itself. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>--as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has been known since its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Marietta</ENAMEX>--is the world's largest defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> revenues of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27 billion</NUMEX>. If its proposed
acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop Grumman</ENAMEX> is approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, it will
be a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1998</TIMEX>. Given that, one might see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> as an exemplary case of corporate rebirth. On the other hand, one
might see it as evidence that in the defense industry, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, it's
easier to fail upward than to disappear.

            Of course, defense is an industry like no other. Barriers
to entry in terms of technology and physical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> are prohibitive, which keeps
domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> out of the business. At the same time, national-security
concerns keep potential foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> at bay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s interest in
keeping its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> supply free from interruptions, meanwhile, means that no
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> can be allowed to go under. Defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> are able to reap
tremendous profits while rarely confronting the risks for which those profits
are supposed to be the reward. The fact that a small number of contracts can
determine a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s profit outlook for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> places a premium on
low-balling bids (which leads, almost inevitably, to cost overruns) and
influence-currying. The result is a system with all the vices of both
regulation and competition, and few of the virtues of either.

            Seen in
this light, perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>'s record is not quite so dismal. Sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>
was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that charged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$646</NUMEX> for a toilet seat. But with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grumman</ENAMEX> charging <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$659</NUMEX> for an ashtray, how else was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> to keep up? And
yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> did pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-5A</ENAMEX> transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> on
which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of parts had not been installed. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX> bought parts from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Shack</ENAMEX> and put them on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MX</ENAMEX> missile-guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> without proper
testing.

            
That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> has been consistently able to
convince others--well, OK, to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--to forget about its
record testifies to the power of the human imagination. (It might also testify
to the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> in campaign contributions, or to
the effect of revolving-door employment in the defense industry.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> has
made historical amnesia into an art form. A short bout of traumatic remembering
seems in order.

            
Ironically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s roots are as deep as any in the aerospace and defense
industries. Founded by auto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Loughhead</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>--with, tellingly enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Northrop</ENAMEX>, who went on to found
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop Aircraft</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> struggled until it produced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vega</ENAMEX>, the plane
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia Earhart</ENAMEX> flew across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vega</ENAMEX>, together with a series
of other sparkling designs, earned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> a place in the high-end market. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> did not capitalize on its advantages until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'30s</TIMEX>, when new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> moved strongly into the passenger<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-plane</ENAMEX> market and started competing
for military contracts as well (including a failed attempt to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> and a successful sale to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>'s reputation was really made during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>,
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> built both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-69 Constellation</ENAMEX> transport (which became the
standard for civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> in the immediate post-war period) and, more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impressively</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-38 Lightning</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> did what they were
supposed to do, and cost what they were supposed to cost. It's not clear
whether that's been true of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> since. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, for instance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> introduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Electra</ENAMEX> turboprop commercial airliner. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electras</ENAMEX> crashed, and within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, production was halted. At the
same time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, thanks to well-placed payments to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>," sold
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-104 Starfighter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>--rejected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>--to both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and West
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. Eventually, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany</ENAMEX> crashed, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> were lost.

            For the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next three decades</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> found itself building planes no one really needed
for more than they wanted to spend. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> tried to sell anti-submarine
reconnaissance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>. It sold giant long-distance transport
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Filipinos</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilians</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>. And
it sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> all over the world. It made these sales, of course, primarily
by bribing foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. But that wasn't actually illegal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>. You might call it a creative and aggressive form of
marketing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>, which was also bribing its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> across the globe, termed this "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> model."

            
At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> was busy running
up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> in cost overruns on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-5A Galaxy</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real procurement
scandal in defense-industry history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was also building the Tristar
passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, plagued from the beginning by equipment problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>
bribed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tristar for All Nippon Airlines</ENAMEX>.
What made these problems truly noteworthy, though, was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> only
survived them thanks to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> government bailout. The market had
spoken, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> was able to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> to offer up a different
answer.

            Once it
survived the bailout, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was unable to avoid rebounding. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
defense budgets helped, as did an aggressive marketing plan abroad and, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importantly</ENAMEX>, the merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Marietta</ENAMEX> and the acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamics</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> helped build the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hubble Telescope</ENAMEX>--no
surprise, really, given how it performed initially--and the space shuttle. It's
currently building the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117A Stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> and the thoroughly unnecessary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>, and is bidding against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> for the contract to build
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Joint Strike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, the last great contracting plum of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>.

            Perhaps, then, "corporate rebirth" is a fitting tag line.
But what's interesting is how similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>'s tactics remain to those it
deployed when it was running what was called "the grease machine." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, for
instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> tried to get the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to pay for the costs
of its merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Marietta</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That same year</TIMEX>, it was investigated by the
government on bribery charges related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX> sales, and fined <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX> for
bribing an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> to help arrange a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$79 million</NUMEX> sale of three
transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. There's always, it seems, another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX> to cut. The
difference now is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has finally figured out how to make its more
unorthodox tactics pay off on the bottom line. The startling fact is that once
the merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX> is done, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> will have only one real competitor
left. The past is gone. The future's bright. Only universal peace can mess
things up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
