
   
   
      
         
            The Internet-Stock Bubble

            The stock market is
certainly reacting faster than ever to the slightest hint of good or bad news.
Whether this means the stock market is more efficient than ever, though, is
another question entirely. The answer may depend on whether you think
"efficient" is a synonym for "jumpy and hysterical."

            As
Exhibit A, we offer the recent trials and tribulations of the so-called
Internet stocks, trials and tribulations that said less about the actual
business of the Internet than about the manic behavior of Wall Street in a
just-won't-quit bull market. This most recent hysteria saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> pouring
billions of dollars into Internet stocks before suddenly--and all at
once--changing their collective mind and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">racing</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX>. In this they
resembled nothing so much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monty Python</ENAMEX> and the Holy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grail</ENAMEX> , who took comfort in screaming "Run away! Run away!" as they fled
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">killer rabbits</ENAMEX> and the like.

            The ride began rather oddly, when some of the most
prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of computer hardware--memory chips, microprocessors, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCs</ENAMEX>--announced that their earnings for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first quarter</TIMEX> would fall short of
the all-knowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' estimates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX> all said that
slowing demand--both in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and at home--was hurting profits, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> emphasized the negative impact of sharp cuts in PC prices. The bad
news crushed these stocks, but much of the money that left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>
immediately flooded into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such as Yahoo!, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and myriad other
search engines, online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, and Internet access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> whose listings
now dot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX>.

            In part,
that move into Internet stocks is simply evidence of what happens when everyone
believes so strongly in the stock market that keeping any money in cash is
regarded as heresy. In other words, if you were a mutual fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, you
couldn't very well sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> and then say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX> I believe I will wait until I
can find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that seems fairly valued." If you did that, you might miss
out on the latest rally. The money had to go somewhere, and when Net stocks
became the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Big Thing</ENAMEX> (for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those few days</TIMEX>), that's where the money
went.

            
Still, there was a certain logic at work in
making Net stocks the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Big Thing</ENAMEX>. If PCs are getting cheaper and cheaper,
then more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will buy them. If more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have PCs, then more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
eventually use the Internet (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> households currently
have access). This in turn means that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will search on Yahoo!, buy
books from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and so on. But while the long-run implications of cheap
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCs</ENAMEX> for the Internet are important, it's hard to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s profit
concerns made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> more valuable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning than</TIMEX>
it was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> before. The same was true of all other Internet companies
whose option-holding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> must have been thanking their personal deities
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis. It was a classic case of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> of good news
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> being priced into its stock all at once. And then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worm</ENAMEX>
turned.

            Why it
turned isn't really clear, but it definitely did. It was a very odd thing to
watch, in fact. Sometime midmorning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Tuesday</TIMEX>, the Net stocks peaked, then
tumbled even more quickly than they had ascended. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, Yahoo!, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX>,
Lycos, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EarthLink, MindSpring</ENAMEX>: All lost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 10 percent and 15 percent</NUMEX> of
their value in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just a few hours</TIMEX>. Apparently, the cheap-PC theory had a few
holes in it.

            Just as the shift of money into Internet stocks was partly
the product of a virtuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> trying to keep their
portfolios invested in stocks that had "momentum," so too was the shift out
partly the product of a vicious circle created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> trying to dump
stocks that suddenly didn't have momentum. The rout also had something to do
with the fact that only a few Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have ever reported profits and
that even those that have profits trade at valuations to which, as they say, no
traditional criteria can be applied. Everyone knows that you can't value these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the way you'd value <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX> (perhaps because if you did
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would all have stock prices that are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-eightieth of what they
are now). But every so often the market does look at their bottom lines, and it
finds that discretion is sometimes the better part of valor.

            Still, the
most dubious part of this little minidrama is not really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' herdlike
advance and retreat as much as it is the governing principle behind that
herdlike behavior. That governing principle is that all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> belong
to something called "the Internet sector" and that it's the sector, and not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, that matters. This is, of course, the principle governing most
institutional investing, which is why pharmaceutical stocks and airline stocks
and semiconductor stocks tend to move as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. It's a rare day when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX>' stock rises while other airline stocks fall. There is the kernel of a
good idea at work here, namely that macroeconomic or external events--like,
say, a fall in the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>--that help one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in an industry will
also help others. But sector investing also tends to reward a successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> for that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>'s success, and in that sense
seems not merely counterintuitive but downright perverse.

            
More to the point, in the case of the Internet,
sector investing rests upon a basic misconception, namely that there are things
we can meaningfully call "Internet stocks." In fact, there are at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
different types of Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, each of which has very different future
prospects. Online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> CDnow, are
still selling into a tiny market but one that's growing explosively. Search
engines, such as Yahoo! and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lycos</ENAMEX>, are evolving into what are called "portal"
sites, hoping to become more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-AOLs</ENAMEX> than just search engines.
Infrastructure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VeriSign, Verity</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX>, are creating
the tools that make the Web work, but their main source of income will come
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNET</ENAMEX>, are trying to make money
packaging content. And, finally, there are the Internet access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, which
is to say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America Online</ENAMEX> and everybody else.

            To be sure, all these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will benefit from having more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use the Internet. But not all
will benefit equally. And even within those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> groups the differences among
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are more important than the similarities. To put it a
different way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, Yahoo!, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, which have established tremendous
brand recognition and clear business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, have more in common with each
other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> does with other online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> or AOL with other access
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>. And yet the strength of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--each, by the way, now
valued at stratospheric heights--is helping carry those around them. The
Internet will undoubtedly be a crucial part of the economy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>.
But Wall Street would be better off remembering that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 12,000</NUMEX> auto
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were around in the early part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. Instead of mindlessly
tossing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> at or taking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> from the Net as such, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> should
be spending their time making sure that it's the future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motors</ENAMEX> of cyberspace that are getting the capital they need.

         
      
   
