
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Weld</ENAMEX>, the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to consider his
nomination to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> quit his job to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to lobby for his cause. Through
surrogates, interviews, and press conferences, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are waging a war of
words. This war isn't bound by strict rules of logic, but it's more
intellectual than an arm-twisting match. It's a contest of conceptualization
and persuasion. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Whichever</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> successfully frames the questions at stake
will capture public opinion and political support, and thereby win. So far, the
war has been waged on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> fronts:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> vs. "social policy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> has stuck doggedly to a single issue:
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. He points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> favors legalizing marijuana for "medical
purposes" (which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> place on the slippery slope toward complete
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legalization</ENAMEX>), favors providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> with clean needles (to prevent the
spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>), and that he prosecuted few drug cases as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. In
short, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> is soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--the last thing we need in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> could reply that he had opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s
medical-marijuana initiative because it was too lax, or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> is a pusher
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, or that it might be a good idea to stop treating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s drug
problem as a "war." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> hasn't touched the drug question. How come? One
rule of the frame game is to avoid issues on which you're guaranteed to lose.
This isn't an Ivy League debating society, where you can win by ingeniously
defending a difficult position. In politics, you're in deep trouble as soon as
you question the war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. This is particularly true if you're fighting for
a job in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, where insecurity over the drug war runs
high. Just ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joycelyn Elders</ENAMEX>.

            Rather
than answer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' charge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> shifted and broadened the conflict. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15</TIMEX>,
he called a press conference to declare: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> has nothing
whatsoever to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> policy. It has everything to do with the future of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. In plain language, I am not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. I do not pass his litmus test on social policy. Nor do I want to."
Overnight, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld-Helms</ENAMEX> standoff became a media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX>. This wasn't just
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> concluded. It was about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' distaste for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s
"moderate" views on social issues such as abortion. With that, the advantage
swung to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> has the more popular position on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> has the
more popular position on abortion.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helms</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Thiessen</ENAMEX> resisted this
maneuver. He insisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' concern was <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, not ideology. The evidence
backs Thiessen up: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> supported pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cohen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense, and has offered to confirm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> without a major marijuana problem, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. But in the frame
game, such petty facts are easily overwhelmed by larger themes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s spin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevails</ENAMEX>, for several reasons.

            To begin with, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s
argument fits nicely into the context of recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> infighting. Having
come apart over foreign policy (trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>) and fiscal policy (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
leadership coup), the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> seem ripe for a civil war over social policy.
Furthermore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> press corps never tires of writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
troubles on abortion and gay rights--though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> hasn't mentioned either issue
in connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> since the confirmation fight began.

            Above
all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> loves to personalize debates. Drug policy is boring, but a fight
between a saucy blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and a surly redneck is fun. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> wasn't even the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s nomination. Others who oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>
have pleaded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> isn't the point. It's a futile argument. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> and his
famous wedge issues are just too colorful.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ideology</ENAMEX> vs. competence. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
who support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s nomination don't want their party torn asunder in the
process. Their solution is to separate the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s ideology from his
competence. They point out that he speaks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, knows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, and is smart
and accomplished. "This is not about the heart and soul of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party," argued <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Shays</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, in a TV debate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 28</TIMEX>. "It's about
whether this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> is competent to serve in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> accept this distinction, because it subverts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s campaign to
broaden the ideological confrontation. They argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s indifference
toward the war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> has affected his competence as a law enforcer and will
do so again if he becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>, however, maintains the fight is
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, even as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> protest it isn't. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helms/Shays</ENAMEX> argument (for a distinction between ideology and competence) is
analytically more sophisticated but viscerally less compelling. Which means it
will probably prevail in a confirmation hearing but lose in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of public
opinion, vanquished by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">libertarian martyrdom</ENAMEX>. In the frame
game, nuance is almost always a loser. Remember, the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to argue for a
distinction between ideology and competence was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>.

            
Perversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> lost the ideology/competence battle by winning the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>/morality battle. Not only did he attack <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15</TIMEX>, but he
deliberately embarrassed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>--which had refrained from quarreling
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>--by calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to speak up for his confirmation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s
caustic apostasy handed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> a persuasive argument against his fitness
for the job--that he's "undiplomatic."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Who started the fight? Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> knows that when a
parent catches you fighting with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, the first thing to do is accuse
the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> of starting it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> should have been able to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>,
since <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms</ENAMEX> arguably started the fight by announcing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> that he would deny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> a hearing. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> blew this moral advantage by attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15</TIMEX>.
It wasn't the first punch thrown, but it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saw.
This allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> to cast his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> as the victim. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, latched on to this as an excuse to side with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> "hurt himself by attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> unfairly and with political
rhetoric that was just uncalled for," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> complained.

            Belatedly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> is trying to
regain the moral high ground. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29</TIMEX>, he pleaded: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Before</ENAMEX> I had ever met
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms</ENAMEX>], before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> really knew anything about me, he said I was unfit to
be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>, had loose lips, and was soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. And I said, 'Where does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> get off saying all these mean things about me?' And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> threw up their hands in alarm and said, 'My goodness, he attacked
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> also has claimed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' "ideological
extortion."

            The
"ideological extortion" argument is particularly ingenious. Typically,
extortion means that you're threatening someone with harm or embarrassment to
extract a concession. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> has no illusions that he can make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> concede
anything. His vow to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s nomination is a promise, not a threat. It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> who's trying to scare <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> into supporting him, by threatening to
turn his fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> into an ideological civil war. His charge of
"ideological extortion" is part of his ideological extortion. And it's
succeeding. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 3</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Lugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, rescued <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> by demanding that
he get a hearing, lest his jihad against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> ignite "civil war in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>."

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Substance</ENAMEX> vs. process. Having lost the
advantage on fronts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> has opened a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, more promising front
recently. He has stopped debating the substance of his quarrel with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>, and
has focused instead on his right to a hearing. At a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 28</TIMEX> press conference,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> repeated his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> question <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times: "I'm going to be asking that one
insistent question: Why should there not be a hearing? Why should one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, in a
democracy, block the conduct of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s business?"

            This new message helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, because it allows <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to defend him without exacerbating
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s internal conflicts. It certainly emboldened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lugar</ENAMEX>. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> cannot be dictatorial, ultimately, when a majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, a
majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, a majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, want action," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lugar</ENAMEX>
said of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 3</TIMEX>.

            Likewise,
the procedural argument allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' obstinacy
without appearing to foment the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s identity crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>, who had refused <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21</TIMEX> to comment on "matters in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>,"
was so moved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s new plea for a "fair hearing" that he repeated that
phrase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times at his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31</TIMEX> press briefing.

            But the true beauty of the "give him a hearing" argument is
that it capitalizes on anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> populism. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 28</TIMEX> press
conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> decried the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> rules" that allow a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> to
thwart the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s will by refusing to schedule a hearing. Framed this way,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s apostasy becomes a virtue instead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>, suggesting candor instead
of a lack of diplomacy.

            Which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> will win the
game? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> say the nomination is doomed. They think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> overlooked
the game's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> rule: that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has its own rules, including the
absolute power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> over supplicants such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>. Why, he's
not even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> anymore, they scoff. He's just a lowly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>. But maybe
they're the ones who have misjudged the game. Maybe the era of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> feeds, and blast-faxes has ended the invisibility and the certainty
of the congressional back-room kill. Maybe every political fight is a frame
game now. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Weld</ENAMEX> can't reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, he can still reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
And maybe that's been his game all along.

         
      
   
