
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> for No. 2

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This October</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis Rent A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Car</ENAMEX> will be spun off by its parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, personal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> giant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFS Inc.</ENAMEX>, in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225-million</NUMEX> initial public offering. I have a modest proposal
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who "try harder." To let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> know what they're in for,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> should change its name. From now on, we'll call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fad</ENAMEX>." I think
it's got quite a ring to it.

            Now it's
true that, not long ago, this very space was filled with invective against
corporate
name changes (which may give you some sense of how far I'll go in pursuit
of a catchy lead). But in this case it's impossible to resist, for in the word
"fad" we have the entire history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX>--and the recent history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
business--summed up in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just three</NUMEX> letters.

            Fittingly enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX>' roots lie in what turned out to be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the great fads of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, namely, air travel. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> scraped together <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85,000</NUMEX> and started his eponymous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, rental-car
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were all in downtown urban areas, making taxis the only way for
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> to get from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> to their destinations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> decided there was a huge market for rental <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>.

            At first,
there wasn't. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warren Avis</ENAMEX> described it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> just didn't
know how to do it." How could they? It was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. There were no credit
cards. Nor were there courtesy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vans</ENAMEX>--oh, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark Ages</TIMEX>!--so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were
parked right outside the door, and the rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> would actually escort you
to yours. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> caught on. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in the industry, behind only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warren Avis</ENAMEX> sold it.

            
That first sale, the product of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warren Avis</ENAMEX>'
fear that he couldn't expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> fast enough to keep up with the
postwar reinvestment boom, was to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Robie</ENAMEX>. Over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 43 years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would change hands <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> more times. When the IPO
is completed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> will have its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> (a collective of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>, in this case). What makes this history of front-office turmoil
really notable is that it has been shaped, in truly uncanny fashion, by the
prevailing currents of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> business ideology.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX>'
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> move into corporate fad-dom came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>, when it was
purchased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>. Now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX> was once one real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, the kind that could topple a democratically elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> without blinking an eye. It was also the prototypical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>,
assembling in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> a stunning array of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from seemingly every
industry on the globe. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX> owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX>, conglomeration was supposed to be
the recipe for success, because diversification would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to offset
losses in one sector with gains from others. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> diversify their
portfolios, the thinking went, so why shouldn't large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> diversify their
ownership?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason they shouldn't, it now seems, is that unless
someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Welch</ENAMEX>--of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX>--is in charge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> tends to
concentrate on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> they know something about and neglect those they
don't. Still, conglomeration as a theory lasted well into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> was there for all of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX> sold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norton Simon</ENAMEX>, which was
then bought whole by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esmark</ENAMEX>, whose name was itself a product of corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faddism</ENAMEX>. And then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esmark</ENAMEX> was purchased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice</ENAMEX>, the ultimate consumer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Butterball</ENAMEX> turkeys, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samsonite</ENAMEX> luggage, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropicana</ENAMEX> orange juice (while paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> for an ad campaign
designed to create brand loyalty around a name, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice</ENAMEX>, that did not appear
on even one of its products).

            But the
transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> into a plaything for theory-spouting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> didn't
really happen until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kohlberg Kravis Roberts</ENAMEX>, the investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that made the leveraged buyout an art form, bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice</ENAMEX> by assuming
large levels of its debt. The argument was that debt forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managements</ENAMEX> to
become more efficient: The important thing wasn't the size of the bottom-line
profit, but rather increasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> cash flow. Large interest payments were
apparently not the problem everyone had thought they were.

            
As part of its effort to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice</ENAMEX>'s
debt, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKR</ENAMEX> sold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesray Capital</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Simon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> had brought LBOs to public notice when he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesray</ENAMEX> had first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bought Gibson Greetings</ENAMEX>, a card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million</NUMEX> and then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX>
later, taken it public for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$290 million</NUMEX>. That deal earned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> himself <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$66</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> on an investment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$330,000</NUMEX> and, not surprisingly, made the LBO more
popular on Wall Street than bad contemporary art.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesray</ENAMEX>'s
purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> was trendy in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ways. It was an LBO. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was run
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> now, which, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> argued, would make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> more
"entrepreneurial." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was no longer part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>, which
was good because everyone was talking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> about focusing on your "core
business." But if the entrepreneurial spirit was willing, the flesh was
apparently weak, because, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesray</ENAMEX> sold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, who bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> through what's called an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee Stock</ENAMEX>
Ownership Plan.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESOPs</ENAMEX> were invented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX>, but did not become
popular until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. Traditional thinking on employee ownership held that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> would sacrifice long-term gains for short-term rewards, which is why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> consulting in post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> disparaged worker
ownership. Critics also suggested that, with their salaries and stock wrapped
up in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were putting too many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> basket.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strangely</ENAMEX>, no one ever said the same about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>.) But by the time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, the new thinking was that there was no
better way of encouraging their creativity and dedication. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, said
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, "will be motivated, they will be happy, they will be competitive." I
have seen the future, and it works.

            Actually, it did work, for a
while. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX>' profits jumped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first six months</TIMEX> of employee
ownership, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> remained profitable for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>. But more
recently, the bloom has gone from the ESOP rose, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> was sold to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFS</ENAMEX>, which also owns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days Inn</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Century 21</TIMEX>. Conglomeration
may not be back in, but franchising is, and that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFS</ENAMEX>'s whole business. You
might say the acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> was therefore inevitable. And given the
recent resurrection of the IPO market, you might say the upcoming public
offering was as well.

            What's really interesting
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> is that each change in management has been accompanied by claims of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superiority</ENAMEX> and inevitability. These claims can't, after all, all be right.
(Though in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did jiggle the tax rules in ways that encouraged
both LBOs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESOPs</ENAMEX>.) If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> was wrong to
orchestrate the management buyout. If franchising is more efficient, the ESOP
was a mistake, as were both conglomeration and the core-business focus.
But nothing like this ever gets said. The new moves in, with scant reference to
the old. The avatars of the new make huge sums of money, all the while
pontificating about the efficiency and rationality of the market. But the
market can be productive without being rational, and you can have change
without progress. Right now, I'm waiting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> to announce that huge new
investment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> has made in its future.

         
      
   
