
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suicide Watch</ENAMEX>

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2 this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Force Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Button</ENAMEX> suddenly went missing in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-10 Thunderbolt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>,
finally crashing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>. The evidence released by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>
indicates suicide. Why he did it is baffling, however. The case violates even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX>' common notions about why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kill themselves.

            Button
flew the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> formation that left an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Air Force</ENAMEX>
base at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:45 a.m.</TIMEX> When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> reached the target bombing range, the flight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> to update their computers. Button confirmed the order at
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:57</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Moments later</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> radioed in preparation for the bombing
run, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX> did not respond. The lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> swung around to catch sight of
Button. Despite <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-mile</NUMEX> visibility, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX> was nowhere to be found.

            Ground radar, however, picked him up. Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Button</ENAMEX>
turned <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 degrees</NUMEX> off his flight path and flew <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 miles</NUMEX> straight into central
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>. His altitude veered wildly. Sometimes he hugged terrain below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>
feet. Other times, he glided above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16,000 feet</NUMEX>. Near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold Dust Peak</ENAMEX>, he circled
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 360 degrees</NUMEX>, then careened downward below the reach of ground radar.
Reconstructed AWACs radar data showed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX> briefly climbed back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 19,000</NUMEX>
feet, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> above the highest mountain. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> later, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:40 p.m.</TIMEX>, he
slammed into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold Dust Peak</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13,000 feet</NUMEX>.

            Button
didn't use any of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> radios. He didn't eject. He didn't attempt to land
at any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> he flew over. He didn't turn on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friend</ENAMEX>-or-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foe</ENAMEX>
identification signal to let others track him. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX>'s difficult maneuvers
show that the plane functioned well and that he had full consciousness and
capacity. The autopilot would have been incapable of these maneuvers.
Everything indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Button</ENAMEX> deliberately flew into the mountain.

            
What a strange suicide, though. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX> had
hardly any risk factors. True, he was male (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> attempt suicide more often,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> succeed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times more). And he had long tussled with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jehovah</ENAMEX>'s
Witness <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> over his abandoning the faith (organized religion lowers
suicide rates). But nothing else fit.

            Over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of suicide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> have a history of mental illness (most often depression) or substance
abuse. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX> had neither. On a recent visit to see him, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> thought he
was his energetic, driven self. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> said he was enthusiastic about his
coming assignment to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. He spoke of buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> there and maybe
finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to bring home. He had had girlfriends before, but after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the desert <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Del Rio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, he joked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, "it was slim
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pickings</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The night</TIMEX> before the crash, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> said he'd ordered a large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pizza</ENAMEX> so he'd have leftovers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next night</TIMEX>. During the mission briefing on
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fateful day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX> was "cutting up and making his corny little jokes,"
just as he usually did.

            Button
showed no signs of substance abuse. No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> were found during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autopsy</ENAMEX>. He was in a stressful job, but that alone does not increase suicidal
tendencies. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX> was young, whereas the incidence of suicide increases
with age and is highest among those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 65</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Kelly</ENAMEX> points out, however, that
in rare cases, suicide may not be motivated by emotional pain. For someone who
doesn't attach meaning to death yet, suicide can be a sudden, rash way out of
trouble. Button seemed like such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. It wasn't just that he was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">motorcycle-riding</ENAMEX> fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>. He had a history of foolhardy judgment that
suggested he didn't fully comprehend death's finality. During survival training
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, he was reprimanded for venturing recklessly far into uncharted
wilderness. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, against the rules, he buzzed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Del Rio</ENAMEX> below <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 feet</NUMEX>,
blew a tire attempting a hotshot "short" landing, and left the authorized route
during a cross-country training mission. Button was impulsive, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">thrill-seeker.</ENAMEX>

            When
Button boarded his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> that day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> suggests, suicide probably wasn't his
plan, but his impulsiveness may have steered him into trouble and then into
suicide. It's conceivable that he veered off on a whim. Perhaps he took a short
joy ride or prematurely dropped a bomb (his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500-pound</NUMEX> bombs are still
missing). Whatever the case, with each misstep he dug his hole deeper. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX> flew through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, he may have come to see crashing as a viable way
out because death had no meaning for him.

            
As unusual as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX>'s case is, it shares one
common characteristic with nearly all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> suicides that occur each year
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are not in a rational state of mind. That may
seem an obvious point, but it is one that we often ignore when assisted suicide
is the topic. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Twain</ENAMEX>, who said that "suicide is the only sane thing
the young or old ever do in this life," we imagine that the elderly and the ill
desire death rationally. But our prejudices are showing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Suicidal patients</ENAMEX>,
whatever their age or condition, almost always suffer from addiction or mental
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. Even when they do not, as with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX>, they usually are not thinking
rationally.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suicide</ENAMEX> also shows how, even in peculiar cases, the desire to die arises from
one's individual history and psychology. Yet, in public discussion of youthful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suicide</ENAMEX>, we're often unwilling to trace it to such causes and try to place
blame elsewhere--on television, music, movies. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this month</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
subcommittee considering stricter restrictions on music lyrics heard an
anguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> blame his son's suicide on shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rocker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>'s
music. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> died with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> playing on his headphones. Numerous
studies show that there is no association between music and suicide. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> found
that country-music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> had higher suicide rates, but subsequent research
disputes these results.)

            Of course, ideas do count. We know, for example, that one
adolescent suicide can trigger others, even through media reports, leading to
"suicide clusters." Had later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> not heard about the first suicide, they
may not have done it when they did. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> insist that an idea
cannot compel even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to commit suicide. It is only a proximate factor in
a vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with stronger causes at work.

            Usually, the causes are an
addictive or mental disorder. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Button</ENAMEX>'s case shows how much more complex
they can be. And how bizarre.

         
      
   
