
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centrists</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Progressives</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this month</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership Council</ENAMEX> released a new poll purporting to show that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX>'s "centrist" agenda. This is the latest salvo
in a pissing match that's been going on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> and its
"progressive" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> are
battling over the soul of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>: Should it become more
conservative, or stand resolutely on the left?

            Not
content to argue on merit, each side has hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> to prove its position
is not only right, but also popular. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAF</ENAMEX> has hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Greenberg</ENAMEX>, one of
the "liberal" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> who helped elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and then got the
boot after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> lost big in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> has hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Penn</ENAMEX>, one of
the "moderate" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> who replaced the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and helped
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pollsters</ENAMEX> have a whole bag of tricks with which to conduct
contests like this one. Here's how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> play some of them.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Rig</ENAMEX> the questions. Overt bias, such as
asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whether they oppose "corporate welfare" or "special rights for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>," is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> stuff. The true art is to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the question so deeply that
no one can see it. There are several ways.

            
               Stack
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deck</ENAMEX>. If you're afraid that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't deem the benefit of your
proposal to be worth the cost, don't mention the cost. Example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> asks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whether they'd like to "create" bonds to improve infrastructure. Better
yet, while ignoring the cost of your proposal, assert the cost of the
alternative. Example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> asks, "Do you think it would be better to stay
within the existing [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>] system--for example, raise payroll taxes
and cut benefits--or would it be better to move toward more structural changes
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> like letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> control portions of their own retirement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX>?" While neglecting to mention the risks involved in privatization, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX>
defines the alternative as a tax hike and (not or ) a benefit
cut.

            
Dictate the dilemma. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> says his
policy will achieve a popular goal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force people</ENAMEX> to choose between the policy
and the goal. Example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> asks, "Do you think the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is to
redistribute existing wealth or to foster conditions that enable everyone to
have a chance to make a higher income?" If you favor opportunity for all, you
have to oppose redistribution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> also asks, "Do you think that a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> policy would limit our trade with other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and be protectionist,
or would a better trade policy be more aggressive at opening up markets for our
goods and increasing trade among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>?" If you favor opening foreign
markets, the question <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> you to oppose trade restrictions--even though the
best argument for trade restrictions is that they're necessary to pry open
foreign markets.

            
               Skew the spectrum. To
prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> repeatedly asks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to choose between a left-wing idea, a right-wing idea, and an idea in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>. Guess which idea wins? This is like being asked how you want your
steak cooked: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take the middle option. Much of the dispute between
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAF</ENAMEX> comes down to whether there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> political choices
(left, right) or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> (left, right, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>). By offering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> alternatives,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> poll begs that question. It certainly doesn't address the reality of
the current two-party system.

            
               Define
the alternative. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> why they voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> instead
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. This causes them to focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> themes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
rejected (cuts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, education, and the environment) and overlook the
ones he co-opted (crime, family values, budget-balancing). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> asks people
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s differences with old-style <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. This causes them to
overlook the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> they count on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
defend.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Massage the data. Once the survey is
completed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> can organize the results in a way that favors his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. Since the public favors "moderation" but doesn't agree on what it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entails</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> uses the word without defining it: "Do you generally consider
yourself liberal, moderate, or conservative<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" In answer, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> say they're moderate, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> conservative, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>. From this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> concludes, "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>." It could equally be concluded that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. But since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> has already succeeded in defining
"moderate" as the opposite of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>," its spin prevails.

            Rather than let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> decide
whether they're "moderate," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> offers them various policies and sorts
their answers into categories, defining the "moderate" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as narrowly as
possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who say they chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the basis of his support for
welfare reform, fighting crime, or a balanced budget--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX> of the
sample--are classified as voting for "moderation." Those who chose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
because he supports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, education, or the environment--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59 percent</NUMEX>--are
classified as voting for "domestic programs." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> spins this as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2-to</NUMEX>-1
mandate for liberalism. What about the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> who voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> because
of "his support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> values and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>," or the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> who liked "his
support for tax cuts for college"? Weren't those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> endorsing
"moderation"?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> plays
the same trick in reverse, by inventing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suburban Values</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, who care
primarily about "better, safer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, safer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and the need for
strengthening traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> values." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> distinguishes these "values
issues"--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> leave--from the "economic issues" that supposedly
preoccupy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. These "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suburban Values</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> double the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 percent to 56 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. But aren't education,
family leave, and the breakdown of community "economic" issues? And are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
who worry about such issues really rejecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and liberalism? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX>'s
taxonomy cheats the "liberal" vote just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>'s taxonomy cheats the
"moderate" vote.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 Grease</ENAMEX> the presentation. Any point you
failed to win by rigging the questions and categories can be cleaned up in the
"executive summary" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>'s spin) and the press release and news
conference (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s spin on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>'s spin). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>'s survey, for
example, asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to pick from a list of possible
reasons why they did so. Thirty percent cite, among other reasons, "his support
for education." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAF</ENAMEX> press release, this magically becomes a mandate for
"increased spending on education."

            When the data contradict his
theory, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> knows what he must do: Dump the data. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> have
been peddling the theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did better than congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> because he was less liberal. So in his survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whether
they regard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> as liberal, moderate, or
conservative. Surprise! More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> apply the term "liberal" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> than to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, and more apply the term "conservative" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> than to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. This unfortunate result goes unmentioned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn's</ENAMEX> summary, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX>'s press release begins as though it never happened: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> rank and
file <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> into the vital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> debate, according to a new survey." The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> spin: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Centrist Path: Big Draw Among</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faithful</ENAMEX>."

            The point isn't that polls
are dishonest. The point is that they disguise argument as science. Which has a
curious--and perhaps salutary--effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> skew their politics to suit
the polls. Meanwhile, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> skew the polls to suit their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>'
politics. One profession's sophistry foils the other's cowardice. Just don't
tell them.

         
      
   
