
   
   
      
         
            Strikes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lies</ENAMEX>, and Videotape

            Start with a "union
advocate" celebrating a successful election late-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hoffa</ENAMEX> style, waving a can of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and shouting: "We won, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>! Whoo-hoo!" Proceed through a docudramatic
depiction of an angry strike and a consumer boycott that forces the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to
shut down. End with a union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> standing in front of a shuttered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>,
looking blitzed, and saying, "I guess we showed them."

            Is this
the ultimate <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>-after video, or what?

            The video was produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest Cannon Inc.</ENAMEX>, the
Kannapolis, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of
furniture coverings and textile bath products, and mailed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,500</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> before they were due to vote in a union election
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two weeks ago</TIMEX>. Not surprisingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> ended up voting against
unionization, by a slim margin. After all, no one likes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who yell
"Whoo-hoo!"

            This was
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> election at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, and the first
in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> faced UNITE, the newly invigorated textile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' union
that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 18 months</TIMEX>, has won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> union elections in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX> defeated an organizing drive by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Amalgamated Clothing and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Textile Workers Union</ENAMEX>, but committed innumerable--well, OK, more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>--labor-law violations in doing so, which is why the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th U.S.</ENAMEX>
Circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> eventually got around to ordering a new election. At
this point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX> hopes UNITE will pick up and move away, but that seems
unlikely at best. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> after the election, union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reps</ENAMEX> filed charges with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Labor Relations Board</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. In fact, perhaps in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>
I'll get to write this story all over again. "Just once I'd like to see the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX> say, 'We lost fair and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, and now it's over,' " says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Reece</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on labor relations. "But they never do."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest Cannon</ENAMEX>'s history suggests that, when
it comes to keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> out of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, it's a firm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm X</ENAMEX> approach--use any means necessary. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1991</TIMEX> election, among other
things company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> interrogated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> about their attitudes toward
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, dismissed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, and refused to give union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reps</ENAMEX> access to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>. More interestingly, although this was not held to be a
violation, following the election <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX> gave a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX>-percent raise to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at its nonunion <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> that had just rejected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACTWU</ENAMEX>--while
delaying a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX>-percent raise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at its unionized <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. This was,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX> insisted, a coincidence.

            In all
this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX> builds on a venerable tradition. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> election at its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>, the last paycheck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> received before the vote contained a note
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> telling them that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> was planning to take their money.
In a race at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon Mills</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murdock</ENAMEX>--who had purchased the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>--promised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> that if they supported him by voting against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, he would
support them by keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> independent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> went down in an
overwhelming defeat, at which point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdock</ENAMEX> sold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX>. (He
had already dumped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' pension funds into insurance annuities run by a
company eventually seized by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>.) And if you want to go way
back: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon</ENAMEX> family averted labor unrest by calling in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> and decorating the tops of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> and
barbed wire. Even as most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>'s textile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> walked out,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cannon workers</ENAMEX> stayed put. Seen in this context, what's a mere video
threatening plant closings?

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX> has not kept all except <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of its plants
"union-free" simply by pushing the limits in fighting organizing drives. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> also has benefited from the special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
location adds to those that have eroded labor's strength nationally. Every
state in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> is a right-to-work <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, which means that closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and
union <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are illegal. Much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> industrialization took place outside
metropolitan areas, encouraging development of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>-town mentality and
hindering industry-wide organizing. Kannapolis was owned--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>--by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> until after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            For most
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, in fact, the history of unionism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> was one of
broken strikes, employer violence, and unkept promises. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>, for example,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon Mills</ENAMEX> walked off the job. They returned after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-and-a-half</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Textile Workers Union</ENAMEX> failed to come through with the
food supplies it had promised them. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> launched "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixie</ENAMEX>," an abortive attempt to organize the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>, but it collapsed
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> proved more interested in raiding other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> than in
organizing new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. There's little evidence that an ingrained conservatism
among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> has kept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> out. But it certainly seems true that
the absence of a tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">unionism</ENAMEX> has made it easier for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to play on fears about union corruption and greed, and to suggest
that plant closings are an inevitable consequence of unionization.

            
The question, of course, is whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> should be able to play on those fears. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Labor</ENAMEX>
Relations Act embodies a rather romantic view of democracy, in which workers
coolly consider both sides of the unionization issue and then vote. The problem
is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLRA</ENAMEX>, in a curious way, saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> making that decision primarily
by talking among themselves. The act envisioned the employer standing to one
side as the vote was held, perhaps expressing its opinion but certainly not
playing an active role in shaping the debate (which is simply to say the NLRA
was designed to encourage unionization). When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> want to play that
active role--as, of course, they all do--all sorts of complicated questions
come into play.

            If, for example, a company
wants to argue that unionization will raise labor costs to the point where it
will be forced to shut down operations, should it be allowed to do so? Is it
coercive for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with supervisory authority to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> how they plan to
vote, or for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to give anti-union speeches on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> time? Answering
these questions requires a constant redefinition of the difference between an
argument and a threat. And while there are many situations--like the dismissal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for organizing--where this difference seems inarguably clear,
elsewhere things are fuzzier. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest</ENAMEX> has used that fuzziness to great
advantage. It has, in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Zucker</ENAMEX>, "banged on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>'
fears."

            To say it's banged on them,
of course, is not to say the fears are not real. The striking thing about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' comments after the vote was how many of them mentioned the possibility
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> shutting down its operations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> exist
because textile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> migrated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> in pursuit of low wages, no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and cheaper materials. It's easy for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s textile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to imagine
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> is the next stop on this trip. As it
happens, there's no evidence at all that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldcrest Cannon</ENAMEX> is contemplating
moving manufacturing abroad, or outsourcing. But in this case, I guess,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">videotape</ENAMEX> speaks louder than words.

         
      
   
