
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exit Andy Grove</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> announces he'll be stepping down as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the most powerful chip company
on the planet, and the market doesn't even blink. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> send the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock higher. What's wrong with this picture?

            Actually,
the picture is just fine. In fact, in a curious way, the market's reaction to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Grove</ENAMEX>'s announcement is the best testimony to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s managerial
genius one can imagine. For what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> succeeded in doing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> was this: He
made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> stronger than just him. His superfluity, in that sense,
becomes the measure of his mastery.

            To be sure, "superfluity" overstates the case, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>
will remain at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Barrett</ENAMEX>, who will
become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>, has already been running much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s day-to-day
continue playing a role in shaping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s long-term strategy, presumably
including its heavy investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that are pushing the technological
edge. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s abdication of his throne also loses some drama from the fact that
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> his public image has become that of a long-range <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> rather
than a hands-on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>. Especially since there's no Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> in the
picture.

            Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrett</ENAMEX> was christened the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> apparent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the succession should go
smoothly, and all indications are that he's a more than capable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>.
Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s announcement was certainly a surprise. There was no hint of it
in the press, and he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a couple of years</TIMEX> older than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrett</ENAMEX> (though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>
has had a much publicized bout with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>). But there was nary a ripple of bad
news out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> when the announcement was made, and the sense of seamlessness
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrett</ENAMEX> have projected has transformed the whole thing into an
elegant passing of the torch ceremony.

            
In fact, there's something invigorating about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s decision, precisely because he's going out at the top of his game. For
most of his career at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> was, if not anonymous, then certainly
overshadowed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Moore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Noyce</ENAMEX>, technological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz kids</ENAMEX> who
co-founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. They were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX>, he was the
nuts-and-bolts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three or four years</TIMEX>, though, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retirement</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noyce</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> was able to take on the visionary
role, even as he seems to have made a conscious choice to become a more public
figure. Magazines now wanted to know his thoughts about the future of computing
and the Internet. They became oddly fond of taking pictures in which his body
was occluded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> while his face would be softly spotlit, pictures that
made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> appear to be a mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> thinking very deep thoughts. Which he
probably was.

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transformation</ENAMEX> was also reflected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s writing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX>, he
published an acclaimed engineering text, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physics and Technology</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Semiconductor Devices</ENAMEX> . (That one just missed getting on the best-seller
list.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, he published an exceptional book on management
theory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Output Management</ENAMEX> , which combined a sophisticated
discussion of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> should be organized, with a surprisingly
convincing analysis of how to evaluate and motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> published Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paranoid Survive</ENAMEX> , which lays out a kind of
Schumpeterian theory of major transformations in the business climate and tries
to explain how to deal with them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s basic idea is that there are "strategic inflection
points," moments where the entire framework in which business has been
conducted is transformed and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> must adapt or die. The arrival of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superstores</ENAMEX> in suburbia, the introduction of the stand-alone PC, the advent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">talkies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>: All these were strategic inflection points. In each case,
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that recognized the changes and adjusted to them flourished,
while those that didn't floundered and eventually went under.

            As might
be expected, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s description of past strategic inflection points is more
convincing than his recipe for recognizing such moments in the future. But
what's especially striking is the way in which the evolution of his books--from
engineering to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to theories of change--tracks his evolution as a
public figure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Grove</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX> 
               Output 
               Management
couldn't have been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man of the Year</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Grove</ENAMEX> of Only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paranoid Survive</ENAMEX> could.

            
In that sense, it's hard to see what more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>
had to accomplish as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price isn't at its
all-time high but, in every other way, it's among the most productive,
profitable, and acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the world. (It's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">most-admired-companies</ENAMEX> list.) And without giving too much
weight to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , it's not likely that a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>--other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, of course--is going to garner more mainstream attention than a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man of</ENAMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>" cover. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Williams</ENAMEX> retired after hitting a home run in his last
at-bat. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s doing something similar, except that, thanks to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chairmanship</ENAMEX>, he has the advantage of stepping aside gracefully without really
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disappearing</ENAMEX>.

            Still, there's a certain
irony in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s ascent to elder statesman, because the idea of him as shaper
of the future makes it easy to miss how much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> were products of
what's now described as the corporate past. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is not, after all, a virtual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. It doesn't outsource all its production. It doesn't have a brand name
as its only real asset. It doesn't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in its corporate headquarters
running the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. It's not what management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Peters</ENAMEX> sees
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of the future, a "floating network/crap game." Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
makes real things. It builds enormously expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that employ
blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, even if they are wearing bunny suits. It invests heavily
in research and development. And it is hugely productive, which is to say that
it makes goods that are more valuable--in a real sense--than the sum of the
various things that go into making them.

            To say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> is a
product of the past, then, is to say only that what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> has done at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is
more like what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Sloan</ENAMEX> did at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> than what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> of Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">startups</ENAMEX> think they're doing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s success
under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>, though, should give pause to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of this free-floating,
no-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, no-employee, just-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-agents</ENAMEX> new economy we're supposedly living
in. For what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> has done exceptionally well is manage. What has allowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> to dominate its many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, who are perennially nipping at its
heels with computer chips that are supposedly faster or cheaper, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
does a much better job of making chips reliably and efficiently. And what has
made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> such a stable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> has been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>'s ability
to plan for change and adapt to it while holding the overall framework steady.
The ease of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrett</ENAMEX>'s succession to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> is the ultimate expression of this, of
course. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noyce</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> did before him, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> brilliantly without
making it dependent upon him. He helped fashion an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> bigger than
himself. And that's why there's nothing at all wrong with this picture.

         
      
   
