
   
   
      
         
            An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Awful Lot of Autos</ENAMEX>

            Imagine walking to the edge
of a cliff, looking down, saying to yourself: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, that's a steep drop. It'll
sure hurt if I jump," and then jumping anyway. Such seems to be the curious
strategy of the world auto industry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX>, as it grapples with
prices that are actually declining, demand that's stagnant, and production
capacity that, against all good sense, just keeps getting bigger.

            Now, in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> respect, this anxiety about the auto industry simply reflects the fact that
it has become the poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for a global economy in which deflation is
suddenly everyone's favorite thing to worry about. Even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s supposedly
high-tech world, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> remain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bellwethers</ENAMEX> for the way people
feel about the economy as a whole. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s gas guzzlers
were taken as emblems of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' inability to adjust to the end of
the postwar boom. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of that decade</TIMEX>, nothing made inflation more real
than the phrase "sticker shock." So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the image of assembly lines churning
out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of unneeded and unwanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> is an excellent
representation of the specter of global recession. This is a specter that seems
to loom larger, of course, after the series of currency crises that have beset
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>.

            In another respect, though, concerns about global
overcapacity in auto production are industry-specific and, by most accounts,
well justified. It isn't just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Greiders</ENAMEX> of the world who think that,
in the near future, there are going to be too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>.
Instead, just about everyone thinks this. What's curious is that no one is
really doing anything about it.

            It's true
that overcapacity concerns are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a decade old</TIMEX> (click for a quick review)
and that the predicted crisis of demand has not yet materialized, though
perhaps it has, and I've just seen it as a pleasant period when car prices have
stayed the same instead of rising. That's because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy has
continued to expand so briskly and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three automakers</ENAMEX> have
restructured their operations to do a better job of matching supply with
demand. (In other words, they downsized.) Overcapacity is, in any case,
difficult to measure, since it's more important for car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to be able to
meet increases in demand than it is for them to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only as many</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> want. You can shut down a line for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> without any
problems if demand falls short. You can't build that line from scratch if
demand rises unexpectedly. By some estimates, in fact, overcapacity of a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> is reasonable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three</ENAMEX>.

            
You wouldn't be wrong, then, to see something a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tad Chicken Littleish</ENAMEX> in all this overcapacity talk, especially when it's being
proffered by the very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> building the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for which there is supposedly no
demand. And there is clearly an element of saber rattling on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, which are anxious about the continued impact on their earnings
of the strong dollar and who want <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, in particular, to open its
markets to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three</ENAMEX> sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, out of a total market of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.6 million</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bonneville</ENAMEX> is as rare a
sight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seoul</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aston</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> is here. Emphasizing the global realities of
overexpansion thus becomes a way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three</ENAMEX> to serve their own interests
without seeming parochial.

            And yet
there are those realities, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> is the most remarkable of them. At a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> economy as a whole seems to be in need of dramatic
restructuring precisely around the issue of excessively free credit for capital
expenditures, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are forging ahead with investment
plans that dwarf anything they've previously done. As a whole, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">automakers</ENAMEX> plan to put <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.72 billion</NUMEX> into expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyundai</ENAMEX>--formerly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugo</ENAMEX>'s poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>--is increasing capital spending by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX>
percent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daewoo</ENAMEX> is doubling its investment. And, most incredibly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kia Motors</ENAMEX>,
which needed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> bailout to save it from its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX>, will be
putting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> into plant expansion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, a threefold increase. Oh,
and then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samsung</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of cool stereos and microwaves, which decided
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that it wouldn't be satisfied until it had become a world-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">automaker</ENAMEX>. What about hand-tooled leather bags? They're nice. Couldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samsung</ENAMEX>
have decided to become a world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of hand-tooled leather bags
instead?

            Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s output--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of which will be
exported--is expected to rise <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three years</TIMEX>, while
even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are among the only bright spots in a
forlorn economy, are adding to capacity. And, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX>, even
as they worry about their inability to raise prices, are breaking ground on new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and pushing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to take more and more overtime.

            In that
sense, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> is just a striking example of what's happening all over. And
it is hard, when reading yet another account of an auto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s concerns
about falling prices, not to want to shake him vigorously and say, "Just say
no, damn it!" If there are going to be too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, then it seems sensible to
stop making <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Except, of course, that if you do you lose all hope of
capturing what market does exist, and except, of course, that when you stop
making <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, you have to close <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and throw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of work.

            
It's important to see that the problem here is
not, no matter what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> says, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are overpaid. Nor is
it really that individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> are overstaffed. After all, the Big Three
are enjoying hefty profits and spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> on share-buyback plans. All
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 3.27</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to build a
vehicle--significantly inferior to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> standards but significantly better
than it ever was, and significantly more efficient than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought
possible for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. (And no, I don't know what a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> looks
like.) The problems that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX> endured during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> and 1980s
were, for the most part, self-inflicted, as the superior performance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> automakers over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX> suggests. But the problem that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
automakers face now is of a macroeconomic, not microeconomic, nature, which is
what must make it so difficult for them to accept. It's about the fact that
within a given industry, supply does not ensure demand, and that what is
rational for the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>--which needs to sell as much of its product as
possible and so has to make sure that its product is available--may be
collectively irrational.

            One interesting question
raised by all this is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are commodities. In other words, does the
fact that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kias</ENAMEX> on the road really make someone less
likely to shell out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22,000</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX>? Auto design and advertising are
all about differentiating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> product from another. But all this talk about
global overcapacity suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX> see themselves as all making the
very same thing. I wonder if that'll make me feel better the next time I see
someone blow by me in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche Boxster</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
