
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Laugh</ENAMEX>

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">occasional Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> based on the premise that who wins in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is often determined by how the issue is framed. The author neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endorses</ENAMEX> nor condemns any of the views expressed, however laudatory or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repellent</ENAMEX>.
            

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
finished? Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> think so. Evidence suggests that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> committed and suborned perjury in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>,
they say, demands that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> be held accountable to the law.

            It's a
perfectly logical argument. But so what? In politics, logic is just a small
part of the art of framing. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> reason carefully about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>, honesty, and criminal behavior, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is playing an entirely
different game. He is turning the scandal into a debate about sex, political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warfare</ENAMEX>, and the disruption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s business. That's how he's going to
survive.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perjury</ENAMEX> vs. sex: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case to be about perjury and cover-up. He
took it up, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> approved his investigation, because
what had happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> found her a plum job after she
thwarted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' efforts to incriminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--eerily resembled what had
happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Whitewater-</ENAMEX>scandal figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>. Through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
hoped to unravel a pattern of cover-up. Indeed, he hoped to wire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and
thereby catch <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>--and perhaps even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--asking her to lie.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> never got his chance.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story leaked, and the press besieged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> with questions about the alleged affair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> initially preserved
an air of dignity by couching their questions in terms of perjury, but they
soon tossed aside that fig leaf and pounced on the subject everyone wanted to
know about: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> have sex? If so, what kind? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCurry</ENAMEX>
answered evasively, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX>. By
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX>, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was gossiping about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">randy president</ENAMEX> and the
nubile intern.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
issued a statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> denying that he had encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to lie.
With that, the question of perjury vanished, trampled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s sexual
feeding frenzy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reporters hounded McCurry</ENAMEX> about details of the alleged affair
and nuances in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s denials. Network-news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-morning</TIMEX>
moderators parsed the semantics of oral sex. Reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had confessed
to an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> compounded the titillation.

            
All these tales about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">humiliating</ENAMEX>, but they won't get him booted from office. Polls show that the
public is far less willing to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for having an affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> than for committing or suborning perjury about it. What's more,
outrage over consensual sex is unsustainable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> soon tires of the
subject. Disgust with the sordid sex curdles into disgust with the sordid
investigation and coverage of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> have accelerated this
spin cycle, accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> of launching what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>
calls "a scuzzy investigation" to dig up "some kind of sleazy sex."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
has to explain or repent his sexual sins. But maybe the public doesn't need to
forgive or understand them. Maybe it just needs to get used to them, as it has
done before. "Everybody knew" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was an adulterer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, argued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week With Sam and Cokie</ENAMEX> ,
responding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Begala</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
not because he was "pure" but because he had "good ideas" that are helping the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Who cares if he's taken another spill off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">chastity wagon</ENAMEX>? All this
talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> sex is already losing its shock value. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> are
pointing out that lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> fooled around, that not one of them was
impeached for it, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of many other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> don't care about
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>.

            Now that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair has been reduced from a perjury scandal to a sex scandal,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> can shut the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> door on it. "The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who count in
any marriage are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that are in it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> argued on the Today
show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>. "We know everything there is to know about each other, and we
understand and accept and love each other." Unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> manages to push the
perjury issue back to center stage, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s defense of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> will
stifle the public's appetite for further investigation.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Legal inquiry vs. political war: Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is doomed assume that he eventually has to tell
the truth about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Says who? A political scandal
isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Socratic</ENAMEX>, scientific, or legal investigation. To get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to stop
asking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't have to give them the truth, he just has
to tire them out. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> call this their "rope-a-dope" strategy,
referring to the boxing tactic of shielding your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with your gloves and
making your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> exhaust himself by uselessly pummeling you against the
ropes. It's effective. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Begala</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
times whether an extramarital physical relationship was improper. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> times,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Begala</ENAMEX> responded by making the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in his own terms. Eventually,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> gave up.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> have
also taken the heat off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by defining the investigation as a political
fight, obliging the press to scrutinize both sides equally. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Johnnie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> are putting the prosecution on trial. Carville
launched the attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, he declared all-out "war"
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp. "The real focus here is on the methods
[and] motives of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carville</ENAMEX>, accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> of
"wiring" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and plying them with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "a politically motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who is allied
with the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX> have linked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr to Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>, and other bogeymen. Polls indicate that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is buying this argument. A plurality blames the scandal on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The war metaphor has changed
the nature of media coverage. Investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> strive for truth, but
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> strive for balance. As political accusations against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
and the right have escalated, the press has devoted a greater share of its
scandal coverage to questioning the methods and motives of those who gathered
the evidence against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. And ethics aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> like to prolong
fights by keeping them even. The more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is afflicted, the more the press
comforts him by afflicting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            The
psychology of war also causes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to focus less on each side's evidence
than on its posture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX> denial of the sex allegations added
nothing but anger to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 21</TIMEX> denial, yet the press called it more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuasive</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> reflexively
expressed confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s denials, their assurances were portrayed as
bolstering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX> requested that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> trial begin sooner than scheduled, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> construed it as a
display of confidence.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>: To deprive
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> of the political fight they crave, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have kept quiet
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case and confined their comments to topics such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>,
taxes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. But this plays into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> strategy. Even
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> focuses public attention on the perjury issue and represents his
investigation as a search for truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can defeat him by persuading the
public--without explicitly saying so--that impeaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for perjury
in a civil suit is less important than getting on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s business.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> put it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX>, "These allegations are false. And I need to go
back to work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> will milk the sex
scandal for as long as possible, but the relentless influx of new issues works
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s favor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wouldn't be able to pull off his
State of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech with the scandal hanging over him. He proved them
wrong and in the process pushed the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> to center stage.
Military confrontation with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> would instantly supplant the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story
and would convert <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s image from lecher to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

            Idealists
think the public won't accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s disjunction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> and
business, between his private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> and his public service. But polls show that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> does accept the disjunction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s job-approval rating has held
steady even as his personal favorability and trustworthiness ratings have
declined. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will overlook his squalid conduct because he makes the
trains run on time. They're not going to "shut down the recovery," suggested
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Begala</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, just "to start asking about whether somebody made a phone
call." How cynical. And how true.

         
      
   
