
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airline Deregulation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair-Weather Friends</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two decades</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> deregulated the airline industry, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> are starting
to sound more than a bit like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Augustine</ENAMEX>: "Give us competition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>! But
not yet!"

            The drive to freeze out
competition can be seen most obviously in the new mergers and alliances that
are shrinking the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> serving any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>
is trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> approval for an alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airways</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX>--already partnered with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> airline
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLM</ENAMEX>--recently announced plans for an alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental Airlines</ENAMEX>.
(Alliances provide many of the benefits of mergers--added routes, global
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">connections</ENAMEX>, oligopoly pricing--without a lot of the costs. In a different age,
they might have been called minicartels.) And it seems likely that the next few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> will see a continued industry consolidation.

            Less
obvious but more telling evidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>' resistance to real competition
can be found in their massive lobbying efforts to protect their current
positions. Those efforts are needed because, despite the seemingly inexorable
drive toward oligopoly in the industry, low-priced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> keep springing
up to try to take away their business. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> for these startups is the
remarkable success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Airlines</ENAMEX>. It has been able to turn flights that
are low on frills but high on goofiness (flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> singing, dumb
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contests</ENAMEX>, and all the rest) into a gold mine by keeping costs low and poaching
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>' business on particular routes. Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air and Legend Airlines</ENAMEX> are trying to carve out regional niches within
which they can challenge the industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to deal with these annoying little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gnats</ENAMEX> is simply to acquire them, though that runs the risk of bringing the
antitrust bloodhounds snooping around. Another option is to turn them into
"feeder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>," which allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> to offer service from major hubs to
smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> choice is simply to freeze the upstarts out by
keeping them off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runways</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> have most takeoff and landing
slots at good-size <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> safely within their grasp.

            At
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O'Hare Airport</ENAMEX>, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> together control <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX>
percent of flights. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> together will own <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of
the air traffic at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83 percent</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Air Lines</ENAMEX>
enjoys a dominant position in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> has a near monopoly on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dallas-Fort Worth</ENAMEX>. There is a certain logic to this arrangement--with the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> flying to any one location relatively limited, engaging in
cutthroat competition in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> makes less sense for the majors than
parceling out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> among themselves. And most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> do fly to nearly
ever major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, though perhaps not exactly when you want them to.

            
However much sense the hub system makes from a
market-protecting angle and as an efficient means of routing air traffic, its
anti-competitive consequences are undeniable. While deregulation undoubtedly
has been a good thing overall, and while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-saver</ENAMEX> fares are often
astonishingly low, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX> have seen a dramatic rise in the price of
tickets purchased without any advance notice (what they call business fares,
since only business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> can afford them). By some accounts, business
fares are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 30 percent</NUMEX> higher than they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two years ago</TIMEX>.

            That's
not because it's become more expensive to carry business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, either. In
fact, since ticketing systems have become more sophisticated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> can do a
much better job of managing demand and filling seats. But those savings have
not been passed along to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Instead, since the supply of airline seats
is limited, as demand rises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> are able to charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> more--at
least those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who absolutely, positively have to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

            
In theory, of course, this oligopoly pricing
should conjure new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> into existence, bringing supply more in line with
demand and eventually harmonizing fares with costs. But there are a number of
things preventing that from happening. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, the creation of
frequent-flyer programs has let the rich get richer, in the sense that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> only reap the benefits of those programs if they fly the same airline
each time. More importantly, the physical universe limits the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">takeoffs</ENAMEX> and landings any single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> can handle in a day. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> have a
stranglehold on those slots, and they've invested a lot of energy and money in
ensuring that they continue to own them.

            There is
another choice, which is that entire new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> could spring up, or smaller
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">airports</ENAMEX> could expand. But here, too, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> have been vigilant. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dallas-Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> has fought fiercely against the
proposed expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love Field</ENAMEX> (where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> landed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1963</TIMEX>).
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wright Amendment</ENAMEX> (sponsored by that paragon of
legislative propriety, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Wright</ENAMEX>) kept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> from flying out
of Love to anywhere but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
passed a law adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to that list and letting small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>
seats or less) fly anywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dallas-Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, backed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, immediately sued everyone involved, even as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ran newspaper
ads warning of "intense congestion," "lots of delays" and, more audaciously,
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Texas</ENAMEX> economy will be less vigorous than it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." How
adding low-fare flights explicitly targeting business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> was going to
cripple the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> economy was not made precisely clear.

            
What the Love-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> fight has made
clear is the basic disingenuousness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> when it comes to
deregulation. While they have pushed hard for "open skies" policies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and lobbied hard against government antitrust intervention, they
have been more than happy to use the legislative process to protect what amount
to sinecures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Field imbroglio</ENAMEX>, in fact, has presented the curious
spectacle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> arguing that increased
competition will threaten the region's economic health, an odd conclusion from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' most fervent supporter of free markets.

            Still, the disingenuousness
is, in a sense, inherent in the industry itself, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> rely on public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">airspace</ENAMEX> and, for the most part, public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> for their business. And this
makes the whole question of what constitutes regulation a complicated one. One
solution being proposed, for instance, would take some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landing</ENAMEX> and takeoff
slots at major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> away from the industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> and auction them off to
smaller, low-fare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>. Now, is that deregulation, or is it re-regulation?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> insist it's the latter. But insofar as dispersing the slots would
foster competition, a strong case can be made that it's the former. Either way,
it's a plan that makes sense.

            Because air space is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>, there's an inclination to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> are natural monopolies
or oligopolies and that flooding the market with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> will actually make
air travel less, not more, efficient. But the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> are a
long way from being saturated in terms of possible routes, and whenever
low-fare <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> arrive, costs quickly drop. More to the point, even as the
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> have been reaping large profits over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>, their
productivity has not risen at all, suggesting that consolidation is not
improving efficiency. It's no surprise that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> want open skies when it
suits them and closed skies when it doesn't. But real competition should
be the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th -anniversary</NUMEX> gift bestowed on these fair-weather friends
of deregulation.

         
      
   
